<bill session="104" type="hj" number="122" updated="2012-11-01T22:45:55-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Continuing Appropriation (fourth)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406863"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on House Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T20:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 270 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 122 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T21:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 270 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T21:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 270. (CR H12490)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12490" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T21:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 122 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T21:35:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T23:10:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T23:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T23:11:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Obey motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T23:26:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T23:45:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 187 - 241 (Roll no. 801). (CR H12503)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12503" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-11-16T00:04:00-05:00">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 277 - 151 (Roll no. 802).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T00:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate. (CR S17103-17147, S17170-17178)</text>
      <reference ref="CR S17103-17147, S17170-17178" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 3055 proposed by Senator Daschle.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Motion to table SP 3055 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 53-46. Record Vote No: 577.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 3056 proposed by Senator Hollings.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Motion to table SP 3056 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 53-46. Record Vote No: 578.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 3057 proposed by Senator Daschle.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Motion to table SP 3057 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 52-45. Record Vote No: 580.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 60-37. Record Vote No: 581.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Senate vitiated previous passage. By unanimous consent. (CR S17487)</text>
      <reference ref="CR S17487" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent. (CR S17487-17489)</text>
      <reference ref="CR S17487-17489" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Amendment SP 3062 proposed by Senator Dole.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Amendment SP 3062 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20T14:59:00-05:00">
      <text>CONSIDERATION OF LEGISLATION - Mr. Livingston asked unanimous consent that it be in order to take from the Speaker's table the joint resolution H.J. Res. 122, with the Senate amendment thereto, and to consider in the House a motion offered by the Chairman of the Committee on Appropriations to dispose of the Senate amendment, that the Senate amendment and motion shall be considered as read, that the motion shall be debatable for one hour equally divided and controlled by the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee, and that the previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to final adoption without intervening motion. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20T14:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Livingston asked unanimous consent that if a recorded vote is ordered, or the yeas and nays are ordered, or a vote is objected to under clause 4 of rule XV, on the question of adopting the motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment to H.J. Res. 122, then the Chair may postpone further proceedings on that question until a later time or place in the legislative schedule of the current legislative day, and may resume such proceedings as though postponed pursuant to clause 5(b) of rule I. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20T15:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to a previous special order the House moved to agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20T15:02:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion to agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20T15:02:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20T16:15:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the motion to agree to the Senate amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the motion was agreed to. Mr. Obey objected to the vote on grounds that a quorum was not present and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to an previous order of the House, further proceedings on the motion were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1995-11-20T18:29:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by recorded vote: 421 - 4, 1 Present (Roll no. 821). (CR  H13629-13630)</text>
      <reference ref="CR  H13629-13630" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20T18:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1995-11-20">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-56.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Administrative Conference of the U.S."/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget reconciliation"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economic conditions"/>
    <term name="Economic forecasting"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Interstate Commerce Commission"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Tax policy"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban renewal"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Welfare reform"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>11/19/1995--Passed Senate amended.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;(There is 1 &lt;a href="/cgi-bin/bdquery/z?d104:HJ00122:@@@D&amp;summ1&amp;"&gt;other summary&lt;/a&gt;).
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Continuing Appropriations Title II: (Unnamed) Title I: Continuing Appropriations - (Sec. 101) Makes further continuing appropriations for FY 1996 for continuing projects and activities, including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees, conducted in 1995 and for which appropriations or other authority would be available in the following Acts: (1) the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996; (2) the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 1996; (3) the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1996; (4) the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1996; (5) the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996; (6) the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996; (7) the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1996; (8) the Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 1996; (9) the Treasury, Postal Service, and General Government Appropriations Act, 1996; and (10) the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996. Sets the rates of such funding. Sets forth limitations on the use of such funds. (Sec. 106) Provides that, unless otherwise provided for in this joint resolution or in the applicable appropriations Act, appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this joint resolution shall be available until whichever of the following occurs first: (1) enactment of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution; (2) the enactment of the applicable appropriations Act by both Houses without any provision for such project or activity; or (3) December 15, 1995. (Sec. 111) Provides in specified circumstances, except for section 106, for the maintenance of a minimal level of funding for projects or activities under any Act listed in section 101. Defines minimal level. (Sec. 112) Requires, except for section 106 and under specified conditions, that whenever the rate for operations for any continuing project or activity would result in a furlough of Government employees, that rate for operations may be increased to a minimum level that would enable the furlough to be avoided. (Sec. 113) Requires, except for sections 106, 111, and 112, that for those programs that had high initial rates of operation or complete distribution of funding at the beginning of FY 1995 because of distributions of funding to States, foreign countries, grantees, or others, similar distributions of funds for FY 1996 shall not be made and no grants shall be awarded for such programs funded by this resolution that would impinge on final funding prerogatives. (Sec. 115) Provides that section 132 of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act of 1988 (which provides that amounts appropriated for the Federal Payment to the District of Columbia shall not be subject to apportionment) shall not apply for this joint resolution. Provides for including in the apportionment for the Federal Payment to the District of Columbia an additional $16,575,016 for reimbursement to the United States for funds loaned for specified capital improvement projects. (Sec. 116) Requires, except for section 106, that the authority and conditions for the application of appropriations of the Office of Technology Assessment as contained in House Report 104-212, shall be followed when applying the funding made available by this joint resolution. (Sec. 119) Requires, except for section 106, the Securities and Exchange Commission's Salaries and Expenses amount to include, in addition to direct appropriations, the amount it collects under the fee rate and offsetting collection authority. (Sec. 120) Requires that funding be made available for the necessary expenses of the Bureau of Mines for: (1) continuing limited health and safety and related research, materials partnerships, and minerals information activities; (2) mineral assessments in Alaska; and (3) terminating all other activities of the Bureau of Mines. (Sec. 121) Requires, except for section 106, that funds for the Environmental Protection Agency shall be made available in the appropriation accounts which are provided in H.R. 2099 as reported on September 13, 1995. (Sec. 122) Sets forth a special formula for determining the rate of operations for projects and activities that would be funded under the heading "International Organizations and Conferences, Contributions to International Organizations" in the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996. (Sec. 123) Provides, except for section 106, that the rate for operations of the following projects or activities shall be only the minimum necessary to accomplish orderly termination: (1) Administrative Conference of the United States; (2) Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations (with an exception); (3) Interstate Commerce Commission; (4) Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation; (5) Land and Water Conservation Fund, State Assistance; and (6) Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, Rural Abandoned Mine Program. (Sec. 124) Directs that: (1) any Federal employees furloughed as a result of a lapse in appropriations, if any, after midnight November 13, 1995, until the enactment of this Act shall be compensated at their standard rate of compensation for the period during which there was a lapse in appropriations; and (2) all obligations incurred in anticipation of the appropriations made and authority granted by this Act for the purposes of maintaining the essential level of activity to protect life and property and bring about orderly termination of Government functions are hereby ratified and approved if otherwise in accord with the provisions of this Act. Title II: Waives parchment printing requirements of the enrollment of: (1) a continuing resolution; (2) a debt limit extension measure; and (3) a reconciliation bill. (Sec. 202) Sets forth the definitions of terms used in this joint resolution. (Sec. 203) States that the President and the Congress: (1) shall enact legislation in the first session of the 104th Congress to achieve a unified balanced budget not later than FY 2002 as estimated by the Congressional Budget Office; (2) agree that the balanced budget must protect future generations, ensure Medicare solvency, reform welfare, and provide adequate funding for Medicaid, education, agriculture, national defense, veterans, and the environment. States further that the balanced budget shall adopt tax policies to help working families and to stimulate future economic growth. Requires the balanced budget agreement to be estimated by the Congressional Budget Office based on its most recent current economic and technical assumptions, following a thorough consultation and review with the Office of Management and Budget, and other Government and private experts.</summary>
</bill>
