<bill session="105" type="h" number="220" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lending Enhancement Through Necessary Due Process Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to clarify the due process protections applicable to directors and officers of insured depository institutions and other institution-affiliated parties, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Bank directors"/>
    <term name="Bank employees"/>
    <term name="Bank fraud"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economic conditions"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Lending Enhancement Through Necessary Due Process Act - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to make the following affirmative defenses available to a director, officer, or institution-affiliated party of an insured depository institution facing a civil action before a Federal court or banking agency: (1) business judgment; (2) regulatory approval; and (3) unforeseeable economic conditions. Sets forth a minimum standard for the order of production of personal financial information by a regulatory agency or court. Declares the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure applicable to Federal banking regulatory agencies with respect to prejudgment attachment of assets. Prohibits the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation from bringing a civil action under State law against an officer or director of an insured depository institution for monetary damages for losses due to a disregard of a duty of care unless the State standard for such duty is as great or greater than the Federal standard.</summary>
</bill>
