<bill session="106" type="hr" number="417" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives concerning the participation of the extremist FPO in the government of Austria.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2000-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H223-224"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H517"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Ambassadors"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Austria"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commercial blacklisting"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="EEC countries"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Extremist movements in politics"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Norway"/>
    <term name="Parliamentary government"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Racism"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2000--Introduced.
Recognizes the right of the Austrian people to express their political views through a democratic election, but reaffirms the right and obligation of the U.S. House of Representatives to express its opposition to the anti-democratic, racist, and xenophobic views that have been expressed by Joerg Haider and other leaders of the FPO and to state its opposition to the party's participation in the Austrian Government.Condemns the insulting, racist, and xenophobic statements which have been made over many years by Haider and other leaders of the party. Expresses regret and dismay that the FPO under Haider's leadership will play a major role in the new Austrian Government. Commends the leaders of the European Union (EU), the 14 other member states of the EU, Canada, Norway, and other countries which have expressed their serious concerns regarding the participation of the FPO in such Government.Calls upon: (1) the President, the Secretary of State, and other U.S. Government officials and agencies to emphasize to Austrian Government officials the dissatisfaction with the inclusion of the FPO in the Government by not promoting or accepting any official contacts at a political level with officials of that Government which includes the FPO, by giving no support to Austrian candidates seeking positions in international organizations, and by receiving Austrian ambassadors only at a technical level; (2) Members of Congress to refuse to meet with ministers and other political leaders of the Austrian Government and to refuse to meet with members of the Austrian Parliament who are members of the parties participating in the governing coalition; and (3) the American people and others to show their strong disapproval of FPO participation in the Austrian governing coalition by refusing to travel to Austria, use Austrian products and services (including Austrian airlines), or invest in Austrian businesses.</summary>
</bill>
