<bill session="105" type="h" number="1470" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transportation Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To empower States with authority for most taxing and spending for highway programs and mass transit programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400590"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400510" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400300" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1997-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="667"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="667"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economic forecasting"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to territories"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Highway planning"/>
    <term name="Highway research"/>
    <term name="Highway use tax"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental tax relations"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Limited access highways"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/1997--Introduced.
Transportation Empowerment Act - Authorizes appropriations out of the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) for the interstate maintenance program, the interstate and Indian reservation bridge program, the Federal lands highways program, public lands highways, parkways and park roads, highway safety programs, and highway safety research and development, through FY 2002. Amends provisions regarding transferability of funds to authorize a State, upon determining that excess funds have been made available to the State for a purpose, to transfer the excess funds to, and use such funds for, any surface transportation purpose (including mass transit and rail) in the State. Specifies that if the Secretary determines that a State has transferred funds to a purpose that is not a surface transportation purpose, the amount of the improperly transferred funds shall be deducted from any amount the State would otherwise receive from HTF for the next fiscal year. Repeals provisions regarding the apportionment formula for resurfacing, restoring, rehabilitating, and reconstructing the Interstate System and sets forth provisions regarding the apportionment of funds to the States for interstate maintenance. Authorizes appropriations for motor carrier safety grants. Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to: (1) extend until October 1, 2002, the availability of HTF funds for authorized expenditures; (2) set a core programs financing rate for gasoline, special motor fuels, and diesel fuel; (3) establish in HTF an Infrastructure Special Assistance Fund; and (4) provide for the return of excess tax receipts to States for transportation purposes. Terminates transfers to HTF's Mass Transit Account on and after October 1, 1997. (Sec. 6) Grants congressional consent to States to enter into interstate compacts to: (1) promote the continuity, quality, and safety of the Interstate System; (2) develop programs to promote and fund surface transportation safety initiatives and establish surface transportation safety standards; (3) conduct long-term planning for surface transportation infrastructure in, and develop design and construction standards for such infrastructure to be used by, participating States; and (4) establish surface transportation infrastructure banks. Sets forth provisions regarding financing and authority of infrastructure banks. (Sec. 7) Requires the head of each executive agency to: (1) assist State and local governments in efforts to privatize the transportation infrastructure assets of the State and local governments; and (2) approve requests from State and local governments to privatize transportation infrastructure assets and waive or modify any condition relating to the original Federal program that funded the asset. Sets forth provisions regarding criteria for approval of requests, the lack of a State or local obligation to repay Federal grant funds for assets that are privatized, the use of proceeds from the privatization of a transportation infrastructure asset, and cost recovery. (Sec. 8) Amends the IRC to reduce taxes on gasoline, diesel fuel, and special fuels funding HTF. (Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 10) Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress describing necessary technical and conforming amendments. (Sec. 11) Makes this Act contingent upon certification by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget that this Act is deficit neutral and meets specified requirements regarding discretionary spending limits.</summary>
</bill>
