<bill session="105" type="h" number="493" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:33-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bipartisan Campaign Reform Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to reform the financing of Federal elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400568" joined="1997-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1997-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="1997-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="1998-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="402284" joined="1997-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1997-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1997-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1997-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400584" joined="1997-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="1997-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1997-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1997-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1997-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1997-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1997-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1997-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1997-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400508" joined="1997-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1997-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1997-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1997-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1997-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="1997-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1997-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400607" joined="1997-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="1997-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="410067" joined="1997-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1997-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1997-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="1997-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1997-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1997-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSIF" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" name="House Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election fraud"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government employees' political activities"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political consultants"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Primaries"/>
    <term name="Pro-choice movement"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>01/21/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: House of Representatives Election Spending Limits and Benefits Title II: Reduction of Special Interest Influence Subtitle A: Limitations on Political Action Committees and Large Contributions of Individuals Subtitle B: Provisions Relating to Soft Money of Political Parties Subtitle C: Soft Money of Persons Other than Political Parties Subtitle D: Contributions Subtitle E: Additional Prohibitions on Contributions Subtitle F: Coordinated and Independent Expenditures Title III: Enforcement and Disclosure Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions Bipartisan Campaign Reform Act of 1997 - Title I: House of Representatives Election Spending Limits and Benefits - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to make candidates for election to the House of Representatives eligible to receive benefits under this Act if they declare that they will not exceed expenditure or contribution limits. Sets forth expenditure limits of $600,000 by a candidate and authorized committees, allowing additional expenditures for: (1) runoffs and contested primaries; and (2) complying candidates running against noncomplying candidates. Entitles eligible candidates to receive certain broadcast media rates and reduced postage rates. Directs the Federal Election Commission (Commission) to certify a candidate who has met the requirements of this title as eligible for benefits under such title. Requires repayment of benefits by a candidate whose certification has been revoked. Sets forth laddered civil penalties for excess expenditures. (Sec. 102) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to: (1) provide for preemption only in situations beyond a station's control; and (2) extend the license revocation provision for failure to provide cable access. (Sec. 104) Amends FECA to set contribution limits for eligible House candidates. (Sec. 105) Sets forth expenditure reporting requirements. Title II: Reduction of Special Interest Influence - Subtitle A: Limitations on Political Action Committees and Large Contributions of Individuals - Amends FECA to modify political action committee contribution limits. Prohibits leadership committees. (Sec. 202) Limits the aggregate amount of large contributions to congressional campaigns. Subtitle B: Provisions Relating to Soft Money of Political Parties - Amends FECA with respect to "soft money" to: (1) prohibit a national committee of a political party (including specified related entities) from soliciting or receiving contributions or making expenditures not subject to such Act; (2) require a State, district, or local committee of a political party to make Federal election year expenditures (with exceptions) from funds subject to such Act; (3) prohibit a national, State, district, or local committee from soliciting or donating funds to a nonprofit organization; and (4) prohibit an incumbent or candidate for Federal office from soliciting or receiving funds not subject to such Act, or solicit or receive funds for a non-Federal election in excess of certain limits or from prohibited sources (with exceptions for State or local candidates in compliance with State law). (Sec. 212) Increases limits on individual contributions to national political parties. (Sec. 213) Imposes or modifies political committee reporting requirements. (Sec. 214) Removes the exclusion of office facility construction or purchase contributions from the definition of "contribution." Subtitle C: Soft Money of Persons Other Than Political Parties - Imposes reporting requirements regarding disbursements over $2,000 by a person other than a political party committee or a candidate. Subtitle D: Contributions - Revises requirements regarding contributions made through an intermediary or conduit. Subtitle E: Additional Prohibitions on Contributions - Prohibits: (1) a person not eligible to register to vote in a Federal election from contributing or promising to contribute in such an election; and (2) a person from accepting or soliciting such a contribution. Subtitle F: Coordination and Independent Expenditures - Revises the definition of "independent expenditure." (Sec. 252) Treats: (1) payments coordinated with a candidate, agent, or committee, as contributions; and (2) certain payments and communications containing express advocacy as expenditures. (Sec. 254) Sets forth related reporting requirements. Title III: Enforcement and Disclosure - Amends FECA to provide for: (1) random compliance audits; (2) certain reporting on an election cycle rather than a calendar year basis; (3) consulting service disclosure; (4) injunction and litigation authority for the Commission; (5) Commission member term limits; (6) expedited Commission procedures and increased penalties for violations of such Act; and (7) mandatory (with exceptions) electronic filing of Commission reports. Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions - Amends FECA to restrict the use of campaign funds for personal purposes. (Sec. 402) Sets forth political advertising provisions for print and broadcast or cablecast communications. (Sec. 406) Restricts political committee insolvency actions to Commission proceedings. (Sec. 407) Directs the Commission to promulgate regulations concerning the use of non-Federal money. (Sec. 408) Prohibits franked mass mailings by a Member in his or her election year. (Sec. 411) Provides for expedited and mandatory Supreme Court review of any appeal of any interlocutory order or final court action on the constitutionality of any provision of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
