<bill session="105" type="h" number="3212" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Court of Veterans Appeals Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to revise the provisions of law relating to retirement of judges of the United States Court of Veterans Appeals, to provide for a staggered judicial retirement option, to rename the Court as the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400504"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1998-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10">
      <text>See H.R.4110.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="4110"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Assassination"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Administrative Provisions Relating to the Court Title II: Staggered Retirement and Recall Provisions Title III: Renaming of Court Court of Veterans Appeals Act of 1988 - Title I: Administrative Provisions Relating to the Court - Authorizes the Court of Veterans Appeals (Court) to prescribe rules and regulations. Requires six months or more served as a Court judge to be credited toward years of service and less than six months to not be credited. Allows for a cost-of-living adjustment to the retired pay of a Court judge only up to an amount that would make such retired pay equal to the pay received by a current Court judge. Allows a Court judge to elect to participate in a survivor annuity within six months after marriage if such judge has retired. Reduces the percentage of pay reduction required of active judges as contributions toward retirement annuities. Prohibits interest payments on retirement pay deductions in the case of Court judges for any period during which such judges: (1) were separated from judicial service or service as a Member of Congress or congressional employee; and (2) were not receiving retired pay or annuities based on such service. Allows a survivor annuity to be paid to the survivors of a judge who dies after having rendered at least 18 months (currently five years) of creditable civilian service. Allows a survivor annuity without a creditable service requirement in the case of a judge who dies of an assassination. Repeals a current requirement that a surviving spouse be at least 50 years of age before receiving such annuity. Increases such annuities at the same time and by the same percentage by which annuities payable from the Judicial Survivors' Annuity Fund are increased. Exempts the Court of Veterans Appeals Retirement Fund from sequestration under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act). Provides a forfeiture of retired pay rights and benefits in the case of any Court judge who, after retirement, represents a client in a claim relating to veterans' benefits. Title II: Staggered Retirement and Recall Provisions - Allows only one individual each year to retire as a Court judge in the years 1999 through 2003. Provides retirement requirements, including age and years of service. Requires a judge to: (1) notify the President and the Court's chief judge of the intent to retire; and (2) retire during the fiscal year in which notification is provided but not earlier than 90 days after such notification is provided. Makes a retired Court judge eligible for recall upon providing the chief judge with written notification. Allows the chief judge to recall such a judge to meet the needs of the Court. Title III: Renaming of Court- Renames the Court as the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.</summary>
</bill>
