<bill session="104" type="hc" number="121" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Urging the President of the United States to seek negotiations with the Republic of Ireland, the United Kingdom, the European Union, and international financial institutions for the purpose of establishing an Ireland Development Bank.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services. subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Capital formation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Great Britain"/>
    <term name="Ireland"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Northern Ireland"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/1995--Introduced.
Urges the President to seek negotiations with the Republic of Ireland, the United Kingdom, the European Union, and international financial institutions to establish an Ireland Development Bank to raise capital for economic development and job creation in the Republic of Ireland, especially the six border counties, and the six counties of Northern Ireland, through the issuance of Ireland Peace Bonds, the proceeds of which would be used to provide supplemental loans and loan guarantees for businesses underserved by other financial institutions.</summary>
</bill>
