<bill session="108" type="h" number="2257" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lower Yellowstone Reclamation Projects Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To convey the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project, the Savage Unit of the Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin Program, and the Intake Irrigation Project to the appurtenant Irrigation Districts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400335"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation districts"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2003--Introduced.
Lower Yellowstone Reclamation Projects Conveyance Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey the works, facilities, and lands of the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project, the Intake Project in Montana, and the Savage Unit of the Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin Program to the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Districts No. 1 (Montana) and No. 2 (North Dakota), the Intake Irrigation District (Montana), and the Savage Irrigation District (Montana), respectively, pursuant to the terms of the Memorandum of Understanding of November 16, 1999, between the Districts and the Bureau of Reclamation. Requires: (1) all conveyances under this Act, except the Diversion Works (land and the diversion dam structure, canal headworks, and first section of the mail canal) to be conveyed in the first stage; and (2) the Diversion Works to be conveyed in the second stage..Requires the Districts to buy Reclamation withdrawn lands as identified in the Memorandum for their value in providing operation and maintenance benefits.Conditions the conveyance on the Secretary requiring payment of: (1) an amount equal to the present value of the remaining water supply repayment obligation from the Savage Irrigation District as full payment of such District's share of the construction of the Savage Unit; and (2) a specified amount from the Pick Sloan Missouri Basin Program (Eastern Division) power customers as full payment for the construction aid-to-irrigation associated with Unit facilities.Conditions the conveyance on the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Districts conveying a perpetual conservation easement to the State of Montana for the purposes of protecting, preserving, and enhancing the conservation values and permitting recreation on Federal lands to be conveyed under this Act. Sets forth requirements regarding: (1) continuation of Pick-Sloan Program irrigation components and pumping power service; and (2) Yellowstone River fisheries protection.</summary>
</bill>
