<bill session="105" type="h" number="3748" updated="2012-11-01T22:49:10-05:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FEC Reauthorization Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">FEC Reauthorization Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to authorize appropriations for the Federal Election Commission for fiscal year 1999, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 6 - 3.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-25T18:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on House Oversight. H. Rept. 105-606.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-25T18:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 342.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election fraud"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>06/25/1998--Reported to House amended.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;(There is 1 &lt;a href="/cgi-bin/bdquery/z?d105:HR03748:@@@D&amp;summ1&amp;"&gt;other summary&lt;/a&gt;).
FEC Reauthorization Act of 1998 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to authorize appropriations for the Federal Election Commission for FY 1999. Conditions availability of a specified amount of such funds on the Commission adopting a re-prioritization plan for improving enforcement procedures and preventing the unnecessary dismissal of appropriate enforcement actions. Provides for the appointment of the Commission's staff director and general counsel by an affirmative vote of four Commissioners. Prohibits: (1) the staff director and general counsel of the Commission from serving for more than four consecutive years without reappointment; (2) an individual appointed to finish an unexpired term of office of a staff director or general counsel from serving beyond that term; or (3) a person serving as staff director or general counsel from subsequently serving in any Commission capacity unless reappointed. Sets forth procedures allowing the Commission to find that a person violated FECA provisions involving the reporting of receipts or disbursements and to impose civil monetary penalties. Entitles any person to file a petition with the appropriate U.S. district court to obtain a review of an adverse determination under such procedures. Requires the Commission's general counsel, within 90 days after the time for responding to a filed complaint has elapsed for all respondents, to provide a recommendation to the Commission regarding whether there is sufficient reason to investigate the violation alleged in the complaint.</summary>
</bill>
