<bill session="108" type="hr" number="55" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that United Nations weapons inspectors should be given sufficient time for a thorough assessment of the level of compliance by the Government of Iraq with United Nations Security Council Resolution 1441 (2002) and that the United States should seek a Security Council resolution specifically authorizing the use of force before initiating any offensive military operations against Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2003-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E134"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Arabs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control verification"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/2003--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) United Nations (UN) weapons inspectors should be given sufficient time to carry out the inspections that are necessary for an assessment of the level of compliance by the Government of Iraq with UN Security Council Resolution 1441 (2002); (2) the United States and other member nations of the UN Security Council should work together to exhaust all peaceful and diplomatic means for disarming Iraq before launching an invasion of Iraq; (3) international emissaries (including European and Arab leaders) should be given time to persuade Saddam Hussein to leave Iraq voluntarily and avert war; (4) before initiating any offensive military operations in Iraq to enforce Resolution 1441, the United States should seek authorization for the use of force from the UN Security Council; (5) the United States should re-engage in the Middle East peace process in an effort to end the violence between Israel and the Palestinians; and (6) the United States should redouble its efforts to secure the U.S. homeland in light of the growing number of intelligence assessments highlighting U.S. vulnerability for further terrorist attacks.</summary>
</bill>
