<bill session="104" type="h" number="1284" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">School-Based Clinic Health Service Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program to provide grants to improve the quality and availability of comprehensive education, health and social services for at-risk youth and their families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Continuum of care"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Homeless children"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Runaway children"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: School-Based or School-Linked Health and Social Services Center Grants Title II: State and Local Coordinated Youth Services Grants Subtitle A: Local Consortia Grants Subtitle B: Statewide Youth Services Center Grants Subtitle C: Provisions Relating to Both Local and Statewide Grant Programs Title III: Implementation Provisions Title IV: Federal Coordinated Youth Services Initiatives School-Based Clinic Health Service Act of 1995 - Title I: School-Based or School-Linked Health and Social Services Center Grants - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to award grants to eligible local community partnerships to coordinate and deliver comprehensive education, health, and social services to children or youth in school-based, school-linked, or community-based locations. Requires partnership use of grant funds for coordination and delivery of specified core services at a school-based, school-linked, or community-based location or locations accessible to and used by at-risk children, youth, and their families. Gives priority to grant applicants whose comprehensive services plan demonstrates: (1) continuity of access to core services on a year-round basis or beyond traditional school or service hours, either on site or through a backup referral system of community-based providers; and (2) the offer of services beyond the in-school population, including core services to out-of-school youth, to the extent practicable. Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Administration, to award planning grants to eligible entities that agree to establish a local community partnership to deliver comprehensive services. Title II: State and Local Coordinated Youth Services Grants - Subtitle A: Local Consortia Grants - Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to award grants to eligible consortia to coordinate and deliver comprehensive core education, health, and social services to at-risk youth through an integrated service delivery network directed by a consortium. Requires such consortia membership to include specified types of local representatives. Requires specified financial or organizational commitments by consortium members. Subtitle B: Statewide Youth Services Center Grants - Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to award grants to eligible States to provide for coordination and delivery of comprehensive education, health, and social services to at-risk youth through the award of State grants to local community partnerships or consortia. Subtitle C: Provisions Relating to Both Local and Statewide Grant Programs - Sets forth requirements for applications and use of grant funds for a consortium or State entity awarded a grant under subtitle A or B. Requires coordination and delivery of the core services through a system of school-based, school-linked, or community-based youth centers to serve in-school and out-of-school youth and their families. Requires coordination and co-location of existing core services in a broader system of health and social services centers accessible to in-school or out-of-school youth (including adolescent parents and runaway and homeless youth), as well as coordination of core services with alternative education and job training and placement opportunities for them. Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to award planning grants to consortia or States. Title III: Implementation Provisions - Makes ineligible for title I funds any community that: (1) is currently receiving State funds to deliver co-located education, health, and social services; or (2) will receive funding from a State funded under subtitle B of title II. Allows such a currently funded community partnership to form a consortium to seek funding for an expanded citywide or countywide youth services network under subtitle A of title II. Requires a local consortium operating in a locality receiving State funding for delivery of such co-located services to include participation from the entities receiving such State funding. Makes eligible for continued funding, at the completion of its five-year grant period under title I, a partnership that has expanded into a citywide or countywide consortium or has become part of a statewide network. Directs the Secretary to: (1) disseminate information on programs under this Act as well as successful and model programs, and to provide technical assistance; and (2) collaborate with the Departments of Education and Labor and the Commission on National and Community Service in such efforts. Authorizes appropriations. Title IV: Federal Coordinated Youth Services Initiatives - Directs the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to establish and administer a special projects of national significance program to award direct grants to public and nonprofit private entities to fund model programs to integrate health and social services, including HIV prevention, provided to special populations of youth at risk. Allows such special projects to include projects targeting youth who are: (1) runaway, homeless, or street youth; (2) immigrants or migrants; (3) in the juvenile justice system; (4) in foster care; (5) in gangs; (6) with a history of substance abuse; (7) with HIV disease; (8) adolescent parents; and (9) Native American. Amends the Claude Pepper Young Americans Act of 1990 to direct the Federal Council on Children, Youth, and Families to: (1) identify program regulations or practices that impede coordination and collaboration; and (2) develop recommendations for creating jointly funded programs, unified assessments, application procedures, confidentiality regulations that facilitate information-sharing, and pertinent legislative action.</summary>
</bill>
