<bill session="104" type="h" number="3500" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Redwood Parks Cooperative Management Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Act to establish a Redwood National Park in the State of California, to increase efficiency and cost savings in the management of Redwood National Park by authorizing the Secretary of the Interior to enter into agreements with the State of California to acquire from and provide to the State goods and services to be used by the National Park Service and the State of California in the cooperative management of lands in Redwood National Park and lands in Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park, Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park, and Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409228"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-04">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/1996--Introduced.
Redwood Parks Cooperative Management Act of 1996 - Amends the Act to establish Redwood National Park in the State of California to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into agreements with such State to acquire from and provide to the State goods and services to be used by the National Park Service or the State, respectively, in the cooperative management of lands in Redwood National Park and lands in Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park, Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park, and Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park, if the Secretary determines that appropriations for that purpose are available and the agreement is in the best interests of the United States. Allows an assignment of a Federal or State employee for work at Redwood National Park, arranged by the Secretary, or an extension of such assignment to be for any period of time determined by the Secretary and the State to be mutually beneficial. Modifies a reporting requirement to direct the Secretary to submit an annual written report to the Congress by January 31 of each year which describes the contracts and cooperative agreements entered into in the previous year.</summary>
</bill>
