<bill session="105" type="h" number="4026" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Megan's Law Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to states to offset costs associated with the Jacob Wetterling Crimes Against Children and Sexually Violent Offender Registration Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400019"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1998--Introduced.
Megan's Law Implementation Act - Amends the Jacob Wetterling Crimes Against Children and Sexually Violent Offender Registration Act to require the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to award a grant to each eligible State to offset costs directly associated with complying with the Act. Names such grant program the Sex Offender Management Assistance Program (SOMA). Directs that grants awarded be: (1) given directly to the State for distribution to State and local entities; and (2) used for training, salaries, equipment, materials, and other costs directly associated with complying with the Act. Requires a chief executive of a State, to be eligible for such a grant, to submit to the Director annually an application assuring that the State: (1) complies with such Act; and (2) has penalties comparable to or greater than Federal penalties for crimes listed in such Act. Requires the Director to conduct a study to assess the efficacy of SOMA and submit recommendations to the Congress. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
