<bill session="107" type="h" number="5176" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Heritage Firearms Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide an amnesty period during which veterans and their family members can register certain firearms in the National Firearms Registration and Transfer Record, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2002-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Amnesties"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Criminal liability"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Machine guns"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2002--Introduced.
Veterans' Heritage Firearms Act of 2002 - Provides a 90-day amnesty period during which veterans and their family members can register in the National Firearms Registration and Transfer Record any firearm acquired before October 31, 1968, by a veteran while a member of the armed forces stationed outside the continental United States. Grants such an individual limited immunity under the Federal criminal code the Internal Revenue Code with respect to the acquisition, possession, transportation, or alteration of such firearm before or concurrent with such registration.Makes a prohibition against transfer or possession of a machine-gun inapplicable to a transfer to or by, or possession by, a museum which is open to the public and incorporated as a not-for-profit corporation under applicable State law.</summary>
</bill>
