<bill session="106" type="h" number="2840" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Children's Asthma Relief Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title V of the Social Security Act to provide for the establishment and operation of asthma treatment services for children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400414"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1999-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1999-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2000-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1999-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1850"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Asthma"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Cockroaches"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Head Start programs"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Integrated pest management"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Mortality"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Vital statistics"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/1999--Introduced.
Children's Asthma Relief Act of 1999 - Amends title V (Maternal and Child Health Services) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to establish an asthma treatment grants program providing comprehensive asthma services for children and other individuals. Authorizes appropriations.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to encourage States to implement plans to carry out activities to assist children with respect to asthma in accordance with the guidelines of the National Asthma Education and Prevention Program and the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (Institute).Provides that if a State CHIP plan under SSA title XXI (Children's Health Insurance) (CHIP) provides for such activities to the Secretary's satisfaction, the Secretary shall make a grant to assist the State in carrying them out. Sets forth certain matching funds requirements. Authorizes appropriations.Amends the Public Health Service Act to include, within the preventive health and health services block grant, any systems for reducing asthma and asthma-related illnesses, especially with regard to children, through urban cockroach pest management in public facilities that minimizes or avoids chemical pesticides through a combination of appropriate practices involving the maintenance, cleaning, and monitoring of such sites.Directs the Institute Director to: (1) identify all Federal programs carrying out asthma-related activities; (2) develop a Federal plan for responding to asthma; and (3) submit recommendations to Congress on ways to strengthen and improve the coordination of such activities. Authorizes appropriations.Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to: (1) conduct local asthma surveillance activities to collect data on the prevalence and severity of asthma and the quality of asthma management; and (2) compile and publish annually data on the prevalence of children suffering from asthma in each State, and the childhood mortality rate associated with asthma nationally and in each State.</summary>
</bill>
