<bill session="105" type="h" number="4115" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Life Insurance Opportunity Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for a special period during which a former member of the armed forces may convert a Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance policy to a Veterans' Group Life Insurance policy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1998-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled veterans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/1998--Introduced.
Veterans Life Insurance Opportunity Act of 1998 - Amends Veterans' Group Life Insurance (VGLI) provisions to allow any person whose Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance (SGLI) was continued after termination of duty or discharge from military service before the date on which VGLI became effective, and whose coverage under SGLI terminated less than four years prior to such effective date, to apply for VGLI coverage within one year from the effective date of VGLI, in an amount equal to the insured's SGLI amount which was not converted to an individual policy under prior law. Provides a coverage period of five years, less the time elapsed between SGLI termination and the effective date of VGLI. Allows such insurance conversion for certain other individuals who did not convert SGLI coverage. Requires a person who cannot meet the good health requirements for VGLI coverage solely because of a service-connected disability to have such disability waived. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide due notice to eligible individuals of the opportunity for such conversion.</summary>
</bill>
