<bill session="106" type="h" number="4938" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Early Access and Tax Credit Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to improve access to health insurance and Medicare benefits for individuals ages 55 to 65 to be fully funded through premiums and anti-fraud provisions, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against income tax for payment of such premiums and of premiums for certain COBRA continuation coverage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="2000-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400613" joined="2000-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-07-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1304-1305"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2918"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Access to Medicare Benefits for Individuals 62-to-65 Years of Age Title II: Access to Medicare Benefits for Displaced Workers 55-to- 62 Years of Age Title III: COBRA Protection for Early Retirees Subtitle A: Amendments to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 Subtitle B: Amendments to the Public Health Service Act Subtitle C: Amendments to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 Title IV: Financing Title V: Credit Against Income Tax for Medicare Buy-In Premiums and for Certain Cobra Continuation Coverage Premiums Medicare Early Access and Tax Credit Act of 2000 - Title I: Access to Medicare Benefits for Individuals 62-to-65 Years of Age - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to add a new part D (Purchase of Medicare Benefits by Certain Individuals Age 62-to-65 Years of Age) under which an enrollee is entitled to the same Medicare benefits as an individual entitled to benefits under Medicare part A (Hospital Insurance) and enrolled under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance).Provides for the determination and payment of monthly premiums under the new part D program.Creates in the Treasury the Medicare Early Access Trust Fund to hold the premiums paid pursuant to this Act and savings from new fraud and abuse initiatives that are obtained pursuant to the Medicare Fraud and Reimbursement Reform Act of 1999. Provides for oversight and accountability concerning the status of the Trust Fund.Title II: Access to Medicare Benefits for Displaced Workers 55-to-62 years of Age - Amends SSA title XVIII to provide access to Medicare benefits to displaced workers (and their spouse) 55-to-62 years of age.Title III: COBRA Protection for Early Retirees - Subtitle A: Amendments to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for COBRA (Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985) continuation benefits for certain retired workers who lose retiree health coverage.Subtitle B: Amendments to the Public Health Service Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to provide for COBRA continuation benefits for certain retired workers who lose retiree health coverage.Subtitle C: Amendments to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for COBRA continuation benefits for certain retired workers who lose retiree health coverage.Title IV: Financing - Provides that any increase in Medicare payments resulting from enactment of this Act shall be offset by reductions in Medicare payments pursuant to the anti-fraud and -abuse provisions of the Medicare Fraud and Reimbursement Reform Act of 1999.Title V: Credit Against Income Tax for Medicare Buy-In Premiums and for Certain COBRA Continuation Coverage Premiums - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide an individual with a tax credit for 25 percent of certain COBRA continuation coverage premiums and Medicare buy-in premiums.</summary>
</bill>
