<bill session="106" type="h" number="2946" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to authorize the Merit Systems Protection Board to conduct an alternative dispute resolution pilot program to assist Federal Government agencies in resolving serious workplace disputes, and to establish an administrative judge pay schedule for administrative judges employed by the Merit Systems Protection Board.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400544"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law judges"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Grievance arbitration"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/1999--Introduced.
Amends Federal civil service law to authorize the Merit Systems Protection Board (MSPB) to establish a three-year program to provide Federal employees and agencies with alternative dispute resolution (ADR) processes to apply to workplace disputes and disagreements involving removals, suspensions for more than 14 days, and other adverse actions under Federal civil service law. Directs the MSPB to test and evaluate a variety of ADR techniques. Authorizes the MSPB to implement its early intervention ADR, allowing any agency or employee to request such early intervention, and authorizing the MSPB Chairman to designate up to three agencies with a substantial number of MSPB appeals for participation in a mandatory early intervention ADR program. Allows any employee or agency to request ADR once an appeal or petition for review of a case is filed with the MSPB. Outlines MSPB procedures for such cases. Direct the MSPB's Office of Policy and Evaluation to establish criteria for evaluating the ADR program and to prepare a report as to whether mandatory ADR is desirable, effective, and appropriate for cases decided by Federal administrative agencies. Authorizes appropriations for the ADR program. Establishes the MSPB Administrative Judge Pay Schedule, with pay levels comparable to that of immigration judges and administrative law judges. Provides, with respect to such Schedule, for initial appointment and advancement, and transition provisions for current judges. Authorizes appropriations to carry out such Schedule.</summary>
</bill>
