<bill session="104" type="h" number="1640" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Low-Income School Choice Demonstration Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a low-income school choice demonstration program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400427"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401081" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400549" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1995-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1995-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404332" joined="1995-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404367" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1995-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="405560" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1995-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1995-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="408142" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408553" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="409228" joined="1995-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="1995-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400398" joined="1995-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="1995-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1044-1045"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Desegregation in education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Educational vouchers"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="School choice"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/1995--Introduced.
Low-Income School Choice Demonstration Act of 1995 - Establishes a low-income school choice demonstration program to determine the effects on students and schools of providing financial assistance to enable low-income parents to select the public or private schools their children will attend. (Sec. 4) Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to award grants to eligible entities to carry out between ten and 20 demonstration projects under which low-income parents receive education certificates for the cost of enrolling their eligible children in a choice school. Sets forth requirements for use of grant funds, authorized projects, award priorities, and applications. (Sec. 8) Requires the amount of an eligible child's education certificate to be determined by the eligible entity, in an amount that provides the recipient with the maximum degree of choice in selecting the choice school the eligible child will attend. Requires an eligible entity to consider certain cost factors in determining such amount. Allows an eligible entity to provide an education certificate to the parent of an eligible child who chooses to attend a school that does not charge tuition or fees in order to pay: (1) the additional reasonable costs of transportation directly attributable to the child's participation in the demonstration project; or (2) the cost of complying with certain special services requirements. Provides for adjustments in certificate amount. Limits the maximum amount of an eligible child's education certificate to the per pupil expenditure for elementary or secondary education (as appropriate) by the local educational agency for the public school to which the child would normally be assigned for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the determination is made. Declares that an education certificate, and funds provided under it, shall not be treated as income of the parents for purposes of Federal tax laws or for determining eligibility for any other Federal program. (Sec. 9) Requires that eligible child participants in such a demonstration project receive whatever special services to which they would otherwise be entitled under certain provisions of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 and the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act. Allows any local educational agency participating in such a demonstration project to count eligible children who otherwise would attend the agency's schools in order to receive funds under any program administered by the Secretary. Allows use of information under the National School Lunch Act to determine a child's eligibility to participate in a demonstration project under this Act and, if needed, to rank families by income. (Sec. 10) Requires each eligible entity receiving a grant under this Act to provide timely notice of the demonstration project to parents of eligible children residing in the area to be served. (Sec. 11) Directs the Comptroller General to contract with an evaluating agency for an annual evaluation of the demonstration program, according to specified criteria.</summary>
</bill>
