<bill session="106" type="h" number="3814" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Technology Worker Temporary Relief Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to the number of aliens granted nonimmigrant status described in section 101(a)(15)(H)(i)(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, to implement measures to prevent fraud and abuse in the granting of such status, to provide for expedited processing of certain employers' petitions with respect to aliens seeking such status, to increase, and modify the use of, fees paid by employers petitioning with respect to such aliens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2000-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Science, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Basic Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Basic Research" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Clothing workers"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Computer programming"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electrical engineering"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronics"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Graduate students"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Numerical Limitations on H-1B Nonimmigrants Title II: Anti-Fraud Provisions for H-1B Nonimmigrants Title III: Expedited Processing for Certain Employers Title IV: Collection and Use of H-1B Nonimmigrant Fees for Scholarships Technology Worker Temporary Relief Act - Title I: Numerical Limitations on H-1B Nonimmigrants - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit additional FY 2000 nonimmigrant special occupation entrants under specified employment-related circumstances.(Sec. 102) Directs the Secretary of State to maintain H-1B visa records. Makes a conforming amendment to the American Competitiveness and Workforce Improvement Act of 1998.Title II: Anti-Fraud Provisions for H-1B Nonimmigrants - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require specialty occupation workers and fashion models admitted under other than H-1B nonimmigrant status to obtain such status.(Sec. 202) Provides with respect to specialty occupation workers for: (1) minimum 35 hour per week employment; and (2) foreign degree verification.(Sec. 204) Directs the Attorney General to impose an employer anti-fraud fee with respect to such aliens. Establishes in the Treasury an H-1B Anti-fraud Account. Obligates specified fee amounts for anti-fraud and alien removal activities.(Sec. 205) Requires a petitioning H-1B employer to be: (1) an institution of higher learning , or a governmental or nonprofit entity; or (2) a U.S. based and State or locally licensed business with specified gross assets.Title III: Expedited Processing for Certain Employers - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish an expedited H-1B petition processing procedure for qualifying employers. Provides for a $250 petition fee, which shall be deposited into the Immigration Examination Fee Account of the Treasury.Title IV: Collection and Use of H-1B Nonimmigrant Fees for Scholarships - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to increase employer H-1B petition fees.(Sec. 402) Amends such Act and the American Competitiveness and Workforce Improvement Act of 1998 to repeal authority to allocate and use specified H-1B Treasury fees for job training and demonstration projects.(Sec. 403) Amends such Acts with respect to the H-1B fee scholarship program to: (1) increase obligated amounts; (2) make such scholarships merit rather than low-income based; and (3) revise program of study eligibility.</summary>
</bill>
