<bill session="105" type="h" number="4558" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Noncitizen Benefit Clarification and Other Technical Amendments Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Noncitizen Benefit Clarification and Other Technical Amendments Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Noncitizen Benefit Clarification and Other Technical Amendments Act of1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical amendments to clarify the provision of benefits for noncitizens, and to improve the provision of unemployment insurance, child support, and supplemental security income benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1998-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-09-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-22T10:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 105-735, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-22T10:06:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 23, 1998.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Camp moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8498-8501" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-09-23T16:29:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T16:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12036" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-10-28">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-10-28" type="public" number="105-306">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-306.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child support enforcement"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare-to-work"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/1998--Passed House amended.
Noncitizen Benefit Clarification and Other Technical Amendments Act of 1998 - Amends the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (PRAWORA) to provide that the new restrictions it imposes on alien eligibility for Supplemental Security Income (SSI) under title XVI of the Social Security Act (SSA) (and thus Medicaid under SSA title XIX) shall not apply to a nonqualified alien who was receiving such benefits on August 22, 1996 (the date of enactment of PRAWORA). (Sec. 3) Amends the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act (NAFTA) to permanently extend the authorization of the Self-Employment Assistance programs. (Sec. 4) Amends SSA title IV part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to reduce, by 20 percent, the penalty for State failure to meet the deadline for compliance with child support data processing and information retrieval requirements, for each performance measure under the child support enforcement incentive payment system for which the State does achieve maximum performance. Amends the Child Support Performance and Incentive Act of 1998 to amend the effective date for State enactment of certain medical child support requirements (in order to allow State legislatures that meet biennially to pass such laws after October 1, 2001). (Sec. 5) Amends PRAWORA to allow nonresident alien professionals to renew their U.S. professional licenses. (Sec. 6) Amends SSA title IV part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) with regard to welfare-to-work grants to eliminate the one year obligation requirement and allow a State to retain certain funds reserved for special projects (or for States small enough to have only one Service Delivery Area), without passing them through to a sub-State entity, even if all the money has not been obligated each fiscal year. (Sec. 7) Amends SSA title XVI to exclude from SSI eligibility and Medicaid benefit calculations up to $2,000 in cash awards made by tax-exempt organizations to children with life-threatening conditions. (Sec. 8) Amends part A (General Provisions) of SSA title XI to authorize the Social Security Administration to recover SSI overpayments by offsetting up to ten percent per month of any Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance benefits under SSA title II.</summary>
</bill>
