<bill session="108" type="hr" number="206" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-30T11:50:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-04-30T11:50:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1350) to reauthorize the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-29T19:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 108-79, by Mr. Sessions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-29T19:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill and provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and the Workforce now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment and shall be considered as read. Makes in order only those amendments printed in H. Rept. 108-79 and provides that they shall be considered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, considered as read, debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent andan opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, not be subject toa demand for a division of the question in the House or in the Committee ofthe Whole, and waives all points of order against the amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-04-29T19:58:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="27">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 27.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T10:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3458-3466" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T10:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 206.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T11:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2003-04-30T11:50:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="149" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 211 - 195 (Roll no. 149).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3458" label="text as passed House"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="h" number="1350"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2003--Passed House without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced in the House on April 29, 2003. The summary of that version is repeated here.)Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 1350 (reauthorizing the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act).</summary>
</bill>
