<bill session="106" type="h" number="4544" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federalization of Crimes Uniform Standards Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide standards for the enactment of Federal crimes, to sunset those Federal crimes that do not meet those standards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400252"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administration of criminal justice"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2000--Introduced.
Federalization of Crimes Uniform Standards Act of 2000 - Establishes the Commission to Review the Federal Criminal Code.(Sec. 4) Specifies that it shall not be in order in either the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any measure containing a provision that would increase the law enforcement responsibilities of the Federal Government, unless that measure is accompanied by a Federal law enforcement impact statement.(Sec. 5) Directs the Commission, for each such measure that is provided to the Commission by a Member of Congress or a congressional committee, to promptly: (1) prepare a Federal law enforcement impact statement with respect to that measure; and (2) provide the statement to that Member or committee. Requires a Federal law enforcement impact statement, for each provision of that measure that would increase the law enforcement responsibility of the Government, to contain the findings, conclusions, and recommendations of the Commission as to the extent to which: (1) that increase in responsibilities would occur only as to core Federal responsibilities; (2) the efforts of States are inadequate to address the purposes to be served by that provision; and (3) the burdens imposed on the Federal court system with respect to that provision could be accommodated within the existing capacity, resources, and structure of that system.</summary>
</bill>
