<bill session="105" type="h" number="4136" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Air Common Sense Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish provisions regarding a proposed rulemaking under the Clean Air Act with respect to the transport, in the eastern portion of the United States, of ozone pollution and oxides of nitrogen and to amend the Clean Air Act to provide a 2-year period prior to the statutory reclassification of areas that fail to attain the national ambient air quality standard for ozone.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400614"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="401033" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400281" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400603" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="1998-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="1998-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/1998--Introduced.
Clean Air Common Sense Act - Sets forth provisions regarding the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency's authority to establish a requirement that States submit measures in State implementation plans under the Clean Air Act to ensure that emission reductions are achieved to mitigate transport of ozone pollution and oxides of nitrogen emissions across States included in the Ozone Transport Assessment Group Region (relating to the eastern portion of the United States). Prohibits: (1) the promulgation of a final rule to establish such requirement before the expiration of the one-year period beginning on the date the Administrator publishes notice that data described in this Act is publicly available; and (2) such rule from becoming effective before the later of May 1, 2005, or the expiration of the five-year period beginning on the date the rule is promulgated. Directs the Administrator, during the one-year period beginning on this Act's enactment, to collect data that the States in such region develop through air quality monitoring and modeling with respect to oxides of nitrogen and other pollutants to be regulated for purposes of a specified 1997 proposed rulemaking. Makes data publicly available after the expiration of such period. Establishes additional time frames with respect to the Administrator's findings, and denial of petitions, regarding sources that emit oxides of nitrogen or other pollutants to be regulated under the proposed rulemaking in violation of interstate pollution abatement requirements. Amends the Clean Air Act, with respect to provisions regarding reclassification of an ozone nonattainment area upon failure to attain standards, to extend the deadline by which the Administrator is required to determine whether an area attained a standard by the applicable attainment date to two years (currently, six months) following such date.</summary>
</bill>
