<bill session="105" type="h" number="1274" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY98-99, NIST</title>
    <title type="popular">NIST FY98-99 Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Institute of Standards and Technology Authorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Institute of Standards and Technology Authorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Institute of Standards and Technology Authorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Technology Administration Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Technology Administration Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for the National Institute of Standards and Technology for fiscal years 1998 and 1999, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1997-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1997-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1997-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="1997-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1997-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-04-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E625"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-04-21T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 105-64.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-04-21T18:17:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="47">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 47.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-04-23T19:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 127 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1274 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 2(l)(6) of rule XI are waived. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24T10:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 127 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24T10:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 127.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1804-1808" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24T10:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1274 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 2(l)(6) of rule XI are waived. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24T10:59:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 127 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24T10:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John J. Duncan Jr. to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24T10:59:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24T11:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1274.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24T11:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24T11:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-04-24T11:20:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24T11:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12254" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Amendment SP 3810 proposed by Senator Coats for Senator Frist.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Amendment SP 3810 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1998-10-09" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Morella moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Barcia objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-13T17:54:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10731-10734" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-13">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-10-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-10-30" type="public" number="105-309">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-309.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="127"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer programming"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="High technology industries"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Industrial property"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Production engineering"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development contracts"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space commercialization"/>
    <term name="Space programs"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology policy"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Year 2000 computer problem"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h31"/>
    <amendment number="s3810"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/9/1998--Passed Senate amended.
Technology Administration Act of 1998 - Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (NISTA) to provide for the extension of Federal financial assistance to Regional Centers for the Transfer of Manufacturing Technology under the Manufacturing Extension Partnership Program after the sixth year of operation. Permits a Center to receive additional funding if it has received a positive evaluation through an independent review at least every two years after such sixth year. Limits the proportion of funding that a Center may receive from the Government after the sixth year to one-third of its capital and annual operating and maintenance costs under the Program. (Sec. 3) Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 respecting the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award to: (1) expand the list of categories for awards to include health care providers and education providers; and (2) permit a third award to be made in a subcategory in any year if the Secretary of Commerce determines that it is merited and can be given at no additional cost to the Government. (Sec. 4) Amends NISTA to require notice of any reprogramming of funds to be provided to the House Committee on Science and the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation concurrently with any such notice provided to the Appropriations Committees. Requires the Secretary to provide 15 days' notice to all such committees before any major reorganization of any program, project, or activity of the Institute. (Sec. 5) Expresses the sense of the Congress regarding correcting and developing contingency plans for year 2000 date-related computer problems of the Institute. (Sec. 6) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Director of the Institute should donate educationally useful Federal equipment to schools to enhance science and mathematic programs. Mandates annual reports to the President. (Sec. 7) Establishes within the Institute a summer teacher science and technology enhancement program to provide for the professional development of mathematics and science school teachers. (Sec. 8) Establishes within the Department of Commerce an Office of Space Commercialization to be the principal unit for the coordination of space-related issues, programs, and initiatives within the Department. (Sec. 9) Directs the Secretary to establish, for FY 1999, the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Technology (EPSCOT) to strengthen the technological competitiveness of States that have historically received less Federal research and development funds than those received by a majority of the States. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary, to: (1) enter into arrangements for the coordination of EPSCOT through the State committees established under the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research (EPSCoR) of the National Science Foundation; and (2) cooperate with any State science and technology council established under EPSCoR and representatives of small business firms and other technology-based businesses. Requires a specified report. (Sec. 10) Establishes Environmental Technology as a separate nomination category with respect to the National Technology Medal. (Sec. 11) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the United States should provide support for the International Arctic Research Center that is similar to support provided for Antarctic research.</summary>
</bill>
