<bill session="107" type="h" number="3975" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for acceptance of the Fourth Amendment to the Articles of Agreement of the International Monetary Fund, to provide for the Special Drawing Rights allocated to the United States pursuant to the amendment to be contributed to the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria, and to require the Secretary of the Treasury to seek negotiations for the purpose of inducing the other member countries of the International Monetary Fund to make similar contributions to that Global Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2002-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="2002-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Monetary Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA17" subcommittee="International Monetary Policy and Trade" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Malaria"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Special drawing rights"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2002--Introduced.
Amends the Bretton Woods Agreements Act to direct the U.S. Governor of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to accept, on behalf of the United States, the fourth amendment to the Articles of Agreement of the IMF approved in resolution numbered 52- 4 of the IMF's Board of Governors.Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) instruct the U.S. Executive Director at the IMF to seek an agreement to include the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (World Bank), in its capacity as administrator of the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria, as a prescribed holder of Special Drawing Rights; (2) upon achieving an agreement, provide for the contribution of one-third of the Special Drawing Rights received by the United States to the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria; and (3) seek to enter into negotiations to induce IMF member countries to contribute their allocated Special Drawing Rights to the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria.</summary>
</bill>
