<bill session="104" type="h" number="2503" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bank Insurance Regulation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the authority of States to regulate national bank insurance activity, to limit the authority of the Comptroller of the Currency to authorize national banks to engage in new insurance activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1995-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="1995-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400265" joined="1995-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance agents"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/18/1995--Introduced.
Bank Insurance Regulation Act of 1995 - Amends Federal banking law (Revised Statutes) to declare that Federal banking statutes may not be construed as limiting or impairing the authority of any State to regulate the manner in which a national bank may engage in insurance activities pursuant to Federal statute within the State. Proscribes State discrimination against national banks: (1) in their functions of providing insurance as principal, agent or broker; or (2) with respect to licensing qualifications and procedures. Confines the provision of insurance by a national bank acting as principal, agent or broker, to specified Federal statutory parameters. States that Federal banking law may not be construed as affecting the authority of a national bank to act as insurance agent or broker consistent with State law. States that Federal banking law does not enable a State to deny to a national bank the authority to provide a product that a State bank is permitted to provide. Declares that it is not incidental to banking for a national bank to provide insurance as a principal, agent, or broker (thus removing most insurance activities from the supervision of the Comptroller of the Currency). Declares to be incidental to banking (thus subject to the Comptroller's supervision): (1) bank provision, as agent or broker, of any annuity contract whose interest is tax deductible; and (2) bank provision, as a principal, agent, or broker, of any type of insurance (other than annuity or title insurance) specifically determined by the Comptroller, before May 1995, to be incidental to banking with respect to national banks. Preserves the authority of a bank holding company to engage in insurance agency activities.</summary>
</bill>
