<bill session="105" type="h" number="2107" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY98, Interior</title>
    <title type="popular">Interior Department FY98 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Deficit Reduction Lock-box Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Deficit Reduction Lock-box Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Androscoggin River Valley Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Forest Resources Conservation and Shortage Relief Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Androscoggin River Valley Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Forest Resources Conservation and Shortage Relief Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Miccosukee Settlement Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Forest Resources Conservation and Shortage Relief Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Miccosukee Settlement Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Department of the Interior and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1998, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400334"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-26">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-17">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-17">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-Up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-07-01T18:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-163, by Mr. Regula.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-07-01T18:41:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="98">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 98.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-07-09T23:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 181 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2107 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Points of order for failure to comply wiht clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI are waived, with specified exceptions. Where points of order are waived against part of a paragraph, points of order against a provision in another part of such paragraph may be made only against such provision and not against the entire paragraph. Amendments printed in the report accompanying this resolution may be offered only by a Member designated and only at the appropriate point in the reading of the bill, debatable for the time specified, and shall not be subject to further amendment. All points of order against said amendments shall be waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 181 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 181.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5062-5122" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2107 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Points of order for failure to comply with clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI are waived, with specified exceptions. Where points of order are waived against part of a paragraph, points of order against a provision in another part of such paragraph may be made only against such provision and not against the entire paragraph. Amendments printed in the report accompanying this resolution may be offered only by a Member designated and only at the appropriate point in the reading of the bill, debatable for the time specified, and shall not be subject to further amendment. All points of order against said amendments shall be waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 181 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steven C. LaTourette to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T18:28:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Sanders amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Sanders requested a recorded vote and further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T18:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Regula asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Gutierrez amendment, and all amendments thereto, be limited to 10 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T18:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gutierrez amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Maloney (NY) amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mrs. Maloney objected to the vote on grounds that a quorum was not present and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 181, further proceedings were postponed and the point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T20:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (OR) raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Smith stated that the language of the bill beginning on page 47, lines 2 through 6, relating to limitation on road purchaser credits to companies that meet the Small Business Administration's definition of a small business, constituted legislation on an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T20:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Regula asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Porter amendment, and all amendments thereto, be limited to 80 minutes, equally divided and controlled as follows: Messers. Dicks, Kennedy, Porter, and Regula, for 20 minutes each.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T20:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 80 minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T23:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Regula asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Klug amendment be limited to 30 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T23:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Klug amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-10T23:58:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Klug amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Klug objected to the vote on grounds that a quorum ws not present and made a point of order that was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 181, the point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T00:25:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Royce amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Royce requested a recorded vote and, pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 181, further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T00:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Regula moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T00:26:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T00:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2107 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T10:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T10:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5137-5168" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T10:03:00-04:00">
      <text>RESUMING UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chairman of the Committee of the Whole announced that the unfinished business was the demand for recorded votes on amendments debated on July 10. Votes will be taken on the amendment offered by Mr. Klug and on the amendment offered by Mr. Royce (in that order).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T10:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crane raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Crane stated that the language on page 76, lines 10-13, relating to funds for the National Endowment for the Arts, was out of order in that it constituted an unauthorized appropriation. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T10:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 181, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Ehlers amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Chabot amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Chabot objected to the vote on grounds that a quorum was not present and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 181, further proceedings were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Regula moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T14:21:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-11T14:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2107 as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="7/10/97 CR H5122-5128" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T13:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5214-5245" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T13:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 181, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Crapo amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T13:41:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Crapo amendment, the Chair put the question and announced that by voice vote, the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Crapo demanded a recorded vote based upon the absence of a quorum and further proceedings were postponed. The point of order was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Istook amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Istook objected to the vote on grounds that a quorum was not present and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 181, further proceedings were postponed and the point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Coburn amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was agreed to. Mr. Yates objected to the vote on grounds that a quorum was not present and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 181, further proceedings were postponed and the point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 181, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Weldon (FL) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T17:16:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on the Weldon amendment the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Weldon demanded a recorded vote based upon the absence of a quorum and the Chair postponed further proceedings. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Regula moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2107 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T19:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5266-5272" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T20:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2107.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T20:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T20:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-07-15T20:52:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="275" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 238 - 192 (Roll no. 275).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T20:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-15T20:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2107.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior. Approved for full committee consideration with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-07-22">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-07-22">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported to Senate by Senator Gorton with amendments. With written report No. 105-56.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-07-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="122">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 122.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-09-11">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9167-9192" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-11">
      <text>Amendment SP 1132 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Gregg.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-11">
      <text>Amendment SP 1132 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-15">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9303-9332" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-15">
      <text>Amendment SP 1188 proposed by Senator Ashcroft.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9363-9375, S9385-9406" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>The excepted committee amendment on p. 55, line 11, through p. 56, line 2, was withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 1197 proposed by Senator Campbell.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 1197 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 1200 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Mack.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 1200 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 1201 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Murkowski.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 1201 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 1202 proposed by Senator Gorton.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 1202 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 1203 proposed by Senator Gorton.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 1203 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 1196 proposed by Senator Hutchinson.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9440-9443, S9448-9501,  S9503-9510" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1204 proposed by Senator Brownback.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1205 proposed by Senator Bryan.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1204 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1188 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 23-77. Record Vote No: 241.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1205 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 49-51. Record Vote No: 242.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Motion to reconsider the vote on SP 1205 rejected by Yea-Nay Vote. 49-51. Record Vote No: 243.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1209 proposed by Senator Bumpers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1209 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1206 proposed by Senator Abraham.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1187 proposed by Senator Hutchinson.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1206 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 26-73. Record Vote No: 244.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1187 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 36-63. Record Vote No: 245.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1212 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Craig.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1212 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1213 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Bumpers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1213 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1214 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Cochran.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1214 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1215 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Murkowski.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1215 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1216 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Murkowski.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1216 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1217 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Murkowski.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1217 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1218 proposed by Senator Jeffords.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Amendment SP 1218 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9532-9627" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1186 proposed by Senator Hutchison.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1186 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 39-61. Record Vote No: 246.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1219 proposed by Senator Stevens.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1219 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Motion to table SP 1196 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 57-42. Record Vote No: 247.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1221 proposed by Senator Enzi.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1222 proposed by Senator Bryan to Amendment SP 1221.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1222 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1221 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1223 proposed by Senator Kyl.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1223 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 34-64. Record Vote No: 248.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1225 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Bennett.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1225 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1226 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Dewine.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1226 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1227 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Graham.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1227 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1228 proposed by Senator Reid.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1228 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1224 proposed by Senator Bumpers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Point of order that the amendment violates the Constitution raised in Senate with respect to SP 1224.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>SP 1224 determined out of order by Yea-Nay Vote. 59-39. Record Vote No: 249.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1229 proposed by Senator Bingaman.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1229 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1230 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Murray.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1230 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1231 proposed by Senator McCain.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1232 proposed by Senator Murkowski to Amendment SP 1231.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1234 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Smith, of OR.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1234 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1235 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator McCain.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1235 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1236 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Mack.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1236 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1237 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Bingaman.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1237 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1238 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Moseley-Braun.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1238 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1239 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Domenici.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1239 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1240 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Stevens.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1240 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1241 proposed by Senator Gorton.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1241 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1242 proposed by Senator Reid.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1242 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1243 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Abraham.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1243 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1244 proposed by Senator Reid for Senator Bryan.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1244 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1245 proposed by Senator Murkowski.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Proposed amendment SP 1232 withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1231 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1246 proposed by Senator Gorton for Senator Murkowski.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1246 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 1245 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 81-14. Record Vote No: 250.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1997-09-18" how="roll" result="pass" roll="251" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Yea-Nay Vote. 93-3. Record Vote No: 251.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendments asks for a conference, appoints conferees Gorton; Stevens; Cochran; Domenici; Burns; Bennett; Gregg; Campbell; Byrd; Leahy; Bumpers; Hollings; Reid; Dorgan; Boxer.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9626" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Regula asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7651" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Yates moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion to instruct conferees on the part of the House to agree to Senate amendments No. 120, 121 and 122, to restore funding for the National Endowment for the Arts.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7651-7653" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Regula, McDade, Kolbe, Skeen, Taylor (NC), Nethercutt, Miller (FL), Wamp, Livingston, Yates, Murtha, Dicks, Skaggs, Moran (VA), and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-22T20:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 105-337 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9004-9034" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-23T17:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 277 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2107. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-24T11:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 277 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-24T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Regula brought up conference report H. Rept. 105-337 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 277.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-24T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-24T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="1997-10-24T14:04:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="531" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 233 - 171 (Roll no. 531).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9540-9541" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-10-24T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-24">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-28">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-28">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1997-10-28" how="roll" result="pass" roll="283" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 84-14. Record Vote No: 283.</text>
      <reference ref="CR  S11253-11275" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1997-10-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1997-10-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1997-11-04">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1997-11-14">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1997-11-14" type="public" number="105-83">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-83.</text>
    </enacted>
    <action datetime="1998-01-27T14:46:00-05:00">
      <text>The Chair laid before the House the veto message from the President.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-01-27T14:46:00-05:00">
      <text>For actions pursuant to the line item Veto Act (P.L. 104-130), see House Document 105-180.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-01-27T14:46:00-05:00">
      <text>The communication was referred to the Committees on Appropriations and the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup" code="HSAP06" subcommittee="Interior" name="House Appropriations"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP06" subcommittee="Interior" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="181"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="277"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Art and state"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Beaches"/>
    <term name="Bears"/>
    <term name="Bering Sea"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Caves"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Columbia River development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commission of Fine Arts"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Dismissal wage"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elephants"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Endangered animals"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy transportation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental degradation"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Eviction"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to territories"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Ferries"/>
    <term name="Fiber optics"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fish culture"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Food service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Forestry"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Forests"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grassland ecology"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Helium"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="House Appropriations"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian gambling operations"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian hunting and fishing rights"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Industrial toxicology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Literature"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Logging"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Man and the Biosphere Programme"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Military base conversion"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military parks"/>
    <term name="Mineral industries"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Mining engineering"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="National Capital Planning Commission"/>
    <term name="National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National lakeshores"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="National scenic areas"/>
    <term name="National seashores"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Old growth forests"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Palau Islands"/>
    <term name="Park rangers"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Petroleum conservation"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radiation victims"/>
    <term name="Railroad land grants"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Restaurants"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rhinoceroses"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Roosevelt Administration"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Second homes"/>
    <term name="Senate Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sparsely populated areas"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Streets"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Submarines"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court decisions"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Tigers"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="U.S. Holocaust Memorial Council"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in recreation"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="White House (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="Wildlife reintroduction"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
    <term name="Zoos"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h222"/>
    <amendment number="h223"/>
    <amendment number="h224"/>
    <amendment number="h225"/>
    <amendment number="h226"/>
    <amendment number="h227"/>
    <amendment number="h228"/>
    <amendment number="h229"/>
    <amendment number="h230"/>
    <amendment number="h231"/>
    <amendment number="h232"/>
    <amendment number="h234"/>
    <amendment number="h235"/>
    <amendment number="h236"/>
    <amendment number="h237"/>
    <amendment number="h238"/>
    <amendment number="h239"/>
    <amendment number="h240"/>
    <amendment number="h241"/>
    <amendment number="s1132"/>
    <amendment number="s1134"/>
    <amendment number="s1135"/>
    <amendment number="s1178"/>
    <amendment number="s1185"/>
    <amendment number="s1186"/>
    <amendment number="s1187"/>
    <amendment number="s1188"/>
    <amendment number="s1194"/>
    <amendment number="s1195"/>
    <amendment number="s1196"/>
    <amendment number="s1197"/>
    <amendment number="s1198"/>
    <amendment number="s1199"/>
    <amendment number="s1200"/>
    <amendment number="s1201"/>
    <amendment number="s1202"/>
    <amendment number="s1203"/>
    <amendment number="s1204"/>
    <amendment number="s1205"/>
    <amendment number="s1206"/>
    <amendment number="s1207"/>
    <amendment number="s1208"/>
    <amendment number="s1209"/>
    <amendment number="s1210"/>
    <amendment number="s1212"/>
    <amendment number="s1213"/>
    <amendment number="s1214"/>
    <amendment number="s1215"/>
    <amendment number="s1216"/>
    <amendment number="s1217"/>
    <amendment number="s1218"/>
    <amendment number="s1219"/>
    <amendment number="s1220"/>
    <amendment number="s1221"/>
    <amendment number="s1222"/>
    <amendment number="s1223"/>
    <amendment number="s1224"/>
    <amendment number="s1225"/>
    <amendment number="s1226"/>
    <amendment number="s1227"/>
    <amendment number="s1228"/>
    <amendment number="s1229"/>
    <amendment number="s1230"/>
    <amendment number="s1231"/>
    <amendment number="s1232"/>
    <amendment number="s1234"/>
    <amendment number="s1235"/>
    <amendment number="s1236"/>
    <amendment number="s1237"/>
    <amendment number="s1238"/>
    <amendment number="s1239"/>
    <amendment number="s1240"/>
    <amendment number="s1241"/>
    <amendment number="s1242"/>
    <amendment number="s1243"/>
    <amendment number="s1244"/>
    <amendment number="s1245"/>
    <amendment number="s1246"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/20/1997--Line item veto by President.
(On June 25, 1998, the Supreme Court ruled that the Line Item Veto Act (Public Law 104-130) is unconstitutional, thus restoring provisions that had been cancelled as summarized below.) (On November 20, 1997, the President exercised his line item veto authority to cancel up to $6.2 million in discretionary budget authority for the following two items included in this Act: (1) the Franklin County Dam in Mississippi; and (2) a conveyance of Federal mineral rights to the State of Montana. The following revised digest summarizes the enacted version of H.R. 2107 as modified by the line item veto.) (Note: The high degree of specificity of the items cancelled precluded their inclusion in the original law's summary. As a result, the original law's summary and the summary of the law after the item vetoes are identical. For more information on the specific items vetoed, see the text of the conference report for H.R. 2107, H.Rept. 105-337, and Presidential Cancellation Numbers 97-75 and 97-76.)) TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of the Interior Title II: Related Agencies Title III: General Provisions Title IV: Environmental Improvement and Restoration Fund Title V: Priority Land Acquisitions, Land Exchanges, and Maintenance Title VI: Forest Resources Conservation and Shortage Relief Title VII: Miccosukee Settlement Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998 - Makes appropriations for the Department of the Interior and related agencies for FY 1998. Title I: Department of the Interior - Makes appropriations for the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for: (1) land and resource management; (2) fire management; (3) remedial action of hazardous waste substances; (4) construction; (5) payments in lieu of taxes to local governments; (6) land acquisition; (7) Oregon and California grant lands; (8) range improvements; (9) service charges, deposits, and forfeitures with respect to public lands; (10) miscellaneous trust funds; and (11) BLM administrative and enforcement expenses. Appropriates funds for the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service for: (1) resource management; (2) construction; (3) natural resource damage assessment activities; (4) land acquisition; (5) the Cooperative Endangered Species Conservation Fund; (6) the National Wildlife Refuge Fund; (7) expenses related to carrying out the African Elephant Conservation Act; (8) expenses related to the North American Wetlands Conservation Act; (9) the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Fund; (10) the Wildlife Conservation and Appreciation Fund; and (11) U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service administrative and enforcement expenses. Makes appropriations for the National Park Service (NPS) for: (1) the National Park System; (2) national recreation and preservation activities; (3) expenses related to carrying out the Historic Preservation Act of 1966; (4) construction; and (5) land acquisition and State assistance from the Land and Water Conservation Fund. Rescinds specified contract authority to obligate funds from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for FY 1998. Prohibits the use of funds by the NPS for activities taken in direct response to the United Nations Biodiversity Convention. Makes appropriations for: (1) the U.S. Geological Survey for surveys, investigations, and research; (2) the Minerals Management Service for royalty and offshore minerals management and oil spill research; (3) the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement for enforcement and the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund; (4) the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) for operation of Indian programs, construction, miscellaneous payments to Indians, and Indian guaranteed loans; (5) assistance to U.S. territories and for carrying out the Compacts of Free Association with respect to Micronesia, the Marshall Islands, and Palau; (6) salaries and expenses of departmental management, the Offices of the Solicitor and the Inspector General, and the National Indian Gaming Commission; and (7) trust programs for Indians. Sets forth prohibitions on the use of specified funds. (Sec. 101) Sets forth provisions regarding the use of funds under this title for emergency reconstruction, replacement, or repair of facilities or equipment. (Sec. 108) Prohibits the use of such funds for specified offshore leasing and related activities. (Sec. 113) Sets forth provisions regarding severance and health benefits for employees of BLM's helium operations. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to provide for training to assist such employees in the transition to other jobs. (Sec. 114) Prohibits the use of funds in this or previous appropriations Acts to establish a new regional office in the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service without the advance approval of the Appropriations Committees. (Sec. 115) Requires the Secretary of the Interior to convey the Bowden National Fish Hatchery to the State of West Virginia for use as part of the State's fish culture program. (Sec. 117) Amends Federal law to increase the limit on annual expenditures for projects on Kili or Ejit as part of rehabilitation and resettlement of Bikini Atoll. Provides for annual adjustments of such amount based on fluctuations in the Consumer Price Index. (Sec. 118) Provides that any funds made available in any Act for tribal priority allocations (TPA) in excess of the funds expended for TPA in FY 1997 shall only be available for distribution to each tribe to the extent necessary to provide a tribe the minimum level of funding recommended by the Joint-Tribal-BIA-DOI Task Force on Reorganization of the Bureau of Indian Affairs Report of 1994 (and to not exceed $160,000 per tribe). States that remaining funds will be allocated according to recommendations of a task force comprised of two designated Federal officials and two tribal representatives from each BIA area. Requires the Secretary, if the task force cannot agree on a distribution by January 31, 1998, to distribute remaining funds based on recommendations of a majority of Task Force members by February 28, 1998. (Sec. 120) Vests in the United States, 90 days after this section's enactment date, all patented and valid unpatented mining claims in the Kantishna Mining District within Denali National Park and Preserve, Alaska, whose owners consent to such action within such 90-day period. Provides for just compensation to be paid to the owners of such claims. (Sec. 121) Extends to October 1, 1998, the deadline by which specified Alaska Native corporations may commence litigation to challenge Department of the Interior determinations that they will not receive conveyances of lands described in a specified 1976 Deficiency Agreement. Authorizes the introduction of any relevant evidence bearing on the interpretation of the Agreement at the court trial if such litigation is commenced. (Sec. 123) Amends the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to require fees to be paid to the National Indian Gaming Commission by class III gaming operations. Revises the rate of fees to be paid by class II and III gaming operations. Caps the total amount of fees imposed during any fiscal year at $8 million (currently, $1.5 million). Makes such requirements inapplicable to self-regulated tribes such as the Mississippi Band of Choctaw. Extends the authorization of appropriations for the Commission. (Sec. 124) Amends Federal law to authorize the legislature of the Government of the Virgin Islands to issue notes in anticipation of the collection of taxes and revenues for the current fiscal year. Bars extensions of notes and prohibits issuance of additional notes until all notes issued during a preceding year have been paid. (Sec. 125) Requires the Secretary to ensure that the lands comprising the Huron Cemetery in Kansas City, Kansas, are used only for religious and cultural uses compatible with the use of such lands as a cemetery and as a burial ground. (Sec. 127) Requires the NPS to initiate a competitive process to allow one entry per day for a passenger ferry into Bartlett Cove in Glacier Bay National Park and Preserve from Juneau, Alaska, for the sole purpose of accessing park or other authorized visitor services or facilities at, or originating from, the public dock area at the Cove. (Sec. 128) Amends Federal law with respect to exploration of the National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska to authorize gas and oil lessees, for conservation purposes, to unite with others in collectively adopting and operating under a unit agreement for any oil or gas pool, field, or like area whenever the Secretary of the Interior deems necessary or in the public interest. Authorizes the Secretary, in order to encourage the greatest ultimate recovery of oil or gas or in the interest of conservation, to waive, suspend, or reduce the rental or minimum royalty, or reduce the royalty on an entire leasehold, whenever the leases cannot be successfully operated under the terms provided. (Sec. 129) Bars the Secretary, during FY 1998, from expending funds made available under this Act to review or approve initial tribal-State compacts for class III gaming entered into on or after this Act's enactment date. (Sec. 130) Expresses the sense of the Senate that the Department of Justice should vigorously enforce the provisions of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act requiring an approved tribal-State gaming compact prior to the initiation of class III gaming on Indian lands. (Sec. 131) Prohibits the expenditure of funds provided in any Act for the promulgation of a proposed or final rule to amend or replace the National Indian Gaming Commission's definition regulations. (Sec. 133) Directs the Secretary, acting through the BLM Director, to convey certain land to Lander County, Nevada. (Sec. 134) Authorizes the city of Las Vegas, Nevada, to submit to the Secretary, acting through the BLM Director, an offer to purchase specified Federal properties on behalf of adjacent real property owners adversely affected by reliance on erroneous private land surveys. Directs the Secretary to convey such properties, subject to valid existing rights, to the city upon payment by the city of the fair market value of the properties as of December 1, 1982, and on the condition that the city convey the properties to such adversely affected landowners. (Sec. 135) Directs the Secretary to accept full title to specified land located in Prince Georges County, Maryland, and, in exchange, to convey specified land in Oxon Cove Park in the District of Columbia to the Corrections Corporation of America. Bars the acquisition of such lands if contaminated with hazardous substances. Absolves the United States of liability for hazardous wastes or substances placed on lands covered by this section after their transfer to any party. Requires the Corporation to indemnify the United States for liabilities arising under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act of 1980 (Superfund) and the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act. (Sec. 136) Requires the NPS to begin negotiations with the University of Alaska, Fairbanks, School of Mineral Engineering to determine compensation for University facilities, equipment, and interests that were destroyed by the Federal Government at the Stampede Mine Site in Denali National Park and Preserve. Title II: Related Agencies - Makes appropriations for the Department of Agriculture for the Forest Service for: (1) forest and rangeland research; (2) forestry activities; (3) the National Forest System; (4) fire management; (5) construction and reconstruction; (6) land acquisition; (7) range rehabilitation and improvement; (8) forest and rangeland research; (9) restoration of the Midewin National Tallgrass Prairie; and (10) administrative expenses. Requires funds appropriated by this Act to implement the Revised Tongass National Forest Land Management Plan to be spent and obligated at the Forest Supervisor and Ranger District levels, subject to specified conditions. Rescinds a specified amount of funds made available to the Department of Energy in FY 1997 or prior fiscal years for clean coal technology projects. Makes appropriations for the Department of Energy for: (1) fossil energy research and development activities; (2) naval petroleum and oil shale reserve activities; (3) energy conservation; (4) economic regulation activities of the Office of Hearings and Appeals; (5) the Strategic Petroleum Reserve; and (6) the Energy Information Administration. Makes appropriations for the Department of Health and Human Services for the Indian Health Service, including Indian health facilities. Makes appropriations for: (1) the Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation; (2) the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development; (3) the Smithsonian Institution; (4) the National Zoological Park; (5) construction; (6) the National Gallery of Art; (7) the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts; (8) carrying out the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Act of 1968; (9) the National Endowment for the Arts (NEA); (10) the National Endowment for the Humanities; (11) the Institute of Museum and Library Services; (12) the Commission of Fine Arts; (13) the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation; (14) the National Capital Planning Commission; and (15) the Holocaust Memorial Council. Sets forth provisions regarding uses of, and limitations on, funds under this title. Title III: General Provisions - Sets forth limitations on the use of funds under this Act, including Buy American requirements. Prohibits Federal contracts with persons found to have falsely labeled products with a "Made in America" inscription. (Sec. 308) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for: (1) planning or offering timber from giant sequoias on BLM or Forest System lands for sale in a manner different than such sales were conducted in FY 1995; (2) entering into a concession contract (by the NPS) which provides for the removal of the underground lunchroom at Carlsbad Caverns National Park; (3) the AmeriCorps program unless the relevant agencies of the Departments of the Interior and Agriculture follow appropriate reprogramming guidelines; (4) demolishing the bridge between Jersey City, New Jersey, and Ellis Island or preventing pedestrian use of such bridge; (5) accepting or processing applications for a patent for mining or mill site claims located under the general mining laws, unless the Secretary of the Interior takes specified actions; (6) acquiring lands in specified Ohio counties for the Wayne National Forest; and (7) funding activities of the western director and special assistant to the Secretary of Agriculture in an amount exceeding FY 1997 funding for such activities. (Sec. 316) Bars the use of funds made available to the Departments of the Interior or Agriculture in any Act to issue or implement, prior to December 1, 1998, final regulations or policies pursuant to the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (ANILCA) to assert jurisdiction or management over navigable waters transferred to the State of Alaska pursuant to the Submerged Lands Act of 1953 or the Alaska Statehood Act of 1959. Amends ANILCA to revise provisions regarding State management of subsistence takings of fish and wildlife on public lands. States that the preference granted is for a reasonable opportunity to take fish and wildlife, consistent with customary and traditional uses, for subsistence purposes. Bars the Secretary of the Interior from implementing provisions related to establishing subsistence resource regions, local advisory committees, and regional advisory councils upon State assumption of management duties unless a court determines that State law is inconsistent with definitions, preferences, and participation requirements of subsistence provisions. Permits State agency actions to be invalidated by the court only if they are arbitrary, capricious, or otherwise not in accordance with the law. Requires the Secretary, before December 1, 1998, to certify if laws consistent with such definition, preference, and participation provisions have been adopted in Alaska. (Sec. 319) Authorizes the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior to limit competition for watershed restoration project contracts as part of the President's Forest Plan for the Pacific Northwest to individuals and entities in timber-dependent areas in Washington, Oregon, and northern California that have been affected by reduced timber harvesting on Federal lands. (Sec. 320) Revises the formula for the distribution of recreational use fees. (Sec. 323) Requires the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture, prior to the completion of any decision document or the making of any decision related to the final Environmental Impact Statements associated with the Interior Columbia Basin Ecosystem Project, to report to the Appropriations Committees on future land and resource management planning, estimated time frames and costs of decisions, estimated production of goods and services from Federal lands, and economic and social conditions of, and environmental impacts on, communities within the Project area. (Sec. 325) Authorizes specified Alaska Native regional health entities to form a consortium to provide all statewide health services provided by the Indian Health Service through the Alaska Native Medical Center and the Alaska Area Office. Sets forth further authorities with respect to health care services provided by the Cook Inlet Region, Inc. (Sec. 327) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to require any person to vacate real property where a term is expiring under a use and occupancy reservation in Sleeping Bear Dunes National Lakeshore, Michigan, until the NPS indicates to the appropriate congressional committees and the reservation holders that it has sufficient funds to remove the residence on such property within 90 days of the residence being vacated. Provides for: (1) at least 90 days' notice to holders of expired reservations to allow them to leave the residence; and (2) fair market value rental rates, in addition to other specified charges, while occupancy continues beyond an expired reservation. (Sec. 328) Bars the use of funds made available in any Act providing appropriations for the Department of the Interior, the Forest Service, or the Smithsonian Institution for the submission of nominations for the designation of Biosphere Reserves pursuant to the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization's Man and Biosphere Program. Repeals such prohibition upon enactment of legislation specifically authorizing U.S. participation in such program. Bars the use of funds made available by this or any other Act to designate any portion of Canaveral National Seashore in Brevard County, Florida, as a clothing-optional area or an area in which public nudity is permitted if such designation would be contrary to county ordinance. (Sec. 329) Requires the Chairperson of the NEA to: (1) award grants only for literature, National Heritage, or American Jazz Masters fellowships; and (2) establish procedures to ensure that no funding provided through a grant, except one made to a State or local arts agency or regional group, may be used to make a grant to any other individual or organization to conduct activities independent of the grant recipient. Prohibits NEA grants from being used for seasonal support to a group unless the application is specific to the contents of the season. (Sec. 331) Authorizes the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture, in FY 1998 through 2002, to make reciprocal delegations of their authorities and responsibilities in support of joint pilot programs to promote customer service and efficiency in the management of public lands and national forests. (Sec. 334) Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture, in FY 1998, to use appropriations for the Forest Service to enter into watershed restoration and enhancement agreements. (Sec. 335) Provides for the termination of the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial Commission. (Sec. 339) Prohibits the expenditure of funds provided in any Act to develop a rulemaking proposal to amend or replace BLM regulations for surface mining or to prepare a draft environmental impact statement (EIS) on such proposal until the Secretary of the Interior certifies to specified congressional committees that the Department of the Interior has consulted with the Governor of each State that contains public lands open to location under the general mining laws. Bars publication of proposed regulations prior to November 15, 1998. (Sec. 340) Authorizes and directs the Secretary of Agriculture to negotiate with Skamania County, Washington, for the exchange of lands or interests in lands constituting the Wind River Nursery Site in the Gifford Pinchot National Forest. Authorizes and directs the County, in return for the Nursery Site properties, to negotiate the conveyance of specified high biodiversity, special management lands within the Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area with the Forest Service. Sets forth additional requirements with respect to such land exchange. (Sec. 342) Prohibits the expenditure of funds under any Act for the introduction of the grizzly bear population in the Selway-Bitteroot area of Idaho and adjacent Montana or for consultations under the Endangered Species Act for Federal actions affecting such population. Permits funds to be used for receiving public comment on the draft EIS of July 1997, issuing a Record of Decision, and for conducting a habitat-based population viability analysis. (Sec. 343) Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to phase in, over a three-year period, the portion of the fee increase for recreation residence special use permit holders which exceeds 100 percent of the previous year's fee. (Sec. 344) Expresses the sense of the Senate with respect to: (1) preserving Civil War battlefields; and (2) Federal funding for the arts. (Sec. 346) Requires the Chairperson of the NEA to establish a grant category for programs that are of national impact or availability or are able to tour several States. Prohibits the Chairperson from making grants exceeding 15 percent, in the aggregate, of NEA funds appropriated by this Act, to any single State, excluding grants made under this section. Revises the composition of the National Council on the Arts to include Members of Congress. (Sec. 347) Sets forth requirements regarding the sale and the availability for processing of western red cedar timber. (Sec. 348) Prohibits the use of funds in this Act for planning, design, or construction of improvements to Pennsylvania Avenue in front of the White House without the advance approval of the Appropriations Committees. (Sec. 349) Bars the use of funds made available under any Act for executing adjustments to annual operating plans, allotment management plans, or terms of existing grazing permits on national forests in Arizona and New Mexico deemed necessary to achieve compliance with 1996 amendments to applicable forest plans until the earlier of March 1, 1998, or such time as the Forest Service publishes a schedule for implementing proposed changes. Title IV: Environmental Improvement and Restoration Fund - Provides for the deposit of one-half of the amounts awarded by the Supreme Court to the United States in United States of America v. State of Alaska into a Treasury fund to be known as the Environmental Improvement and Restoration Fund. Makes the Fund available for certain deferred maintenance and modernization projects of the NPS, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the BLM, and the Forest Service and for marine research activities in the North Pacific, Bering Sea, and Arctic Ocean by the Secretary of Commerce. Title V: Priority Land Acquisitions, Land Exchanges, and Maintenance - Makes appropriations for priority land acquisitions, land exchange agreements, other activities consistent with the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965, and critical maintenance by the BLM, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, NPS, and Forest Service, to be derived from the Land and Water Conservation Fund and to remain available through FY 2001. Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, such funds. Sets forth requirements for the acquisition of the Headwaters Forest in Humboldt County, California, by the Secretary of the Interior and certain interests in Montana by the Secretary of Agriculture to provide for the preservation of Yellowstone National Park. Title VI: Forest Resources Conservation and Shortage Relief - Forest Resources Conservation and Shortage Relief Act of 1997 - Amends the Forest Resources Conservation and Shortage Relief Act of 1990 (the Act) to except purchases of unprocessed timber from Federal lands west of the 119th meridian in the State of Washington from specified limitations on substitutions of unprocessed Federal timber for unprocessed timber from private lands if: (1) the private lands are owned by the purchaser; or (2) the purchaser has the exclusive right to harvest timber from the private lands during a period of more than seven years and may exercise that right at any time. Makes existing provisions regarding applications for approval of sourcing areas applicable to sourcing areas for processing facilities located outside the northwestern private timber open market area (defined as the State of Washington). Requires the Secretary concerned, in making a determination to approve an application for sourcing areas for timber manufacturing facilities in Idaho, to consider the private timber export and the private and Federal timber sourcing patterns for the applicant's facilities and other facilities in the same vicinity and the relative similarity of private and Federal timber sourcing patterns. Provides that private timber sourcing patterns shall not be a factor in such determinations in States other than Idaho. Prohibits the Secretary, in deciding whether to approve an application, from: (1) considering land located in Washington; or (2) conditioning approval on the inclusion of such land in the applicant's sourcing area, except to the extent requested by the applicant. Establishes boundaries and requirements for sourcing areas for processing facilities in Washington. Permits relinquishment of sourcing areas at any time. Makes unprocessed timber from private lands within a relinquished sourcing area immediately exportable after unprocessed timber from Federal land from within such area is no longer in the possession of the former area holder. Revises restrictions on the export of unprocessed timber from State and public land with respect to States with annual sales of more than 400 million board feet to prohibit exports originating from public lands as of this Act's enactment date (thus, changing current effective dates). (Sec. 603) Provides for reduction or suspension of penalties with respect to specified violations of the Act, based on mitigating factors. Prohibits debarment of any person from bidding for or entering into a contract for the purchase of unprocessed timber from Federal lands unless the head of the appropriate Federal agency finds, on the record and after an opportunity for a hearing, that debarment is warranted. Permits the withholding of a contract award during a debarment proceeding. (Sec. 604) Excludes timber processed into incidental volumes of grade three and four sawlogs from the definition of unprocessed timber under the Act. (Sec. 605) Requires the Secretary concerned to issue regulations that impose marking requirements on unprocessed timber under certain conditions. Excludes certain logs or timber from such requirements based on size. Provides waivers from such requirements under certain conditions. Title VII: Miccosukee Settlement - Miccosukee Settlement Act of 1997 - Ratifies the August 1996 Settlement Agreement between the Florida Department of Transportation and the Miccosukee Tribe. (Sec. 705) Directs the Secretary of the Interior, as trustee for the Miccosukee Tribe, to assist in the fulfillment of the settlement agreement concerning the transfer of: (1) certain Miccosukee tribal land to the Florida Department of Transportation; and (2) certain Florida land to the United States to be received and accepted in trust for the use and benefit of the Miccosukee Tribe, as Miccosukee Indian Reservation lands. (Sec. 706) Exempts payments or conveyances made to the Tribe under the agreement from Federal and State taxation.</summary>
</bill>
