<bill session="105" type="h" number="1998" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Yates Firearm Registration and Crime Prevention Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To disarm lawless persons and assist State and Federal law enforcement agencies in preventing and solving gun crimes by requiring registration of all firearms and firearm transfers and requiring permits for the possession and transfer of firearms and ammunition.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411947"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug addicts"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Expatriation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mentally ill"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Stalking"/>
    <term name="Unmarried couples"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/1997--Introduced.
Yates Firearm Registration and Crime Prevention Act of 1997 - Amends the Federal criminal code to make it unlawful for any person who: (1) owns a firearm in the United States to fail to register such firearm with the Secretary of the Treasury within one year after this Act; (2) manufactures a firearm in, or imports a firearm into, the United States to fail to register such firearm within seven days of such manufacture or importation; or (3) transfers, or to whom is transferred, a firearm in the United States to fail to register such firearm within seven days of such transfer. Makes it unlawful for any person who loses a firearm or discovers a firearm to have been stolen to fail to report such loss or theft to the Secretary within 48 hours. Makes it unlawful for a person to: (1) possess a firearm or ammunition in or affecting commerce unless the Secretary has issued to such person a valid firearms permit; or (2) transfer or receive such a firearm or ammunition unless the transferee or recipient has and displays to the transferor a valid permit. Provides permit application requirements. Authorizes an owner to dispose of a firearm at a place designated by the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to pay the fair market value of such firearm. Provides penalties for noncompliance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
