<bill session="104" type="hr" number="66" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Government Resolution of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Rules of the House of Representatives to ban gifts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="1995-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="402524" joined="1995-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1995-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1995-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1995-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="1995-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1376"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Standards of Official Conduct</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Rules and Organization of the House.</text>
      <committee name="House Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Rules of the House" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/1995--Introduced.
Clean Government Resolution of 1995 - Amends rule XLIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit Members, officers, or employees of the House from accepting a gift from anyone. (Currently, such individuals are permitted to accept gifts of $100 or less and other gifts of greater value, subject to certain conditions.) Lists exceptions to such prohibition, including: (1) gifts motivated by a personal friendship rather than the position of the Member, officer, or employee (gifts over $250 are subject to a waiver by the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct); (2) items that are not used and are returned to the donor; (3) items of little intrinsic value; (4) bequests, inheritances, and other transfers at death; (5) political contributions reported as required by law; (6) food, lodging, transportation, and entertainment provided on an official basis by Federal, State, and local governments; (7) informational materials sent to a Member's office; (8) nonmonetary awards, trophies, mementos, or honorary degrees; (8) consumable products provided to a Member's office by a home-State business which are primarily intended for consumption by persons other than the Member or staff; (9) awards and prizes given in events open to the public; (10) opportunities and benefits available to the public or Federal employees; (11) opportunities and benefits offered to members of a group in which membership is unrelated to congressional employment; and (12) opportunities and benefits based on outside business or employment activities when it is clear that such opportunities and benefits have not been offered or enhanced because of an individual's official status. Prohibits House Members, officers, or employees from accepting payments or reimbursements for: (1) meals or entertainment, with exceptions for meals or entertainment provided by a relative or friend or at widely attended gatherings; and (2) travel expenses from anyone (including a foreign government) other than a relative or friend. Subjects Members, officers, or employees who violate such gift restrictions to disciplinary action by the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</summary>
</bill>
