<bill session="106" type="h" number="3301" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Children's Health Research and Prevention Amendments of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Advancement in Pediatric Autism Research Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Autism Statistics, Surveillance, Research, and Epidemiology Act of 1999 (ASSURE)</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Children's Asthma Relief Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Folic Acid Promotion and Birth Defects Prevention Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Fragile X Research Breakthrough Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Newborn and Infant Hearing Screening and Intervention Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Pediatric Research Initiative Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Poison Control Center Enhancement and Awareness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Pregnant Mothers and Infants Health Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Safe Motherhood Monitoring and Prevention Research Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to children's health.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400028"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2000-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400568" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="2000-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2000-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2000-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400532" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="2000-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2000-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2000-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2000-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400547" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2000-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="2000-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2000-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="2000-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400508" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400281" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="2000-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2000-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400329" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2000-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2000-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400540" joined="2000-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2000-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400613" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2000-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and women"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arthritis"/>
    <term name="Asthma"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Autism"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Black women"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Bone diseases"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cancer research"/>
    <term name="Cerebral palsy"/>
    <term name="Cesarean section"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Cockroaches"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Deaf"/>
    <term name="Deafness"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Demography"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled children"/>
    <term name="Disabled infants"/>
    <term name="Diseases"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Drugs and women"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Epilepsy"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to nursing education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to substance abuse programs"/>
    <term name="Fetal alcohol syndrome"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Head Start programs"/>
    <term name="Head injuries"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Hearing disorders"/>
    <term name="Heart diseases"/>
    <term name="Hereditary diseases"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human genetics"/>
    <term name="Immunology"/>
    <term name="Infant mortality"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Integrated pest management"/>
    <term name="Joint diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Maternal and infant welfare"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical research personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mental retardation"/>
    <term name="Mentally disabled"/>
    <term name="Mentally disabled children"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Mortality"/>
    <term name="Mothers"/>
    <term name="Nervous system diseases"/>
    <term name="Neurology"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Pediatricians"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Physical education and training"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Poisons"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Prenatal care"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Psychotropic drugs"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Regional medical programs"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Urology"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Vital statistics"/>
    <term name="Vitamins"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
    <term name="Weight loss"/>
    <term name="Wife abuse"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Revision and Extension of Programs Subtitle A: Pediatric Research Initiative Subtitle B: Other Programs Title II: Children's Health Research and Prevention Activities Subtitle A: Early Detection, Diagnosis, and Treatment Regarding Hearing Loss in Infants Subtitle B: Autism Chapter 1: Surveillance and Research Regarding Prevalence and Pattern of Autism Chapter 2: Expansion, Intensification, and Coordination of Activities of Department of Health and Human Services with Respect to Autism Subtitle C: Poison Control Center Enhancement and Awareness Subtitle D: Birth Defects Prevention Activities Chapter 1: Folic Acid Promotion Chapter 2: National Center on Birth Defects and Developmental Disabilities Subtitle E: Safe Motherhood Monitoring and Prevention Research Subtitle F: Pregnant Mothers and Infants Health Promotion Subtitle G: Utilization of Preventive Health Services Subtitle H: Research and Development Regarding Fragile X Subtitle I: Children and Epilepsy Subtitle J: Asthma Treatment Services for Children Subtitle K: Juvenile Arthritis and Related Conditions Subtitle L: Childhood Skeletal Malignancies Subtitle M: Reducing Burden of Diabetes Among Children and Youth Subtitle N: Miscellaneous Provisions Children's Health Research and Prevention Amendments of 1999 - Title I: Revision and Extension of Programs - Subtitle A: Pediatric Research Initiative - Pediatric Research Initiative Act of 1999 - Amends the Public Health Service Act (the Act) to mandate establishment, in the National Institutes of Health (NIH), of a Pediatric Research Initiative. Authorizes appropriations.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) (Secretary) to make available within the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development enhanced support for extramural activities relating to the training and career development of pediatric researchers. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle B: Other Programs - Extends through FY 2003 programs under the Act for: (1) immunizations; (2) screenings, referrals, and education regarding lead poisoning; and (3) the prevention and control of injuries, including traumatic brain injury.Title II: Children's Health Research and Prevention Activities - Subtitle A: Early Detection, Diagnosis, and Treatment Regarding Hearing Loss in Infants - Newborn and Infant Hearing Screening and Intervention Act of 1999 - Mandates grants or cooperative agreements to: (1) develop statewide newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation, and intervention programs and systems; and (2) provide technical assistance to State agencies to complement an intramural program and to conduct applied research related to newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation, and intervention programs and systems. Requires NIH to continue a program of research and development on the efficacy of new screening techniques and technology. Mandates Federal coordination and collaboration with State and local agencies, consumer groups, national medical, health, and education specialty organizations, deaf or hard-of-hearing individuals and their families, qualified professional personnel, and related commercial industries. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle B: Autism - Chapter 1: Surveillance and Research Regarding Prevalence and Pattern of Autism - Autism Statistics, Surveillance, Research, and Epidemiology Act of 1999 (ASSURE) - Authorizes grants and cooperative agreements for the collection, analysis, and reporting of data on autism and pervasive developmental disabilities.Mandates establishment, through grants or cooperative agreements, of three to five centers of excellence in autism and pervasive developmental disabilities epidemiology to collect and analyze autism information.Requires that the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDCP) serve as the coordinating agency for autism and pervasive development disabilities surveillance through the establishment of a clearinghouse for data generated from the monitoring programs created under this chapter.Mandates establishment of an Advisory Committee for Autism and Pervasive Developmental Disabilities Epidemiology Research.Authorizes appropriations.Chapter 2: Expansion, Intensification, and Coordination of Activities of Department of Health and Human Services With Respect to Autism - Advancement in Pediatric Autism Research Act of 1999 - Directs the NIH Director to expand, intensify, and coordinate the activities of NIH with respect to autism. Requires such Director, among other things, to make awards of grants or contracts to public or nonprofit entities for centers of excellence regarding research on autism. Authorizes appropriations.Authorizes the Secretary to make awards of grants and cooperative agreements for the collection, analysis, and reporting of data on autism and pervasive developmental disabilities. Directs the Secretary to establish no less than three regional centers of excellence in autism and pervasive developmental disabilities epidemiology to collect and analyze information on the number, incidence, correlates, and causes of autism and related developmental disabilities. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a clearinghouse within the CDCP for the collection and storage of such data; and (2) coordinate the Federal response to requests for assistance regarding potential or alleged autism or developmental disability clusters. Authorizes appropriations.Requires the Secretary to establish a program to provide information and education on autism to health professionals and the general public. Authorizes appropriations.Directs the Secretary to establish an Autism Coordinating Committee to coordinate HHS efforts concerning autism.Subtitle C: Poison Control Center Enhancement and Awareness - Poison Control Center Enhancement and Awareness Act - Directs the Secretary to provide coordination and assistance to regional poison control centers for the establishment of a nationwide toll-free telephone number to be used to access such centers. Authorizes appropriations.Mandates a national media campaign to educate the public about poison prevention and the availability of local poison control resources and to conduct advertising campaigns concerning the nationwide toll-free number. Authorizes appropriations.Mandates grants for certified regional poison control centers to achieve financial stability and to prevent, and provide treatment recommendations for, poisoning. Mandates other grant uses. Sets forth center certification requirements. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle D: Birth Defects Prevention Activities - Chapter 1: Folic Acid - Folic Acid Promotion and Birth Defects Prevention Act of 1999 - Directs the Secretary to carry out a program, directly or through grants or contracts, for professional and public education and training, research, and epidemiological activities regarding folic acid and birth defects. Authorizes appropriations.Chapter 2: National Center on Birth Defects and Developmental Disabilities - Establishes a National Center on Birth Defects and Developmental Disabilities to: (1) collect, analyze, and make available date on birth defects; (2) conduct applied epidemiological research on prevention of such defects; and (3) provide birth defect prevention information and education to the public. Transfers to such Center all activities, budgets, and personnel of the National Center for Environmental Health that relate to birth defects, folic acid, cerebral palsy, mental retardation, child development, newborn screening, autism, fragile X syndrome, fetal alcohol syndrome, pediatric genetics, and disability prevention. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle E: Safe Motherhood Monitoring and Prevention Research - Safe Motherhood Monitoring and Prevention Research Act - Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) establish a national monitoring and surveillance program to identify and promote the investigation of deaths and severe complications that occur during pregnancy; (2) expand the Pregnancy Risk Assessment Monitoring System to provide surveillance and collect data in each State; and (3) expand the Maternal and Child Health Epidemiology Program to provide technical support, financial assistance, or the time-limited assignment of senior epidemiologists to maternal and child health programs in each State. Authorizes appropriations.Permits the Secretary to carry out specified activities to promote safe motherhood. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle F: Pregnant Mothers and Infants Health Promotion - Pregnant Mothers and Infants Health Protection Act - Requires the Secretary to: (1) collect, analyze, and make available data on prenatal smoking and alcohol and illegal drug usage; (2) conduct applied epidemiological research on the prevention of prenatal and postnatal smoking and alcohol and illegal drug usage; (3) support, conduct, and evaluate the effectiveness of educational and cessation programs; and (4) provide information and education to the public on the prevention and implications of prenatal and postnatal smoking and alcohol and illegal drug usage. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle G: Utilization of Preventive Health Services - Directs the Secretary to make grants to public or nonprofit entities to establish and operate regional centers for identifying particular populations of patients and to facilitate the appropriate utilization of preventive health services by such patients. Requires the Secretary to give priority to various populations of infants, young children, and their mothers. Requires the evaluation of strategies developed through grant funding. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle H: Research and Development Regarding Fragile X - Fragile X Research Breakthrough Act of 1999 - Requires the Director of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development to: (1) expand, intensify, and coordinate the Institute's activities respecting research on the mental retardation disease known as fragile X; and (2) make grants to, and enter into contracts with, public or private nonprofit entities for the development and operation of at least three centers for fragile X research. Requires each center to conduct basic and clinical research, which may include clinical trials of new or improved diagnostic methods and drugs or other treatment approaches. Allows such centers to use grant funds to provide fees to individuals serving as subjects in clinical trials.Requires the Director to provide for the coordination of the centers' activities, including the exchange of information. Requires each center to use the facilities of a single institution, or be formed from a consortium of cooperating institutions. Allows support to be provided to a center for up to five years, with authorized extensions. Authorizes appropriations.Requires the Secretary to enter into contracts with qualified health professionals who agree to conduct fragile X research in return for repayment (up to $35,000 for each year of service) of such health professionals' educational loans. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle I: Children and Epilepsy - Directs the Secretary, through grants to or contracts with public or nonprofit private entities, to develop and implement public health surveillance, education, research, and intervention strategies to improve the lives of persons with epilepsy, with a particular emphasis on children. Authorizes appropriations.Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to State and local governments for carrying out demonstration projects to improve access to health and other services regarding seizures to encourage early detection and treatment in children and others residing in medically underserved areas. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle J: Asthma Treatment Services for Children - Children's Asthma Relief Act of 1999 - Directs the Secretary to award grants to eligible entities to establish an asthma treatment grants program providing comprehensive asthma services for children and other individuals. Authorizes appropriations.Directs the Secretary to encourage States to implement plans to carry out activities to assist children with asthma in accordance with the guidelines of the National Asthma Education and Prevention Program and the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (Institute).Provides that if a State child health plan under title XXI (Children's Health Insurance) of the Social Security Act provides for such activities to the Secretary's satisfaction, the Secretary shall make a grant to assist the State in carrying them out. Sets forth certain matching funds requirements. Authorizes appropriations.Amends the Act to include, within the preventive health and health services block grant, any system for reducing asthma and asthma-related illnesses, especially with regard to children, through urban cockroach pest management in public facilities through a combination of biological, cultural, physical, and chemical tools that minimizes economic, health, and environmental risks.Requires the Institute Director to: (1) identify all Federal programs carrying out asthma-related activities; (2) develop a Federal plan for responding to asthma; and (3) submit recommendations to Congress on ways to strengthen and improve Federal coordination of such activities. Authorizes appropriations.Requires the CDCP Director to: (1) conduct local asthma surveillance activities to collect data on the prevalence and severity of asthma and the quality of asthma management; and (2) compile and publish annually data on the prevalence of children suffering from asthma in each State and the childhood mortality rate associated with asthma nationally and in each State.Subtitle K: Juvenile Arthritis and Related Conditions - Requires the Directors of the National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases and the National Institute of Allergies and Infectious Diseases to expand and intensify their respective programs of research and related activities concerning juvenile arthritis and related conditions. Requires the NIH Director, through a grant, cooperative agreement, or contract, to establish an information resource center on arthritis and related conditions. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle L: Childhood Skeletal Malignancies - Directs the Secretary to: (1) study environmental and other risk factors for childhood skeletal cancers; (2) carry out projects to improve outcomes among children with such cancers and related secondary conditions; and (3) ensure that such activities are coordinated with other Public Health Service activities focused on childhood cancers and limb loss. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle M: Reducing Burden of Diabetes Among Children and Youth - Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop a system to collect data on juvenile diabetes, including its incidence and prevalence, and to establish a national database for such data; (2) conduct or support long-term epidemiological studies concerning juvenile diabetes; (3) implement a national public health effort to address type 2 diabetes in youth; (4) support regional clinical centers for the cure of juvenile diabetes; and (5) implement a national effort to develop a vaccine for type 1 diabetes. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle N: Miscellaneous Provisions - Requires the NIH Director to report to Congress concerning research activities with respect to rare diseases in children.</summary>
</bill>
