<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="357" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:47-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="961" sequence="2"/>
  <status datetime="1995-05-10T19:48:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <offered datetime="1995-05-10"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to retain provisions regarding Clean Water Act funding authorizations, assistance to small and rural communities, control of water pollution from combined sewer overflows (CSOs) and consistency of State programs with the Environmental Protection Agency's Great Lakes water quality guidance; replace wetlands language with provisions providing incentives for States to assume authority over wetlands regulation through delegation from EPA; expedite the Federal wetlands permitting process; make the Agriculture Department responsible for determining which areas are to be designated wetlands on all agriculture lands; require the establishment of a coordinating committee of Federal, State, and local officials to help develop and field-test national wetlands policies and a strategy for restoration of wetlands ecosystems; strike provisions establishing new requirements to compensate landowners for losses in property value resulting from Federal regulation; retain the special runoff control provisions currently applicable to coastal areas, but modify the current program in accordance with recommendations of the Coastal States Organization; allow affected States to target runoff control programs to the areas most threatened by pollution and give greater authority to use incentive-based programs and planning and manageme.t measures in lieu of enforceable requirements; retain the existing storm water management program, making several changes in the program, including placing a ten-year moratorium on the implementation of any new storm water requirements for light industries or communities with a population of less than 100,000; and prohibit the application of numeric effluent limits to municipal storm water permits.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute (printed as amendment No.49 in the Congressional Record of May 9, 1995) that would retain the provisions in the bill regarding Clean Water funding authorizations, assistance to local communities, control of combined sewer overflows, and coordination of state programs for compliance with EPA Great Lakes water quality guidelines. The amendment would not include those provisions in the bill which authorize waivers to secondary treatment requirements for sewage treatment plants in costal communities with a population of less than 20,000; nor would it allow waivers and modifications of discharge permits for industrial facilities and sewage treatment plants, or allow states to downgrade designated uses of water bodies and applicable water quality standards. The amendment would substitute the provisions in the bill regarding wetlands with provisions that delegate authority over wetlands to the States; grant to the Dept. of Agriculture responsibility for designating wetlands on agricultural land; establish federal, state, and local coordinating committee to develop and test national wetlands policies and procedures for wetland restoration. The amendment would not include the new requirements in the bill for compensating landowners for property losses resulting from regulation.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Saxton.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1995-05-10T19:48:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="312">
      <text>On agreeing to the Saxton amendment (A002) as amended Failed by recorded vote: 184 - 242 (Roll no. 312).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
