<bill session="106" type="h" number="232" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Biennial Budget Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a two-year Federal budget cycle, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400334"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1999-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1999-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1999-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="1999-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1999-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1999-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="1999-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biennial budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget reconciliation"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Capital budgets"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Federal budget process"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fiscal year"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="House Government Reform"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Senate Rules and Administration"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
Biennial Budget Act of 1999 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to revise the Federal and congressional budget processes by establishing a two-year budgeting and appropriations cycle and timetable. Revises the timetable with respect to the congressional budget process. (Sec. 4) Amends the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act to define the budget biennium as the two consecutive fiscal years beginning on October 1 of any odd-numbered year. Makes conforming amendments to provisions regarding the congressional budget process. Revises provisions relating to the reconciliation process to: (1) raise the ceiling on debate in the Senate on any reported reconciliation measure from 20 to 100 hours; and (2) provide a point of order against consideration of reconciliation measures in the House of Representatives or the Senate which change any provision of law other than those which provide certain new budget or spending authority relating to Government corporations or gifts made to the United States, relate to revenues, or specify the amount of the public debt limit. (Sec. 5) Conforms provisions governing the President's budget to the biennial framework. (Sec. 6) Requires all Acts making regular appropriations for the support of the Government to be enacted for a biennium and to specify the amount of appropriations provided for each fiscal year in that period. (Sec. 7) Requires the heads of Federal agencies, the Comptroller General, and the heads of specified legislative branch agencies to provide requested information and assistance to the chairmen and ranking minority members of the House and Senate standing committees with respect to program administration. (Sec. 8) Makes conforming amendments regarding the biennial budget cycle to the Rules of the House of Representatives. (Sec. 9) Applies this Act to bienniums beginning after September 30, 2001.</summary>
</bill>
