<bill session="106" type="h" number="4904" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-26T18:41:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-09-26T18:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To express the policy of the United States regarding the United States relationship with Native Hawaiians, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2000-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1301-1302"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-897.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-26T18:32:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="541">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 541.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T18:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8146-8153" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T18:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4904.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-09-26T18:41:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8146-8149" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-10-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="893">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 893.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2899"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2899"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2899"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal incorporation"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Homestead law"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Statehood (American politics)"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2000--Passed House amended.
Establishes the U.S. Office for Native Hawaiian Affairs (Office) within the Office of the Secretary of the Interior.(Sec. 5) Requires the Attorney General to designate a Department of Justice official to assist the Office in the implementation and protection of the rights of Native Hawaiians and their political, legal, and trust relationship with the United States.(Sec. 6) Establishes the Native Hawaiian Interagency Task Force to: (1) coordinate Federal policies that affect Native Hawaiians or actions by Federal agencies which may significantly or uniquely impact on Native Hawaiian resources, rights, or lands; (2) assure that each Federal agency develops a policy on consultation with Native Hawaiians; and (3) assure the participation of such agencies in the development of an annual report on Task Force activities to specified congressional committees.(Sec. 7) Establishes a process for development of a membership roll for organizing a Native Hawaiian Interim Governing Council and for election of a Native Hawaiian government. Recognizes the right of the Native Hawaiian people to adopt organic governing documents. Requires the elected officers of the government to submit such documents to the Secretary for certification.Extends Federal recognition to the government as the representative governing body of the Native Hawaiian people upon election of officers and certification by the Secretary that the documents: (1) were adopted by a majority vote of the adult members listed on the roll; (2) are consistent with Federal law and the special trust relationship between the United States and its native peoples; (3) provide for exercise of governmental authorities exercised by other governments representing U.S. native peoples; (4) provide for the protection of civil rights; (5) prevent the sale, disposition, lease, or encumbrance of assets of the government without its consent; (6) establish criteria for citizenship in the government; and (7) provide authority for the government to negotiate with Federal, State, and local governments and other entities.(Sec. 8) Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 9) Permits the United States, upon Federal recognition of the Native Hawaiian government, to enter into an agreement with the State of Hawaii and the government regarding the transfer of lands, resources, and assets dedicated to Native Hawaiian use under existing law to the government.</summary>
</bill>
