<bill session="108" type="h" number="4797" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Continuity of Operations Demonstration Project Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a demonstration project to enhance the ability of Federal agencies to continue to operate during an extended emergency situation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2004-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2004-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2004-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2004-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2004-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2004-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2004-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2004-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2004-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2004-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1370-1371"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Decentralization in government"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telecommuting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2004--Introduced.
Continuity of Operations Demonstration Project Act - Directs the Chief Human Capital Officers Council, in order to test the preparedness of the Government to continue to operate in the event of an extended emergency situation, to establish a demonstration project under which, through agreements with two or more agencies, a representative range of Government services and operations (both essential and nonessential) shall be performed under circumstances simulating a situation in which Federal employees are, as a result of a sudden and unexpected contingency, required to work: (1) from home or other sites apart from their usual and customary duty station; and (2) for a continuous period of not less than 30 days. Directs the Council, in carrying out the demonstration project, to ensure that specified requirements are met with respect to: (1) communications; (2) access to technologies, information, or other resources; (3) participation (limited to those employees who would otherwise have been eligible to telework); and (4) coordination with otherwise existing Federal telework policies, requirements, and funding.</summary>
</bill>
