<bill session="106" type="h" number="2232" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Debt Relief and Development in Africa Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide bilateral and multilateral debt relief to countries in sub-Saharan Africa.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="1999-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International corporations"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/1999--Introduced.
Debt Relief and Development in Africa Act of 1999 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to direct the President, subject to authorization of appropriations, to cancel or reduce all amounts owed to the United States by heavily indebted poor countries (HIPCs) in sub-Saharan Africa as a result of concessional and nonconcessional loans made, guarantees issued, or credits extended prior to January 1, 1996, under any provision of law. Sets forth eligibility requirements for cancellation or reduction of debt for HIPCs. Directs the President, in canceling or reducing debt, to give priority to HIPCs that have demonstrated a sustained commitment to poverty alleviation or to the poorest HIPCs (as determined by its per capita income, the United Nations' Human Development Index, or another relevant measure of poverty), and the highest priority to HIPCs that meet both requirements.(Sec. 2) Provides that cancellation or reduction of debt shall not be considered assistance for purposes of any law limiting assistance to a country.Declares the sense of Congress that amounts that would otherwise be provided by the United States for development aid or other debt relief should not be reduced on account of any appropriations for debt cancellation or reduction.Authorizes appropriations.Sets forth certain procedures for the making of new loans, extending new credits, or issuing new guarantees to the governments of developing countries.(Sec. 3) Directs the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (AID) to establish and carry out a program to provide assistance, including technical assistance, to HIPCs in sub-Saharan Africa for the purpose of: (1) establishing plans for the development of such countries' natural resources in a manner that will benefit their population; and (2) negotiating or renegotiating equitable contracts with foreign or multinational corporations for the development of natural resources.Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 4) Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to prohibit the Export-Import Bank of the United States from insuring, guaranteeing, extending or participating in an extension of credit to any private entity that is involved in developing natural resources in a sub-Saharan African HIPC unless the contract between the entity and the government of such country (including any enterprise owned or controlled by any such government) is made available to the public.(Sec. 5) Urges the President to establish efforts with other countries that are members of the Paris Club of Official Creditors (Paris Club), and, if necessary, with other creditors to: (1) cancel or reduce debts owed each such country by a sub-Saharan African HIPC as a result of concessional loans and nonconcessional loans made, guarantees issued, or credits extended before January 1, 1996; and (2) establish Paris Club procedures to ensure greater transparency in the decision-making process, including specified measures.(Sec. 6) Amends the International Financial Institutions Act to urge the President, in order to accelerate multilateral debt relief and promote economic and human development and poverty alleviation in sub-Saharan African HIPCs, to commence efforts within the Paris Club, as well as the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (World Bank), the International Monetary Fund (IMF), the African Development Bank, and other appropriate multilateral development institutions, to make certain modifications in the HIPC Initiative, including: (1) that the provision of debt reduction shall not be conditioned on any a sub- Saharan African HIPC's adopting or implementing any structural adjustment program, but may be conditioned on good governance, transparency, or the elimination of economic corruption; (2) the revision of country eligibility requirements under the HIPC Initiative; (3) the adoption of a human development action plan and fund by sub-Saharan African HIPCs; (4) that debt reduction shall not be provided to a country that has not established a natural resources development plan; (5) the timing of the provision of debt relief; (6) specified goals for the amount of debt reduction; (7) transparency and participation by sub-Saharan African HIPCs in HIPC decision making; (8) the evaluation of debt relief eligibility by the African Development Bank; (9) the establishment of a Monitoring Panel for each country that is eligible to receive debt reduction under the HIPC Initiative; (10) priority with respect to the provision of debt reduction be given to the poorest countries and countries committed to poverty alleviation; (11) the provision of HIPC Initiative review; and (12) that the HIPC Initiative shall not terminate until all debt reduction has been completed under this Act.Urges the President to commence efforts to ensure that creditors draw upon their own resources to finance debt reduction under the HIPC Initiative to the extent possible without diverting funds from other high priority poverty alleviation programs.Authorizes appropriations to the HIPC Trust Fund.Declares the sense of Congress that amounts that would otherwise be provided by the United States for development aid or other debt relief should not be reduced on account of any such appropriations.Directs the President to report annually to specified congressional committees on progress made in accomplishing the goals in this Act.Directs the President to work with member countries of the international financial institutions to ensure, through specified measures, transparency and public participation in decisions to make new loans (including the terms and conditions of such loans) to developing countries.Amends the Bretton Woods Agreements Act to prohibit the U.S. director to the IMF from voting for any proposal to sell or otherwise convert or liquidate gold, unless there are in effect laws and procedures to ensure that all the proceeds obtained from its sale, conversion, or liquidation are deposited in the HIPC Trust Fund, and that such funds are only used for debt reduction under the HIPC Initiative.</summary>
</bill>
