<bill session="105" type="h" number="4239" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financial Contract Netting Improvement Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To revise the banking and bankruptcy insolvency laws with respect to the termination and netting of financial contracts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1998-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Bank fraud"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Certificates of deposit"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Margins (Security trading)"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Options (Contract)"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Swaps (Finance)"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/1998--Introduced.
Financial Contract Netting Improvement Act of 1998 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (FDIA) to redefine specified contracts, agreements, and transfers entered into with an insolvent insured depository institution before the appointment of a conservator or receiver for it. (Sec. 2) Excludes from the meaning of securities contract (which may be terminated or repudiated by a conservator or receiver) any agreement (with specified exceptions) providing for the transfer of securities against the transfer of funds by the securities transferee with a simultaneous agreement by such transferee to transfer certain securities to the original transferor against the transfer of funds. Excludes from the meaning of swap agreement any transaction, no matter how documented, that is in substance a commercial, consumer, or industrial loan. Declares that no person shall be stayed or prohibited from exercising any right to cause the acceleration of any qualified financial contract with an insured depository institution which arises upon the appointment of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) as receiver at any time after such appointment. (Sec. 3) Declares that no provision of law shall be construed as limiting the right or power of the FDIC, or authorizing any court or agency to limit or delay, in any manner, the FDIC's right or power to transfer, disaffirm, or repudiate any qualified financial contract of a failed institution. Prohibits enforcement of a walkaway clause in a qualified financial contract of a failed insured depository institution (a clause that either does not create a payment obligation of a party, or extinguishes it solely because of such party's status as a nondefaulting party). (Sec. 4) Revises guidelines governing transfers of qualified financial contracts of an insolvent institution to include: (1) transfers to a foreign bank or foreign financial institution (including its branch or agency) (but only when the contractual rights of the parties to such qualified financial contracts are enforceable substantially to the same extent as permitted under such Act); and (2) transfers of contracts subject to the rules of a clearing organization. Defines financial institution to include a broker or dealer, a depository institution, a futures commission merchant, or any other institution as determined by FDIC regulation. Suspends certain termination rights of counterparties to a qualified financial contract with an insolvent insured depository institution until after the receiver's appointment, or after receipt of notice that the contract has been transferred. Declares that none of the following institutions shall be considered a financial institution for which a conservator, receiver, trustee in bankruptcy, or other legal custodian has been appointed or which is otherwise the subject of a bankruptcy or insolvency proceeding: (1) a bridge bank; or (2) an FDIC-organized depository institution for which a conservator is appointed either immediately upon organization, or at the time of a purchase and assumption transaction between such institution and the FDIC as receiver for a depository institution in default. (Sec. 5) Prescribes guidelines for: (1) the disaffirmance or repudiation of qualified financial contracts by the conservator or receiver for a failed depository institution; and (2) the treatment of a master agreement as a single agreement and a single qualified financial contract. (Sec. 7) Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act of 1991 to make conforming amendments with respect to: (1) bilateral netting contracts; (2) security agreements; (3) clearing organization netting contracts; (4) contracts with uninsured national banks; and (5) contracts with uninsured Federal branches or agencies. (Sec. 8) Amends the Federal Bankruptcy Code to reflect the changes made by this Act and to: (1) deny an automatic stay to set-offs under certain swap agreements and netting agreements; and (2) restrict the avoidance power of the bankruptcy trustee regarding certain master netting agreement transfers to those transfers that are fraudulent in nature. Sets forth statutory guidelines for: (1) the termination or acceleration of designated contracts and agreements; and (2) commodity broker and stockbroker liquidation with respect to the priority of unsecured claims, or customer property or distributions. (Sec. 9) Amends the FDIA to authorize the FDIC to prescribe more detailed recordkeeping requirements for qualified financial contracts (including market valuations) by insured depository institutions. (Sec. 10) Exempts specified collateralization agreements from the contemporaneous execution requirement that renders invalid certain agreements against FDIC interests in certain asset acquisitions. (Sec. 11) Amends Federal bankruptcy law to specify the date for the measure of damages in connection with: (1) rejection by the bankruptcy trustee of designated contracts and agreements relating to executory contracts and unexpired leases; or (2) the liquidation, acceleration, or termination of such contracts and agreements. (Sec. 12) Amends the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1971 to provide that neither the filing of a protective decree by the Securities Investor Protection Corporation (SIPC), nor any court protective order, shall operate as a stay of a creditor's contractual rights to liquidate, terminate, or accelerate designated contracts and agreements. Allows such application, order, or decree, however, to operate as a stay of foreclosure on securities collateral pledged by the debtor, whether or not with respect to one or more of such contracts or agreements, or securities sold by the debtor under a repurchase agreement.</summary>
</bill>
