<bill session="104" type="hr" number="237" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-10-18T17:49:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-10-18T17:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2259) to disapprove certain sentencing guideline amendments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400327"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-10-17T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-279, by Ms. Pryce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-17T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2259 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. A specified amendment is in order. An amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of S. 1254, as passed by the Senate, shall be considered as adopted in the Committee of the Whole and in the House. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of further amendment. No further amendment shall be in order except the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, debatable for 1 hour and not subject to amendment. After passage of the bill, it shall be in order to take from the Sp eaker's table and consider the bill S. 1254. It shall be in order to move to strike all afte...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-10-17T18:25:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="101">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 101.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T16:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10255-10263" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-10-18T17:49:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="2259"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/17/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the modified closed rule for consideration of H.R. 2259 (disapproving certain sentencing guideline amendments).</summary>
</bill>
