<bill session="106" type="h" number="4161" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Right to Organize Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen the rights of workers to associate, organize and strike, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2000--Introduced.
Right to Organize Act of 2000 - Amends the National Labor Relations Act (NLRA) to revise requirements relating to employer and labor organization (union) presentations to employees on issues relating to union representation.(Sec. 2) Requires that, if an employer (or employer representative) addresses employees on the employer's premises or during work hours on such issues, the employees be assured, without loss of time or pay, an equal opportunity to obtain, in an equivalent manner, information concerning issues from a union.Requires that unions, subject to reasonable regulation by the National Labor Relations Board, have: (1) access to areas in which employees work; (2) the right to use the employer's bulletin boards, mailboxes, and other communication media; and (3) the right to use the employer's facilities for the purpose of meetings with respect to the exercise of the rights guaranteed by NLRA.(Sec. 3) Requires the Board to: (1) award back pay equal to three times the employee's wages upon finding that an employee was discharged as a result of an unfair labor practice; and (2) notify the employee of the right to sue for punitive damages and (compensatory) damages with respect to wrongful discharge under the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947 (LMRA).Amends LMRA to: (1) prohibit employers from discharging employees for exercising rights protected under NLRA; and (2) allow employees to file civil actions in U.S. district courts to recover punitive damages when they have been discharged as a result of an unfair labor practice, or if actionable, in any State court to recover damages based on wrongful discharge.(Sec. 4) Amends NLRA to establish mediation and arbitration procedures for initial contract collective bargaining agreements. Requires mediation if the employer and union cannot reach agreement on their own within 60 days after certification of a new union. Allows either party to transfer matters remaining in controversy to the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service for binding arbitration if the parties have not reached agreement 30 days after a mediator is selected.</summary>
</bill>
