<bill session="107" type="h" number="3843" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Information Technology Work Force and Acquisition Improvement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Clinger-Cohen Act of 1996 to extend until January 1, 2008, a program applying simplified procedures to the acquisition of certain commercial items; to establish an exchange program between the Federal Government and the private sector in order to promote the development of expertise in information technology management; and to authorize telecommuting for Federal contractors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2002-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Telecommuting"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2002--Introduced.
Federal Information Technology Workforce and Acquisition Improvement Act of 2002 - Amends the Clinger-Cohen Act of 1996 to extend until January 1, 2008, the authority to issue solicitations for purchases of commercial items in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold pursuant to the special simplified procedures.Establishes an information technology exchange program between the Government and the private sector. Provides for one-year assignments of executive agency information technology management employees to private sector organizations, and of private sector information technology management employees to executive agencies.Sets forth administrative provisions governing such assignments, including pay, creditable service, life and health insurance coverage, reimbursement, liability, and Federal employee status.Requires the Federal Acquisition Regulation to be amended to permit the use of telecommuting by employees of Federal contractors in the performance of contracts with executive agencies.</summary>
</bill>
