<bill session="104" type="h" number="914" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Environmental Lender and Fiduciaries Liability Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act and the Solid Waste Disposal Act to limit the liabilities under these Acts of both fiduciaries and lending institutions, including finance lessors, guarantors, and others directly or indirectly holding indicia of ownership primarily to protect a security interest in property which is subject to either Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1995-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400300" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1995-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-13">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Commercial law"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/1995--Introduced.
Environmental Lender and Fiduciaries Liability Amendments Act of 1995 - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to exclude from the definition of "owner or operator," for purposes of limiting liability for releases of hazardous substances, a person who, without participating in the management of a vessel or facility, holds indicia of ownership primarily to protect a security interest in such vessel or facility. Defines "indicia of ownership" as an interest in property acquired: (1) for securing payment of a loan or indebtedness or the performance of an obligation; (2) evidencing ownership under a lease financing transaction where the lessor does not initially select or ordinarily control the daily operation or maintenance of the property; or (3) in the course of protecting a security interest or right of reimbursement or subrogation under a guaranty. Makes liable for any release or threatened release of a hazardous substance attributable to their activities: (1) a holder of a security interest who takes certain actions concerning transfer, protection, or abandonment of property; and (2) a fiduciary or trustee who acquires ownership or control of a property. Makes conforming amendments to the Solid Waste Disposal Act.</summary>
</bill>
