<bill session="105" type="h" number="1148" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Panama Canal Commission Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize expenditures for fiscal year 1998 for the operation and maintenance of the Panama Canal, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400569"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="1997-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06">
      <text>See H.R.1119.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="1119"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air travel"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Dismissal wage"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Interoceanic canals"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Maritime law"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Panama"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal Commission"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Relocation of employees"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Subtitle A: Authorization of Appropriations Subtitle B: Amendments to Panama Canal Act of 1979 Subtitle A: Authorization of Appropriations - Panama Canal Commission Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998 - Authorizes the Panama Canal Commission to make expenditures as necessary for the operation, maintenance, improvement, and administration of the Panama Canal for FY 1998. Makes funds available for the purchase, and transportation to Panama, of passenger motor vehicles (limiting the per vehicle purchase price to $22,000). Subtitle B: Amendments to Panama Canal Act of 1979 - Panama Canal Act Amendments of 1979 (sic) - Amends the Panama Canal Act of 1979 to: (1) empower the Commission to appoint U.S. citizens as notaries public, and to conduct and promote commercial activities related to the management, operation, or maintenance of the Canal; (2) exempt Commission officers and employees from Federal post-employment restrictions following termination of their employment on December 31, 1999; (3) repeal certain Commission employee pay, travel and transportation provisions; (4) authorize the Administrator of the Commission to pay a bonus to a newly recruited employee or an employee who must relocate to accept a position (requires the employee to contract to complete a period of employment established by the Commission) and to pay a retention bonus to other employees under specified circumstances; (5) authorize the Commission (currently, the President) to regulate the Panama Canal Board of Appeals; (6) authorize use of the Panama Canal Revolving Fund to pay severance pay to Commission employees; (7) direct an executive agency (currently, the Commission) to enter into supplies and materials contracts and other transactions with the Republic of Panama; (8) provide a time limitation with respect to the filing of admiralty claims with the Commission; (9) authorize the Commission to establish toll rates for yachts using the Canal; (10) revise generally Federal provisions concerning retirement eligibility for Commission employees; and (11) authorize reserve and retired military personnel to accept employment with the Panama Canal Authority (the successor to the Commission).</summary>
</bill>
