<bill session="106" type="h" number="2820" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-03T20:00:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-03T20:00:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the ownership and operation of the irrigation works on the Salt River Pima-Maricopa Indian Community's reservation in Maricopa County, Arizona, by the Salt River Pima-Maricopa Indian Community.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400173"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="1999-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T19:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T19:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8713-8717" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T19:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2820.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-10-03T20:00:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8713-8714" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2000--Passed House amended.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Salt River Pima-Maricopa Indian Community all rights and interests of the United States in and to the irrigation works on the Community's reservation which were formerly operated by the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA). Grants the Community full ownership and operating authority on the date of conveyance of the works.Requires the operation of the works consistent with specified standards, including those for: (1) equitable distribution of water; and (2) a due process system for determination of any request for distribution of water.Cancels on the conveyance date any charges for construction of the works that were deferred.Provides that, upon such date, the works shall no longer be considered a BIA irrigation project and will not be eligible for Federal benefits based solely on the fact that the works were formerly such a project.</summary>
</bill>
