<bill session="106" type="h" number="2734" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Choice for Electricity Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To allow local government entities to serve as nonprofit aggregators of electricity services on behalf of their citizens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1999-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="1999-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Public utility regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
Community Choice for Electricity Act of 1999 - Permits a customer group, or any entity (including a unit of State or local government) acting on behalf of such group, to acquire retail electric energy on an aggregate basis if the customer group is served by one or more local distribution companies subject to retail competition.Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to declare that any State that permits a retail electric consumers group to choose among competing electric energy suppliers shall also permit any general purpose local government unit (or group of such units acting together) to offer to act as purchasing agent for consumers' group purchasers in order to purchase electric energy on an aggregate basis (community choice aggregation). Prescribes implementation guidelines.Requires any State that has deregulated retail sales of electricity to permit local governments to exercise local franchise powers.Excludes from the purview of this Act: (1) non-participating municipal electric utilities and non-participating rural electric cooperatives; and (2) States that have adopted retail competition prior to the date of enactment of this Act. Allows subsequent regulations implementing any State law adopting retail competition to pertain to an opt-out aggregation plan as it may be undertaken by a general purpose local government unit.</summary>
</bill>
