<bill session="105" type="h" number="3133" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Human Cloning Research Prohibition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the expenditure of Federal funds to conduct or support research on the cloning of humans, and to express the sense of the Congress that other countries should establish substantially equivalent restrictions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1998-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="408459" joined="1998-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="1998-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-01-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E49"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-01-28">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-01-28">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cloning"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="DNA"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Human embryology"/>
    <term name="Human genetics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in science"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/28/1998--Introduced.
Human Cloning Research Prohibition Act - Prohibits the expenditure of Federal funds to conduct or support any research on the cloning of humans. Directs the Director of the National Science Foundation to enter into an agreement with the National Research Council for a review of the implementation of this Act. Mandates a report to the Congress containing the results of that review, including the conclusions of the National Research Council on: (1) the impact that the implementation of this Act has had on research; and (2) recommendations for any appropriate changes to this Act. States that nothing in this Act shall restrict other areas of scientific research not specifically prohibited by this Act, including important and promising work that involves: (1) the use of somatic cell nuclear transfer or other cloning technologies to clone molecules, DNA, cells other than human embryo cells, or tissues; or (2) the use of somatic cell nuclear transfer techniques to create animals other than humans. Expresses the sense of the Congress that other countries should establish substantially equivalent prohibitions.</summary>
</bill>
