<bill session="108" type="h" number="2520" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Union Chapel Fossil Footprint Site Preservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to acquire by donation certain property in Alabama to provide for the protection and preservation of certain rare paleontological resources on that property, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400004"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Paleontology"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2003--Introduced.
Union Chapel Fossil Footprint Site Preservation Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to accept, if willingly donated by the New Acton Coal Mining Company, Inc., Cordova, Alabama, the Union Chapel Paleozoic Footprint Preserve, Union Chapel, Alabama, in order to preserve and protect certain rare paleontological resources. Declares that the requirements of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 shall not apply to the New Acton Mining Company, Inc. regarding further reclamation of the Preserve. Permits the return to the New Acton Coal Mining Company, Inc., of all funds held in escrow pending further reclamation of the Union Chapel Mine by the Director of the Surface Coal Mining Commission of the State of Alabama.</summary>
</bill>
