<bill session="104" type="h" number="2406" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-09T18:23:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-05-09T18:23:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Housing Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">United States Housing Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal the United States Housing Act of 1937, deregulate the public housing program and the program for rental housing assistance for low-income families, and increase community control over such programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1995-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="401587" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="402524" joined="1995-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403015" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1995-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="405317" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1995-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1995-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1996-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="1995-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1995-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services. Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10653"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-11-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 18.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01T20:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Banking and Financial Services. H. Rept. 104-461, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-02-01T20:41:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="222">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 222.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-04-25T17:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, H. Rept. 104-461, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-07T22:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 426 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2406 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Banking now printed in the bill. Amendment shall be considered by title rather than by section. Prior to consideration of any other amendment, it shall be in order to consider a Lazio amendment printed in the Congressional Record of May 7, 1996, debatable for 10 minutes and not subject to further amendment. If that amendment is adopted, the bill, as amended, shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment. After passage of t...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T16:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 426 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 426.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4569-4643" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2406 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Banking now printed in the bill. Amendment shall be considered by title rather than by section. Prior to consideration of any other amendment, it shall be in order to consider a Lazio amendment printed in the Congressional Record of May 7, 1996, debatable for 10 minutes and not subject to further amendment. If that amendment is adopted, the bill, as amended, shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment. After passage of the bill, it shall be in order to ta...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 426 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steve Gunderson to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T17:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 426, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lazio amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T20:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL - At the conclusion of debate on the Fields amendment, the Chair put the question on the Fields amendment and declared that by voice vote, the noes had prevailed. Mr. Fields subsequently asked for a recorded vote, and pending that request, made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings were postponed on the amendment and the point of order was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T21:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lazio asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the proposed Frank (MA) amendment No. 7, and all amendments thereto, be limited to not to exceed one hour. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T21:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Frank asked unanimous consent to offer in a modified form the amendment printed as amendment No. 7 in the Congressional Record of May 7, 1996. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T21:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair announced the unfinished business to be the request for a recorded vote on the Fields (LA) amendment, which had been postponed earlier in the day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T22:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lazio asked unanimous consent that debate on all amendments to the bill, and any amendments thereto, be limited to ten minutes, equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, except as follows: 1. The modified Frank (MA) amendment No. 7, debatable for one hour; 2. the Kennedy (MA) amendment No. 17, debatable for one hour; 3. Velazquez amendment Nos. 33 and 34, to be offered en bloc and debatable for twenty minutes; 4. Roemer amendment No. 22, debatable for twenty minutes; and 5. Hayworth amendment No. 9, debatable for twenty minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T22:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lazio moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T22:53:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T22:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2406 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T11:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4662-4738" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T11:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T11:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the order of the House of May 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Frank (MA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Mr. Kennedy asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Frank (MA) amendment, and all amendments thereto, be extended for an additional ten minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T13:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hinchey asked unanimous consent to consider the Hinchey amendment en bloc. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T13:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May, 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hinchey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kennedy asked unanimous consent that the amendments printed in the Congressional Record of May 7, 1996 as amendment Nos. 14 and 18 be considered en bloc. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May, 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kennedy en bloc amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T13:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kennedy asked unanimous consent that it be in order to consider an amendment to title 3 of the bill without prejudice to consideration of further amendments to title 2 of the bill. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T13:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May, 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Kennedy amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T13:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lazio asked unanimous consent that the Kennedy (MA) be modified. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T13:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Vento asked unanimous consent that it be in order to consider an amendment to title 5 of the bill without prejudice to consideration of further amendments to title 2 of the bill. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May, 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Vento amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May, 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Velazquez en bloc amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Valazquez amendment and annouce that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Kennedy requested a recorded vote and, pending that request, made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 426, the Chair postponed further consideration of the amendment. The point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May, 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sanders amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May, 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kennedy amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Traficant asked unanimous consent that it be in order to consider an amendment to title 4 of the bill without prejudice to consideration of further amendments to title 3 of the bill. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May, 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Traficant amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T14:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May, 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Filner amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T14:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May, 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waters amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T15:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Durbin amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T15:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Volkmer moved to strike the enacting clause.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T15:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Volkmer motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T15:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to strike the enacting clause withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - At the conclusion of debate on the Durbin amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Durbin asked for a recorded vote and pending that, made a point of order that a quorum was not present. The Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment and the point of order was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER RESERVED - Mr. Kennedy of Massachusetts reserved a point of order against the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ney amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Hayworth amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of May 8, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Roemer amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2406.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T17:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T17:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kennedy (MA) moved to recommit with instructions to Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T17:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Kennedy (MA) motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T17:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T18:15:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 196 - 226 (Roll No. 160).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4737" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-05-09T18:23:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="161" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 315 - 107 (Roll no. 161).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Laid on the table. See S. 1260 for further action.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4753" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="426"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="104" type="s" number="1260"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1260"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation in crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community policing"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data transmission systems"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Eviction"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Group homes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Housing codes"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Housing for the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Housing management"/>
    <term name="Housing statistics"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian youth"/>
    <term name="Industrialized building"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Management information systems"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Moderate income housing"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Pets"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Prefabricated buildings"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public service employment"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban planning"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1017"/>
    <amendment number="h1018"/>
    <amendment number="h1019"/>
    <amendment number="h1020"/>
    <amendment number="h1021"/>
    <amendment number="h1022"/>
    <amendment number="h1023"/>
    <amendment number="h1024"/>
    <amendment number="h1025"/>
    <amendment number="h1026"/>
    <amendment number="h1027"/>
    <amendment number="h1028"/>
    <amendment number="h1029"/>
    <amendment number="h1030"/>
    <amendment number="h1031"/>
    <amendment number="h1032"/>
    <amendment number="h1033"/>
    <amendment number="h1034"/>
    <amendment number="h1035"/>
    <amendment number="h1036"/>
    <amendment number="h1037"/>
    <amendment number="h1038"/>
    <amendment number="h1039"/>
    <amendment number="h1040"/>
    <amendment number="h1041"/>
    <amendment number="h1042"/>
    <amendment number="h1043"/>
    <amendment number="h1044"/>
    <amendment number="h1045"/>
    <amendment number="h1046"/>
    <amendment number="h1047"/>
    <amendment number="h1048"/>
    <amendment number="h1049"/>
    <amendment number="h1050"/>
    <amendment number="h1051"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/9/1996--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: General Provisions Title II: Public Housing Subtitle A: Block Grants Subtitle B: Admissions and Occupancy Requirements Subtitle C: Management Subtitle D: Homeownership Subtitle E: Disposition, Demolition, and Revitalization of Developments Subtitle F: General Provisions Title III: Choice-Based Rental Housing and Homeownership Assistance for Low-Income Families Subtitle A: Allocation Subtitle B: Choice-Based Housing Assistance for Eligible Families Subtitle C: Payment of Housing Assistance on Behalf of Assisted Families Subtitle D: General and Miscellaneous Provisions Title IV: Accreditation and Oversight of Local Housing and Management Authorities Subtitle A: Housing Foundation and Accreditation Board Subtitle B: Accreditation and Oversight Standards and Procedures Title V: Repeals and Conforming Amendments Title VI: National Commission on Housing Assistance Programs Cost Title VII: Native American Housing Assistance Subtitle A: Block Grants and Grant Requirements Subtitle B: Affordable Housing Activities Subtitle C: Allocation of Grant Amounts Subtitle D: Compliance, Audits, and Reports Subtitle E: Termination of Assistance for Indian Tribes under Incorporated Programs Subtitle F: Loan Guarantees for Affordable Housing Activities Subtitle G: Other Housing Assistance for Native Americans Title VIII: National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Consensus Committee United States Housing Act of 1996 - Title I: General Provisions - Provides for the organization of local housing and management authorities (LHMA) to manage and operate public and assisted housing. Limits housing assistance eligibility and admission of those convicted of drug-related criminal activity and of drug or alcohol abusers. Establishes community work and family self-sufficiency requirements. (Sec. 115) Prohibits using funds under this Act to indemnify contractors or subcontractors against costs regarding infringement of intellectual property rights. Title II: Public Housing - Subtitle A: Block Grants - Directs the Secretary to provide eligible LHMAs with block grant funding for capital and operating activities. Subtitle B: Admissions and Occupancy Requirements - Establishes low-income housing requirements. Authorizes LHMAs to: (1) permit income-mixed occupancy; (2) waive occupancy requirements for law enforcement personnel; (3) establish occupancy preferences; and (4) designate housing for elderly and disabled families. Subtitle C: Management - Sets forth LHMA management provisions, including regarding: (1) management by other entities, including resident-requested independent managers; (2) housing quality requirements; and (3) resident councils and management corporations. Subtitle D: Homeownership - Authorizes LHMAs to carry out a low-income family home ownership program. Subtitle E: Disposition, Demolition, and Revitalization of Developments - Authorizes LHMAs to demolish or dispose of nonviable public housing projects. (Sec. 262) Authorizes severely distressed public housing revitalization grants. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 263) Allows LHMAs to convert a development to choice-based rental housing under this Act. Subtitle F: General Provisions - Authorizes appropriations for: (1) capital and operating block grants; and (2) operation safe home relocations. Title III: Choice-Based Rental Housing and Homeownership Assistance for Low-Income Families - Subtitle A: Allocation - Authorizes contracts with LHMAs for housing assistance for low-income families. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the conversion of certain unused section 8 assistance (United States Housing Act of 1937) to housing assistance under this title. Subtitle B: Choice-Based Housing Assistance for Eligible Families - Provides housing assistance under this title only to: (1) low-income families; or (2) families that qualify to receive such assistance under other Federal law. (Sec. 329) Authorizes LHMAs to: (1) provide a home ownership option; and (2) make assistance payments involving manufactured homes. Subtitle C: Payment of Housing Assistance on Behalf of Assisted Families - Authorizes LHMAs to make housing assistance payments contracts with unit owners. Subtitle D: General and Miscellaneous Provisions - Defines specified terms for purposes of this title. (Sec. 372) Authorizes rental assistance fraud recoveries. Title IV: Accreditation and Oversight of Local Housing and Management Authorities - Subtitle A: Housing Foundation and Accreditation Board - Establishes the Housing Foundation and Accreditation Board to: (1) evaluate deep subsidy housing programs; (2) establish LHMA performance standards; (3) develop effective LHMA financial and performance audits; (4) establish LHMA accreditation guidelines; and (5) classify LHMAs by performance categories. Subtitle B: Accreditation and Oversight Standards and Procedures - Directs the Board to establish LHMA performance benchmarks and accreditation procedures. (Sec. 435) Directs the Secretary to seek performance agreements with agencies that are troubled or at risk of becoming troubled. Authorizes redirecting or withholding funds from local governments whose actions substantially contribute to an LHMA being designated as troubled. (Sec. 437) Authorizes block grant contracts (under title II) to provide for conveyance of title or possession to the Secretary in cases of substantial default. (Sec. 438) Authorizes removal of ineffective LHMAs. (Sec. 439) Directs the Secretary to either take over or contract out the management of chronically troubled LHMAs. (Sec. 440) Provides that a State or local government comprehensive housing affordability strategy shall not be in compliance with provisions of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act unless it includes provisions to improve any troubled public housing agency in its area. (Sec. 443) Applies this subtitle to resident management corporations. Title V: Repeals and Conforming Amendments - Repeals the United States Housing Act of 1937. Repeals specified program provisions under: (1) the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974; (2) the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act; (3) the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987; (4) the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992; (5) the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993; (6) the Housing Act of 1954; (7) the Housing and Community Development Amendments of 1981; (8) the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1991; (9) the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Act, 1992; (10) the Housing and Urban-Rural Recovery Act of 1983; and (11) the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987. (Sec. 502) Amends the Housing Act of 1959 with regard to elderly housing assistance. Declares that, for determining assisted housing eligibility, a person does not have a disability or handicap solely because of the use of a controlled substance or alcohol. Amends the Housing and Urban-Rural Recovery Act of 1983 regarding pet ownership in assisted rental housing for the elderly or handicapped. Directs the Secretary to investigate security contracts awarded by grantees with over 4,500 units under the Public and Assisted Housing Drug Elimination Act of 1990. Mandates actions regarding non-compliant contracts. Provides for reductions in the number of units assisted under contracts under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 and section 236 of the National Housing Act. (Sec. 503) Amends the Anti-Drug Abuse Act of 1988 to replace the drug elimination pilot program with an expanded program of crime elimination grants for public and other low-income federally assisted housing. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 504) Deems rehabilitation activities by Pennrose Properties in New Jersey to have been conducted under specified provisions of the United States Housing Act of 1937. (Sec. 505) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to: (1) modify the definition of "metropolitan city;" and (2) extend an exception for the City and County of Los Angeles regarding the provision of public services. (Sec. 506) Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to allow the transfer of surplus real property to nonprofit organizations that exist to provide housing for homeless or low-income individuals or families. (Sec. 507) Amends the Housing Act of 1949 to deem the city of Altus, Oklahoma, a rural area. (Sec. 508) Presumes State occupancy standards reasonable and, in the absence of State standards, presumes two persons per bedroom reasonable. (Sec. 509) Mandates implementation of the Ida Barbour Revitalization Plan of Portsmouth, Virginia. (Sec. 510) Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act and the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to modify income requirements. (Sec. 511) Amends National Housing Act provisions relating to rental and cooperative housing for lower income families to modify rental requirements. (Sec. 512) Amends Federal law to declare that an obligation containing a gold clause issued on or before October 27, 1977, is discharged on payment in U.S. coin or currency, notwithstanding any assignment or novation (or both) after that date, unless all parties agree to a gold clause in the new agreement. (Sec. 513) Mandates a demonstration program, involving LHMAs and Indian housing authorities, focusing on reducing costs, achieving greater cost effectiveness, and giving incentives to families with children where the head of the household is working (or seeking or preparing for work). (Sec. 514) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to authorize denial of federally assisted housing occupancy for tenants who were, during the last three years, engaged in criminal activity on or off the premises. Allows requiring applicants to consent to criminal record access. Sets forth tenancy termination causes. Allows criminal record access. (Sec. 515) Declares that it is the sense of the Congress that products purchased with this Act's funds should be American made. (Sec. 516) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to limit the amount obtained from obligations guaranteed under specified provisions that may be used for certain housing purposes. (Sec. 517) Mandates consultation with local governments and LHMAs before settlement or consent decree under title III of this Act or the United States Housing Act of 1937, as in effect before this Act. Title VI: National Commission on Housing Assistance Programs Cost - Establishes the National Commission on Housing Assistance Programs Cost to: (1) analyze the per-unit cost to Federal, State, and local governments, public housing agencies, and other parties, of Federal assisted housing programs; and (2) estimate the future taxpayer liability under Federal assisted housing programs before enactment of this Act. Makes available funds from the amounts available for policy, research, and development activities of the Department of Housing and Urban Development. Title VII: Native American Housing Assistance - Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 - Subtitle A: Block Grants and Grant Requirements - Mandates grants to Indian tribes for affordable housing activities. Permits retention of program income. Authorizes appropriations Subtitle B: Affordable Housing Activities - Sets forth national objectives concerning Indian tribe affordable housing activities. Defines eligible activities, including acquisition, construction, reconstruction, and rehabilitation. Requires maintenance of operating assistance. Permits using grant amounts through certain investments. Subtitle C: Allocation of Grant Amounts - Provides for grant allocation. Subtitle D: Compliance, Audits, and Reports - Provides for compliance, audits, and reports. Subtitle E: Termination of Assistance for Indian Tribes under Incorporated Programs - Terminates, for Indian tribes, public and new rental housing assistance provided under the United States Housing Act of 1937. (Sec. 763) Terminates Indian housing assistance by amending the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (Youthbuild and HOME programs), the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act (emergency shelter and rural homelessness grant programs), and the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993 (Innovative Homeless Initiatives Demonstration Program). Subtitle F: Loan Guarantees for Affordable Housing Activities - Authorizes: (1) guarantees for tribal obligations issued to finance affordable housing activities; and (2) grants for interest costs. Authorizes appropriations. Subtitle G: Other Housing Assistance for Native Americans - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to authorize guarantees of housing loans to Indian tribes. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act to authorize the Federal National Mortgage Association (FNMA) to guarantee the loans. (Sec. 782) Allows Indian owners to lease for a 50-year term any restricted Indian lands. (Sec. 783) Authorizes appropriations for training and technical assistance to Indian housing authorities and tribally designated housing entities. Title VIII: National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Consensus Committee - National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1996 - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to mandate a consensus committee for maintenance and revision of Federal manufactured home construction and safety standards. Repeals provisions establishing the National Manufactured Home Advisory Council.</summary>
</bill>
