<bill session="106" type="hr" number="24" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives congratulating President Pastrana and the people of Colombia for moving the peace process forward and calling on the government and all other parties to the current conflict in Colombia to end the guerrilla and paramilitary violence which continues to pose a serious threat to democracy as well as economic and social stability in Colombia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Guerrilla warfare"/>
    <term name="Hostages"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Missionaries"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/1999--Introduced.
Congratulates: (1) the people of Colombia for their continued demonstration of support for the democratic process as well as for an end to the internal conflict; and (2) President Andres Pastrana for his strong commitment to seek an end to the guerilla and paramilitary violence in Colombia and for his initiatives to begin a peace process. Urges: (1) Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia and National Liberation Army guerrilla leaders, and the leaders of the paramilitary groups, to end the violence, sever their relationships with the narcotics trade, and negotiate a peace accord with the Colombian Government which would provide lasting peace, reaffirm democratic principles, and end the cultivation, production, and trade of narcotics; and (2) the international community to play a more proactive role in trying to resolve the internal conflict by encouraging all sides to participate in the peace process. Reaffirms U.S. support for the peace process. Commits the United States to assist the Colombian Government in finding a peaceful resolution and to continue U.S. assistance to help strengthen political stability, foster economic growth, and combat the drug trade within Colombia.</summary>
</bill>
