<bill session="107" type="h" number="5722" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate certain lands in Colorado as wilderness.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400265"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-11-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Flight training"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/13/2002--Introduced.
Amends the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993, Public Law 96-560 (designating certain National Forest System lands in the State of Colorado for inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System), and the American Wilderness Act of 1978 to designate specified lands in Acorn Creek, Gunnison, and Pitkin Counties, Colorado, as wilderness areas.Designates certain land in Eagle County, Colorado, as wilderness, the Red Table Mountain Wilderness Area (the "Area"). Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to allow for the maintenance of rights-of-way and access roads located within the Area in order to operate a transmission line or electrical power line.Withdraws all Federal lands within the Area from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) the operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.Permits continued aerial navigation training exercises by the Colorado Army National Guard in the Area.Declares that Congress does not intend for the establishment of protective perimeters or buffer zones around the Area.States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to: (1) constitute a reservation of any water or water rights in lands designated as wilderness; (2) affect any conditional or absolute water rights in Colorado; (3) establish a precedent with regard to future wilderness designations; or (4) affect compacts and decrees apportioning water among and between Colorado and other States.Prohibits the Secretary from making instream flow permit conditions within or upstream of the Area on existing facilities on National Forest System lands.</summary>
</bill>
