<bill session="107" type="hr" number="488" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-18T17:50:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-07-18T17:50:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5120) making appropriations for the Treasury Department, the United States Postal Service, the Executive Office of the President, and certain Independent Agencies, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-07-17T22:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 107-585, by Mr. Linder.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-17T22:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The rule waives points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI (prohibiting unauthorized appropriations or legislative provisions in an appropriations bill. Provides that the amendment printed in (H. Rept. 107-585) may be offered only at the appropriate point in the reading of the bill, shall be considered as read, and shall not be subject to amendment. Provides for priority in recognition to Representative Goss of Florida or his designee to offer the amendment printed in the report. Waives all points of order against the amendment printed in the report. Authorizes the Chair to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-07-17T22:57:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="195">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 195.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4909-4916" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18T16:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 488.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 258 - 156 (Roll no. 322).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2002-07-18T17:50:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="323" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 224 - 188 (Roll no. 323).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4909-4910" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="107" type="h" number="5120"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2002--Reported to House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 5120 (FY 2003 Treasury Department, United States Postal Service, Executive Office of the President, and certain Independent Agencies appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
