<bill session="106" type="h" number="4106" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Savings for Working Families Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of Individual Development Accounts (IDAs) that will allow individuals and families with limited means an opportunity to accumulate assets, to access education, to own their own homes and businesses, and ultimately to achieve economic self-sufficiency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400320"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2000-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2000-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2000-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="2000-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2000-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400590" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2000-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400508" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2000-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2000-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2000-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400540" joined="2000-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2023"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development banking"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Personal budgets"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Working poor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/28/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Qualified Individual Development Accounts for Low-Income Workers Title II: Qualified Individual Development Account Program Investment Credits Savings for Working Families Act of 2000 - Title I: Individual Development Accounts For Low-Income Workers - Sets forth requirements for qualified individual development accounts (IDAs) for low-income workers, including: (1) the basic structure and administration of qualified IDA programs established by qualified financial institutions (QFIs) or qualified nonprofit organizations (QNOs); (2) procedures for opening an IDA with a QFI or a QNO and contributing money (of up to a certain amount, except in the case of qualified rollovers) in accordance with specified guidelines to qualify for matching funds from QFIs, QNOs, State, local, or private sources to be held in a parallel account; (3) QFI or QNO deposits of all matching funds (matched dollar-for-dollar for the first 500 contributed by an eligible individual to an IDA for any taxable year) for each IDA in a parallel, interest-bearing account at a QFI or QNO; (4) procedures for withdrawals from an IDA for qualified higher education expenses, first-time homebuyer costs, business capitalization costs, or rollovers to other IDAs of the individual or the individual's spouse or dependents; (5) certification to the Secretary of the Treasury or designated organization that qualified IDAs and other described accounts are operating pursuant to this Act, and termination of qualified IDA programs if the Secretary, or designated organization, determines that a QFI, or QNO, is not operating a qualified IDA program in accordance with this Act; and (6) reporting, monitoring, and evaluation requirements. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 105) Allows for withdrawal from an IDA for non-qualified expenses, but with forfeiture of all corresponding matching funds and interest earned on them, unless the withdrawn funds are recontributed within one year.(Sec. 108) Disregards funds in parallel accounts of program participants for purposes of certain means-tested Federal programs.Title II: Qualified Individual Development Account Program Investment Credits - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for a qualified IDA program investment by an eligible taxpayer (a QFI or a non-QFI meeting specified criteria) during the taxable year.(Sec. 202) Declares that QFIs which establish qualified IDA programs shall not receive credit for funding, administration, and education expenses under any test contained in regulations for the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 for those activities and expenses related to such programs and accounted for in the tax credit above.(Sec. 203) Authorizes an individual to designate that a specified portion of any overpayment of tax for a taxable year attributable to the earned income credit shall be deposited by the Secretary into the individual's IDA.</summary>
</bill>
