<bill session="106" type="h" number="2540" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">1999 Omnibus Adoption Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish grant programs and provide other forms of Federal assistance to pregnant women, children in need of adoptive families, and individuals and families adopting children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1999-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1565"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Commerce, the Judiciary, Banking and Financial Services, Armed Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Adopted children"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Adoptive parents"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Birth control"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Childbirth"/>
    <term name="Church and state"/>
    <term name="Churches"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Congregate housing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Family leave"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Group homes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Poor women"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Prenatal care"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sick leave"/>
    <term name="Single women"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women prisoners"/>
    <term name="Women soldiers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Expansion of Adoption Tax Credit Title II: Leave Equity for Adoptive Families Title III: Adoption Counseling Title IV: Adoption Information for Members of the Armed Forces Title V: Federal Prisons Title VI: Accreditation of Adoption Service Providers Title VII: Adoption and Foster Care Data Collection Title VIII: Refundable Credit for Medical Expenses of Pregnancies with Children Placed for Adoption Title IX: Maternal Health Certificates Program Title X: Rehabilitation Grants for Maternity Housing and Services Facilities Title XI: Repeal of National Clearinghouse on Adoption Information Title XII: National Commission on Adoption 1999 Omnibus Adoption Act - Title I: Expansion of Adoption Tax Credit - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase the dollar amount of qualified expenses for the adoption tax credit; (2) double the limit on the amount of a taxpayer's adjusted gross income that is used in computing the income limitation applicable to adoption tax credits; (3) make permanent the adoption tax credit for adoptions of children without special needs; and (4) provide for adjustment of such dollar and income limitations for inflation.Title II: Leave Equity for Adoptive Families - Establishes leave requirements for an employee needing leave because of the placement of a son or daughter with the employee for adoption or foster care, and provides for civil actions against an employer to enforce such requirements, subject to specified limitations.Title III: Adoption Counseling - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish a national adoption counseling program for pregnant women and infertile married couples. Allows for the participation of religious organizations. Directs the Secretary to require that each program providing voluntary family planing services with a grant from the Secretary provide nondirective counseling and referrals regarding prenatal care and delivery, infant and foster care, and adoption.Title IV: Adoption Information for Members of the Armed Forces - Requires the Secretary of each military department and the Secretary of Transportation with respect to the Coast Guard when outside naval jurisdiction to ensure that members of the armed forces under their jurisdiction have information concerning adoption readily available to them.Title V: Federal Prisons - Amends the Federal criminal code to direct the Attorney General to take appropriate action to assure that information regarding the option of planning adoption for the child is made available to each female prisoner who is or may be pregnant.Title VI: Accreditation of Adoption Service Providers - Amends SSA title IV part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) to: (1) require State plans to provide for State laws to prohibit adoption services by unaccredited persons, and require State accreditation of adoption service providers; and (2) require the State to establish standards for such accreditation.Title VII: Adoption and Foster Care Data Collection - Amends SSA title IV part E to provide for State adoption and foster care data collection and reporting systems for HHS.Title VIII: Refundable Credit for Medical Expenses of Pregnancies with Children Placed for Adoption - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for a refundable tax credit of up to $5,000 per child for medical expenses of pregnancies with children placed for adoption.Title IX: Maternal Health Certificates Program - Directs the Secretary to establish a maternal health certificates program to cover maternity and housing services facility expenses incurred by eligible pregnant women. Authorizes appropriations.Title X: Rehabilitation Grants for Maternity Housing and Services Facilities - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to implement a grant program to assist eligible nonprofit entities to rehabilitate buildings for use as housing and services facilities for eligible pregnant women. Allows for the participation of religious organizations. Authorizes appropriations.Title XI: Repeal of National Clearinghouse on Adoption Information - Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1986 to repeal the National Clearinghouse on Adoption Information.Title XII: National Commission on Adoption - Establishes the National Commission on Adoption to review all adoption programs and related activities. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
