<bill session="108" type="h" number="960" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Seniors Health and Independence Preservation Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to consolidate and restate the Federal laws relating to the social health maintenance organization projects, to make such projects permanent, to require the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission to conduct a study on ways to expand such projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="306"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Age"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuum of care"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Demography"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Patient satisfaction"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2003--Introduced.
Seniors Health and Independence Preservation Act of 2003 - Amends part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) consolidate and restate the Federal laws relating to the social health maintenance organization (SHMO) demonstration projects; and (2) make the projects permanent.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to promulgate a regulation that permits each SHMO demonstration project to expand its service area to include areas within the State served by the organization that are not contiguous to any other service area of the organization.Permits the participation in the SHMO demonstration project program of: (1) the five organizations authorized under the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 to demonstrate the concept of SHMOs that were approved by the Secretary in 1995; and (2) each entity that received a planning grant in 1998 under the 1997 Grants Program for Reforming Service Delivery for Dual Eligible Beneficiaries to develop a Second Generation Social HMO Demonstration Program.Requires the Secretary to notify the appropriate congressional committees prior to making any change to the benefits available under a SHMO demonstration project.Directs the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission to study and report to Congress on the cost-effectiveness of SHMO demonstration projects and their potential expansion.Requires the Secretary to conduct, and report to Congress on, a comparative qualitative survey of the satisfaction of Medicare beneficiaries enrolled in: (1) the original Medicare fee-for-service program under Medicare parts A (Hospital Insurance) and B (Supplementary Medical Insurance); (2) a Medicare+Choice plan under Medicare part C (Medicare+Choice); and (3) an SHMO.</summary>
</bill>
