<bill session="106" type="h" number="3264" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Investment Incentive Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Investment Company Act of 1940 to promote the establishment of small business investment companies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400592"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1999-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/1999--Introduced.
Small Business Investment Incentive Act of 1999 - Amends the Investment Company Act of 1940 to exempt from securities registration requirements any company that is not in the business of issuing redeemable securities, the operations of which are subject to regulation by the Small Business Administration (SBA) as a small business investment company (SBIC) if: (1) the company's activities are limited to providing financial and business advice to small business concerns as an SBIC licensed by the SBA; (2) the company's securities are sold only to accredited investors, the SBA, or such other persons that the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) may permit; and (3) the company does not purchase any security issued by an investment company or by any company that would be an investment company except for specified exclusions, with certain exceptions. Requires companies proposing to be so exempted to notify the SEC of such intent.</summary>
</bill>
