<bill session="104" type="h" number="1922" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the exchange of certain lands in Gilpin County, Colorado.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409954"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400265" joined="1995-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1319-1320"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29">
      <text>See H.R.2437.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="h" number="2437"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2437"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2437"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="985"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/1995--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to Lake Gulch, Inc., a Colorado corporation, specified lands in Gilpin County, Colorado, in exchange for: (1) certain lands comprising approximately 40 acres located in Larimer County, Colorado, within the boundaries of Rocky Mountain National Park; (2) certain lands located within and adjacent to the United States Bureau of Land Management San Luis Resource Area in Conejos County, Colorado; and (3) certain lands located within the United States Bureau of Land Management Royal Gorge Resource Area in Huerfano County, Colorado. Allows the Secretary of the Interior and Lake Gulch to agree to substitute alternative lands if one or more of the precise offered land parcels is unable to be conveyed. Directs the Secretary to notify and consult with the County and City and afford such units of local government the opportunity to acquire or reserve easements or rights-of-way parallel to North Clear Creek in Gilpin, Colorado, prior to transferring any lands which are contiguous to North Clear Creek out of public ownership. Expresses that the exchange will be contingent upon Lake Gulch executing an agreement with the United States: (1) containing terms which are acceptable to the Secretary of the Interior; (2) granting the United States a covenant that none of the selected lands (which currently lie outside the legally approved gaming area) will ever be used for gaming; and (3) permanently holding the United States harmless for liability and indemnifying the United States against all costs arising from activities, operations, or other acts conducted by Lake Gulch or its employees, agents, successors or assigns on the selected lands after their transfer to Lake Gulch.</summary>
</bill>
