<bill session="106" type="h" number="2693" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Child Care and Development Grant Act of 1990 to provide for improved care for young children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Child care block grants"/>
    <term name="Child care workers"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Head Start programs"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/1999--Introduced.
Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to establish a program of assistance for child care activities for young children (under age three).Authorizes appropriations.Authorizes the use of such program funds for child care activities for young children, including activities designed to: (1) increase availability of child care services for young children; (2) provide support services for networks of family child care providers; (3) provide or support programs that provide training, services, materials, equipment, or other support to caregivers, eligible child care providers, and family child care providers that provide child care to young children (including purchasing equipment such as cribs and high chairs); (4) provide funds to increase compensation offered and provide bonuses to caregivers, eligible child care providers, and family child care providers who provide child care to children under age three, especially those caregivers and providers who have formal education in early childhood development; (5) provide and support networks between health care providers and caregivers, eligible child care providers, and family child care providers that provide child care to young children; and (6) provide child care services for young children who are enrolled in Head Start programs.</summary>
</bill>
