<bill session="104" type="h" number="2564" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-29T11:34:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-11-29T11:34:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the disclosure of lobbying activities to influence the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400549" joined="1995-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1995-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="1995-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1995-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404142" joined="1995-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="1995-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="405317" joined="1995-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1995-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1995-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1995-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1995-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1995-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="1995-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Government Reform and Oversight, Rules, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-02">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-11-08">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 30 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-11-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12193-12194"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T21:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 104-339, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T21:17:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Government Reform Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 14, 1995.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T21:17:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Rules Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 14, 1995.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T21:17:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Ways and Means Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 14, 1995.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T21:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Government Reform discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T21:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Rules discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T21:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-11-14T21:25:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="181">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 181.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T16:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 269 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2564 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Upon adoption of this resolution, it shall be in order for the Speaker to declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House for consideration of the bill. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 2(l)(6) of rule XI shall be waived. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against any amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution shall be waived. If H.R. 2564 is passed by the House in a form identical to S. 1060, as passed by the Senate, it shall be in order without intervention of any point of order to consider the Senate bill in the House. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the Senate bill to final passage withou...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T19:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 269 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T19:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Canady asked unanimous consent that, during the consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole, the Chairman may postpone until a time during further consideration in the Committee of the Whole a request for a recorded vote on any amendment, and that the Chairman may reduce to not less than five minutes the time for voting on any postponed question that immediately follows another vote without intervening business, provided that the time for voting on the first in any series of questions be not less than 15 minutes; and further, that debate on each amendment to the bill and any amendments thereto be limited to 30 minutes, equally divided and controlled. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T19:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 269.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13099-13138" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T19:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2564 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Upon adoption of this resolution, it shall be in order for the Speaker to declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House for consideration of the bill. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 2(l)(6) of rule XI shall be waived. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against any amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution shall be waived. If H.R. 2564 is passed by the House in a form identical to S. 1060, as passed by the Senate, it shall be in order without intervention of any point of order to consider the Senate bill in the House. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the Senate bill to final passage withou...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T19:51:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 269 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T19:51:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jim Kolbe to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T19:51:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 269, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with two hours of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T21:23:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Fox amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T21:48:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the Fox amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Fox asked for a recorded vote. Pursuant to the earlier unanimous consent agreement, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T21:50:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Clinger amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T22:25:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the Clinger amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was agreed to. Mr. Canady objected to the vote on grounds that a quorum was not present and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the earlier unanimous consent agreement, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T22:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2564 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T22:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T22:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T22:29:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Kaptur amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T22:40:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the English amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T23:02:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the English amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. English objected to the vote on grounds that a quorum was not present and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the earlier unanimous consent agreement, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T23:04:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Weller amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T23:36:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the Weller amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Weller objected to the vote on grounds that a quorum was not present and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the earlier unanimous consent agreement, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T23:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2564 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-28T18:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13682-13690" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-28T18:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Canady asked unanimous consent that in the further consideration of the bill in the Commmittee of the Whole, prior to the votes on the four amendments which were considered on November 16 upon which further proceedings were postponed, that Messrs. Fox, Clinger, English, and Weller each be recongized for 2 1/2 minutes in support of their amendments and that Mr. Canady be recognized for 2 1/2 minutes in opposition to each amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-28T18:14:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-28T18:15:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with five additional minutes of debate on the Fox amendment, on which further proceedings were previously postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-28T18:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with five additional minutes of debate on the Clinger amendment, on which further proceedings were previously postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-28T18:34:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with five additional minutes of debate on the English amendment, on which further proceedings were previously postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-28T18:43:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with five additional minutes of debate on the Weller amendment, on which further proceedings were previously postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-28T19:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Canady moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-28T19:42:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-28T19:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2564 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29T10:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13738-13745" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29T10:31:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29T10:37:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of November 16, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Traficant amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29T11:11:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2564.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29T11:12:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-11-29T11:34:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="828" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 421 - 0 (Roll no. 828).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29T11:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29T11:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Laid on the table. See S. 1060 for further action.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="269"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="h" number="2268"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1060"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service system"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional leadership"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International propaganda"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Local officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h902"/>
    <amendment number="h903"/>
    <amendment number="h904"/>
    <amendment number="h905"/>
    <amendment number="h906"/>
    <amendment number="h909"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/31/1995--Introduced.
Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 - Requires registration with the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives (appropriate congressional officials) by any individual lobbyist (or the individual's employer if it employs one or more lobbyists) within 45 days after the individual first makes, or is employed or retained to make, a lobbying contact with either the President, the Vice President, a Member of Congress, or any other specified Federal officer or employee, including certain high-ranking members of the uniformed services. Defines a lobbyist as any individual employed or retained by a client for financial or other compensation for services that include more than one lobbying contact (but not an individual whose lobbying activities constitute less than 20 percent of the time engaged in the services provided to that client over a six-month period). (Sec. 4) Provides for: (1) special registration filing rules in cases involving multiple clients and contacts; and (2) registration termination in cases where a registrant is no longer employed or retained by a client to conduct lobbying activities and does not anticipate any additional lobbying activities for such client. Specifies the contents of such registration. Provides for exemptions from registration requirements above in cases involving lobbying income of $5,000 or less (for a particular client) or total expenses of $20,000 or less (in the case of an organization whose employees engage in lobbying activities on the organization's behalf) (adjusted periodically for inflation) for the semiannual period. (Sec. 5) Requires registrants to file semiannual lobbying activity reports with the appropriate congressional officials. Specifies the contents of such reports. (Sec. 6) Specifies various duties of the appropriate congressional officials for carrying out this Act, including reviewing registrations and reports filed under it, and making copies of them available to the public. (Sec. 7) Sets forth penalties for violations involving the requirements of this Act. (Sec. 9) Amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to: (1) replace references to political propaganda with references to informational materials; and (2) add to the exemption from registration requirements under such Act for certain lawyers providing legal representation to disclosed foreign principals to apply it to such representative actions as judicial proceedings and criminal or civil law enforcement inquiries, investigations, or proceedings. Exempts from the requirements of the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 any agent of a foreign government, foreign political party, or other foreign entity not organized for business that registers under this Act. (Sec. 10) Revises (Byrd Amendment) limitations on use of appropriated funds to influence certain Federal contracting and financial transactions, removing obsolete reporting requirements, among other changes. (Sec. 11) Repeals the Federal Regulation of Lobbying Act. Repeals provisions of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act and the Housing Act of 1949 relating to lobbyist activities. (Sec. 14) Sets forth special rules for the identification of: (1) foreign and other clients on whose behalf lobbying contacts are made with a covered legislative or executive branch official; and (2) such covered officials. (Sec. 15) Permits tax-exempt charitable organizations required to report lobbying expenses by the Internal Revenue Code to report, under this Act, only good faith estimates of such expenses in order to meet specified reporting (including exemption from such reporting) requirements of this Act. (Sec. 16) Amends provisions of Federal law known as the Ramspeck Act to repeal authority extending competitive status to certain legislative and judicial branch employees involuntarily separated without prejudice from their respective branch, entitling them to transfer to the competitive service in the executive branch. (Sec. 17) Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to promulgate regulations on the manner and extent that experience in a position other than a competitive one may be considered in making appointments to a competitive position. Prohibits the grant, in such regulations, of any preference based on the fact of service in the legislative or judicial branch. Directs OPM to study excepted service considerations for competitive service appointments relating to this Act. (Sec. 18) Makes certain civic leagues or organizations not organized for profit but operated exclusively for the promotion of social welfare, and certain local associations of employees whose net earnings are devoted exclusively to charitable, educational, or recreational purposes, ineligible for Federal funds in any form if they engage in lobbying activities. (Sec. 19) Amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to require the Attorney General to report to Congress semiannually on administrative matters (currently "from time to time") including registration filings. (Sec. 20) Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to: (1) augment the dollar value categories for required disclosure of income, assets, and liabilities of subject individuals, but limiting disclosure requirements for their spouses and dependent children to income, assets, and liabilities held jointly with the subject individual, and leaving unspecified any such amounts or values exceeding $1 million; and (2) require the financial disclosure reports of subject individuals to include the category of the total cash value of any interest of the reporting individual in a qualified blind trust, except under certain circumstances. (Sec. 21) Amends the Federal criminal code to apply to the Deputy United States Trade Representative (Deputy USTR) the same three-year prohibition against representing, aiding, or advising a foreign entity after leaving Government service as applies to the United States Trade Representative (USTR). Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to prohibit any person who has directly represented, aided, or advised a foreign entity in any trade negotiation, or trade dispute, with the United States from being appointed as USTR or Deputy USTR. (Sec. 23) Expresses the sense of the Senate that lobbying expenses should not be tax deductible.</summary>
</bill>
