<bill session="106" type="h" number="2891" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Competitive Access to Federal Buildings Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide reasonable and non-discriminatory access to buildings owned or used by the Federal Government for the provision of competitive telecommunications services by telecommunications carriers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1999-09-21" withdrawn="1999-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, Hazardous Materials and Pipeline Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW08" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, Hazardous Materials and Pipeline Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1301"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1301"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Antennas"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/1999--Introduced.
Competitive Access to Federal Buildings Act - Amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to authorize the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to: (1) implement policies for federally-owned buildings and structures for providing non-discriminatory access to such buildings and structures for the provision of telecommunications or information services by telecommunications carriers; and (2) advise the Federal Communications Commission on the development of such policies for commercial property. Prohibits a Federal agency from entering into a contract to rent or lease commercial property unless the property owner or operator permits such non-discriminatory access for a carrier that has obtained, where required, a Federal or State certificate of public convenience and necessity for the provision of such services and that seeks to provide such services to tenants. Allows such owner or operator to: (1) charge a reasonable fee for such access; and (2) impose other reasonable, non-discriminatory requirements in connection with such access. Prohibits a Federal agency from entering into a contract with an owner or operator unless such owner or operator agrees to resolve disputes regarding such access. Authorizes the waiver of this Act's prohibitions on a case-by-case basis: (1) by a Federal agency head when such agency would be unable to obtain any suitable space in that area; and (2) by the President for national security reasons. Directs the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Telecommunications and Information, to promulgate final rules to apply the requirements of this Act to all Federal buildings and structures.</summary>
</bill>
