<bill session="106" type="h" number="5244" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tribal-State Tax Fairness Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the payment of State taxes on the sale of cigarettes and motor fuel by tribal retail enterprises to persons that are not members of the tribe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400317"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2000-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2000-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="2000-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2000-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2000-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental tax relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tobacco tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2000--Introduced.
Tribal-State Tax Fairness Act of 2000 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, within 60 days after receiving a petition from the government of a State within which a tribal retail enterprise is located alleging the non-collection of a covered State tax (a tax imposed on the purchase of tobacco products or motor fuel) by such enterprise: (1) to determine whether the enterprise is properly collecting and remitting such State tax; and (2) if it is not, to notify and direct the enterprise to collect such tax and remit it to the Secretary on a monthly basis. Provides for the determination of the amount to be so remitted (which differs depending on the existence or non- existence of a tribal-State agreement). Requires mediation if such amount cannot be determined. Requires the Secretary to return remitted amounts to the State within 30 days.Provides for the mediation of disputes between tribes and States under tribal-State agreements, with enforcement provisions. Allows any person with information that a tribe is not remitting appropriate covered State taxes to submit such information to the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to commence an administrative action for appropriate State relief. Provides for judicial review of determinations made by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
