<bill session="104" type="h" number="1277" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Private Property Impact Assessment Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve procedures for determining when a taking of private property has occurred, and to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to report to Congress with respect to takings under progress at the Department of Agriculture.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400505"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-24">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.925.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG26" subcommittee="Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="925"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural production"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/1995--Introduced.
Private Property Impact Assessment Act of 1995 - Provides that no agency action that will have binding force on an owner of property with respect to the use of that property shall take effect until the President certifies that the agency is in compliance with the guidelines required by this Act. Requires the President by rule to issue guidelines: (1) for assessing whether a proposed agency action will have the potential for taking private property or imposing a negative impact on private property; and (2) minimizing that taking or impact wherever possible. Requires each agency to issue rules implementing such guidelines. Directs the President, after affording the public notice and an opportunity to comment, to report to the Congress on each agency's compliance with this Act along with any recommendations for additional legislative or administrative action to minimize the taking of private property by the Federal Government. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to study and report to the Congress on the effect of this Act on the farm economy and agricultural production of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
