<bill session="106" type="h" number="5623" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-11-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-11-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chemical Security and Right to Know Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Clean Air Act to ensure that adequate actions are taken to detect, prevent, and minimize the consequences of accidental releases that result from criminal activity that may cause substantial harm to public health, safety, and the environment and to ensure that the public has access to information regarding hazardous chemicals in the community and the potential for accidental releases of those chemicals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control equipment"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Flammable materials"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/2/2000--Introduced.
Chemical Security and Right to Know Act of 2000 - Amends provisions of the Clean Air Act regarding accidental releases of hazardous substances anticipated to cause death, injury, or serious health or environmental effects to require the Attorney General to: (1) determine whether owners or operators of stationary sources have taken adequate actions to detect, prevent, and minimize the consequences of criminal releases that may cause harm to public health and safety and the environment; and (2) promulgate requirements to ensure that such actions are taken, if they have not been taken.Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to make risk management plans submitted by certain stationary source owners or operators publicly available.</summary>
</bill>
