<bill session="108" type="h" number="5030" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Invest in American Workers Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Trade Act of 1974 to provide trade adjustment assistance to the services sector and for communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400274"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Diversification in industry"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="High technology"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2004--Introduced.
Invest in American Workers Act of 2004 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to extend trade adjustment assistance (TAA) to workers in a service sector firm or its subdivision. Defines service sector firm as an entity engaged in the business of providing information technology or other high technology services. Revises group eligibility requirements for TAA to include: (1) a shift, by such worker's firm or its subdivision to a foreign country, in provision of services, like or directly competitive with services provided by the service sector's firm or its subdivision; and (2) the situation where a worker's firm or its subdivision obtains or is likely to obtain such services from a foreign country. Requires the Secretary of Labor to certify as eligible to apply for TAA any adversely affected secondary workers in a service sector firm or its subdivision. Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance for the establishment of industrywide programs for new service development. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to establish a Trade Adjustment Assistance for Communities Program at the Department of Commerce. Authorizes: (1) an eligible community to develop a strategic plan for community economic adjustment and diversification; (2) the Secretary of Commerce, upon receipt of an application from the community, to award a grant for such development and, upon approval of the plan, a grant to carry out any certified project or program to be included in the plan; and (3) additional grants, under specified conditions, to provide the non-Federal share of a project. Waives the time limitation on the use of eligibility and entitlement to educational assistance under the Montgomery GI Bill for certain veterans who file claims for unemployment compensation. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the tax credit for health insurance costs of eligible individuals. Repeals the limitation on penalty-free distributions from individual retirement plans to unemployed individuals for health insurance premiums.</summary>
</bill>
