<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="392" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:56-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="3326" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2009-07-30T13:24:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400286"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  <description>Manager's amendment provides that funds be made available for the Joint POW/MIA Accounting from within the funds available; increases the amount available for transfer to the Fisher House and Suites; redirects funds otherwise available for advance procurement of additional F-22 aircraft, and provides for spare and repair parts including engines for the F-22 and C-17, aircraft defensive systems, and aircraft weapon systems; includes a technical revision in the Defense Health Program and shifts $26,000,000 from operation and maintenance funding to research, development, test and evaluation; prohibits further outsourcing of utility functions at the U.S. Military Academy at West Point; makes additional funds available for Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction, Defense; prohibits conversion of government-owned ammunition plants; and allows for funds to be transferred to the Coast Guard for operating expenses.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in Part A of House Report 111-233 to (1) provide that funds be made available for the Joint POW/MIA Accounting from within the funds available; (2) increase the amount available for transfer to the Fisher House and Suites; (3) redirect funds otherwise available for advance procurement of additional F-22 aircraft, and provide for spare and repair parts including engines for the F-22 and C-17, aircraft defensive systems, and aircraft weapon systems; (4) include a technical revision in the Defense Health Program and shift $26,000,000 from operation and maintenance funding to research, development, test and evaluation; (5) prohibit further outsourcing of utility functions at the U.S. Military Academy at West Point; (6) make additional funds available for Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction, Defense; (7) prohibit conversion of government-owned ammunition plants; and (8) allow for funds to be transferred to the Coast Guard for operating expenses.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30T10:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Murtha.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9080-9082, H9120-9121" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9080" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2009-07-30T13:24:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="661">
      <text>On agreeing to the Murtha amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 269 - 165 (Roll no. 661).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
