<bill session="104" type="h" number="2936" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that if a member nation of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, the Republic of Korea, or Japan does not agree, by the end of fiscal year 1997, to contribute to the United States for each fiscal year an amount equal to the full direct costs to the United States of United States military forces permanently stationed ashore in that country for that fiscal year, all such United States forces assigned in that country shall be withdrawn not later than the end of fiscal year 1999 and to provide that the amount of all such contributions and the amount of savings from such withdrawals shall be deposited in the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402454"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committees on National Security, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E173"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-05">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Collective security agreements"/>
    <term name="Defense burdensharing"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military posture"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/1996--Introduced.
Urges the President to enter into negotiations for the purpose of revising host-nation agreements with North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) countries, the Republic of Korea, and Japan, so that each country agrees to contribute to the United States for each fiscal year an amount equal to the total direct costs (including personnel costs) incurred by the United States owing to the presence of U.S. military personnel permanently stationed in each country. Directs the President to order the withdrawal of all U.S. armed forces in each country that does not enter into a revised host-nation agreement by September 30, 1997. Requires amounts received by the United States by reason of such agreement to be deposited in the Hospital Insurance Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
