<bill session="104" type="h" number="257" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish certain requirements relating to the transfer or disposal of public lands managed by the Bureau of Land management, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-17">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Prohibits amounts appropriated or otherwise made available after enactment of this Act from being obligated or expended by the Secretary of the Interior for the acquisition of any lands or interests therein which are to be administered by the Bureau of Land Management. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire lands or interests therein for administration by the Bureau only by exchange, donation, or from amounts made available from the Bureau of Land Management Land Sale and Acquisition Fund (established by this Act) pursuant to this Act. Establishes the Fund. Directs that there be deposited into the Fund all amounts received by: (1) the Secretary from the disposal of any lands or interests therein administered by the Bureau; and (2) the United States by gift for acquisition of lands to be administered by the Bureau. Allows amounts to be made available from the Fund for the acquisition of lands or interests therein to be administered by the Bureau. Requires annual budget requests submitted by the Secretary to include information as to whether the Bureau, through preparation of land-use plans pursuant to the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, has identified public lands which are suitable for transfer to other management or for disposal which transfer or disposal has been delayed because of incomplete surveys or other reasons. Authorizes the Secretary to include a proposal for additional legislation in such request to facilitate such transfer or disposal.</summary>
</bill>
