<bill session="106" type="h" number="4446" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that the Secretary of Energy may continue to exercise certain authorities under the Price-Anderson Act through the Assistant Secretary of Energy for Environment, Safety, and Health.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2000-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-23T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Commerce. H. Rept. 106-694, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Armed Services for a period ending not later than July 21, 2000 for consideration of such provisions of the bill as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(c), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the Committee on Armed Services for a period ending not later than July 21, 2000..</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-21T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Armed Services. H. Rept. 106-694, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-21T17:40:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="445">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 445.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2000--Reported to House amended, Part II.
Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (the Price-Anderson Act) to authorize the Secretary of Energy to exercise through the Assistant Secretary of Energy for Environment, Safety, and Health specified authorities regarding civil monetary penalties for violation of Department of Energy safety regulations, except with respect to the National Nuclear Security Administration.Authorizes the Secretary to exercise such authorities with respect to the National Nuclear Security Administration only through the Administrator for Nuclear Security (consistent with the Secretary's delegation authority under the Department of Energy Organization Act).</summary>
</bill>
