<bill session="104" type="h" number="1859" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sexual Harassment Prevention Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require employers to post, and to provide to employees individually, information relating to sexual harassment that violates title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1996-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sexual harassment of women"/>
    <term name="Supervisors"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/1995--Introduced.
Sexual Harassment Prevention Act of 1995 - Directs employers (including Federal and congressional agencies) to keep posted in conspicuous places a notice prepared or approved by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission that sets forth: (1) the definition of sexual harassment found in the Code of Federal Regulations; (2) the fact that sexual harassment is a violation of the Civil Rights Act of 1964; (3) information describing how to file a complaint with the Commission alleging such harassment; (4) an address and toll-free number to be used to contact the Commission; and (5) other information required by the Commission. Provides for annual notices by employers to individual employees which provide such information and a description of the procedures used by the employers to resolve allegations of sexual harassment. Requires employers to provide to each supervisory employee information specifying the responsibility of, and the methods to be used by, such employee to ensure that immediate and corrective action is taken to address allegations of sexual harassment. Prescribes civil penalties for willful violations of this Act. Requires the Commission to provide a toll-free telephone number for the use of employers and employees in order to obtain information concerning this Act.</summary>
</bill>
