<bill session="104" type="hr" number="139" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-09T15:02:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-05-09T15:02:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 1361) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 1996 for the Coast Guard, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400107"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-05-03T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-111, by Mr. Diaz-Balart.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-03T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1361 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill. The first two sections of each title of the substitute shall be considered as read. Points of order against the substitute for failure to comply with clause 5(a) of rule XXI or section 302(f) or section 401(b) of the Budget Act shall be waived.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-05-03T11:52:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="43">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 43.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-05-09T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4559-4562" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-09T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-09T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-05-09T15:02:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-05-09T15:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="1361"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/3/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the open rule for the consideration of H.R. 1361 (authorizing appropriations for the Coast Guard for FY 1996).</summary>
</bill>
