<bill session="104" type="h" number="3819" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Act establishing the National Park Foundation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400590" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="410887" joined="1996-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1298"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Emblems"/>
    <term name="Federal incorporation"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/1996--Introduced.
Revises the purpose of the National Park Foundation to: (1) include developing and implementing means of securing funds from the private sector to enhance funding for the National Park System (NPS) without supplanting otherwise available appropriated funds; and (2) exclude accepting and administering private gifts on behalf of the National Park Service. Grants the Foundation exclusive authority to license or authorize persons to use such trademarks, symbols, likenesses, or slogans that are adopted and owned by the Foundation and for which it has filed an application with the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office for the purpose of representing, promoting, or advertising for commercial purposes or pecuniary gain that an individual, company, or particular good service is an official sponsor or official supporter of the NPS or the Service. Specifies conditions under which such license or authorization may be granted, such as subjecting the criteria and guidelines for the competitive issuance and the maintenance of a license or authorization to the prior written approval of the Secretary of the Interior. Authorizes the Foundation to license property. Prohibits the Foundation, except as provided in this Act, from: (1) engaging in any business for pecuniary profit or gain; (2) operating any commercial establishment or enterprise within NPS units; or (3) engaging in any lobbying activities concerning NPS management. Requires: (1) all of the Foundation's income, net of reasonable operating expenses, contributions to local government, and reserves determined necessary or appropriate by its Board to be provided for the Service's benefit; and (2) all net income derived from the licenses and authorizations under this Act to be expended in accordance with Service's policies and priorities on programs, projects, or activities that benefit the NPS or the Service as identified by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Foundation. Sets forth congressional reporting requirements. Subjects persons to a civil suit and remedies for unlawful use of the Foundation's name, trademark, symbol, slogan, or any facsimile or simulation thereof to suggest falsely that an individual, company, or particular good or service is an official sponsor or official supporter of the NPS or the Service for commercial purposes. Includes the Foundation as a private corporation established under Federal law for purposes of provisions concerning audits of federally chartered corporations.</summary>
</bill>
