<bill congress="107" type="hr" number="327" updated="2012-10-31T13:26:58-05:00">
  <status datetime="2002-06-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Paperwork Relief Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Small Business Paperwork Relief Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Small Business Paperwork Relief Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Small Business Paperwork Relief Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, for the purpose of facilitating compliance by small businesses with certain Federal paperwork requirements and to establish a task force to examine the feasibility of streamlining paperwork requirements applicable to small businesses.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, for the purpose of facilitating compliance by small business concerns with certain Federal paperwork requirements, to establish a task force to examine information collection and dissemination, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor state="IN" title="Rep" thomas_id="154" district="6" name="Burton, Dan"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor name="Capito, Shelley Moore" district="2" title="Rep" state="WV" sponsored_at="2001-03-15" thomas_id="1676"/>
    <cosponsor name="Ferguson, Mike" district="7" title="Rep" state="NJ" sponsored_at="2001-03-15" thomas_id="1659"/>
    <cosponsor name="Graves, Sam" district="6" title="Rep" state="MO" sponsored_at="2001-03-15" thomas_id="1656"/>
    <cosponsor name="Grucci, Felix J., Jr." district="1" title="Rep" state="NY" sponsored_at="2001-03-15" thomas_id="1662"/>
    <cosponsor name="Manzullo, Donald A." district="16" title="Rep" state="IL" sponsored_at="2001-03-15" thomas_id="733"/>
    <cosponsor name="Ose, Doug" district="3" title="Rep" state="CA" sponsored_at="2001-03-15" thomas_id="1585"/>
    <cosponsor name="Otter, C. L. (Butch)" district="1" title="Rep" state="ID" sponsored_at="2001-03-15" thomas_id="1646"/>
    <cosponsor name="Pence, Mike" district="2" title="Rep" state="IN" sponsored_at="2001-03-15" thomas_id="1649"/>
    <cosponsor name="Putnam, Adam H." district="12" title="Rep" state="FL" sponsored_at="2001-03-15" thomas_id="1645"/>
    <cosponsor name="Schrock, Edward L." district="2" title="Rep" state="VA" sponsored_at="2001-03-15" thomas_id="1673"/>
    <cosponsor name="Toomey, Patrick J." district="15" title="Rep" state="PA" sponsored_at="2001-03-15" thomas_id="1594"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <referral datetime="2001-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned"/>
    </referral>
    <referral datetime="2001-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </referral>
    <referral datetime="2001-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy Policy, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
    </referral>
    <referral datetime="2001-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </referral>
    <action datetime="2001-03-14T14:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 89 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 327 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Bill is open to amendments. Shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the Congressional Record and numbered 1. Each section of that amendment shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15T10:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 89 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15T10:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 89.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H932-942" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15T10:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 327 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Bill is open to amendments. Shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the Congressional Record and numbered 1. Each section of that amendment shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15T10:12:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 89 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15T10:12:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Vito Fossella to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15T10:12:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 327.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15T11:10:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 327.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15T11:10:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15T11:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2001-03-15T11:34:00-05:00">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 418 - 0 (Roll no. 50).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H941-942" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <referral datetime="2001-03-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/>
    </referral>
    <action datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Senate Committee on Governmental Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4733-4737" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-05-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-17T20:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 444 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of Senate amendments to H.R. 327 with 1 hour of general debate. Provides for a single motion offered by the Chairman of the Committee on Government Reform, or his designee, to concur in the Senate amendments and waives all points of order against consideration of the motion. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to final adoption without intervening motion or demand for division of the question.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18T13:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 444 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18T13:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 444, the House moved to agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18T13:27:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion to agree to the Senate amendments to H.R. 327.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18T14:13:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2002-06-18T14:37:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 418 - 0 (Roll no. 233).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H3623-3632" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H3623-3625" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18T14:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2002-06-18">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2002-06-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2002-06-28">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted datetime="2002-06-28">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 107-198.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Industrial standards"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary date="2002-05-22" status="Passed Senate amended.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;(There are 2 &lt;a href=&quot;/cgi-bin/bdquery/z?d107:HR00327:@@@D&amp;summ1&amp;&quot;&gt;other summaries&lt;/a&gt;)">Small Business Paperwork Relief Act of 2002 - Amends the Paperwork Reduction Act to require the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, annually, to publish in the Federal Register and make available on the Internet a list of the regulatory compliance assistance resources available to small businesses. Requires each Federal agency, with respect to the collection of information and the control of paperwork, to establish one agency point of contact to act as a liaison with small businesses.Requires each agency to make efforts to further reduce the information collection burden for small businesses with fewer than 25 employees.Establishes a task force to: (1) identify ways to integrate the collection of information across Federal agencies and programs; (2) examine the feasibility and benefits of publishing a list of the collections of information applicable to small businesses; (3) recommend a plan for the development of an interactive Government-wide system regarding the collection of information as it applies to small business; and (4) report on its findings and recommendations to the Director, specified congressional committees, and the Small Business and Agriculture Regulatory Enforcement Ombudsman.Requires each agency with Federal regulatory authority to submit an initial and final report to the Ombudsman and specified congressional committees on: (1) the number of enforcement actions in which a civil penalty is assessed; (2) the number of such actions against a small entity; (3) the number of actions in which the penalty is reduced or waived; and (4) the total monetary amount of the reductions or waivers.</summary>
</bill>
