<bill session="104" type="h" number="834" updated="2012-11-01T22:43:56-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To nullify the 25 percent pay increase that was afforded to Members of Congress and certain other Government officials by the Ethics Reform Act of 1989; to repeal section 225 of the Federal Salary Act of 1967, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405939"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on House Oversight, the Judiciary, Ways and Means, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Legislative and Budget Process.</text>
      <committee name="House Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Civil Service"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSRU" name="House Rules"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU02" name="House Rules" subcommittee="Legislative Process"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>02/06/1995--Introduced.
Applies this Act to the Vice President, Members of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and certain offices and positions of the legislative as well as executive (Executive Schedule) branch. Declares that, on and after the first day of the first Congress beginning after the next election of Representatives, the rate of basic pay for each such office or position shall be equal to the rate which would then be payable if neither of specified sections of the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 and the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1992 had been enacted. Repeals certain related provisions of such Acts. Requires adjustment, on the day after such day, in the rate of pay for: (1) judicial branch offices and positions in general, according to applicable Federal law; and (2) district court judges in particular, so that theirs shall be equal to the rate payable to a Senator or Member of the House (or the lesser of these, if such rates are not the same). Amends the Federal Salary Act of 1967 to repeal the mandate and authorization for the Citizens' Commission on Public Service and Compensation, thus abolishing it.</summary>
</bill>
