<bill session="106" type="h" number="5512" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 23 of title 5, United States Code, to clarify the disclosures of information protected from prohibited personnel practices; to require a statement in nondisclosure policies, forms, and agreements that such policies, forms, and agreements conform with certain disclosure protections; to provide certain authority for the Special Counsel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="2000-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Information leaking"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Office of Special Counsel"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/2000--Introduced.
Amends civil service provisions to prohibit: (1) taking or failing to take any personnel action with respect to an employee or applicant because of a disclosure of information that such person believes evidences a violation of law, gross mismanagement, abuse of authority, or a danger to public health or safety (current law), without restriction as to the time, place, form, motive, or context of such disclosure, and including a disclosure made in the ordinary course of an employee's duties; and (2) the implementation or enforcement of nondisclosure policies, forms, and agreements that do not contain the statement that such nondisclosure policies do not supersede, conflict with, or otherwise alter Federal employee obligations, rights, or liabilities.Permits representation by attorneys for the Office of the Special Counsel in civil actions brought in connection with such disclosures of information or provisions relating to political activities. Allows the Special Counsel to obtain judicial review of any final order or decision of the Merit Systems Protection Board with respect to a case concerning such a disclosure or provision.</summary>
</bill>
