<bill session="106" type="h" number="3521" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Accountability for Regulatory Information Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, to provide for a report by the General Accounting Office to Congress on agency regulatory actions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2000-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="2000-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400547" joined="2000-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2000-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO01" subcommittee="National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Federal mandates"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2000--Introduced.
Congressional Accountability for Regulatory Information Act of 2000 - Authorizes a committee of either House of Congress with legislative or oversight jurisdiction relating to a regulatory action published by an agency to request the Comptroller General to review the action. Requires the Comptroller General to report to the requesting committee within 180 days (with an earlier requirement with respect to a proposed rule making or interim final rule making) and to include an independent analysis of the potential benefits and costs of the action, the alternative regulatory approaches, the extent to which the action would affect State and local governments, and the differences in results between such analysis and the agency analyses.Requires the head of an agency to include on the first page of each statement published by the agency that is not a rule a notice that the statement has no general applicability or future effect, as applicable, and is not binding on the public.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
