<bill session="106" type="h" number="3174" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Employment Security Financing Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the Social Security Act, the Wagner-Peyser Act, and the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 to improve the method by which Federal unemployment taxes are collected and to improve the method by which funds are provided from Federal unemployment tax revenue for employment security administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="2000-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2000-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2000-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="2000-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400588" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400242" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400265" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400534" joined="2000-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="2000-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400540" joined="1999-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-10-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2212-2213"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental tax relations"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Amendments to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 Title II: Unemployment Trust Fund Accounts Title III: Grants to States for Employment Security Administration Title IV: Extended Unemployment Compensation Title V: Federal Employment Security Service Title VI: Advances to State Unemployment Compensation Benefit Accounts Employment Security Financing Act of 1999 - Title I: Amendments to the Internal Revenue Code of 1996 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) Chapter 23 to revise Federal Unemployment Tax Act (FUTA) employer excise tax rate requirements.(Sec. 101) Repeals the 0.2 surtax for calendar years after 1999. (Ends the current FUTA employer tax rate of 6.2 percent of total employee wages after 1999, and begins a 6.0 rate in 2000).(Sec. 103) Sets forth additional requirements for approval of State laws.(Sec. 105) Revises the definition of State unemployment funds.(Sec. 106) Defines a State Employment Security Administration Account (State ESAA) as a special account within the Unemployment Trust Fund (the Fund) to provide administrative funds to pay the cost of services performed by the State agency in accordance with FUTA and the Social Security Act.(Sec. 107) Provides for collection of FUTA taxes by, as well as payment of FUTA taxes to, State agencies.(Sec. 109) Amends the IRC to repeal the prohibition against assessment of unpaid FUTA taxes.Title II: Unemployment Trust Fund Accounts - Amends title IX (Employment Security Administrative Financing) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to establish in the Fund: (1) a State Employment Security Administration Account (State ESAA) for each State; (2) a Supplemental Employment Security Administration Account (Supplemental ESAA) for the administration of employment security programs, under FUTA and SSA titles IX and III (Grants to States for Unemployment Compensation Administration), by States whose average civilian labor force populations number less than one million; and (3) the Secretary of Labor Employment Security Administration Account (Labor Secretary ESAA) for the Secretary to carry out administrative duties under such SSA and FUTA provisions. Makes appropriations to the Fund for credit to such accounts according to specified formulas.(Sec. 201) Authorizes to be made available from State ESAAs, upon State request and subject to appropriation by the legislative body of each State, in addition to amounts otherwise appropriated by the Congress, special administrative funds.(Sec. 202) Amends SSA title IX to repeal authority for the Employment Security Administration Account (the ESAA) in the Unemployment Trust Fund.(Sec. 203) Authorizes, for FY 2005 and thereafter, certain administrative expenditures from State ESAAs for: (1) State administration of unemployment compensation laws; (2) public employment services under the Wagner-Peyser Act; (3) certain veterans' programs; (4) collection of amounts due under FUTA; and (5) administration of statistical programs essential for development of estimates of the gross domestic product and other national statistical series, including those related to employment and unemployment. Provides for such expenditures upon State request, subject to appropriation by the State legislative body, in amounts up to 140 percent of the amount appropriated to the State agency from Federal employment security funds for the previous fiscal year.Authorizes $5 million out of the Supplemental ESAA for each of FYs 2005 and beyond expenditures by States whose average civilian labor force populations number less than one million for allocation by the Council of States with Lesser Populations. Establishes such Council.Authorizes, for FY 2005 and thereafter, expenditures from the Labor Secretary ESAA, in amounts up to 140 percent of that appropriated for the prior year, for the Department's performance of functions for the same administrative purposes for which expenditures from State ESAAs are authorized, plus: (1) establishment and maintenance of the employment security system under the Wagner-Peyser Act; and (2) payments of the Federal share of annual amortization costs of the unfunded liability for the State employment security agencies with independent retirement plans as determined by the Secretary.Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, for FY 2005 and thereafter, to pay from the Labor Secretary ESAA into the Treasury the amount determined by the Secretary of Labor to be allocated to the Department of the Treasury to cover its costs for performing its functions under: (1) SSA titles III (Unemployment Insurance), IX (Employment Security), and XII (Advances to State Unemployment Funds), including the expenses of banks for servicing unemployment benefit payment and clearing accounts which are offset by the maintenance of balances of Treasury funds with such banks; (2) FUTA; and (3) any Federal unemployment compensation law with respect to which responsibility for administration is vested in the Secretary of Labor.(Sec. 204) Provides for transfer of amounts attributable to reduced credits to State ESAAs.(Sec. 205) Provides for advances from a revolving fund within the Federal Unemployment Account (FUA) to State ESAAs.(Sec. 206) Provides for treatment of excess amounts in State ESAAs.(Sec. 207) Requires that excess amounts in the Federal Unemployment Account (FUA) be transferred to State ESAAs according to a State allocation formula.(Sec. 208) Repeals a reporting requirement relating to transfers between FUA and the ESAA.(Sec. 209) Revises treatment of certain amounts in the Extended Unemployment Compensation Account (EUCA). Transfers, at the end of FY 2004 and each fiscal year thereafter, excess EUCA amounts to State ESAAs, as specified.(Sec. 210) Provides for treatment of amounts elected by ineligible States.(Sec. 211) Revises SSA requirements relating to State use of certain funds (known as Reed Act funds) transferred to a State unemployment benefit account.(Sec. 212) Revises SSA provisions for the Unemployment Trust Fund (the Fund). Requires deposit into: (1) the State's Unemployment Compensation Benefit Account (UCBA) of contributions and payments in lieu of contributions under the State law; (2) the State ESAA of State agency collections under FUTA and of certain other transfers or deposits under SSA and FUTA; and (3) the Transition ESA of IRS collections under FUTA after January 1, 2001.(Sec. 213) Provides as separate book accounts in the Fund: (1) the Transition ESA; (2) each State UCBA; (3) each State ESAA; (4) the Supplemental ESAA; (5) the Labor Secretary ESAA; (6) the FUA; (7) the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Account; and (8) the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Administration fund.(Sec. 214) Revises SSA provisions for the Extended Unemployment Compensation Account (EUCA) to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to use a specified formula to determine the excess in EUCA at the close of FY 2004 and each subsequent fiscal year. Sets forth the terms of transfer of such excess EUCA funds to State UCBAs.(Sec. 215) Amends SSA title IX to repeal interfund borrowing authority with respect to the ESAA, FUA, EUCA, and other Federal accounts.Title III: Grants to States for Employment Security Administration - Repeals requirements for use and payments of specified available funds to assist States in administering their unemployment compensation laws, under SSA title III (Grants to States for Unemployment Compensation Administration).(Sec. 302) Revises requirements relating to: (1) certification of State laws; (2) limitations on use of State UCBA funds; and (3) proper use of administrative funds, and replacement of such fund expended for other purposes.(Sec. 303) Provides that States shall not be required to comply with the Secretary of Labor's interpretations of methods of administration requirements under SSA title III, if such interpretations impose additional administrative burdens on them, unless the Congress enacts legislation approving such an interpretation.Title IV: Extended Unemployment Compensation - Amends the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 to: (1) eliminate certain requirements relating to State laws; and (2) provide that payments to the States go to their Unemployment Compensation Benefit Accounts (UCBAs).Title V: Federal Employment Security Service - Amends the Wagner-Peyser Act (WPA) to direct the U.S. Employment Security Service (USESS), as of October 1, 2000, to assist in coordinating public employment services throughout the country and assure that the requirements of SSA titles III and IX and of FUTA are met. (Eliminates current functions of the USESS as of such date.)(Sec. 503) Revises WPA requirements for: (1) transfer of USESS property to States; and (2) State use of public employment service funds.(Sec. 504) Repeals, as of October 1, 2004, WPA provisions for: (1) Federal appropriations authority; (2) Federal use of funds; (3) State and Federal planning, fiscal controls, and accounting procedures; (4) the Secretary's authority to make rules and establish performance standards; and (5) authorization of appropriations to the Secretary to provide funds for reimbursable agreements with the States to operate certain statistical programs for estimates of gross national product and other national statistical series, including those related to employment and unemployment.Title VI: Advances to State Unemployment Compensation Benefit Accounts - Amends SSA title XII (Advances to State Unemployment Funds) to revise requirements for: (1) transfers from the Federal Unemployment Account (FUA) to State UCBAs; (2) State use of such transferred funds; (3) determination of interest rate on such advances to States.</summary>
</bill>
