<bill session="106" type="h" number="3013" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Alaska Native Claims Technical Amendments Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to allow shareholder common stock to be transferred to adopted Alaska Native children and their descendants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-10-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2030"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-13">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2124-2125"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="2803"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="3013"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1702"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Adopted children"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estates (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1999--Introduced.
Alaska Native Claims Technical Amendments Act of 1999 - Amends the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to authorize an Alaska Native to transfer Settlement Common Stock to a descendant notwithstanding an adoption, relinquishment, or termination of parental rights that may have altered or severed the legal relationship between the donor and recipient. (Sec. 3) Includes any corporation, partnership, joint venture, sole proprietorship, trust, or affiliate with which a Native Corporation or its affiliate engages in one or more commercial transactions that exceed $20,000 in a calendar year within the entities excluded from the definition of "employer" for purposes of application of the Civil Rights Act of 1964. (Sec. 4) Includes as a Settlement Trust any trust operated for the benefit of shareholders (current law), Natives, and descendants of Natives. (Sec. 5) Includes within lands authorized to be allotted to Alaska Native veterans lands: (1) in the National Petroleum Reserve-Alaska which the eligible person used and occupied; (2) that were not vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved when the eligible person first used and occupied such land, but which prior to December 18, 1971, became vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved during the time the eligible person used and occupied the land; or (3) that were not vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved when the eligible person first used and occupied such land, but which became vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved after the above date, and remain so. Makes eligible for such allotments Alaska veterans who served during the period between August 5, 1964, and May 7, 1975 (currently, the period between January 1, 1969, and December 31, 1971) and served on active duty for at least six months. Outlines allotment approval procedures, including the right to protest a proposed allotment. (Sec. 7) Withdraws for two years from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws certain lands in the vicinity of Elim, Alaska. Authorizes the Elim Native Corporation to select and receive title to 50, 000 acres of land within the withdrawn lands to replace lands deleted from the original Norton Bay Reservation by executive order in 1929. Outlines selection procedures. States that conveyance of selected lands shall constitute full satisfaction of Corporation claims to replacement lands. (Sec. 8) States that no person acquiring a land interest under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act shall be liable for contamination cleanup costs at the time the land was acquired unless such person was directly responsible for such contamination.</summary>
</bill>
