<bill session="108" type="hr" number="838" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the creation of refugee populations in the Middle East, North Africa, and the Persian Gulf region as a result of human rights violations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400289"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2004-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="sr" number="325"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab countries"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Christianity"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Constitutions"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Jews"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious education"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2004--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States deplores the past and continuing violation of the human rights and religious freedoms of minority populations in Arab countries; (2) with respect to Jews and Christians displaced from Arab countries, for any comprehensive Middle East peace agreement to be enduring, constitute an end to Middle East conflict, and provide for finality of all claims, the agreement must resolve all outstanding issues, including the rights of all peoples displaced from Arab countries; and (3) the United States will work to ensure that both the Law of Administration for the State of Iraq for the Transitional Period and the permanent constitution are universally applied to all groups forced to leave Iraq. Urges the President to: (1) instruct the U.S. Representative to the United Nations and all U.S. representatives in bilateral and multilateral fora that, when the United States considers resolutions that allude to the issue of Middle East refugees, the U.S. delegation should ensure that the relevant text refers to multiple refugee populations that have been caused by the Arab-Israeli conflict and any explicit reference to the resolution of the Palestinian refugee issue is matched by a similar reference to the resolution of the issue of Jewish refugees from Arab countries; and (2) make clear that the United States supports the position that the issue of refugees and the mass violations of human rights of minorities in Arab countries must be resolved in a manner that includes redress for the rights of all refugees displaced from Arab countries and recognition that Jewish and Christian property, schools, and community property were lost as a result of the Arab-Israeli conflict.</summary>
</bill>
