<bill session="108" type="h" number="1772" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-24T10:35:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-24T10:35:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Advocacy Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Small Business Advocacy Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Small Business Advocacy Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve small business advocacy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400362" joined="2003-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-18T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 108-162.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-18T17:20:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="79">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 79.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T10:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Manzullo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T10:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5720-5724" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T10:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1772.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-06-24T10:35:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5720-5721" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Deregulation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2003--Passed House amended.
Small Business Advocacy Improvement Act of 2003 - Requires appointment to the position of Chief Counsel of the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration (SBA) without regard to political affiliation and on the basis of fitness to perform duties. Prohibits appointment of an individual who has served as an SBA officer or employee within the last five years. Requires the Office to: (1) recommend methods for the delivery of financial assistance to small businesses owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, women, and veterans (currently, to minority enterprises); (2) make recommendations and submit relevant reports to the President, the chairmen and ranking members of the congressional small business committees, and the SBA Administrator; (3) maintain economic databases and make such information available to the Administrator and Congress; and (4) coordinate functions with the Small Business and Agriculture Regulatory Enforcement Ombudsman.Requires the Chief Counsel to submit annually to the Office of Management and Budget and the congressional small business and appropriations committees the Office's appropriation estimate and request. Requires each budget of the United States submitted by the President to include a separate statement of the amount of appropriations requested for the Office of Advocacy that indicates whether the proportion of funds requested for the Office compared to those requested for the SBA has increased, decreased, or stayed the same relative to the amounts appropriated for each for the previous year.Authorizes the Chief Counsel to appoint a Principal Deputy Chief Counsel, as well as regional advocates.Requires the Administrator (currently, the Chief Counsel) to conduct an SBA program for the development of rural small businesses engaged in tourism-related activities.Requires the Chief Counsel to report annually to specified congressional committees and the Administrator on SBA compliance with Federal agency regulatory requirements.Increases and extends through FY 2006 the authorization of appropriations for the Office.</summary>
</bill>
