<bill session="106" type="h" number="297" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-23T14:23:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-05-23T14:23:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lewis and Clark Rural Water System Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Lewis and Clark Rural Water System Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the construction of the Lewis and Clark Rural Water System and to authorize assistance to the Lewis and Clark Rural Water System, Inc., a nonprofit corporation, for the planning and construction of the water supply system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1999-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E40-41"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <calendar datetime="2000-05-23T11:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="348">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 348.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-05-23T11:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-633.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-23T11:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Doolittle moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-23T11:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3538-3540" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-23T11:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 297.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-23T11:23:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-23T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3581-3582, H3583" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-05-23T14:23:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="217" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 400 - 13 (Roll no. 217).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3538-3539" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-05-23T14:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-23T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 297.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-05-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="571">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 571.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="244"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Plumbing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water rates"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water supply engineering"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2000--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Lewis and Clark Rural Water System Title II: Sly Park Unit Conveyance Title III: Treatment of Project Costs for Sly Park Unit Title IV: City of Roseville Pumping Plant Facilities Title I: Lewis and Clark Rural Water System - Lewis and Clark Rural Water System Act of 2000 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to make grants to the Lewis and Clark Rural Water System, Inc., a nonprofit corporation, for the planning and construction of a water supply project to provide service to specified counties in South Dakota, Minnesota, and Iowa.(Sec. 104) Specifies that mitigation for fish and wildlife losses incurred as a result of the construction and operation of the water supply project be on an acre-for-acre basis, based on ecological equivalency, concurrent with project construction.(Sec. 105) Requires the Western Area Power Administration to make available, at the firm power rate, the capacity and energy required to meet the pumping and incidental operational requirements of the water supply project during the period beginning May 1, and ending October 31, of each year from power designated for future irrigation and drainage pumping for the Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin program. Makes the portions of the water supply project constructed with assistance under this title eligible to receive firm power from the program for operation during such period of each year, for as long as the water supply system operates on a not-for-profit basis.(Sec. 106) Provides that this Act shall not: (1) limit the authorization for water projects in South Dakota, Iowa, and Minnesota; or (2) preempt State water rights. Specifies the Federal and non-Federal share of the cost. Requires the Secretary to provide funds for the city of Sioux Falls, South Dakota, equal to 50 percent of the incremental cost of its participation in the project.(Sec. 109) Authorizes the Secretary, at the request of the water supply system, to allow the Bureau of Reclamation to provide project construction oversight to the water supply project.(Sec. 110) Specifies that the water supply system shall retain title to all project facilities during and after construction and shall be responsible for all operation, maintenance, repair, and rehabilitation costs.(Sec. 111) Authorizes appropriations.Title II: Sly Park Unit Conveyance - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey the Sly Park Dam and Reservoir, the Camp Creek Diversion Dam and Tunnel, and conduits and canals as authorized under the American River Act (Sly Park Unit) to the El Dorado Irrigation District, California.Authorizes the Secretary to receive specified amounts from the District to relieve payment obligations and extinguish debts associated with specified contracts. Provides that upon such payment: (1) the amounts paid shall be credited toward repayment of capital costs of the Central Valley Project in an amount equal to the associated undiscounted obligation; and (2) the Unit shall no longer be a Federal reclamation project or a unit of the Central Valley Project and the District shall not be entitled to receive any further reclamation benefits.Title III: Treatment of Project Costs for Sly Park Unit - Authorizes the Secretary, to the extent costs associated with the Sly Park Unit are included as a reimbursable cost of the Central Valley Project, to exclude such costs in excess of those repaid by Unit beneficiaries from the pooled reimbursable costs of the Project until such time as the facility is operationally integrated into the water supply yield of the Project.Title IV: City of Roseville Pumping Plant Facilities - Directs the Secretary to credit up to a specified amount to the unpaid capital obligation of the city of Roseville, California, as such obligation is calculated in accordance with applicable Federal reclamation law and Central Valley Project rate setting policy, in recognition of future benefits to be accrued by the United States as a result of the city's purchase and funding of the installation of additional pumping plant facilities in accordance with a specified letter of agreement with the United States. Requires: (1) the Secretary to simultaneously add an equivalent amount of costs to the capital costs of the Central Valley Project; and (2) such added costs to be reimbursed in accordance with reclamation law and policy. Provides for the credited amount to take effect upon the date on which: (1) the city and the Secretary have agreed that the installation of the facilities has been completed in accordance with the terms and conditions of the letter of agreement; and (2) the Secretary has issued a determination that such facilities are fully operative as intended.</summary>
</bill>
