<bill session="106" type="h" number="1662" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide for the inclusion of mentoring programs for novice teachers in the professional development activities of local educational agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority teachers"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/1999--Introduced.
Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require inclusion of mentoring programs for novice teachers in professional development activities of local educational agencies (LEAs), under provisions for improving basic programs operated by LEAs. Revises ESEA provisions for the Dwight D. Eisenhower Professional Development Program to require: (1) the national clearinghouse to disseminate information on model teacher mentoring programs; (2) State applications to describe how the State will administer a teacher mentoring system with specified characteristics; (3) local activities to include mentoring programs to help novice teachers; and (4) States to report on the impact of State and local mentoring programs on teaching quality and teacher retention rates.</summary>
</bill>
