<bill session="106" type="h" number="1553" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-19T17:53:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-05-19T17:53:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">FY2000-2001 National Weather Service Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Weather Service and Related Agencies Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Weather Service and Related Agencies Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2000 and fiscal year 2001 for the National Weather Service, Atmospheric Research, and National Environmental Satellite, Data and Information Service activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-18T14:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 106-146.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-05-18T14:23:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="83">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 83.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-18T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 175 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1553 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate, the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment, the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T10:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 175 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 175.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3352-3353" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1553 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate, the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment, the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 175 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John Shimkus to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1553.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Postponed Vote - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Hutchinson by voice vote and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hutchinson objected to the voice vote pending the absence of a quorum. Further proceedings on the amendment were postponed and the point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Vacate Request for a Recorded Vote - Mr. Hutchinson asked unanimous consent that his earlier request for a recorded vote on the amendment he offered be vacated. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1553.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-05-19T17:53:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19T17:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1553.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="175"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1639"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric research"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation agreements"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Capital budgets"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Earth resources satellites"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood forecasting"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Geodesy"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Meteorological research"/>
    <term name="Meteorological satellites"/>
    <term name="Meteorology"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanography"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Supercomputers"/>
    <term name="Tornadoes"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Weather"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h110"/>
    <amendment number="h111"/>
    <amendment number="h112"/>
    <amendment number="h113"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/19/1999--Passed House amended.
National Weather Service and Related Agencies Authorization Act of 1999 - Authorizes appropriations for FY 2000 and 2001 to the Secretary of Commerce to enable the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to carry out: (1) Operations, Research, and Facilities activities of the National Weather Service (NWS); (2) Procurement, Acquisition, and Construction activities of NWS; (3) Atmospheric Research Operations, Research, and Facilities environmental research and development activities of the Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OOAR); (4) Atmospheric Research Procurement, Acquisition, and Construction environmental research and development activities of OOAR; (5) Operations, Research, and Facilities environmental research and development and related activities of the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service (NESDIS); (6) Procurement, Acquisition, and Construction environmental research and development and related activities of NESDIS; and (7) Operations, Research, and Facilities environmental research and development and related activities required to meet recurring facilities operations costs associated with the David Skaggs Research Center in Boulder, Colorado. Revises requirements for the Secretary of Commerce's duties with respect to the NWS to include responsibilities for: (1) serving as the sole official source of weather and flood warnings; (2) issuing storm warnings; (3) collecting, exchanging, and distributing meteorological, hydrological, climatic, and oceanographic data and information;(4) preparing hydrometeorological guidance and core forecast information; and (5) issuing marine and aviation forecasts and warnings. Bars the NWS from providing or assisting other entities to provide a service that is currently provided or can be provided by commercial enterprise, unless: (1) the service provides vital weather warnings and forecasts for the protection of life and property of the general public; or (2) the U.S. Government is obligated to provide such service under international aviation agreements to provide meteorological services and exchange meteorological information. Directs the Secretary to report to the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate detailing all NWS activities which do not conform to requirements of this Act and outlining a timetable for their termination. Expresses the sense of the Congress that NWS must fully take into account the dangerous and life threatening nature of weather patterns in Wind Zone IV, otherwise known as tornado alley, before making any determination to close any of its local weather service offices. Requires the NOAA Administrator to exclude from consideration for grant agreements made after FY 1999 under the activities for which funds are authorized under this Act, any person who received funds (other than due to membership in a class specified by law for which assistance is awarded to class members according to a formula) appropriated for a fiscal year after FY 1999 under a grant agreement from any Federal funding source for a project that was not subjected to a competitive, merit-based award process. Makes such an exclusion effective for a period of five years after receipt of such Federal funds. Directs the Administrator to make available through NOAA's Internet home page the abstracts relating to all research grants and awards made with funds authorized by this Act. Prohibits any funds authorized pursuant to this Act from being expended by an entity unless such entity agrees, in expending such assistance, to comply with the Act of March 3, 1933, known as the Buy American Act. Expresses the sense of the Congress that entities receiving any equipment or products that may be authorized to be purchased with financial assistance provided under this Act should, in expending such assistance, purchase only American-made equipment and products. Requires the Secretary to provide to each recipient of such assistance a notice describing such statement. Prohibits any person who has been finally determined by a court or Federal agency to have intentionally affixed a label bearing a "Made in America" inscription or any inscription with the same meaning to any product sold in or shipped to the United States that is not made in the United States, from receiving any contract or subcontract made with funds provided pursuant to this Act pursuant to debarment, suspension, and ineligibility procedures.</summary>
</bill>
