<bill session="105" type="h" number="873" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Land Recycling Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to limit Federal authority for response action for releases subject to State voluntary response programs, to provide protection for prospective purchasers of land, and for innocent landowners, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400161"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1997-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1997-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400584" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1997-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1997-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1997-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400329" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1997-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1997-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-02-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E349-351"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-09">
      <text>See H.R.2727.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2727"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/1997--Introduced.
Land Recycling Act of 1997 - Prohibits, with exceptions, the President and any person other than a State from using authorities of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) or the Solid Waste Disposal Act to commence an administrative or judicial action with respect to a release or threatened release at a facility that is, or has been, the subject of a voluntary response plan in a State that: (1) certifies that it has enacted a program established to allow a person to respond voluntarily to the release or threatened release of hazardous substances at a facility; and (2) notifies the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency that a plan for voluntary response at a particular facility is being implemented under such program. Authorizes the Administrator to gather information regarding facilities subject to a voluntary response program but only for purposes of determining whether a facility qualifies for listing on the National Priorities List. Exempts facility remediation activities undertaken pursuant to a voluntary response plan from Federal permit requirements. (Sec. 3) Amends CERCLA, with respect to defenses to liability of an owner of after-acquired property, to deem a person to have made (under current law, "undertaken") appropriate inquiry into the property's previous ownership and uses if the person establishes that an environmental site assessment was conducted which meets specified requirements (compliance with an American Society for Testing and Materials standard or with standards issued by the Administrator) and the person fulfills certain responsibilities concerning information compilation. (Sec. 4) Absolves from liability for response actions bona fide prospective purchasers to the extent liability at a facility for a release or threat thereof is based solely on ownership or operation of a facility. Gives a lien upon a facility to the United States for unrecovered response costs in any case in which there are such unrecovered costs for which the owner is not liable by reason of this Act and the facility's fair market value has increased above that which existed six months before the action was taken.</summary>
</bill>
