<bill session="104" type="hr" number="272" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-17T11:43:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-11-17T11:43:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Authorizing a specified correction in the form of the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 2491) to provide for reconciliation pursuant to section 105 of the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 1996, and waiving points of order against the corrected conference report.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T22:37:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-348, by Mr. Dreier.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T22:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2491 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Vacating the proceedings of 11/15/95, by which the conference report accompanying the bill was presented to the House and ordered printed. The managers on the part of the House may immediately present the conference report in the form actually ordered reported to the House and to be presented in the Senate, with a pertinent corrected part as depicted in sections 3 of this resolution, relating to food stamp eligibilty. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration shall be waived.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-11-16T22:38:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="127">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 127.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-11-17T10:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13148-13156" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-17T10:08:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-17T11:23:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-11-17T11:43:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="810" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 230 - 193 (Roll no. 810).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-11-17T11:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="2491"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/1995--Introduced.
Vacates the proceedings of November 15, 1995, by which the conference report on H.R. 2491 (budget reconciliation) was presented to the House of Representatives and ordered printed so that the managers on the part of the House may present the conference report in the form actually ordered reported to the House as a product of the meeting and actually to be presented in the Senate, corrected as specified. Validates the existing signatures of the conference committee as authorizing the presentation of such conference report to the House in corrected form. Waives all points of order against the consideration of the corrected conference report.</summary>
</bill>
