<bill session="107" type="h" number="3394" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-11-27">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-11-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cyber Security Research and Development Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Cyber Security Research and Development Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Cyber Security Research and Development Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Cyber Security Research and Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize funding for computer and network security research and development and research fellowship programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2001-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2001-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2001-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2001-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2001-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="2001-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2001-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="2001-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-04">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-04">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-12-06">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-01-29T14:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Weldon (FL) asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Science, Space and Technology have until midnight on Jan. 31 to file a report on H.R. 3394. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-04T13:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 107-355, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-04T13:10:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Education and the Workforce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Feb. 4, 2002.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-04T13:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Education and the Workforce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-02-04T13:11:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="208">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 208.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05T19:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 343 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3394 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-07T10:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 343 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-07T10:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 343.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H206-215" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-07T10:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3394 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-07T10:48:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 343 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-07T10:48:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John E. Sununu to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-07T10:49:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3394.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-07T11:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3394.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-07T11:29:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-02-07T11:52:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="13" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 400 - 12 (Roll no. 13).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H211-213" label="text as passed House"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-02-07T11:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-16">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-16">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10599-10601" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-16">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 2182 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2002-10-16" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 2182 with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-12T14:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Boehlert moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-12T14:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 3394.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2002-11-12T14:54:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8067-8079" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8067-8070" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-11-12T14:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2002-11-12">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2002-11-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2002-11-27">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2002-11-27" type="public" number="107-305">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 107-305.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="107" type="hr" number="343"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="2182"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="107" type="s" number="2182"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="2182"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="107" type="s" number="2182"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Computer integrated manufacturing systems"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cryptography"/>
    <term name="Curriculum planning"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Foreign students"/>
    <term name="Government internships"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Industry-university relations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/16/2002--Passed Senate amended.
Cyber Security Research and Development Act - Authorizes appropriations to the National Science Foundation (NSF) and to the Secretary of Commerce for the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to establish new programs, and to increase funding for certain current programs, for computer and network security (CNS) research and development and CNS research fellowships.(Sec. 4) Requires the NSF Director to award grants for CNS through: (1) basic research in innovative approaches to the structure of hardware and software; and (2) multidisciplinary research centers of institutions of higher education (IHEs) or consortia thereof which may partner with government laboratories or for-profit institutions.(Sec. 5) Requires the NSF Director to establish programs of grants to IHEs for: (1) capacity-building of undergraduate and master's degree programs in CNS; (2) graduate traineeships in CNS research; and (3) CNS faculty development traineeship programs to enable graduate students to pursue academic careers in cyber security upon completion of doctoral degrees. Requires the Secretary to provide certain education-related grants under the Scientific and Advanced Technology Act of 1992, but authorizes funds only to support activities to improve education in CNS-related fields. Requires that CNS be included among the fields of specialization supported by NSF's Graduate Research Fellowships program under the National Science Foundation Act of 1950.(Sec. 7) Amends the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 to require the NSF to take a leading role in supporting research and education activities to improve networked information systems' security.(Sec. 8) Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (NISTA) to require the NIST Director, through the Director of the Office for Information Security Programs, to establish a program of assistance to IHEs that enter into partnerships with for-profit entities to support research to improve CNS. Authorizes the NIST Director to establish a program to award post-doctoral research fellowships, including senior fellowships, to individuals seeking research positions at institutions engaged in research activities related to CNS. Provides for periodic program review, as well as a comprehensive review after five program years.Requires the NIST Director to develop CNS checklists for Federal Government computer hardware or software systems.(Sec. 9) Amends NISTA to authorize appropriations to enable the Computer System Security and Privacy Advisory Board to: (1) identify emerging issues related to computer security, privacy, and cryptography; (2) convene public meetings, and (3) publish and disseminate information.(Sec. 10) Requires NIST to carry out specified types of intramural computer security research.(Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of Commerce for NIST for: (1) the CNS research program; and (2) intramural computer security research.(Sec. 12) Requires the NIST Director to arrange with the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences to study and report to specified congressional committees on vulnerabilities of the Nation's network infrastructure and recommendations for improvements.(Sec. 13) Requires the NSF and NIST Directors to: (1) coordinate the research programs under this Act; and (2) work with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to ensure that programs under this Act are taken into account in any Government-wide cyber security research effort.(Sec. 16) Prohibits the award of grants or fellowships under this Act to: (1) individuals who are in violation of their status as nonimmigrants under the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA); (2) individuals who are aliens from a country that is a state sponsor of terrorism, under the Enhanced Border Security and VISA Entry Reform Act (EBSVERA); or (3) institutions that have materially failed to comply with recordkeeping and reporting requirements to receive nonimmigrant students or exchange visitor program participants under INA or the Illegal Immigration Reform and Responsibility Act of 1996, or have been suspended or terminated under EBSVERA.(Sec. 17) Requires a report to Congress reviewing this Act to ensure that grants and fellowships are being awarded to individuals and institutions in compliance with INA in order to protect our national security.</summary>
</bill>
