<bill session="104" type="hr" number="493" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Urging that certain actions be taken with respect to Vietnamese asylum seekers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403545"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Refugee policy"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Thailand"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Vietnamese"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/1996--Introduced.
Declares that: (1) the United States should demand that forced repatriation and the inhumane treatment of Vietnamese asylum seekers should cease; and (2) the United Nations (UN) should not be involved in or provide funds for such activities and should assure the protection of all applicants to the Resettlement Opportunities for Vietnamese Returnees Program from incarceration or harassment from Vietnamese officials. Provides that Vietnamese asylum seekers: (1) who, on appeal to the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, have been designated as refugees should be protected from repatriation and interviewed for resettlement in the United States; (2) in the refugee camps in Hong Kong, the Philippines, Indonesia, and Thailand who have a relationship with the United States and those who apparently quality as refugees under specified criteria should be given access to U.S. immigration officials for resettlement interviews; (3) who are accepted for resettlement in the United States should be admitted under the FY 1997 immigration ceiling for Vietnamese nationals; (4) previously repatriated to Vietnam who have volunteered for the Program should be immediately interviewed for resettlement in the United States under such criteria; and (5) repatriated to Vietnam before having an opportunity to sign up for the Program should be provided with the regulations and application forms for the Program.</summary>
</bill>
