<bill session="104" type="h" number="2756" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Health Security Partnership Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make payments to each State for the operation of a comprehensive health insurance plan ensuring health insurance coverage for individuals and families in the State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400300"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1995-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1995-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1995-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1995-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14244-14245"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health care reform"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tobacco tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Federal Payments to States Title II: Requirements for Comprehensive Health Plans Title III: Financing Mechanisms Title IV: Tax Deductibility of Health Insurance American Health Security Partnership Act of 1995 - Title I: Federal Payments to States - Mandates payments to States for comprehensive health insurance plans certified under title II of this Act. Title II: Requirements for Comprehensive Health Plans - Requires each State to submit (by July 1999) and operate (by 2000) a comprehensive health insurance plan designed to be administered by the State and having at least: (1) coverage for all individuals in the State; (2) benefits comparable to that available under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program (deeming coverage under titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to meet this requirement); (3) home- and community-based care when medically appropriate; (4) community premium rating; (5) payment by the State of supplemental amounts to ensure that all individuals may obtain coverage at reasonable rates; (6) quality control mechanisms; and (7) premium control and cost control mechanisms. (Sec. 203) Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to exempt from ERISA State laws conforming to or reflecting a plan certified under this Act. (Sec. 204) Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to condition Medicaid payments to a State on the State having a certified plan in effect by the deadline. (Sec. 205) Modifies the method for determining the amount of the "community spouse resource allowance" for Medicaid provisions relating to transferring resources to a community spouse. Title III: Financing Mechanisms - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to increase the highest corporate income tax rate. (Sec. 302) Amends Medicaid provisions to reduce the maximum Federal medical assistance percentage. (Sec. 303) Amends the IRC to increase the tax rate on tobacco and related products. Title IV: Tax Deductibility of Health Insurance - Allows a tax deduction for insurance that constitutes medical care.</summary>
</bill>
