<bill session="105" type="h" number="607" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-13">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Mortgage Insurance bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeowners Insurance Protection Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Homeowners Insurance Protection Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Homeowners Insurance Protection Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Home Owners Protection Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Senior Citizen Home Equity Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to require notice of cancellation rights with respect to private mortgage insurance which is required by a creditor as a condition for entering into a residential mortgage transaction, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An Act to amend the National Housing Act to prevent the funding of unnecessary or excessive costs for obtaining a home equity conversion mortgage, to require automatic cancellation and notice of cancellation rights with respect to private mortgage insurance required as a condition for entering into a residential mortagage transaction, to abolish the Thrift Depositor Protection Oversight Board, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400577" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1997-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1997-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400601" joined="1997-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="408476" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="409228" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1997-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400609" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1997-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-18">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 36 - 1.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Banking and Financial Services. H. Rept. 105-55.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-04-16T12:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="39">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 39.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Leach moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1557-1566, H1581-1582" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16T14:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-04-16T15:13:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="80" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 421 - 7 (Roll no. 80).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-13">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12681" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-13">
      <text>Amendment SP 1637 proposed by Senator Lott for Senator D'Amato.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-13">
      <text>Amendment SP 1637 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1997-11-13" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-01-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="318"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Colonias"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estate planning"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Home equity conversion"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage interest rates"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Real property tax"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Resolution Funding Corporation"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Settlement costs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Thrift Depositor Protection Oversight Board"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1637"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/13/1997--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Senior Citizen Home Equity Protection Subtitle A: Senior Citizen Home Equity Protection Subtitle B: Temporary Extension of Public Housing and Section 8 Rental Assistance Provisions Subtitle C: Reauthorization of Federally Assisted Multifamily Rental Housing Provisions Subtitle D: Reauthorization of Rural Housing Programs Subtitle E: Reauthorization of National Flood Insurance Program Subtitle F: Native American Housing Assistance Title II: Homeowners Protection Act Title III: Abolishment of the Thrift Depositor Protection Oversight Board Title I: Senior Citizen Home Equity Protection - Senior Citizen Home Equity Protection Act - Subtitle A: Senior Citizen Home Equity Protection - Amends the National Housing Act with respect to home equity conversion mortgages to: (1) require full disclosure to the mortgagor of all mortgage costs, including estate planning, financial advice, or other related costs; and (2) provide for the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (Secretary) to impose restrictions to ensure that the mortgagor is not charged for such costs. (Sec. 112) Provides for implementation of such provisions by the Secretary. Subtitle B: Temporary Extension of Public Housing and Section 8 Rental Assistance Provisions - Amends the Balanced Budget Downpayment Act, I to extend through FY 1998 provisions regarding public housing ceiling rents, the definition of income adjustments, and repeal of Federal preferences for assisted housing. (Sec. 122) Amends the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations for Additional Disaster Assistance, for Anti-terrorism Initiatives, for Assistance in the Recovery from the Tragedy that Occurred in Oklahoma City, and Rescissions Act, 1995 to extend through FY 1998 the suspension of the public housing demolition and disposition one-for-one replacement requirement. (Sec. 123) Amends the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996 to extend through FY 1998 provisions regarding use of public housing modernization funding for mixed income developments. (Sec. 124) Amends the Balanced Budget Downpayment Act, I to extend minimum rent provisions through FY 1998. (Sec. 125) Amends the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996 to extend through FY 1998 suspension of certain provisions (take-one-take-all, notice of contract termination, and endless lease) of the section 8 rental assistance program. Subtitle C: Reauthorization of Federally Assisted Multifamily Rental Housing Provisions - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to increase the number of units and extend through FY 1998 the risk-sharing and housing finance agency multifamily housing finance pilot programs. (Sec. 132) Amends the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997 to state that the Secretary's authority to manage and dispose of multifamily housing includes the provision of grants and loans from the General Insurance Fund. (Sec. 134) Sets forth owner mortgage prepayment and voluntary mortgage insurance termination provisions, which shall be applicable during the period October 1, 1997, through March 31, 1998. Subtitle D: Reauthorization of Rural Housing Programs - Amends the Housing Act of 1949 to extend through FY 1999: (1) set-aside authority for targeted rural underserved areas and colonias, and for rural rental housing funds; (2) loan authority for housing and related facilities for elderly persons and families and other low-income persons and families; and (3) authorization of appropriations for multifamily rural rental housing loan guarantees. Subtitle E: Reauthorization of National Flood Insurance Program - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to extend through FY 1999 flood insurance program authority, borrowing authority, and emergency implementation authority. Authorizes appropriations through FY 1999 for related studies. Subtitle F: Native American Housing Assistance - Makes specified technical changes to the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996, the United States Housing Act of 1937, the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act, and the Public and Assisted Housing Drug Elimination Act of 1990. (Sec. 164) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to make the provisions permitting designation of housing for elderly and disabled families applicable to Indian housing. (Sec. 165) Amends the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 with respect to: (1) the definition of "Indian area"; (2) block grant tax exemption; (3) civil rights applicability; (4) low-income requirements; (5) tenant selection; (6) environmental review under the Indian housing loan guarantee program; and (7) public availability of information. Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to repeal authority for the Indian housing early childhood development program. Amends the Public and Assisted Housing Drug Elimination Act of 1990 to provide for tribal eligibility under the drug elimination program. Title II: Homeowners Protection Act - Prescribes guidelines for mandatory termination of private mortgage insurance (PMI) for a residential mortgage when the principal balance is first scheduled to reach or actually reaches 80 percent of the original value of the property securing the mortgage loan, including: (1) a mortgagor's written cancellation request; (2) automatic termination; (3) final termination; (4) no further payments; and (5) return of unearned premiums. Cites exceptions for high risk loans. (Sec. 204) Prescribes disclosure requirements for PMI amortization schedules, including for: (1) new mortgages at the time of transaction; (2) high-risk mortgages; (3) mortgage transactions entered into prior to enactment of this Act; (4) annual written updates; (5) PMI cancellation or termination; and (6) lender paid mortgage insurance. (Sec. 207) Prohibits fees for such disclosures. (Sec. 208) Subjects any servicer, mortgagee, or mortgage insurer in violation of this Act to civil liability for damages incurred by each mortgagor to whom the violation relates. (Sec. 209) Preempts: (1) State law governing PMI, unless such law requires PMI termination at an earlier date or when a lower mortgage loan principal balance is achieved; and (2) servicing agreements entered into by Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, or any private investor or note holder. (Sec. 210) Prescribes enforcement guidelines for Federal banking agencies. Title III: Abolishment of the Thrift Depositor Protection Oversight Board - Abolishes the Thrift Depositor Protection Oversight Board. Provides for the continuation of Resolution Funding Corporation orders, resolutions, determinations, and regulations. Transfers to the Secretary of the Treasury the authority of the Thrift Depositor Protection Oversight Board, and the duties of the Resolution Funding Corporation. (Sec. 301) Amends the Resolution Trust Corporation Completion Act to remove the Chairperson of the Thrift Depositor Protection Oversight Board from mandatory membership on the Affordable Housing Advisory Board. Repeals the directive that such Board conduct its meetings where substantial residential property assets of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or the Resolution Trust Corporation are located.</summary>
</bill>
