<bill session="108" type="h" number="2803" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Housing Finance Regulatory Restructuring Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Office of Housing Finance Oversight in the Department of the Treasury to ensure the financial safety and soundness of Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, and the Federal home loan banks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400348"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets, Insurance and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets, Insurance and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank employees"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Housing Finance Board"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal home loan banks"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Holding companies"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2003--Introduced.
Housing Finance Regulatory Restructuring Act of 2003 - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to establish the Office of Housing Finance Oversight (Office) as the regulatory authority for the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (enterprises) in lieu of the regulatory authority of : (1) the Director of the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight of the Department of Housing and Urban Development; (2) the Federal Housing Finance Board; and (3) the general regulatory and other authority of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development. Prohibits the Secretary of the Treasury (Secretary) from merging or consolidating the functions or responsibilities of the Office with any other office or bureau of the Department of the Treasury, or with any other function or program administered by the Secretary. Establishes the position of the Director of the Office, subject to the general oversight of the Secretary. Prohibits the Secretary from: (1) intervening in any matter or proceeding before the Director unless specifically provided by law; or (2) delaying or preventing the issuance of any rule or promulgation of any regulation by the Director. Directs the Director to ensure that the enterprises and the Federal home loan banks are adequately capitalized and operating safely. Makes conforming amendments to: (1) Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act; (2) Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act; (3) Federal criminal law; (4) Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973; (5) Housing and Community Development Act of 1980; (6) Federal Home Loan Act; (7) Federal law governing executive schedule pay rates; and (8) Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978. Abolishes the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and the Federal Housing Finance Board. Transfers to the Office their respective functions, personnel, and property.</summary>
</bill>
