<bill session="107" type="h" number="5118" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-16T13:14:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-07-16T13:14:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Accounting Industry Reform bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Corporate Fraud Accountability Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Corporate Fraud Accountability Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for enhanced penalties for accounting and auditing improprieties at publicly traded companies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2002-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2002-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="2002-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400168" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="2002-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2002-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2002-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-16T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-16T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4683-4694" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-16T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5118.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-16T13:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-07-16T13:14:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="299" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 391 - 28 (Roll no. 299).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4683-4684" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-07-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="3763"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Accounting and financial statements"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing and auditors"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Chief executive officers"/>
    <term name="Chief financial officers"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Corporate accountability"/>
    <term name="Corporate collapse"/>
    <term name="Corporate corruption"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Executives"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Postal crimes"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2002--Passed House amended.
Corporate Fraud Accountability Act of 2002 - Amends Federal criminal law to: (1) increase the maximum penalties for mail fraud and for wire fraud; and (2) establish criminal penalties for knowing perpetration of securities fraud and for tampering with a record or otherwise impeding an official proceeding.(Sec. 4) Requests the United States Sentencing Commission to: (1) promptly review sentencing guidelines applicable to securities and accounting fraud; and (2) expeditiously consider promulgation of new sentencing guidelines to provide an enhancement for officers of directors of publicly traded corporations who commit fraud and related offenses. Prescribes guidelines for Commission consideration, including a request that it ensure that the sentencing guidelines and policy statements reflect the serious nature of securities, pension, and accounting fraud and the need for aggressive and appropriate law enforcement action to prevent such offenses. Sets a deadline for promulgation of such guidelines.(Sec. 5) Amends Federal bankruptcy law to declare nondischargeable in bankruptcy debts that have been incurred in violation of Federal or State laws governing securities fraud, deceit, or manipulation.(Sec. 6) Amends Federal criminal law to mandate that senior corporate officers certify in writing that financial statements fairly and accurately represent in all material aspects the operations and financial condition of the issuer.Subjects senior corporate officers to criminal liability for violations of this requirement, including: (1) maximum imprisonment of ten years for knowingly violating financial report requirements; and (2) maximum imprisonment of 20 years for willfully violating such requirements.(Sec. 7) Subjects any attempt or conspiracy to commit any offense against the United States to the same penalties as those prescribed for the offense.(Sec. 8) Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to: (1) increase criminal penalties for violations; and (2) authorize the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to seek a temporary injunction to freeze extraordinary payments earmarked for designated persons or corporate staff under investigation for possible violations of Federal securities laws.(Sec. 10) Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Securities Act of 1933 to authorize the SEC to prohibit violators of certain provisions from serving as officers or directors of a publicly traded corporation.(Sec. 11) Amends Federal criminal law to establish criminal penalties for intentional retaliation against any person who has provided information to a law enforcement officer regarding the commission of a Federal offense.</summary>
</bill>
