<bill session="106" type="h" number="2887" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TVA Customer Protection Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Power Act to ensure that certain Federal power customers are provided protection by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400012"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1323"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1323"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction equipment"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Corporate debt"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Public utility regulation"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley Authority"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley development"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/1999--Introduced.
TVA Customer Protection Act of 1999 - Amends the Federal Power Act (FPA) to include the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) within the definition of "public utility" (thus encompassing TVA within the jurisdiction of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC). Cites conditions under which disposition of TVA facilities is exempt from FPA property disposition strictures.(Sec. 4) Prohibits FERC from issuing any permit or authorization that would allow TVA charges or rates to recover costs incurred in the conduct of activities or operations outside the United States. Mandates an annual TVA status report detailing its activities or operations outside the United States.(Sec. 5) Sets constraints upon retail sales of electric power by TVA within an area assigned by law as the distributor service area.Sets forth prerequisites for a FERC certification of public convenience and necessity in connection with any proposed TVA acquisition, construction, or sales of electric generation capacity.Directs FERC to conduct an evidentiary hearing, according to specified requirements, to determine the value of TVA-owned property whose cost was incurred to provide electric service to TVA distributors and customers.(Sec. 6) Mandates filing and full disclosure of TVA documents in the same manner as is required of other public utilities.(Sec. 7) Amends the Tennessee Valley Authority Act to provide that TVA shall be deemed to be a person and not a government, for purposes of the antitrust laws (thus subjecting TVA to such laws).(Sec. 9) Denies TVA the power to provide any services related to construction equipment, contracting, and engineering services. Mandates that proceeds received from disposition of its used construction equipment be applied to TVA debt reduction.(Sec. 10) Revamps TVA authority to issue bonds to finance its power program so as to: (1) reduce in annual increments the total authorized amount of TVA indebtedness; (2) mandate annual TVA certification that its cumulative indebtedness is less than its bond authorization; and (3) mandate specific authority granted by an act of Congress as a precondition to TVA contracts for power sales or delivery which would have the effect of making TVA a power supply source outside the area for which it was the primary source of power as of 1957.</summary>
</bill>
