<bill session="105" type="hr" number="576" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-06T14:28:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-06T14:28:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing consideration of the bill (H.R. 4259) to allow Haskell Indian Nations University and the Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute each to conduct a demonstration project to test the feasibility and desirability of new personnel management policies and procedures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-10-05T20:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-779, by Mr. Hastings (WA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-05T20:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4259 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate, the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five minute rule. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. The Chairman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority in recognition the basis of whether the Member offering the amendment has caused it to be printed in the Congressional Record. Amendments shall be considered read. The Chairman may postpone a request for a recorded vote and reduce to five minutes the minimum time for electronic voting.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-10-05T20:53:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="268">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 268.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-06T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9628-9629" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-06T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-06T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-10-06T14:28:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-06T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="4259"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1998--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 4259 (allowing Haskell Indian Nations University and the Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute to test the feasibility and desirability of new personnel management policies and procedures).</summary>
</bill>
