<bill session="107" type="hr" number="442" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-12T21:02:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-06-12T21:02:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Supporting responsible fatherhood and encouraging greater involvement of fathers in the lives of their children, especially on Father's Day.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400392"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2002-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-12T20:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Education and the Workforce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-12T20:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Osborne asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-12T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>RESERVATION OF OBJECTION - Mr. Osborne proceeded with an explanation of the resolution under a reservation of objection by Ms. Carson.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-12T21:02:00-04:00">
      <text>REMOVAL OF RESERVATION OF OBJECTION - Subsequently, the reservation of objection was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-12T21:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3487-3492" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2002-06-12T21:02:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3492" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-06-12T21:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Fathers"/>
    <term name="Mothers"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Special days"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2002--Passed House without amendment.
Urges: (1) men to understand the level of responsibility fathering a child requires, especially in the encouragement of academic, moral, and spiritual development; (2) mothers to encourage fathers to play an active role in child-rearing; and (3) American institutions, and government entities at every level, to promote public policies that encourage and support the efforts of, and remove barriers to, responsible fatherhood.Recognizes the need to encourage active involvement of fathers in the rearing and development of their children. Encourages each father to devote time, energy, and resources to his children, recognizing that children need not only material support, but even more importantly, a secure and nurturing family environment.Commends the millions of fathers who serve as wonderful, caring parents for their children, while also recognizing that there are children who will have no one with whom to celebrate on Father's Day.Calls on fathers across the Nation to use Father's Day to reconnect and rededicate themselves to their children's lives, to spend Father's Day with their children, and to express their love and support for their children.</summary>
</bill>
