<bill session="105" type="h" number="1609" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ISTEA Reauthorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Federal Transit Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1997-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400584" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1997-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="1997-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1997-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="1997-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="406284" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400600" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="408553" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400329" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="1997-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1997-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1997-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1997-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400613" joined="1997-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-09">
      <text>See H.R.2400.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2400"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Appalachia"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bikeways"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Car pools"/>
    <term name="Carbon monoxide"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Earthquake engineering"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to territories"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Ferries"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highway beautification"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Highway planning"/>
    <term name="Highway research"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Limited access highways"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Management audit"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Materials research"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Motorcycles"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Population density"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad finance"/>
    <term name="Railroad rolling stock"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Scenic byways"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seat belts"/>
    <term name="Smog"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Subways"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Toll roads"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation policy"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban transportation"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Highway Programs Title II: Transit Programs ISTEA Reauthorization Act of 1997 - Title I: Highway Programs - Authorizes appropriations out of the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) for FY 1998 through 2003 for: (1) the National Highway System (NHS); (2) the surface transportation program; (3) the bridge program; (4) congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program; (5) the minimum allocation program; (6) apportionment adjustments; (7) the Interstate System reimbursement program; (8) level of effort bonus; (9) certain projects under the Federal lands highways program; (10) Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) highway safety programs; (11) FHWA highway safety research and development; and (12) the Appalachian development highway program. (Sec. 103) Amends Federal-aid highway law to revise the formula for determining the State apportionment of funds for the NHS and the surface transportation program. Extends through FY 2003 the set aside of Federal highway funds for discretionary projects for the resurfacing, restoring, rehabilitating, and reconstructing of routes on the Interstate System. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to conduct, and submit to specified congressional committees, a study of the impact of the movement of goods on transportation infrastructure as a measure of need for apportioning funds for the NHS. (Sec. 104) Earmarks 50 percent of NHS funds apportioned to States for Interstate maintenance projects. Repeals the State apportionment of Federal highway funds (nondiscretionary) for resurfacing, restoring, rehabilitating, and reconstructing the Interstate System. (Sec.105) Revises the formula for the apportionment of funds to States under the congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program. Authorizes States that are apportioned more than 15 percent of the total amount of such apportioned funds to transfer, with the approval of the metropolitan planning organization, all or a portion of the amount that exceeds such percentage to the State's apportionment of funds under the surface transportation program. Prohibits the use of transferred funds for a project which will result in the construction of new capacity available to single occupant vehicles unless the project consists of a high occupancy vehicle facility available to single occupant vehicles only at other than peak travel times. . (Sec. 106) Extends for an additional six-fiscal year period the obligation of a State to allocate surface transportation program funds for Federal-aid highways and highway safety construction in urbanized areas with a population over 200,000. (Sec.107) Increases the minimum amount of apportioned highway bridge replacement and rehabilitation program funds that a State shall receive in any fiscal year. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1998 through 2003 for the discretionary bridge and off-system bridges programs. Amends the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to authorize appropriations for FY 1998 through 2003 for the highway timber bridge research and demonstration program. (Sec.108) Revises for FY 1998 and each fiscal year thereafter the formula for determining the amount of highway funds that would be required to ensure a State's percentage of the total apportionments in each fiscal year and allocations for the prior fiscal year for specified transportation programs is not less than 90 percent of the percentage that the population of the State is of the population of the United States (as determined by the Secretary based on the most recent revised estimate of State populations prepared by the Bureau of Census). (Sec. 110) Provides for the adjustment of funds apportioned to States for the surface transportation program. (Sec. 111) Directs the Secretary to allocate Federal highway funds to eligible States in a ratio that the financial level of effort of each State exceeds the financial level of effort of all States in a fiscal year, except that no State may receive more than ten percent of the total amount made available for such fiscal year. Earmarks a specified amount of such funds to certain States that have a high level of effort as measured by equivalent motor fuel taxes collected. Directs the Secretary to transfer amounts allocated to a State under this section to the State's apportionment of funds for the surface transportation program. (Sec. 112) Extends through FY 2003: (1) the strategic highway research program; (2) the applied research and technology program; (3) the seismic research program; (4) intelligent transportation systems; (5) the scenic byways program; and (6) construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities (discretionary). (Sec. 115) Amends Federal-aid highway law to authorize the Secretary to make grants to Mexican and Canadian border States that demonstrate the need due to increased traffic resulting from implementation of the North American Free Trade Act for assistance in carrying out transportation projects that are necessary to relieve traffic congestion in the border region, in particular to connect the NHS with Federal border crossing facilities, or to improve enforcement of motor carrier safety laws there. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 116) Sets forth highway transportation program streamlining provisions including: (1) authorizing States to give priority for high priority segments of corridors of national significance for inclusion in transportation improvement projects; (2) Federal and State environmental reviews for surface transportation projects; (3) State credit for non-Federal share of the cost of projects for toll revenues that are generated and used by public, quasi-public, and private agencies to build or improve highways, bridges, or tunnels that serve interstate commerce; (4) encouragement of alternative transportation purposes, including bikeway and walkway projects, of historic bridges; and (5) simplifying the administration of enhancement projects and congestion mitigation and air quality projects with costs of less than $500,000. Title II: Transit Programs - Federal Transit Act of 1997 - Amends Federal mass transportation law to authorize urbanized areas with a population of less than 200,000 to use block grant mass transportation assistance for either operating or capital purposes. (Sec. 205) Authorizes appropriations through FY 2003 for discretionary grants and loans for: (1) fixed guideway modernization; (2) capital projects for new fixed guideway systems and extensions to existing fixed guideway systems; and (3) replacement of buses and related equipment and to construct bus-related facilities. (Sec. 206) Authorizes appropriations through FY 2003 for certain apportionments to urbanized areas for fixed guideway modernization (nondiscretionary). Authorizes appropriations through FY 2003 for specified mass transportation programs. Authorizes appropriations through FY 2002 for: (1) the national mass transportation institute; and (2) university research institutes. Authorizes appropriations through FY 2003 for transportation centers (including set-asides). (Sec. 208) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal a certain limitation on the transfer of amounts from the Mass Transit Account of the Highway Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
