<bill session="105" type="h" number="4789" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Elderly and Disabled Protection Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require criminal and abusive work history background checks for direct care employees in nursing facilities, home health agencies, and hospice programs under the Medicare and Medicaid Programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400429"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1998-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1998-10-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Elder abuse"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Hospices (Terminal care)"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/1998--Introduced.
Elderly and Disabled Protection Act of 1998 - Declares that a nursing facility (including a skilled nursing facility), home health agency, or hospice program (covered facility) under the Medicare and Medicaid programs of titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act may not: (1) employ an individual as a direct care employee unless the facility has requested from the State direct care employee registry a background check (including a criminal as well as an abusive work history background check); or (2) continue to employ such an individual if the background check report reveals a conviction of a disqualifying crime. Requires the covered facility to report to such registry documented findings of patient abuse by a direct care employee. Imposes civil penalties upon covered facilities that violate such requirements. Defines "direct care employee" as a paid, nonvolunteer nurse aide, home health care aide, personal care assistant, private duty nurse aide, day attendant, housekeeper, library attendant, laundry assistant, or similar worker who performs nursing or related tasks involving direct patient care in a covered facility. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish methods by which State direct care registries can pool and share criminal background check summaries and documented findings of patient abuse (national registry coordination system). Requires each State to expand its direct care employee registry in order to carry out such background checks and other related functions, including reporting of summary information to the national registry coordination system. Sets forth procedures for criminal and abusive work history background checks.</summary>
</bill>
