<bill session="106" type="h" number="2724" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-24">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical corrections to the Water Resources Development Act of 1999.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05T23:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Shuster asked unanimous consent to consider as introduced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05T23:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H7433-7434" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-08-05T23:49:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H7433" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05T23:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-09-29">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-10-13">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported to Senate by Senator Chafee with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 106-183.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-10-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="316">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 316.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S14310-14311" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08">
      <text>Amendment SP 2773 proposed by Senator Grassley for Senator Warner.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08">
      <text>Amendment SP 2773 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1999-11-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14310" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10T17:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Boehlert moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11915-11916" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10T17:43:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1999-11-10T17:44:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H 11915-11916" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10T17:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-10">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1999-11-24">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1999-11-24" type="public" number="106-109">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-109.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2773"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/8/1999--Passed Senate amended.
Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1992 to: (1) increase the authorization of appropriations for the water-related environmental infrastructure and resource protection and development project for Jackson County, Mississippi, and provide a project for the elimination or control of combined sewer overflows for the County; (2) increase the authorization of appropriations for the project for the elimination of combined sewer overflows in Manchester, New Hampshire; (3) eliminate reference to additional authorization of appropriations (thus, repealing) for certain water-related environmental infrastructure and resource protection and development projects for Atlanta, Georgia, and Paterson, Passaic County, and Passaic Valley, New Jersey; (4) decrease the authorization of appropriations for the water-related environmental infrastructure and resource protection and development project for Elizabeth, New Jersey; and (5) increase the authorization of appropriations for such a project for North Hudson, New Jersey, and modify such project to provide for the elimination or control of combined sewer overflows for the North Hudson Sewerage Authority (currently, for such overflows in North Hudson).Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1999 to: (1) authorize appropriations for FY 1999 through 2009 for implementation of a long-term resource monitoring program with respect to the Upper Mississippi River Environmental Management Program (currently, such funding is designated for a program for the planning, construction, and evaluation of measures for fish and wildlife habitat rehabilitation and enhancement); (2) authorize the Secretary of the Army to carry out modifications to the navigation project for the Delaware River, Pennsylvania and Delaware, if such project as modified is technically sound, environmentally (currently, economically) acceptable, and economically justified; (3) subject certain previously deauthorized water resources development projects to the seven-year limitation governing project deauthorizations under the Act, with the exception of such a project for Indian River County, Florida; (4) except from a certain schedule of the non-Federal cost of the periodic nourishment of shore protection projects constructed after December 31, 1999, those projects for which a District Engineer's Report has been completed by such date; (5) require that the project cooperation agreement for the Comite River Diversion Project for flood control include a provision that specifies that any reduction in the non-Federal share that results from certain modifications be credited toward the share of project costs to be paid by the Amite River Basin Drainage and Water Conservation District; (6) allow the Secretary to provide additional compensation to Chesapeake City, Maryland (currently, to the City of Chesapeake, Maryland) for damage to its water supply resulting from the Chesapeake and Delaware Canal Project; (7) provide for the submission of certain reports on water resources development projects by the Secretary, notwithstanding Federal reporting termination provisions; and (8) authorize and provide for an authorization of appropriations for the existing program for the safety and operations expenses of the Federal Railroad Administration, and make available for obligation funds currently appropriated for such program.</summary>
</bill>
