<bill session="104" type="h" number="14" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Municipal Securities Reform and Simplified Disclosure Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal the exemption from disclosure requirement for municipal securities, and to require the Securities and Exchange Commission to publish model disclosure forms to facilitate compliance with the disclosure requirements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Municipal Securities Reform and Simplified Disclosure Act of 1995 - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to direct the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to publish model disclosure forms and clauses for common transactions in order to facilitate compliance with the disclosure requirements intended to aid issuers and investors in municipal securities by utilizing readily understandable language to simplify the technical nature of the disclosures. Mandates that such model forms and clauses be published for any application, report, or document in connection with the issuance, sale, or distribution of such securities. Declares that this Act may not be construed to require municipal securities issuers to use any such model form or clause prescribed by the SEC.</summary>
</bill>
