<bill session="108" type="h" number="3688" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Integrity of the United States Courts Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for review in the Court of International Trade of certain determinations of binational panels and committees under the North American Free Trade Agreement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400319"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="2004-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400410" joined="2004-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1893"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2003--Introduced.
Integrity of the United States Courts Act of 2003 - Amends the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act to permit a party or person to file with the U.S. Court of International Trade an appeal of a determination of a binational panel or committee, alleging that a panel or committee determination was based on a misinterpretation of U.S. law, a member of a binational panel or committee is guilty of gross misconduct, bias, or serious conflict of interest, or that the panel or committee seriously departed from a fundamental rule of procedure or exceeded its own authority, and such actions have materially affected panel or committee determinations with respect to antidumping and countervailing duty cases and threaten the integrity of the panel or committee review process. Authorizes a person to commence an action in the U.S. Court of International Trade if such person has requested a panel or committee review of an antidumping or countervailing duty determination, but such panel or committee is not convened within 120 days. Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to grant the U.S. Court of International Trade jurisdiction over the review of a final determination of a binational panel or an investigating authority.Declares that the amendments made by this Act with respect to antidumping and countervailing duty law shall apply to goods from Canada and Mexico.</summary>
</bill>
