<bill session="106" type="h" number="3172" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Welfare-to-Work Amendments of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the welfare-to-work program and modify the welfare-to-work performance bonus.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="1999-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-11-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-11-05">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.3073.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-05T17:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 106-456, Part I.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="3073"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Child support enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drugs and employment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Paternity"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Underemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployed"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare recipients"/>
    <term name="Welfare-to-work"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/1999--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Welfare-to-Work Amendments of 1999 - Amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act with regard to Welfare-to-Work grants to States. Changes from mandatory to discretionary the authority of a project grantee to expend its funds for the benefit of TANF recipients. Repeals current allocation percentage requirements, as well as the current requirement that a recipient meet two of the following criteria: (1) be a school dropout or have no general equivalency degree, and have low reading or math skills; (2) require substance abuse treatment for employment; or (3) have a poor work history. (Retains the current requirement that a recipient must either have received Aid to Families with Dependent Children (AFDC) or TANF for 30 months or be within 12 months of losing eligibility because of a time limit.)Prescribes criteria for the provision of project funds to assist certain noncustodial parents to participate in employment or related activities that will enable them to make regular child support payments. Prescribes requirements for such recipients, including an oral or written personal responsibility contract containing certain conditions.Authorizes Welfare-to-Work projects to assist: (1) children between ages 18 and 25 who have received foster care maintenance payments; (2) State TANF recipients with significant barriers to self-sufficiency (as determined according to criteria of the local private industry council); and (3) custodial parents with incomes below 100 percent of the poverty line.Makes vocational educational or job training for up to six months an allowable activity.Permits certain grantees which are not private industry councils or workforce investment boards to provide Welfare-to-Work employment services directly.Repeals the requirement for quarterly State data reports on the Welfare-to-Work program.Reduces the set-aside under provisions for grants for successful performance bonuses.Reduces appropriations for FY 1999.</summary>
</bill>
