<bill session="105" type="h" number="4068" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make certain technical corrections in laws relating to Native Americans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-23">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-07-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-18T12:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-733.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-18T12:30:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="421">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 421.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T15:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T15:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8488-8490" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T15:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-09-23T15:25:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T15:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11303-11304" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-01">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1998-10-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-06">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-10-14" type="public" number="105-256">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-256.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian gambling operations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Water allocation (Policy)"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/1998--Passed House amended.
Amends Federal law to authorize leases granted on lands held in trust for the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon and on the Cabazon Indian Reservation in California to be for terms of up to 99 years. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to extend the terms of specified Indian health care demonstration projects at the Oklahoma City and Tulsa clinics in Oklahoma through FY 2002. Amends the Indian Health Care Improvement Act to extend the authorization of appropriations for such projects through FY 2002. Amends the Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Restoration Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to accept additional Oregon lands in trust for the Confederated Tribes of Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Indians for a reservation. Includes certain counties in Oregon in the service area of the Confederated Tribes of the Siletz Indians for purposes of determining eligibility for Federal assistance programs. Authorizes the Lower Sioux Indian Community in Minnesota to convey to a buyer, without further U.S. approval, all Community interest in specified real property in Redwood County, Minnesota. Amends the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians Recognition Act to require the Secretary of the Interior to accept title to 2,000 acres (and permits the Secretary to accept title to additional acres) of real property located in the Umpqua River watershed upstream from Scottsburg, Oregon, or the northern slope of the Rogue River watershed upstream from Agness, Oregon, if transferred to the United States by or on behalf of the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe and to place such land in trust for the Tribe. Incorporates such land into the Tribe's reservation. Amends the Jicarilla Apache Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act to extend until December 31, 2000, the date by which two partial final decrees concerning water rights must be entered in order to prevent the termination of the Jicarilla Apache Water Resources Development Trust Fund. Approves a water rights stipulation and settlement agreement between such Tribe and other parties. Amends the San Luis Rey Indian Water Rights Settlement Act to authorize and direct the Secretary of the Interior to disburse a specified amount of funds, from interest earned by the San Luis Rey Tribal Development Fund and prior to completion of the final settlement of the water rights dispute, for economic development of the La Jolla, Rincon, San Pasqual, Pauma, and Pala Bands of Mission Indians in San Diego County, California. Amends the Native Hawaiian Health Care Improvement Act to revise conditions pertaining to Native Hawaiian health scholarships. Amends the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 1996 to: (1) repeal a provision setting forth certain use restrictions relating to a service facility of the Ketchikan Indian Corporation; and (2) revise a provision authorizing the conveyance of certain property to the Corporation to allow the sale of such property.</summary>
</bill>
