<bill session="108" type="h" number="2909" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Utah Test and Training Range Protection Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Utah Test and Training Range Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure the continued availability of the Utah Test and Training Range to support the readiness and training needs of the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2003-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-06-03T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-521.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-06-03T15:29:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="300">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 300.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="211"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="Military communications"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mountains"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2004--Reported to House amended.
Utah Test and Training Range Protection Act - States that nothing in this Act or the Wilderness Act shall: (1) preclude low-level overflights and operations of military aircraft, missiles, or unmanned aerial vehicles over the Utah Test and Training Range (Range), including the Dugway Proving Ground; (2) preclude the designation of new or expansion of existing units of special use airspace or the use or establishment of military training routes over such Range; (3) prevent any required maintenance of existing communications, instrumentation, or electronic tracking systems in the Range or the addition of communications, instrumentation, or equipment necessary for effective testing and training to meet military requirements in wilderness study areas located beneath special use airspace of the Range, upon specified determinations by the Secretary of the Interior; (4) preclude the continuation of a current memorandum of understanding between the Departments of the Interior and Air Force with respect to emergency access and response within the Range; or (5) permit ground military operations in covered wilderness of the Range, unless such operations are otherwise permissible under Federal law and consistent with the Wilderness Act. Directs the Secretary to develop, maintain, and revise land use plans for Federal lands located in the Range, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense. Limits the issuance of rights-of-way in the Range. Designates certain Federal lands in Tooele County, Utah, as the Cedar Mountain Wilderness Area. Withdraws such lands from all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, including mining and mineral and geothermal leasing. Authorizes fish and wildlife management and livestock grazing within such areas, as appropriate. Releases the Browns Springs Cherrystem area from its status as a wilderness study area. Directs the Secretary to identify approximately 640 additional acres of Bureau of Land Management lands in Utah to be administered in trust for the benefit of the Skull Valley Band of Goshutes.</summary>
</bill>
