<bill session="107" type="h" number="496" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-03-21T11:21:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-03-21T11:21:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Independent Telecommunications Consumer Enhancement Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Independent Telecommunications Consumer Enhancement Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Independent Telecommunications Consumer Enhancement Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to promote deployment of advanced services and foster the development of competition for the benefit of consumers in all regions of the Nation by relieving unnecessary burdens on the Nation's two percent local exchange telecommunications carriers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="2001-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2001-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400026" joined="2001-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2001-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2001-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400588" joined="2001-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="2001-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400305" joined="2001-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2001-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2001-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2001-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2001-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2001-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-02-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E128-129"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-02-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-03-13T18:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 107-20.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-03-13T19:01:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="15">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T11:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Upton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T11:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1030-1034" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T11:07:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 496.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-03-21T11:21:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1030-1031" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T11:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Corporate management"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Internet service providers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Management information systems"/>
    <term name="Price regulation"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Telephone rates"/>
    <term name="Trade regulation"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2001--Passed House amended.
Independent Telecommunications Consumer Enhancement Act of 2001 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to define a "two percent carrier" as an incumbent local telecommunications exchange carrier whose access lines are fewer than two percent of the Nation's subscriber lines installed in the aggregate nationwide.Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), in adopting rules that apply to incumbent local exchange carriers, to separately evaluate the burden that any proposed regulatory, compliance, or reporting requirements would have on two percent carriers.Prohibits the FCC from requiring a two percent carrier to: (1) file cost allocation manuals or Automated Reporting and Management Information systems; or (2) establish or maintain a separate affiliate to provide any common carrier or noncommon carrier services or to maintain separate officers, personnel, facilities, books or accounts, or other operations.States that the participation or withdrawal from participation by a two percent carrier of one or more study areas in the common line tariff administered and filed by the National Exchange Carrier Association or any successor tariff or administrator shall not obligate such carrier to participate or withdraw from participation in such tariff for any other study area. Allows the FCC to require a two percent carrier to give 60 days notice of its intent to participate or withdraw.Allows any two percent carrier to deaverage its interstate switched or special rates and file contract-based tariffs for interstate switched or special access services immediately upon certifying to the FCC that an unaffiliated carrier has engaged in facilities-based entry within such carrier's service area.Provides limitations on FCC review of a two percent carrier's merger or acquisitions.Requires FCC determination within 90 days with respect to a two percent carrier's request for reconsideration or other review of an FCC rule, policy, or other requirement.</summary>
</bill>
