<bill session="107" type="h" number="5460" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-01T18:10:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-01T18:10:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reclamation Recreation Management Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Reclamation Recreation Management Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize and amend the Federal Water Project Recreation Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6867-6869" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5460.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-10-01T18:10:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6867-6868" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Groundwater pollution"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Saline water conversion"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2002--Passed House amended.
Reclamation Recreation Management Act of 2002 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Federal Water Project Recreation Act to allow fees to be collected under a project for recreation or fish and wildlife enhancement (project) and retained and used by the participating non-federal entities for operation, maintenance, and replacement of recreation facilities on project lands and waters being managed by such entities. Requires excess revenues to be credited to the Reclamation Fund.Repeals provisions limiting the modification of such projects. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) investigate, plan, construct, replace, manage, operate, maintain, or otherwise provide for public use and enjoyment of project lands, facilities, and water areas in a manner coordinated with other project purposes; and (2) modify or expand existing facilities.Requires: (1) amounts collected for admission to or recreation use of project land and waters to be deposited into a special account in the Fund; and (2) at least 60 percent of such amounts to be used at the site from which the fees were collected.Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) investigate, plan, design, construct, replace, manage, operate, and maintain recreation and fish and wildlife enhancement facilities and services; and (2) acquire or otherwise make available adjacent lands or interests for public recreation or fish and wildlife use.Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into agreements with other non-federal entities for recreation and concession management at Bureau of Reclamation projects; and (2) make available to the public information about Bureau programs.(Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to construct recreational facilities at Lost Creek Reservoir, Utah.(Sec. 5) Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary to participate in the planning, design, and construction of, and land acquisition for, a project to reclaim and reuse wastewater, including degraded groundwaters, within and outside the service area of the City of Austin Water and Wastewater Utility, Texas. Prohibits the Federal cost share of such project from exceeding 25 percent.(Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary to conduct a feasibility study on raising the height of Arthur V. Watkins Dam and thereby enlarging the Willard Bay Reservoir for the development of additional storage to meet water supply needs within the Weber Basin Project area. Requires a report from the Secretary to Congress. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 7) Amends the Water Desalination Act of 1996 to: (1) authorize the Secretary to enter into cooperative and interagency agreements (as well as to award grants and enter into contracts) for research to develop processes for converting saline water into water suitable for beneficial uses; and (2) extend the authorization of appropriations through FY 2008.</summary>
</bill>
