<bill session="104" type="h" number="1019" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Microenterprise Opportunity Expansion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assist in the development of microenterprises and microenterprise lending.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402763"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-23">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development banking"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal Home Loan Bank Board"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/23/1995--Introduced.
Microenterprise Opportunity Expansion Act - Amends the Social Security Act to exclude, for purposes of determining eligibility for public assistance benefits, any resources and income used primarily for a small-sized business (microenterprise) owned by an individual otherwise eligible for such assistance. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prescribe guidelines under which individuals starting microenterprises are entitled to unemployment compensation. Permits the use of funds in a State unemployment fund to assist eligible individuals in starting microenterprises. Amends the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to treat grants and loans made to certain microenterprises by a regulated financial institution as community reinvestments. Amends the Home Owners' Loan Act to treat as a qualified thrift investment the aggregate amount of microenterprise loans held by a savings association. Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to permit the use of Federal community development funds for the administrative and operating costs of entities providing support for microenterprises. Requires each Federal banking agency to establish a division to promote microenterprises to be known as the Microenterprise Technical and Operations Office. Directs the Financial Institutions Examination Council to study and report to the Congress on: (1) the administration of the microenterprise loan provisions of this Act; and (2) the credit needs of certain small businesses ineligible for microenterprise loans.</summary>
</bill>
