<bill session="108" type="h" number="2847" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hawaii Agriculture/Livestock Shipping Open Market Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Merchant Marine Act, 1920, to allow transportation of certain agricultural goods and livestock in Hawaiian noncontiguous trade on foreign-flag vessels, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400069"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1593-1594"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Coastwise shipping"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Farm produce"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Flags of convenience"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2003--Introduced.
Hawaii Agriculture/Livestock Shipping Open Market Act of 2003 - Amends the Merchant Marine Act, 1920, to make the requirement that all cargo shipping between U.S. ports occur exclusively on U.S. flagged vessels inapplicable with respect to transportation in Hawaii noncontiguous trade of merchandise that is a forest product, agricultural product, or livestock on a foreign qualified freight vessel for which the Secretary of Transportation has issued a certificate of documentation. Amends the Shipping Act, 1916, to repeal certain requirements regarding: (1) the percentage of ownership of a corporation operating in coastwise trade owned by U.S. citizens; and (2) seizure and forfeiture of documented vessels. Requires jurisdiction for an action brought for recovery for injury to or death of a seaman against a defendant employer that does not reside or maintain an office in the United States and that engages in any enterprise that makes use of one or more ports in the United States to be under the district court most proximate to the place of the occurrence of the personal injury or death that is the subject of the action. Authorizes the employer of a master or member of the crew of a vessel, at the employer's election, to participate in an authorized compensation plan under the Longshore and Harbor Workers' Compensation Act. Subjects all vessels operating in the U.S. coastwise trade to minimum international labor and environmental standards. Sets requirements for non-citizens irregularly engaging in the U.S. domestic coastwise trade.</summary>
</bill>
