<bill session="105" type="h" number="1364" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Health Insurance and Lower Deficit Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to States to provide uninsured children with access to health care insurance coverage and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the excise taxes on tobacco products for the purpose of funding such grants and reducing the deficit.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1997-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="402284" joined="1997-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1997-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1997-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1997-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1997-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1997-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1997-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409228" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1997-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1997-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Free ports and zones"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tobacco tax"/>
    <term name="Vending machines"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare fraud"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Children's Health Insurance Grant Program Subtitle A: Voluntary State Grant Programs Subtitle B: Assistance Subtitle C: Definitions and Miscellaneous Provisions Title II: Increase in Excise Tax on Tobacco Products Child Health Insurance and Lower Deficit Act of 1997 - Title I: Children's Health Insurance Grant Program - Subtitle A: Voluntary State Grant Programs - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize each State to establish a children's health insurance program. Requires participating States to contract with insurance issuers, ensure that policies are available to all eligible children, and provide certain premium and cost sharing payments. Mandates coverage that is either: (1) equivalent to the medical assistance available under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act; or (2) comparable to benefits under the Federal Employees' Health Benefits Program plan having the largest enrollment. Requires each participating State, for each area served by a health center, to contract directly with the health center for direct services. Subtitle B: Assistance - Bases eligibility on family income (as a percentage of the poverty line), with assistance paid to the issuer (or, for a child receiving direct services, to the provider). Regulates the amount of grants to States. Provides for taking into account cost variations among States. Authorizes appropriations. Allows a State to use up to a specified percentage of the grants to meet the needs identified in the statewide needs assessments prepared under provisions of the Social Security Act relating to preventive and primary care services for pregnant women, mothers, and infants up to age one. Subtitle C: Definitions and Miscellaneous Provisions - Prohibits an employer that elects to make health coverage contributions from conditioning or varying the contributions because of an individual's eligibility for assistance under provisions of this Act. Provides for the application of specified provisions of title XXVII (Assuring Portability, Availability, and Renewability of Health Insurance Coverage) of the Public Health Service Act relating to preexisting conditions, portability, eligibility, guaranteed availability, and network plans and financial capacity. Title II: Increase in Excise Tax on Tobacco Products - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the tax on cigarettes, cigars, cigarette papers, cigarette tubes, smokeless tobacco, and pipe tobacco. Imposes a tax on floor stocks of tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes.</summary>
</bill>
