<bill session="106" type="h" number="1137" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dakota Water Resources Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend Public Law 89-108 to increase authorization levels for State and Indian tribal, municipal, rural, and industrial water supplies, to meet current and future water quantity and quality needs of the Red River Valley, to deauthorize certain project features and irrigation service areas, to enhance natural resources and fish and wildlife habitat, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400323"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E438"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-30">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="623"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Freshwater ecology"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grassland ecology"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Multipurpose projects"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water rates"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water supply engineering"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/1999--Introduced.
Dakota Water Resources Act of 1999 - Amends Federal provisions relating to the Garrison water diversion unit, North Dakota (part of the Pick-Sloan Missouri River Basin Program), to include within authorized unit purposes the development of municipal, rural, and industrial water systems, fish, wildlife, and other natural resource conservation and development, recreation, flood control, ground water recharge, and augmented stream flows (currently, only irrigation is authorized). Authorizes the State of North Dakota (currently, only the Secretary of the Interior) to plan and construct within the State a multipurpose water resource development irrigation project. Directs the Secretary to estimate the actual construction cost of unit facilities already in existence, as well as their annual operation, maintenance, and replacement costs. Makes the Secretary responsible for operation and maintenance (O&amp;M) costs of that portion of the capacity of such facilities that remain unused. Requires the Secretary to enter into one or more contracts with North Dakota to carry out this Act, including O&amp;M of the completed unit facilities and design and construction of new facilities. Authorizes water systems constructed under this Act to deliver Missouri River water into the Hudson Bay basin, after a certain determination. (Sec. 3) Revises provisions concerning unit operational costs to make nonreimbursable: (1) all fish and wildlife enhancement costs incurred in connection with waterfowl refuges or production areas, as well as wildlife conservation areas proposed for Federal or State administration; and (2) 50 percent of recreation area costs, if non-Federal public bodies assume the remainder of such costs. Provides for the determination of such non-Federal share. Deauthorizes Taayer Reservoir and Lonetree Dam and Reservoir as project features. (Sec. 4) Allows the calculation of interest during construction of a feature only until such feature is substantially complete, and regardless of whether it is placed into service. (Sec. 5) Includes certain areas of North Dakota within the area in which the Secretary is authorized to develop irrigation facilities, but prohibits the development of any such facility in the Hudson Bay-Devils Lake Basin. Allows such developed irrigation to receive Pick-Sloan pumping power. Directs the Secretary to investigate and report on an undesignated 28,000 acres of irrigation areas in North Dakota. (Sec. 6) Prohibits any reallocation of project costs to Pick-Sloan customers. (Sec. 7) Revises provisions authorizing the construction of municipal, rural, and industrial water systems in North Dakota to: (1) authorize the State to use Federal and non-Federal funds for grants or loans for such systems; (2) make additional projects eligible for such funding; (3) authorize the State to develop and implement a water conservation program; (4) make nonreimbursable the costs of features constructed on the Missouri River by the Secretary of the Army before the date of enactment of this Act; and (5) add Turtle Mountain to the areas in which the Secretary is required to maintain necessary water systems. (Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary to select and construct a feature or features to deliver Missouri River water to the Sheyenne River water supply and release facility. Directs the Secretary and the State to jointly report to Congress on the comprehensive water quality needs of the Red River Valley and options for meeting those needs. Requires environmental impact statements to be provided. Directs the Secretary to construct, operate, and maintain a Sheyenne River water supply and release feature capable of delivering a specified water supply for the cities of Fargo and Grand Forks and surrounding communities. (Sec. 9) Directs the Secretary to enter into an agreement with the State to convey U.S. rights and interests in the Oakes Test Area. (Sec. 10) Authorizes additional appropriations to carry out provisions added by this Act. (Sec. 11) Directs the Secretary, from funds authorized under this Act, to make an annual Federal contribution to the Natural Resources Trust (previously named the Wetlands Trust), limiting such annual contribution to $12 million. Directs the Secretary to make additional annual contributions equal to five percent of the total amount appropriated for such Trust in a fiscal year. Adds to authorized Trust uses the enhancement, restoration, and management of grassland conservation and riparian areas. Adds to Trust authority the power to fund incentives for conservation practices by landowners.</summary>
</bill>
