<bill session="107" type="h" number="829" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Election Standards Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Federal Election Commission to set uniform national standards for Federal election procedures, change the Federal election day, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2001-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election Day"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Election fraud"/>
    <term name="Electoral college"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2001--Introduced.
National Election Standards Act of 2001 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to direct the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to provide uniform national election standards meeting specified criteria with regard to procedures for elections to Federal office.Authorizes the FEC to make grants to States to provide for the cost of implementing such standards for Federal elections. Establishes civil and criminal penalties for violation of such standards.Amends Federal presidential elections and vacancies law and other Federal election law to provide for a change in the date with respect to the timing of the appointment of presidential and vice presidential electors, and with respect to the timing of the holding of congressional elections.Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require each State to establish procedures to allow voters in the State to register to vote at the polling place at the time of voting in a Federal general election.</summary>
</bill>
