<bill session="106" type="h" number="161" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Real Estate Investment Trust Modernization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to restrict imposition of Medicaid liens and Medicaid estate recovery for long-term care services in the case of certain individuals who have received benefits under long-term care insurance policies for at least 3 years, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow the carryover of reimbursement maximums for flexible spending arrangements, to allow the reimbursement of long-term care insurance premiums by FSA's, and to repeal the inclusion in income of long-term care coverage provided through FSA's.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400587"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400588" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1999-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Estates (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to prohibit the imposition of Medicaid home liens and Medicaid estate recovery for long-term care services in the case of an individual who has received benefits under a qualified long-term care insurance policy for at least three years during the five-year period ending on the date of provision of such services. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) repeal the inclusion in an employee's gross income of employer-provided coverage (through a flexible spending or similar arrangement (FSA)) of qualified long-term care services; (2) allow the carryover of amounts in excess of the maximum amount of reimbursement under an FSA; and (3) exclude from gross income the reimbursement of long-term care insurance premiums by FSAs (as well as the reimbursement of health insurance premiums during unemployment).</summary>
</bill>
