<amendment session="107" chamber="h" number="433" updated="2013-07-17T08:15:54-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="1542" sequence="2"/>
  <status datetime="2002-02-27T15:16:00-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400414"/>
  <offered datetime="2002-02-27"/>
  <description>Amendment increases FCC's forfeiture penalties for phone companies which violate the telecommunications law; doubles from 1 year to 2 years the statute of limitations for the FCC to bring enforcement actions against phone companies; gives the FCC "cease and desist" authority to use against phone companies which violate any of the telecommunications laws; and directs the FCC to study the impact of the enhanced penalties and report back to Congress within one year after enactment.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 and printed in part B of House Report 107-361 to increase the FCC's forfeiture penalties for phone companies which violate the telecommunications law by elevating the current cap from $1.2 million to $10 million and increasing the current $120,000 fine per violation or each day of a continuing violation to $1 million. For repeat offenders, the amendment doubles these increased forfeiture penalties to $ 2 million per violation or each day of a continuing violation, capped at $20 million. The amendment doubles from 1 year to 2 years the statute of limitations for the FCC to bring enforcement actions against phone companies, gives the FCC clear, statutory "cease and desist" authority to use against phone companies which violate any of the telecommunications laws and directs the FCC to study the impact of the enhanced penalties under the bill and report back to Congress within one year after enactment.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-02-27T14:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Upton.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H597-601" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H597" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2002-02-27T15:16:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="43">
      <text>On agreeing to the Upton amendment (A002) Agreed to by recorded vote: 421 - 7 (Roll no. 43).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
