<bill session="104" type="h" number="3551" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Shore Protection Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Act entitled "An Act authorizing Federal participation in the cost of protecting the shores of publicly owned property" to confirm and clarify the authority and responsibility of the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to promote and carry out shore protection projects, including beach nourishment projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1996-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1996-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1996-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404142" joined="1996-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1996-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400584" joined="1996-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="1996-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1996-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="1996-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1996-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="1996-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1996-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1996-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1996-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="1996-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1996-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1996-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1996-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1996-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="1996-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1996-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="1811"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1811"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Beach erosion"/>
    <term name="Beaches"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Dunes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/29/1996--Introduced.
Shore Protection Act of 1996 - Includes as U.S. policy the prevention of damage to U.S. beaches and the promotion of shore protection projects (projects) and related research that encourages the protection, restoration, and enhancement of sandy beaches. Directs the Secretary of the Army to: (1) recommend, conduct, and report to the Congress on studies concerning projects that meet established criteria; (2) recommend to the Congress the authorization or reauthorization of projects based on study results; (3) consider the economic, ecological, local, and regional benefits of such projects; and (4) carry out the projects in coordination with any other Federal projects. Directs the Secretary to: (1) construct any project authorized by the Congress for which funds have been appropriated through a construction agreement with a non-Federal interest; (2) report annually to the appropriate congressional committees on the status of all ongoing shore protection studies and projects; and (3) reimburse non-Federal interests (currently, local interests) for work done on authorized projects (current law) or separable elements of such projects. Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1992 to require similar written agreements with non-Federal interests for shoreline projects carried out under such Act. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) cooperate with a State in the preparation of a comprehensive State or regional plan for the conservation of coastal resources; (2) encourage State participation in plan implementation; and (3) submit reports and recommendations to the Congress concerning Federal participation in such plan. Amends the Flood Control Act of 1970 to include within authorized projects shore protection projects, including beach nourishment and the replacement of sand.</summary>
</bill>
