<bill session="104" type="h" number="3782" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Electric Power Competition and Consumer Choice Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modernize the Public Utility Company Act, the Federal Power Act, and the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to promote competition in the electric power industry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1255"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Corporate divestiture"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Holding companies"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Monopolies"/>
    <term name="Price discrimination"/>
    <term name="Public utility regulation"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/1996--Introduced.
Electric Power Competition and Consumer Choice Act of 1996 - Declares the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935 inapplicable to an electric utility company or any holding company of such utility if any subsidiary, associate, or affiliate of either the electric utility or the holding company has received a Certification of Competition under the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (PURPA) from the appropriate State regulatory authority. Amends PURPA to codify standards of competition for electric utilities. Sets forth a voluntary State certification program under which a State regulatory authority may elect to issue to a regulated electric utility over which it has ratemaking authority a State certification of compliance with standards and requirements of competition. Instructs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to establish criteria for State certification in accordance with specified Federal standards of competition, including a retail competition standard and a divestiture standard. Sets forth minimum certification requirements. Provides that upon passage of this Act: (1) no law shall be construed to preempt otherwise applicable State authority to review the prudence of any wholesale or retail cost incurred by a utility; and (2) no Federal statute shall be construed to preempt FERC authority to examine existing affiliate contracts or transactions. (Sec. 4) Amends the Federal Power Act regarding public utility mergers and acquisitions to prohibit acquisition of an interest in a public utility that results in effective control or ownership unless: (1) an arms-length relationship exists between all parties; and (2) FERC has made certain mandatory findings concerning the maintenance of effective competition and substantial electric service cost reductions. Authorizes FERC to establish conditions governing such transactions. (Sec. 5) Amends the Federal Power Act to repeal current conflict of jurisdiction requirements and prohibit any public utility or affiliate to use its ownership or control of any resource to create or maintain a situation inconsistent with effective competition in any market in which competition would benefit consumers. Delineates parameters within which FERC shall order a public utility to desist from any violation of such prohibition. (Sec. 6) Amends the Federal Power Act to instruct FERC to promulgate rules establishing tariffs applicable in the largest feasible regions within which a single transmission rate schedule is available for use by buyers or sellers of generation. Requires that such tariffs be designed, among other things, to prevent multiple transmission service charges based on the number of transmission owners rather than on actual transmission costs. (Sec. 7) Grants State regulatory bodies and FERC access to the books and records of a public utility, including its affiliates or associates.</summary>
</bill>
