<bill session="106" type="h" number="4682" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Title XI Mortgage Access and National Shipbuilding Initiative Extension Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Merchant Marine Act, 1936, to direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a simplified formula by which application may be made for Smaller Ship Shared-Risk Financing Guarantees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400598"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Merchant marine"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2000--Introduced.
Title XI Mortgage Access and National Shipbuilding Initiative Extension Act - Amends title XI of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 to require the Secretary of Transportation to establish a simplified form and process for application for Smaller Ship Shared-Risk Financing Guarantees. Sets forth certain eligibility requirements and restrictions and conditions with respect to such guarantees.Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Coast Guard and subject to appropriations, to provide financial assistance for research projects proposed to and selected by the U.S. Passenger Vessel Association that: (1) foster business process or design technologies to avoid or mitigate adverse environmental impacts from domestic passenger vessel operations; (2) promote cost-effective solutions to passenger and crew safety issues arising from such operations and changing technologies; and (3) propose, promote, or assess the feasibility of waterborne passenger transport in U.S. locales with existing or foreseeable nonwaterborne transport congestion.Declares that the authority created under the National Shipbuilding and Shipyard Conversion Act of 1933 to extend the availability of title XI obligation guarantees to eligible export vessels and for U.S. shipyard modernization shall continue until terminated or otherwise modified by Congress.</summary>
</bill>
