<bill session="105" type="h" number="3469" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient Right to Independent Appeal Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require that group and individual health insurance coverage and group health plans provide for external appeals in the case of adverse determinations involving experimental treatment, significant costs, or a serious medical condition.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1998-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="1998-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="1998-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1998-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="1998-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1998-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1998-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1998-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400613" joined="1998-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-03-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E395-396"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/1998--Introduced.
Patient Right to Independent Appeal Act of 1998 - Amends the Public Health Service Act and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require a group health plan, and a health insurer offering group coverage, (and, for the Public Health Service Act, health coverage offered in the individual market) to provide for an external appeals process for certain adverse determinations if the denial or failure: (1) involves a determination that a treatment is experimental; (2) is based on a determination that services are not medically necessary and the amount is over a threshold; or (3) jeopardizes the patient's life or health. Requires that the appeal be conducted under a contract between the plan or issuer and one or more appeal entities unless: (1) for health insurance issuers, the State selects the appeal entity; or (2) for group health plans, the Secretary of Health and Human Services designates the appeal entity. Provides for certification of appeal entities. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require a group health plan to provide for an external appeals process for certain adverse determinations if the denial or failure: (1) involves a determination that a treatment is experimental; (2) is based on a determination that services are not medically necessary and the amount is over a threshold; or (3) jeopardizes the patient's life or health. Requires that the appeal be conducted under a contract between the plan or issuer and one or more appeal entities unless the Secretary of Health and Human Services designates the appeal entity. Provides for certification of appeal entities. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to apply this Act's requirements relating to the Public Health Service Act to entities offering coverage under titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to the extent that such requirements provide greater protections for enrollees and do not conflict directly with requirements otherwise imposed by law.</summary>
</bill>
