<bill session="104" type="h" number="2621" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-14T13:39:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-12-14T13:39:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enforce the public debt limit and to protect the social security trust funds and other federal trust funds and accounts invested in public debt obligations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400567"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T12:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Archer moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T12:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T12:18:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T12:18:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules and announced that, by voice vote, the measure was not agreed to. Mr. McCrery objected to the vote on grounds that a quorum was not present, and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to clause 5, rule I, the Speaker announced that the vote would be postponed until later in the day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T14:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12232-12238" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="1995-11-14T15:09:00-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="791" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Failed by recorded vote (2/3 required): 247 - 179 (Roll No. 791).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12247-12248" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-07T15:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 293 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2621 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the House. A specified amendment is in order. Upon adoption of this resolution, the amendment printed in the report accompanying this resolution shall be considered as having been adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-14T11:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 293 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-14T11:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 293.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14885-14899" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-14T11:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2621 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the House. A specified amendment is in order. Upon adoption of this resolution, the amendment printed in the report accompanying this resolution shall be considered as having been adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-14T11:40:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-14T13:00:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-14T13:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gibbons moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-14T13:01:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Gibbons motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-14T13:09:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-14T13:29:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 190 - 229 (Roll no. 861).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14899" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-12-14T13:39:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="862" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 235 - 103, 77 Present (Roll no. 862).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-14T13:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="293"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Black lung"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debt limit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government employees' life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h923"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/14/1995--Passed House amended.
Prohibits a U.S. officer or employee from: (1) delaying the deposit or credit of any amount into any Federal fund, otherwise varying from normal procedures for making deposits or credits, or refraining from investments in public debt obligations of amounts in such fund if the purpose of such action or inaction is to not increase the amount of outstanding public debt obligations; and (2) disinvesting amounts in any such fund which are invested in public debt obligations if a purpose is to reduce the amount of outstanding public debt obligations. Prescribes that during any period for which cash benefits or administrative expenses would not be payable from a covered benefits fund because of an inability to issue further public debt obligations due to the applicable public debt limit, such obligations held by a covered benefits fund will only be sold or redeemed for payment of: (1) such benefits; or (2) administrative expenses and only if cash assets of such fund are not available from month to month for the purpose of making such payments. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to notify each House of the Congress and the Comptroller General not less than three days before an expected sale or redemption.</summary>
</bill>
