<bill session="105" type="h" number="4581" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dietary Supplement Fairness in Advertising Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to provide that certain advertisements of a dietary ingredient or dietary supplement shall not be considered to constitute an unfair or deceptive practice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1998-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1998-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1998-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1732"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Laboratory animals"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/1998--Introduced.
Dietary Supplement Fairness in Advertising Act - Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to declare that an advertisement for a dietary ingredient or supplement is not unfair competition or a deceptive act or practice if it is made consistent with: (1) certain provisions of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FDCA) relating to dietary supplements; and (2) the amendments made by this Act. Requires that, before the Federal Trade Commission determines whether an advertisement or advertiser is in FDCA compliance, the advertiser have the opportunity to consult directly with any scientific expert that advised the Commission concerning the applicability of FDCA provisions to the dietary ingredient or supplement. Declares that the inclusion, in an advertisement for a dietary ingredient or supplement meeting FDCA requirements, of truthful information that is not misleading concerning the usefulness or potential usefulness of an ingredient or supplement based on a study related to that ingredient or supplement is not unfair competition or a deceptive act or practice if that information identifies the type of study (in vitro, human, animal, epidemiological, or other) in the advertisement. Requires that, when the Commission makes a consent agreement regarding a complaint of unfair competition or a deceptive act or practice concerning the advertisement of a dietary ingredient or dietary supplement, the agreement cover only the ingredient or supplement class that is the subject of the complaint.</summary>
</bill>
