<bill session="106" type="h" number="3570" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Urban Wet Weather Priorities Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to establish nationally consistent requirements for controlling urban wet weather flows, to provide additional funds to municipalities to meet those requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400235"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2000-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2000-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban runoff"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2000--Introduced.
Urban Wet Weather Priorities Act of 2000 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require each permit, order, or decree issued pursuant to such Act for a discharge from a combined storm and sanitary sewer to conform to the Combined Sewer Overflow Control Policy signed by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency on April 11, 1994. Authorizes the Administrator, notwithstanding specified compliance schedules and permit limitations, to issue or execute a permit, order, or decree for discharges from such sewers that includes a schedule for compliance with a long-term control plan for a term of up to 15 years.(Sec. 4) Requires the Administrator to issue regulations which establish a program to control discharges from municipal sanitary sewer overflows. Includes within program elements a prohibition on avoidable overflows and provisions for remediation and treatment.Authorizes the Administrator to issue a permit for a discharge from a municipal separate sanitary sewer due to stormwater inflows or infiltration for a term of up to 15 years. Grants a compliance schedule of longer than 15 years if compliance within such period is not within the economic capability of the owner or operator.(Sec. 5) Requires implementation of stormwater best management practices to be the basis on which to determine compliance with the water quality and technology based requirements of the Act. Authorizes adjustments to plans and practices to be required to reduce the impacts of any municipal wet weather discharges associated with continuing water quality impairments that continue to occur after implementation of best management practices. Prohibits the Administrator from requiring compliance with numeric effluent limitations or fixed numeric pollutant load reductions in a permit for discharges from municipal separate storm sewers.(Sec. 6) Requires the Administrator to conduct municipal demonstration programs relating to watershed management of wet weather flows and the control of pollutants from separate storm sewer systems for determining controls that are cost-effective in reducing pollutants from urban stormwater runoff. Authorizes appropriations.Permits the Administrator to make grants to local government entities for: (1) planning, design, and construction of facilities to intercept, transport, or control flows from separate storm sewer systems and combined or sanitary sewers; (2) planning and implementation of urban wet weather control measures and management practices; and (3) development and implementation of urban watershed management plans. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
