<bill session="106" type="h" number="4603" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Deposit Insurance Increase Feasibility Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require studies and reports on the feasibility and potential impact of increasing the maximum amount of deposit insurance under the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and the Federal Credit Union Act from $100,000 to $200,000 per depositor or such other amount as may be determined to be appropriate, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400152"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2000--Introduced.
Deposit Insurance Increase Feasibility Act of 2000 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and the Federal Credit Union Act to direct the Federal banking agencies and the National Credit Union Administration Board to conduct feasibility studies for reports to Congress concerning: (1) increasing the maximum limits on deposit insurance per depositor; (2) potential benefits and risks to consumers and designated institutions as a result of such increase; (3) the impact such increase would have upon the reserve ratios of the Bank Insurance Fund and the Savings Association Insurance fund; and (4) the impact such increase would have upon potential changes in the semiannual assessment system, or in the rate of assessment.</summary>
</bill>
