<bill session="105" type="h" number="4654" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Asthma Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Education with increased authority with respect to asthma programs, and to provide for increased funding for such programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1998-10-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1847"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Asthma"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary school students"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1998--Introduced.
Asthma Act - Authorizes additional appropriations to the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute to carry out the National Asthma Education and Prevention Program for FY 1999 through 2003. Requires the coordinating committee established for such Program to report to the Congress on the scope of asthma in the United States, all Federal programs that carry out asthma-related activities, and any recommendations for strengthening and better coordinating such activities. Authorizes additional appropriations to the Centers for Disease Control to collaborate with the States to expand the scope of activities carried out to determine the incidence and prevalence of asthma, and prevent its health consequences. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Service to make grants to nonprofit private entities for projects to carry out community outreach activities regarding asthma information, education, and services. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to carry out a program to encourage the States to implement plans to assist children with respect to asthma, including matching grants to any State with a children's health insurance program under title XXI of the Social Security Act. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to local educational agencies for programs to carry out asthma-related activities for children at specified elementary and secondary schools located in communities with a significant number of low-income or underserved individuals. Authorizes appropriations. Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) hospitals should be encouraged to offer asthma-related education and training to asthma patients and their families upon such patients' discharge; (2) hospitals should, with respect to information on asthma, establish telephone services for patients and communicate with primary service providers; (3) managed care organizations should be encouraged to disseminate asthma clinical practice guidelines to providers, collect and maintain asthma data, and offer asthma-related education and training to asthma patients and their families; and (4) all Federal, State, and local asthma-related activities should promote Public Health Service guidelines and recommendations on asthma diagnosis and management, and be designed in consultation with relevant organizations and advocates representing asthma sufferers.</summary>
</bill>
