<bill session="107" type="h" number="5443" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Arizona Water Settlements Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Central Arizona Project Settlement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Gila River Indian Community Water Rights Settlement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Southern Arizona Water Rights Settlement Amendments Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for adjustments to the Central Arizona Project in Arizona, to authorize the Gila River Indian Community water rights settlement, to reauthorize and amend the Southern Arizona Water Rights Settlement Act of 1982, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400173"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2002-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="2002-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2002-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land subsidence"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water allocation (Policy)"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water supply engineering"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2002--Introduced.
Arizona Water Settlements Act - Central Arizona Project Settlement Act of 2002 - Sets forth general permissible uses of the Central Arizona Project (CAP) (a water reclamation project), including for domestic, municipal, fish and wildlife, and industrial purposes.Sets forth requirements for the reallocation of CAP non-Indian agricultural and uncontracted municipal and industrial priority water.Requires the Secretary of the Interior and the State of Arizona to develop a program to ensure the availability of a specified amount of agricultural priority water to Arizona Indian tribes during water shortages.Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms the Arizona Water Settlement Agreement.Allows excess funds from the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund to be used against annual payments for CAP owed by the Central Arizona Water Conservation District.Authorizes appropriations for compliance with specified biological opinions relating to impacts of CAP water delivery and storage.Gila River Indian Community Water Rights Settlement Act of 2002 - Approves the Gila River Indian Community Water Rights Settlement Agreement. Describes reallocated Community water rights and revises Community water delivery requirements. Provides for waiver and release of Community water rights claims against Arizona.Establishes the Gila River Indian Community Water OM&amp;R Trust Fund.Directs the Secretary to repair and remediate Community subsidence and related damage.Requires the Secretary to assist in reducing the total water demand for irrigation use in the upper valley of the Gila River.Rewrites the Southern Arizona Water Rights Settlement Act of 1982 as the Southern Arizona Water Rights Settlement Amendments Act of 2002. Sets forth water delivery requirements and construction obligations with respect to the San Xavier Indian Reservation and the Schuk Toak District as well as permissible water uses. Reauthorizes a cooperative fund for operation, maintenance, and repair costs associated with water delivery to the Reservation and District. Provides for waiver and release of water rights claims of the Tohono O'odham Nation (formerly the Papago Tribe). Sets forth requirements regarding after-acquired trust lands on behalf of the Nation. Reauthorizes a trust fund established for such Nation.</summary>
</bill>
