<bill session="104" type="h" number="3192" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Satellite Home Viewer Protection Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make amendments to section 119 of title 17 of the United States Code.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407899"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1996-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E486"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Copyright infringement"/>
    <term name="Direct broadcast satellites"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/28/1996--Introduced.
Satellite Home Viewer Protection Act of 1996 - Amends Federal copyright law to require a satellite carrier that makes secondary transmissions of a primary transmission by a network station, prior to providing broadcasting signals to a subscriber, to provide such subscriber with a written statement describing and quoting the network territorial restrictions related to such retransmission. Requires a satellite carrier, within 30 days of receipt of a challenge by a network station as to whether a subscriber is an unserved household within the predicted Grade B contour of such station, to: (1) inform the subscriber of the challenge; and (2) offer such subscriber the option of the satellite carrier conducting a measurement of the signal intensity of the subscriber's household to determine whether such household is an unserved household. Requires the satellite carrier to: (1) terminate service to such a household if its subscriber does not request a signal intensity measurement within 30 days of notification of the challenge from the satellite carrier; and (2) notify the network station that such service has been terminated. Outlines procedures to be taken after a signal measurement has been taken. Repeals a provision allowing a network station to challenge a subscriber outside the predicted Grade B contour of the network station. Authorizes satellite carriers and network broadcasters to negotiate the terms and conditions of the signal intensity measurement described under this Act. Requires a complete description of such agreement to be filed with the Register of Copyrights within 30 days after its execution. Provides for arbitration of such an agreement if the parties cannot agree to terms and conditions within 30 days after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
