<bill session="104" type="h" number="1605" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Adult Education and Family Literacy Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide assistance to States and local communities to improve adult education and family literacy, to help achieve the National Educational Goals for all citizens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="411677" joined="1995-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E990"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities. to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="797"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Career education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of Indians"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to adult education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Leadership"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Migrant education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School-to-work transition"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Amendment to the Adult Education Act Amendment Title II: Effective Date; Transition Title III: Repeals of Other Acts Adult Education and Family Literacy Reform Act of 1995 - Title I: Amendment to the Adult Education Act Amendment - Adult Education and Family Literacy Act - Amends the Adult Education Act (AEA) to revise and rename it the Adult Education and Family Literacy Act. Provides for a performance partnership with States and localities for provision of adult education and family literacy services. Consolidates the following current programs under a single funding mechanism of State grants for adult education and family literacy: (1) Library Literacy Program; (2) Workplace Literacy Partnerships; (3) Literacy Training for Homeless Adults; (4) Literacy Program for Prisoners; (5) Even Start; (6) State grants for adult education; (7) Gateway grants for adult education in public housing; (8) State literacy resource centers; (9) Literacy for Institutionalized Adults; (10) an education coordination program serving adults with basic education needs under the Job Training Partnership Act; (11) the National Institute for Literacy; and (12) aid for research, evaluation, and technical assistance. Authorizes appropriations for State grants for adult education and family literacy. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to reserve limited amounts for: (1) awards for national excellence; (2) national leadership activities and the National Institute for Literacy; and (3) Even Start family literacy programs for migratory families and Indian families. Establishes a new title I, Adult Education and Family Literacy, with provisions for: (1) program authority and priorities; (2) State grants for adult education and family literacy; (3) Even Start literacy programs and grants; (4) State administration requirements; (5) State plans; (6) applications from eligible applicants; (6) State- established performance goals and indicators and technical assistance for their establishment; (7) evaluation, improvement, and accountability; (8) allotments to States and reallotment; and (9) a study of statistics on the number of immigrants and limited English proficient individuals in each State, and a report on the feasibility and advisability of including such populations in the State allotment formula. Establishes a new title II, National Leadership, with provisions for: (1) national leadership activities; (2) awards for national excellence; and (3) the National Institute for Literacy. Revises the Institute's current duties, including establishment of a national electronic database and cooperation with the National Education Goals Panel. Sets forth provisions for the Institute's Advisory Board, adult education and literacy career fellowships, and biennial reports to the Congress and the Interagency Group (the Secretaries of Education, Labor, and Health and Human Services). Establishes a new title III, General Provisions, with provisions for State requests for and Federal granting of waivers of statutory or regulatory provisions under specified education and job training laws. Title II: Effective Date; Transition - Sets forth effective date and transition provisions. Title III: Repeals of Other Acts - Repeals: (1) provisions for the Even Start program under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965; (2) the National Literacy Act; and (3) provisions for grants to States for workplace and community transition training for incarcerated youth offenders under the Higher Education Act of 1965.</summary>
</bill>
