<bill session="104" type="h" number="2123" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Savings Association Insurance Fund Capitalization Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To accelerate capitalization of the Savings Association Insurance Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404139"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Bank reserves"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal home loan banks"/>
    <term name="Financing Corporation"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/1995--Introduced.
Savings Association Insurance Fund Capitalization Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to direct the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to impose a single additional special assessment upon certain members of the Savings Association Insurance Fund (SAIF) and the Bank Insurance Fund (BIF). Earmarks assessment proceeds for deposit into the SAIF. Eliminates specified required determinations by the FDIC Board of Directors to reduce the number of conditions under which unexpended Resolution Trust Corporation funds shall be provided to the SAIF. Declares that interest earned on any FDIC deposit insurance fund, except the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation Resolution Fund, shall be available for Financing Corporation carrying costs. Amends the Federal Home Loan Bank Act to require the Financing Corporation to impose assessments upon each member of any deposit insurance fund (currently only each SAIF member) to cover any interest shortfall in such fund. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to declare that any balance in a deposit insurance fund which exceeds its designated reserve shall be refunded. Requires the FDIC to merge the BIF and the SAIF into one deposit insurance fund after the SAIF first achieves its designated reserve ratio. Mandates that the Federal banking agencies jointly study and report to the Congress on: (1) the consolidation of national bank and savings association charters into a unified charter for depository institutions; and (2) the most feasible means to convert national banks and savings associations into depository institutions with a unified charter.</summary>
</bill>
