<bill session="107" type="h" number="577" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-02-05T18:50:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-02-05T18:50:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require any organization that is established for the purpose of raising funds for the creation of a Presidential archival depository to disclose the sources and amounts of any funds raised.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">A bill to amend title 44, United States Code, to require any organization that is established for the purpose of raising funds for creating, maintaining, expanding, or conducting activities at a Presidential archival depository or any facilities relating to a Presidential archival depository to disclose the sources and amounts of any funds raised, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400116"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2001-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="2001-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2001-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="2001-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="2001-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2001-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="2001-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2001-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2001-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2001-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E166"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Efficiency, Financial Management and Intergovernmental Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05T14:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Horn moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05T14:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H115-118" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05T14:19:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 577.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05T14:46:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05T18:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H122" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-02-05T18:50:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="6" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 392 - 3 (Roll no. 6).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H115-116" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05T18:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05T18:51:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-03-21">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-06-11">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman without amendment. With written report No. 107-160.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-06-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="413">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 413.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO16" subcommittee="Government Efficiency, Financial Management and Intergovernmental Relations" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Presidential libraries"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/2002--Passed House amended.
Requires any organization that is established for the purpose of raising funds for a presidential archival depository to annually submit to the National Archives and Records Administration, the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate information respecting every contributor who, with regard to: (1) a presidential archival depository of a President who currently holds the Office of President or for which the Archivist of the United States has not accepted, taken title to, or entered into an agreement to use any land or facility, gave the organization monetary or in-kind contributions totaling $200 or more; or (2) a depository of a President who no longer holds such Office and for which the Archivist has accepted, taken title to, or entered into an agreement to use any land or facility, gave the organization contributions totaling $5,000 or more. Requires the Archivist to make any such information available to the public through the Internet or a successor technology.Makes it unlawful for: (1) a contributor or an organization to submit false material information or omit material information concerning the contribution; or (2) a person to make or accept a contribution made in another person's name.</summary>
</bill>
