<bill session="108" type="h" number="4574" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Security Education Program Enhancement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title VIII of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1992, as amended, to revise the funding mechanism for scholarships, fellowships, and grants to institutions under the National Security Education Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2004-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2004-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2004-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="2004-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2004-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Select Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Area studies"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intelligence community staff"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2004--Introduced.
National Security Education Program Enhancement Act of 2004 - Amends the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1992 to require the Director of Central Intelligence (DCI) to transfer specified amounts to the Secretary of Education from Intelligence Community Management (ICM) appropriations to carry out national security education scholarship, fellowship, and grant programs. Revises post-education service obligations for such programs to: (1) allow a delay in the commencement of service obligations; (2) require only a one-year obligation for scholarship recipients; and (3) allow service obligations to be served with a variety of Federal agencies. Requires the DCI to transfer ICM funds to carry out grant programs for the National Flagship Language Initiative (an Initiative for achieving advanced proficiency in languages designated as critical to national security). Amends the David L. Boren National Security Education Act of 1991 to require students receiving training under the Initiative to enter into service agreements with the intelligence community element providing such training or reimburse the United States. Directs the Secretary of Defense to take steps to increase the number of qualified educational institutions receiving Initiative grants. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to award scholarships to U.S. citizens who are native speakers of languages designated as critical and not proficient at a professional level in English to enable them to pursue English studies. Requires recipients to enter into service agreements. Requires the DCI to transfer ICM funds to carry out such program.</summary>
</bill>
