<bill session="105" type="h" number="300" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airport Community Representation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to permit a State located within 5 miles of an airport in another State to participate in the process for approval of airport development projects at the airport.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1997-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1997-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Airport Community Representation Act - Amends Federal aviation law to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to approve the application for an airport development project grant located within five miles of a State boundary only if: (1) a policymaking committee has been established consisting of a specified number of members from each State located within five miles of the airport and the State in which the airport is located; and (2) the sponsor has fully considered the findings of the committee with respect to the project. Authorizes the Secretary to approve an eligible agency's application to impose a passenger facility fee to finance an airport-related project located within five miles of a State boundary only if, among other things, the eligible agency has complied with the requirements of this Act to the same extent as an airport development project sponsor is required to comply.</summary>
</bill>
