<bill session="104" type="h" number="3170" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Port Revitalization Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To dispose of contaminated dredged sediments in a more environmentally responsible manner, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1996-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1996-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="1996-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1996-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407226" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="407817" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1996-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1996-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1996-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1996-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E478"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dikes (Engineering)"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sedimentation"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/1996--Introduced.
Port Revitalization Act of 1996 - Provides that the cost of providing land-based and confined aquatic dredged material disposal facilities (facilities) associated with the construction, operation, and maintenance of any Federal navigation project for any harbor or other federally maintained waterway shall be considered a general navigation feature (thereby allowing the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund to be used to cover such dredging and disposal activities). Provides for the determination of the Federal share of the costs of operation and maintenance (O&amp;M) of such disposal facilities, as well as eligible O&amp;M costs related to such facilities. Prohibits the expenditure of such funds until the Secretary of the Army determines that such funds are not otherwise required to cover other eligible O&amp;M costs assigned to commercial navigation. (Sec. 3) Authorizes the Secretary, at the request of a non-Federal project sponsor, to provide additional capacity at a facility constructed by the Army beyond that which would be required for project purposes if the non-Federal sponsor agrees to pay all costs associated with the construction of the additional capacity. Allows such costs to be recovered through the assessment of user fees from third parties whose dredged materials are deposited in such facilities and who enter into agreements for the use of such facilities. Requires all user fees collected to be used by the Secretary for O&amp;M costs associated with the facility. Authorizes the Secretary to participate in the construction and use of facilities developed by non-Federal interests if such facilities are necessary to the construction or O&amp;M of a Federal navigation project. Authorizes the Secretary to pay disposal fees associated with the use of such facilities. Authorizes the Secretary to use management techniques to extend the useful life of all land-based and confined dredged material disposal facilities constructed and managed by the Secretary after the enactment of this Act. (Sec. 4) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to lower, effective on January 1, 1997, the tax imposed on the use of any U.S. port to 0.085 (currently, 0.125) percent of the value of the commercial cargo involved. Directs the Secretary, in each calendar year, to conduct an assessment of the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund to determine whether such tax should be reduced or increased to ensure that such Fund remains at a sufficient level to pay the eligible O&amp;M costs under this Act and the Water Resources Development Act of 1986. Requires an annual report from the Secretary to the Congress on such determination. (Sec. 5) Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1992 to add as a purpose of a pilot project under such Act the development of one or more sediment decontamination technologies on a pilot scale demonstrating a capacity of at least 500,000 cubic yards per year. Extends permanently the authorization of appropriations for such pilot project. Requires the Secretary and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to report annually to the Congress on the results of the project, including the development of decontamination technologies. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary to construct, operate, and maintain a dredged material containment facility for the Port of New York-New Jersey substantially in accordance with a final report of the Army Chief of Engineers. Requires the Secretary to maintain the facility for the public benefit after it has been filled to capacity with dredged material.</summary>
</bill>
