<bill session="104" type="hj" number="136" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-22">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Continuing Appropriation (fifth)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406863"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T13:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T13:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Livingston asked unanimous consent to discharge the Committee on Appropriations and to consider the bill with 20 minutes of debate, equally divided, and that the previous question on the bill be considered as ordered. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T13:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated previous order of the House.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15608-15616" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T13:45:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order the House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T14:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey asked unanimous consent to extend the time for debate for 6 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T14:05:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T14:27:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T14:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T14:28:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Obey motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T14:38:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T14:59:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 161 - 200 (Roll no. 885).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15616" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-12-22T15:00:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T15:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S19232" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1995-12-22" type="public" number="104-69">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-69.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Gay marriage"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homosexuality"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Lesbians"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Unmarried couples"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h926"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/22/1995--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Aid to Families with Dependent Children and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance Title II: District of Columbia Title III: Veterans Affairs Title I: Aid to Families with Dependent Children and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance - Makes continuing appropriations for FY 1996, at a level that is to be no more than the current level, for the following: (1) all projects and activities funded under the account heading "Family support payment to States" (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) under the Administration For Children and Families in the Department of Health and Human Services; (2) all projects and activities funded under the account heading "Payments to States for foster care and adoption assistance" (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) under the Administration for Children and Families in the Department of Health and Human Services; and (3) all administrative activities necessary to carry out the above projects and activities. (Sec. 106) Makes appropriations in this title available, unless otherwise provided for in this title or an applicable appropriations Act, until the first of the following events: (1) enactment of an appropriation for any project or activity of this title; (2) enactment of the applicable appropriations Act without any provision for such project or activity; or (3) January 3, 1996. Title II: District of Columbia - Makes continuing appropriations for FY 1996, at a level that is to be no more than the current level, for the District of Columbia. (Sec. 206) Makes appropriations in this title available, unless otherwise provided for in this title or an applicable appropriations Act, until the first of the following events: (1) enactment of an appropriation for any project or activity of this title; (2) enactment of the applicable appropriations Act without any provision for such project or activity; or (3) January 3, 1996. (Sec. 211) Provides that if funding is not provided for an ongoing project or the project's rate of operations is significantly reduced it may be continued at a minimal level. Defines minimal level as the current rate reduced by 25 percent. (Sec. 216) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated under this title to implement any system of registration of unmarried cohabiting couples, whether homosexual, lesbian, or heterosexual. Title III: Veterans Affairs - Makes continuing appropriations, in any case during FY 1996 in which appropriations are not otherwise available for the programs and activities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to ensure payment of the following: (1) existing veterans' benefits; and (2) Veterans Health Administration contractors when due for services provided that relate directly to patient health and safety. Defines existing benefits as those that have been adjudicated and authorized for payment as of: (1) December 15, 1995; or (2) if appropriations for such benefits are available (other than as provided for above) after December 15, 1995, the last day on which appropriations for payment of such benefits are available. Makes the above provisions of this title ineffective on January 3, 1996.</summary>
</bill>
