<bill session="106" type="h" number="723" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Making Affordable Prescriptions Available for Seniors Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program of pharmacy assistance fee for elderly persons who have no health insurance coverage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1999-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the aged"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medigap"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/1999--Introduced.
Making Affordable Prescriptions Available for Seniors Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish a program of pharmacy assistance for persons at least 65 years old with no pharmacy benefits from an insurance policy supplemental to title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act or coverage from any third party payor, and whose income is under a specified level. Allows an annual enrollment fee (of not over $15) and deductibles. Mandates copayments not over $10 per prescription. Prohibits approval of an application under provisions of the Public Health Service Act relating to biological products or provisions of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act relating to new drugs if the drug manufacturer submits with the application the results of research carried out by the National Institutes of Health, or under an agreement under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980, until the manufacturer agrees to pay to the Secretary of Health and Human Services seven percent of the gross sales receipts.</summary>
</bill>
