<bill session="108" type="hr" number="846" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-11-20T10:57:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-11-20T10:57:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09T09:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 108-772, by Mr. Sessions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-10-09T09:36:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="251">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 251.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T09:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10081-10085, H10086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T09:04:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 846.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T09:45:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10085" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T09:45:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At conclusion of debate on H. Res. 846 the chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hastings (FL) objected to the vote based on the absence of a quorum and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the resolution until later in the legislative day. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2004-11-20T10:57:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="538" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 159 (Roll no. 538).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10081" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T10:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2004--Passed House without amendment.
Waives a specified requirement of rule XIII to provide for consideration or disposition of: (1) a bill or joint resolution making continuing appropriations for FY 2005, an amendment thereto, or a conference report thereon; or (2) a bill or joint resolution making general appropriations for such fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
