<bill session="105" type="h" number="3437" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tobacco Market Transition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide market transition assistance for quota holders, active tobacco producers, and tobacco-growing counties, to authorize a private Tobacco Production Control Corporation and tobacco loan associations to control the production and marketing and ensure the quality of tobacco in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="1998-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400609" joined="1998-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Risk Management and Specialty Crops.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG24" subcommittee="Risk Management and Specialty Crops" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural diversification"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Farm production quotas"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to rural areas"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
    <term name="Tobacco settlement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Tobacco Community Revitalization Trust Fund Title II: Tobacco Market Transition Assistance Title III: Establishment of Private Tobacco Production Adjustment and Quality Assurance Programs Tobacco Market Transition Act - Title I: Tobacco Community Revitalization Trust Fund - Establishes in the Treasury the Tobacco Community Revitalization Trust Fund which shall make expenditures available for specified compensation, transition, and related assistance to tobacco producers. Authorizes appropriations (as repayable advances). Title II: Tobacco Market Transition Assistance - Directs the Tobacco Production Control Corporation (Corporation) (established by this Act) to temporarily: (1) compensate eligible quota tobacco holders for loss of tobacco quota asset value; and (2) make transition payments to eligible active tobacco producers. Sets forth payment provisions. (Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) forgive specified loans to tobacco loan associations; and (2) transfer to such associations appropriate loan inventory titles and no net cost tobacco funds. (Sec. 204) Directs the Corporation to provide grants to eligible political subdivisions for tobacco community economic development activities. (Sec. 205) Directs the Corporation to make transition payments to tobacco warehousemen and consider making payments to certain other persons adversely affected by the dismantling of the Federal tobacco program or tobacco settlement legislation. (Sec. 206) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to treat amounts received for loss of quota asset value as long-term capital gain income and active producer transition payments as regular income unless: (1) used for qualified debt repayment; or (2) transferred to a tobacco farmer individual retirement account (as provided for by this Act). Title III: Establishment of Private Tobacco Production Adjustment and Quality Assurance Program - Establishes the Tobacco Production Control Corporation which shall: (1) establish a licensing system for tobacco production and marketing; and (2) enter into agrements with tobacco loan associations to administer licensing, price support, and marketing activities. (Sec. 303) Sets forth tobacco price support levels and penalty provisions.</summary>
</bill>
