<bill session="104" type="h" number="2069" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To help avoid the costs and disruptions of agency shutdowns when there is a lapse in appropriations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1995-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government spending"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/1995--Introduced.
Amends Federal law to permit an officer or employee of the U.S. or District of Columbia government to obligate as may be necessary during a lapse in appropriations to continue any project or activity funded in the preceding fiscal year if any appropriation bill for a fiscal year is not enacted into law prior to the beginning of such fiscal year. Specifies that obligations for a project or activity be at a rate of operations not exceeding the lesser of: (1) the rate of operations provided for in the regular appropriation Act, including a continuing resolution; or (2) in the absence of such an Act, the rate of operations provided for such project or activity in the preceding fiscal year. Requires that the authority to obligate be made available for the period beginning with the first day of such fiscal year and ending with the earlier of: (1) the enactment date of the applicable regular appropriation bill for such fiscal year, regardless of whether such law provides for such project or activity; or (2) the last day of such fiscal year. Sets forth provisions concerning the authority to obligate for a project or an activity during a fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
