<bill session="105" type="h" number="2051" updated="2012-11-01T22:48:27-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Voice Campaign Finance Reform Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to promote increased disclosure of spending on campaigns for election for Federal office, improve the ability of the Federal Election Commission to enforce the laws governing the financing of such campaigns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400138"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-06-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1327)</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1327"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSIF" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" name="House Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>06/25/1997--Introduced.
Public Voice Campaign Finance Reform Act of 1997 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to provide for: (1) intermediaries and conduits to report on bundled contributions in the same time and manner as a political committee which is not an authorized committee of the candidate; (2) certain communications to be treated as independent expenditures; and (3) mandatory electronic filing for persons reporting contributions, expenditures, or disbursements in an amount exceeding a threshold established by the Federal Election Commission. (Sec. 3) Directs the Commission to require each political committee filing a report to include with the report a filing fee when the amount of contributions, expenditures, or disbursements covered by the report exceeds a threshold established by the Commission. Revises the standard for referral of certain violations to the Attorney General. Requires the Commission to conduct random audits of the reports of political committees. (Sec. 4) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for reduced broadcast media rates for candidates. (Sec. 5) Amends FECA to set forth restrictions on the use of non-Federal funds. (Sec. 6) Revises requirements for the composition of the Commission and terms of Commissioners and replaces them with new requirements, including one that Commissioners serve no more than a single term.</summary>
</bill>
