<bill session="108" type="h" number="1888" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require public disclosure of noncompetitive contracting for the reconstruction of the infrastructure of Iraq, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2003-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2003--Introduced.
Requires the head of a U.S. executive agency that enters into a contract for the repair, maintenance, or construction of infrastructure in Iraq without full and open competition to publish in the Federal Register or Commerce Business Daily and otherwise make available to the public within 30 days after the contract is entered into: (1) the amount of the contract; (2) a brief description of its scope; (3) a discussion of how the agency identified, and solicited offers from, potential contractors to perform the contract, together with a list of the potential contractors that were issued solicitations for the offers; and (4) the justification and approval documents on which was based the determination to use procedures other than procedures that provide for full and open competition. Authorizes an agency head to: (1) withhold from such publication and disclosure any document classified for restricted access in accordance with an Executive order in the interest of national defense or foreign policy; and (2) redact any part so classified in a document not so classified before publication and disclosure of the document. Requires the agency head to make available an unredacted version of such a document to the chairman and ranking member of specified congressional committees.</summary>
</bill>
