<bill session="105" type="h" number="3467" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">California Spotted Owl Interim Protection Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To address the protection of the California spotted owl and its habitat in the Sierran Province of Region 5 of the Forest Service through the use of an interim management direction consistent with the requirements of existing public land management and environmental laws and by setting a date certain for the completion of a final environmental impact statement for the management of the California spotted owl.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409228" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="410084" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1998-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Endangered animals"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Owls"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/1998--Introduced.
California Spotted Owl Interim Protection Act of 1998 - Directs the U.S. Forest Service: (1) within six months, to begin using the preferred alternative contained in the revised version of the draft environmental impact statement (EIS) prepared by the Service in 1996 for the California spotted owl as its interim management direction for the owl in the ten national forests in the Sierran Province of Region 5 of the Service; and (2) to use such preferred alternative, modified as required below, as its interim management direction until such time as a final EIS and record of decision are released. Directs the Service: (1) before implementation of the preferred alternative, to evaluate and modify the assessment regarding fire and fuels reduction contained in the revised draft EIS to address the concerns raised in the December 1997 final report of the panel of scientists that was appointed by the Secretary of Agriculture to review the revised draft EIS; (2) within 18 months, to complete a final EIS and record of decision; and (3) within 12 months, to issue a proposed final EIS for public comment and review. Specifies that: (1) nothing in this Act shall preclude the Service from developing a long-term conservation strategy for the Sierra Nevada Mountains; and (2) the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report every six months describing the Service's progress toward completion of the final EIS within the specified time periods.</summary>
</bill>
