<bill session="113" type="h" number="2368" updated="2013-07-17T16:07:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Grants for Renewable Energy Education for the Nation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GREEN Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide support to develop career and technical education programs of study and facilities in the areas of renewable energy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/13/2013--Introduced.
Grants for Renewable Energy Education for the Nation Act or GREEN Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to partnerships of local educational agencies (LEAs), postsecondary institutions, and clean and renewable energy industry representatives to develop programs of study focused on emerging careers and jobs in the fields of clean and renewable energy. Requires a priority be given to grant applications that: (1) use online learning or other innovative methods to deliver a program of study to individuals outside the partnership, and (2) focus on low-performing students and special populations. Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive grants to LEAs and postsecondary institutions to promote development of career and technical educational facilities that are energy efficient and use renewable energy practices.</summary>
</bill>
