<bill session="106" type="h" number="3382" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Justice for Victims of Terrorism Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the enforcement of certain anti-terrorism judgments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400584" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1999-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="h" number="3485"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1796"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Alien property"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hostages"/>
    <term name="Immunities of foreign states"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International claims"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Sabotage"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Trading with the enemy"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/1999--Introduced.
Justice for Victims of Terrorism Act - Amends the Federal judicial code to revise the definition of "agency or instrumentality of a foreign state" for purposes of provisions regarding exceptions to: (1) the jurisdictional immunity of a foreign state where money damages are sought against a foreign state for personal injury or death that was caused by an act of torture, extrajudicial killing, aircraft sabotage, hostage taking, or the provision of material support or resources for such an act (jurisdictional provisions); and (2) the immunity from attachment or execution where the judgment relates to a claim for which the foreign state is not immune (attachment provisions).Directs that moneys due from or payable by the United States to any State against which a judgment is pending under jurisdictional provisions be subject to attachment and execution in like manner and to the same extent as if the United States were a private person.Authorizes the President, upon determining on an asset-by-asset basis that a waiver is necessary in the national security interest, to waive attachment provisions in connection with (and prior to the enforcement of) any judicial order directing attachment in aid of execution or execution against the premises of a foreign diplomatic mission to the United States, or any funds held by or in the name of such foreign diplomatic mission determined by the President to be necessary to satisfy actual operating expenses of such foreign diplomatic mission. Specifies that a waiver shall not apply to the proceeds of: (1) such use if the premises of a foreign diplomatic mission has been used for any non-diplomatic purpose (including use as rental property); or (2) a sale or transfer if any asset of a foreign diplomatic mission is sold or otherwise transferred for value to a third party. Treats all assets of any agency or instrumentality of a foreign state as assets of that foreign state.</summary>
</bill>
