<bill session="106" type="h" number="2381" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protection of United States Troops From Foreign Prosecution Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit United States economic assistance for countries that ratify the treaty known as the Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court, a treaty that provides for the establishment of an International Criminal Court, an illegal and illegitimate institution that violates the principles of self-government and popular sovereignty, as well as accepted norms of international law, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1999-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1999-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1999-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1999-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1999-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/1999--Introduced.
Protection of United States Troops From Foreign Prosecution Act of 1999 - Prohibits any Federal agency from: (1) taking any action that has the effect of implementing the provisions of the Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court (ICC Treaty) (adopted in Rome, Italy, on July 17, 1998, by the United Nations Conference of Plenipotentiaries on the Establishment of an International Criminal Court); (2) providing funding or other support for the International Criminal Court; or (3) transferring any person to the Court.Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should inform both allies and adversaries of the United States that ratification of the ICC Treaty will be considered an unfriendly act directed at the United States, and will adversely affect bilateral relations between the United States and that country.Amends the Foreign Relations Act of 1961 to prohibit U.S. economic assistance to any country that ratifies the ICC Treaty.Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should instruct the U.S. representative to the United Nations (UN) to veto any attempt by the UN Security Council to refer a matter to the Court for investigation.</summary>
</bill>
