<bill session="104" type="h" number="3892" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">D'Oench Duhme Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify treatment of certain claims and defenses against an insured depository institution under receivership by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410887"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="648"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Bank fraud"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/1996--Introduced.
D'Oench Duhme Reform Act - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Act to revise its D'Oench Duhme provisions which render unenforceable against the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) in its capacity as receiver of an insured depository institution any secret side agreements not recorded in the institution's records. Declares that an agreement against the interests of the FDIC in its capacity as receiver is not enforceable against it unless the agreement is in writing and was executed by the insured depository institution in the ordinary course of business. Declares that no court may prohibit the adjudication of specified types of claims and defenses against the FDIC in its capacity as receiver of an insured depository institution, including certain intentional tort claims and other claims that do not relate to specific assets acquired by the FDIC. Declares that, except as otherwise provided by Federal or State law, the FDIC may not defeat a claim related to an asset by demonstrating that it acquired the asset as a holder in due course without actual knowledge of the claim, unless it also demonstrates that the asset was not acquired upon its appointment as conservator or receiver or as part of a purchase and assumption transaction. Excepts from this provision vendor agreements for the sale or purchase of goods or services delivered to an insured depository institution before the appointment of a receiver for such institution.</summary>
</bill>
