<bill session="108" type="h" number="4112" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Death Care Disclosure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish consumer protections, including disclosure requirements, relating to funeral service contracts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400136"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Funeral industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telemarketing"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Welfare recipients"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2004--Introduced.
Federal Death Care Disclosure Act - Classifies as deceptive trade practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act funeral provider practices that: (1) fail to make timely price disclosures regarding funeral goods and services; (2) fail to give an itemized written statement to a purchaser of funeral goods or services at the conclusion of the discussion related to such goods or services and prior to providing any services beyond taking possession of a deceased human body for embalming; (3) make specified misrepresentations concerning funeral goods and services; (4) condition the furnishing of goods and services upon the purchase of other goods and services; (5) provide embalming services without prior approval (except in specified circumstances); (6) involve unsolicited telephone offers or door-to-door direct offers to sell funeral goods or services, crematory services, interment rights, or other cemetery and memorialization goods or services; (7) fail to comply with specified requirements governing cash advance items; and (8) fail to comply with specified prepaid contract requirements. Directs the Commission to establish minimum standards concerning State mandated consumer disclosures in prepaid contracts for the purchase of funeral, cemetery, or crematory goods or services. Establishes a private right of action for persons injured by a violation of this Act. Exempts States with a comparable or greater level of consumer protection from application of this Act or related regulations.</summary>
</bill>
