<bill session="106" type="h" number="2443" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Targeted Gun Dealer Enforcement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, relating to the regulation of firearms dealers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="1999-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1999-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1999-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1306"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/1999--Introduced.
Targeted Gun Dealer Enforcement Act of 1999 - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to prohibit, and set penalties for, making certain false or fictitious statements with respect to the identity of the person purchasing or attempting to purchase a firearm or ammunition. Prohibits a licensed dealer from transferring a firearm without notifying the transferee whether applicable State law requires persons to be licensed to carry concealed firearms in the State or prohibits the carrying of concealed firearms in the State. Rewrites Brady Act provisions to allow the Secretary of the Treasury to suspend or revoke a license and to assess and collect a civil penalty of up to $10,000 per violation, subject to specified requirements and procedures. Directs the Secretary to designate a licensed dealer as a "high-volume crime gun dealer": (1) upon determining that the dealer sold, delivered, or otherwise transferred to one or more unlicensed persons at least 25 firearms that, during the preceding calendar year, were used during the commission or attempted commission of a criminal offense under, or were possessed in violation of, Federal, State, or local law; or (2) immediately upon the expiration date of a suspension of that dealer's license for a willful violation that involved one or more firearms that were subsequently used during the commission or attempted commission of a criminal offense under Federal, State, or local law. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) the effective period of such designation; (2) requirements for designation notification by the Secretary to the appropriate U.S. attorney's office, appropriate State and local law enforcement agencies, and State and local agencies responsible for issuing business licenses in the jurisdiction; (3) dealer reporting and record keeping requirements regarding the transfer of a handgun; (4) inspection of such dealer at any time without a showing of reasonable cause or a warrant for purposes of determining compliance with requirements of this Act; (5) handgun transfer record keeping requirements for local police departments; (6) time requirements for license renewal decisions; and (7) suspension of the license of a high-volume crime gun dealer for violations. Sets penalties for failure to comply with requirements of this Act. (Sec. 3) Amends the Brady Act to authorize a successor licensee to retain the records of a discontinued firearms or ammunition business or submit them to the Secretary. Authorizes the Secretary to receive and centralize any information or records submitted and to maintain such information or records in whatever manner will enable their most efficient use in law enforcement investigations. Directs the Secretary to retain a record of each firearms trace conducted by the Secretary unless the Secretary determines that there is a valid law enforcement reason not to retain the record. Requires a licensed importer, manufacturer, and dealer to submit to the Secretary a monthly report of each firearm received from an unlicensed person, excluding any identifying information relating to the transferor or any subsequent purchaser. (Sec. 4) Prohibits, and sets penalties for, knowingly transferring a firearm having reasonable cause to believe that it will be used to commit a crime of violence or drug trafficking crime. Increases penalties for trafficking in firearms with obliterated serial numbers. (Sec. 5) Directs the United States Sentencing Commission to amend the Federal sentencing guidelines to reflect the amendments made by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
