<bill session="106" type="h" number="4883" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Fuel Reliability Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize and direct the maintenance of a reliable and economic uranium enrichment, conversion, and mining industry, to assure the nuclear non-proliferation objects of the United States, to provide for the deployment of advanced uranium enrichment technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400390"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400519" joined="2000-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-07-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6090"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6440"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate debt"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Corporate liquidations"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Mining engineering"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear industry"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear research"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Patent licenses"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2000--Introduced.
The Nuclear Fuel Reliability Act of 2000 - Instructs the chief executive (Transition Manager) responsible for the daily operations of the United States Enrichment Enterprise (USEE), and the Secretary of Energy to submit a plan to the President for the total reacquisition of USEC Inc. (United States Enrichment Corporation). Mandates congressional review of the reacquisition plan.Authorizes the United States to take USEC Inc., upon plan implementation. Authorizes sums for deposit into the United States Enrichment Enterprise Fund in order to effectuate Federal ownership.Authorizes the Secretary of Energy to terminate the Executive Agent Agreement between the United States and USEC, Inc. after USEE has been established. Sets forth implementation and transition guidelines.Establishes the United States Enrichment Enterprise as a Federal agency to: (1) operate as a self-financing business enterprise; (2) maintain a reliable, economical domestic source of uranium mining, enrichment, and conversion services; (3) lease Department of Energy uranium enrichment facilities and maintain continued operations of certain gaseous diffusion plant; (4) sell uranium and conversion services so as not to cause a material adverse impact upon domestic conversion or mining industries; (5) sell enriched uranium and related services to the Department of Energy to maintain a strategic reserve of low enriched uranium; (6) conduct research and development to deploy alternative uranium enrichment technologies; and (7) continue to meet objectives of ensuring the nation's common defense and security.Amends the USEC Privatization Act to subject the conversion component of the uranium hexaflouride delivered to the Russian Executive Agent to the restrictions applicable to equivalent amounts of uranium. Prescribes procedural guidelines for uranium transfers and sales.Authorizes the Department of Energy (DOE) to contract with USEE to operate gaseous diffusion plants on hot standby if a gaseous diffusion plant is closed.Directs DOE to: (1) assess the long term needs of the domestic nuclear utility industry with respect to low enriched uranium; and (2) establish adequate strategic reserves to assure reliable supply (100 percent of U.S. demand and 100 percent of U.S. obligations to any other country under the Nuclear Nonproliferation Act of 1978) in the event a uranium enrichment plant is closed and the United States is dependent upon only one gaseous diffusion plant.Authorizes DOE to contract with USEE to purchase at cost the separative work unit (SWU, or the level of effort required to increase the concentration of U-235 in natural uranium) delivered under the Agreement between Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Russian Federation Concerning the Disposition of Highly Enriched Uranium Extracted from Nuclear Weapons, dated February 18, 1993 (Russian HEU Agreement).</summary>
</bill>
