<bill session="104" type="h" number="4292" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Displaced Worker Retraining Act of 1993</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a comprehensive program of adjustment assistance to workers displaced as a result of any program, project, or activity carried out under Federal law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400572"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment subsidies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Grants to States to Provide Worker Adjustment Assistance Benefits to Eligible Displaced Workers Title II: Worker Adjustment Assistance Benefits Subtitle A: Income Support Subtitle B: Wage Supplements Subtitle C: Training Subtitle D: Rapid Response Assistance, Basic Readjustment Services, Relocation Allowances, and Job Search Allowances Title III: General Provisions Displaced Worker Retraining Act of 1993 (sic) - Establishes a comprehensive program of adjustment assistance to workers displaced as a result of any program, project, or activity carried out under Federal law. Authorizes appropriations. Title I: Grants to States to Provide Worker Adjustment Assistance Benefits to Eligible Displaced Workers - Directs the Secretary of Labor to make grants to applicant States to provide worker adjustment assistance benefits to eligible dislocated workers. Title II: Worker Adjustment Assistance Benefits - Subtitle A: Income Support - Sets forth dislocated worker eligibility conditions. Requires a dislocated worker to be actively seeking employment or enrolled in training to be eligible for income support. Allows those eligible for income support to apply for training under subtitle C. (Sec. 212) Provides for weekly income support, including amount and duration, income support factors, additional weeks, adjustment of amount, wage supplement offsets, and application of State laws. Subtitle B: Wage Supplements - Provides for weekly wage supplements, in specified amounts for a maximum of 156 weeks, for eligible displaced workers. Makes dislocated workers who are eligible for such wage supplements also eligible to apply for part-time training under subtitle C. Requires offset of such wage supplement weeks by any income support weeks received under subtitle A. Subtitle C: Training - Sets forth conditions for State approval of training for displaced workers. Requires priority for training for occupations and industries that utilize new technologies. Sets forth requirements relating to State and Federal payment of training costs, as well as training costs paid from other sources. (Sec. 232) Lists types of training programs that may be approved. Sets certain restrictions on State approval. Makes 156 weeks of such training the maximum number which a dislocated worker may receive. Allows a State to authorize specified limited forms of supplemental assistance during such training. (Sec. 233) Directs a State to pay costs of any approved on-the-job training of a displaced worker, but only if certain conditions are met, such as nondisplacement of current workers, nonimpairment of collective bargaining agreements, and certification of continued employment for the trained worker. (Sec. 235) Prohibits declaring a displaced worker ineligible for State or Federal unemployment insurance or benefits under this Act because that individual is in or is entering approved training. Subtitle D: Rapid Response Assistance, Basic Readjustment Services, Relocation Allowances, and Job Search Allowances - Entitles to 13 weeks of rapid response assistance and 156 weeks of basic readjustment services: (1) any displaced worker, whether or not eligible for subtitle A or B benefits; or (2) any individual who has received notice of impending total or partial separation from employment and who had at least ten weeks of employment during the 52 weeks preceding such notice. Provides for State delivery of rapid response assistance, with oversight by the Secretary. (Sec. 242) Allows a displaced worker, whether or not eligible for subtitle A or B benefits, to apply to the State for: (1) a relocation allowance; and (2) a job search allowance. Sets forth conditions for approval of such allowances. Title III: General Provisions - Sets forth general provisions relating to fraud and recovery of overpayments, penalties, subpoena power, and regulations.</summary>
</bill>
