<bill session="105" type="h" number="3404" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require additional public education, outreach, and participation with respect to the disposal of napalm and certain other materials owned or controlled by the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400417"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1998-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1998-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Military Readiness" name="House National Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Napalm"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Plastics"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/1998--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Defense to inform the public through an outreach program in communities near a disposal site (within ten miles) and along the disposal shipment route no later than 120 days before the disposal of: (1) napalm; (2) any material that includes polystyrene, gasoline, and benzene; (3) ammunition larger than small- caliber ammunition; or (4) explosives. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish near the disposal site an outreach office (staffed by Department of Defense personnel) and information repositories; (2) provide a mobile outreach unit to service communities near the site; and (3) establish a Citizens' Advisory Committee to study and comment on disposal issues of concern to the community. Requires the Secretary, before carrying out a disposal project, to certify the training adequacy and capabilities of entities that are likely to respond to an emergency. Directs the Secretary to obtain from the: (1) Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) a certification that the health and welfare of the public and of workers are protected near the site and along the route; and (2) Occupational Safety and Health Administration a certification that the site is safe for disposal workers and that such workers are properly trained for such work. Requires the Secretary, after soliciting appropriate comments, to complete an environmental impact statement for any such disposal project. Directs the Secretary to provide funds to the HHS Secretary to monitor, collect, and review air, soil, and water samples near the site and along the route to ensure the protection during the project of human health and the environment. Requires the Secretary, before carrying out any such project, to study and test alternative technologies for the disposal. Directs the Secretary to obtain scientific and technical advice regarding such disposals from the National Academy of Sciences and to provide funds to the Academy to investigate the safety and performance of any disposal project. Requires the Secretary, for any such project, to develop a master implementation plan, with weekly plan updates, to be made available to the public through the information repositories required under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
