<bill session="106" type="h" number="5391" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Moment of Remembrance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the White House Commission on the National Moment of Remembrance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Emblems"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Memorial Day"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="White House conferences"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/2000--Introduced.
National Moment of Remembrance Act - Establishes a White House Commission on the National Moment of Remembrance to provide national coordination for, and encourage national, State, local, and tribal participation in, the commemoration of Memorial Day and the National Moment of Remembrance.Requires the Director of the Committee Management Secretariat of the General Services Administration to appoint an individual as Executive Director and White House Liaison to: (1) serve as a liaison between the Commission and the President; and (2) coordinate the Commission's and the President's efforts on all matters relating to this Act, including matters relating to the National Moment of Remembrance.Establishes as an agency of the Commission the Moment of Remembrance Alliance to assist the Commission, including by: (1) planning, organizing, and implementing an annual White House Conference on the National Moment of Remembrance and other similar events; (2) promoting the observance of Memorial Day and the National Moment of Remembrance; and (3) establishing incentives for Federal, State, and local governments and private entities to sponsor and participate in programs initiated by the Commission or the Alliance.</summary>
</bill>
