<bill session="105" type="h" number="4788" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Automobile Lease Advertising Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Consumer Credit Protection Act to enhance the advertising of the terms and costs of consumer automobile leases, to permit consumer comparison of advertised lease offerings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2091-2093"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/1998--Introduced.
Consumer Automobile Lease Advertising Act of 1998 - Amends the Consumer Credit Protection Act to increase from $25,000 to $50,000 the maximum amount of a contractual obligation of a consumer lease to which the Act applies. Mandates annual adjustment of such limit based upon changes reported in the Consumer Price Index by the Department of Labor. Prescribes additional lease advertising disclosure requirements for advertising media, including radio and television broadcasting and toll-free telephones. Prohibits specified automobile lease advertising practices, including: (1) statements that no downpayment is required when the lessor actually requires certain payments upon lease initiation; and (2) lease terms that are available only to selected customers. Mandates that: (1) advertised lease payment amounts for automobiles be calculated on the basis of a formula prescribed by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Board), and be accompanied by specified time and mileage disclosures; and (2) automobile dealerships place additional disclosures within a prominent location in the dealership. Empowers the Federal Trade Commission to enforce this Act. Amends the Truth in Lending Act to set forth a maximum civil penalty for noncompliance with such Act.</summary>
</bill>
