<bill session="106" type="h" number="5320" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare+Choice Rescue Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to revise and improve the Medicare+Choice Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400226"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Medigap"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2000--Introduced.
Medicare+Choice Rescue Act of 2000 - Amends part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA), with respect to payments to Medicare+Choice organizations, to: (1) increase the national per capita Medicare+Choice growth percentage in 2001 and 2002; (2) eliminate the reduction in Medicare+Choice payment rates by budget neutrality adjustments; (3) establish a payment floor for Medicare+Choice plans, as well as an additional floor for an annual increase in Medicare+Choice capitation rates; and (4) apply a budget neutrality principle to the new Medicare+Choice risk adjustment methodology.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to correct for misestimates in the national per capita Medicare+Choice growth rate by providing for an increase by 3.6 percent in the amount of payment otherwise applicable to Medicare+Choice organizations offering Medicare+Choice plans in 2001. Limits retroactive adjustments.Amends Medicare part C to provide for: (1) continuous open enrollment and disenrollment under Medicare+Choice and Medicare supplemental policy (Medigap) provisions on coverage election periods; and (2) variations in premiums and benefits under Medicare+Choice within counties.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide that risk-adjustment methodology under Medicare+Choice, insofar as it makes adjustments to capitation rates for health status, shall not only apply to ten percent of 1/12 of the annual Medicare+Choice capitation rate in the case of an eligible individual who is institutionalized until the first year in which the Secretary implements a modification of such methodology based on health status so that such methodology includes medical diagnostic factors from all provider settings (including hospital and nursing facility settings).</summary>
</bill>
