<bill session="104" type="h" number="1288" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Interstate Transportation of Municipal Waste Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to permit Governors to limit the disposal of out-of-State solid waste in their States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="404996" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="408092" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="1995-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E138"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="589"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/1995--Introduced.
Interstate Transportation of Municipal Waste Act of 1995 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize a State Governor, if requested by an affected local government, to prohibit the disposal of out-of-State municipal waste in: (1) any landfill or incinerator subject to the jurisdiction of the Governor or the local government; and (2) landfill cells that do not meet the State's design and location standards and leachate collection and groundwater monitoring requirements for new landfills. Permits such Governors, without the request of such entities, to limit the quantity of out-of-State municipal waste received for disposal, or the disposal of such waste, at landfills covered by exceptions under this Act. Authorizes States to ban imports from large exporting States if the volumes of municipal solid waste exported by such States did not meet reduction targets. Prohibits discrimination against any particular landfill and against shipments of out-of-State waste on the basis of State of origin. Exempts from a Governor's authority to prohibit the disposal of out-of-State waste: (1) landfills that received documented shipments of such waste in 1993 and are in compliance with State laws relating to design and location standards, leachate collection, groundwater monitoring, and financial assurance for closure and post-closure and corrective action; (2) proposed landfills that, prior to January 1, 1993, received an authorization as part of a host community agreement from the affected local government to receive municipal waste generated out-of-State and a State notice of decision to grant a construction permit; or (3) incinerators that received documented shipments of such waste during 1993 and are in compliance with performance standards under the Clean Air Act and State laws relating to facility design and operations. Authorizes States to deny permits for the construction or operation of a new landfill or incinerator or a major modification of an existing landfill or incinerator if: (1) the State has approved a State or local comprehensive solid waste management plan developed under Federal or State law; and (2) the denial is based on the State's determination that there is not a local or regional need of the landfill or incinerator in the State.</summary>
</bill>
