<bill session="105" type="h" number="153" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Metropolitan Airport Noise Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to exempt noise and access restrictions on aircraft operations to and from metropolitan airports from certain Federal review and approval requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Metropolitan Airport Noise Reduction Act - Amends Federal transportation law to define "nonmetropolitan airport" to mean an airport serving an area with a population of less than one million individuals. Applies the program for the review of airport noise and access restrictions to nonmetropolitan airports only. Requires the application for a waiver of compliance with Stage 3 noise levels to contain assurances that operations of aircraft which do not so comply will not be concentrated at one or more airports. Prohibits an airport noise or access restriction on the operation of Stage 2 or Stage 3 aircraft to or from a metropolitan or nonmetropolitan airport in effect on November 5, 1990, from being modified, superseded, or repealed to make such restriction less stringent.</summary>
</bill>
