<bill session="104" type="h" number="3408" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to revise the provisions of law relating to payment of retired pay of retired members of the Armed Forces to former spouses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400608"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Divorcees"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Post exchanges"/>
    <term name="Separation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/1996--Introduced.
Requires that the disposable retired pay of a member or former member of the armed forces to whom a final decree of divorce, dissolution, annulment, or legal separation is issued before the date that such member begins to receive retired pay, for purposes of determining the amount of such payments to the former spouse, shall be computed based on the pay grade and length of service of the member while married to the former spouse. Requires the former spouse to make application for his or her share of such retired pay within one year from the date of the final decree. Amends the Uniformed Services Former Spouses' Protection Act to require the Secretary of Defense to prescribe regulations to provide that a former spouse of a member of the armed forces loses commissary and exchange privileges when a decree of divorce, dissolution, or annulment becomes final.</summary>
</bill>
