<bill session="104" type="h" number="3673" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-16T13:58:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-07-16T13:58:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Compensation and Readjustment Benefits Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans' Compensation and Readjustment Benefits Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to revise and improve certain veterans programs and benefits, to authorize the American Battle Monuments Commission to enter into arrangements for the repair and long-term maintenance of war memorials for which the Commission assumes responsibility, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400504"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="1996-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1996-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400127" joined="1996-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1996-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="407838" joined="1996-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="410695" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1996-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T20:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 104-649.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-06-27T20:49:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="328">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 328.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Stump moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7552-7557" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-07-16T13:58:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16T13:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Parks, Preservation and Recreation.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>See S.1711.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Parks, Historic Preservation, and Recreation" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2513"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2851"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3248"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3459"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3495"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3611"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1711"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Atomic bomb"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational television"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Flight training"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Homeless veterans"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Korean War, 1950-1953"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lung cancer"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf War"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radiation victims"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/1996--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Veterans Compensation Benefits Title II: Education and Other Readjustment Benefits Title III: Other Matters Veterans' Compensation and Readjustment Benefits Amendments of 1996 - Title I: Veterans Compensation Benefits - Adds bronchiolo-alveolar carcinoma to the list of diseases that will be considered service-connected (and therefore compensable) when occurring in a radiation-exposed veteran. (Sec. 102) Considers any veteran age 65 or older and a patient in a nursing home as totally and permanently disabled for purposes of eligibility for veterans' disability compensation. (Sec. 103) Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct a pilot program under which veterans' medical disability evaluation examinations may be made under contract by persons other than employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs. (Sec. 104) Reduces the annual clothing allowance for veterans who are incarcerated and furnished clothing by the penal institution. (Sec. 105) Amends the Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 1994 to extend the due date for a final report from the Veterans' Claims Adjudication Commission concerning the disposition of claims for veterans' benefits. Provides funding. Title II: Education and Other Readjustment Benefits - Repeals provisions prohibiting the Secretary from approving the enrollment of an eligible veteran or other person in a course offered at an educational institution when such institution has been in operation for less than two years. Prohibits the Secretary from approving enrollment in a course not leading to a standard college degree when: (1) the institution or branch thereof offering the course has been operating for less than two years; or (2) following either a change in ownership or a move, the institution does not retain substantially the same faculty, student body, and courses. Provides for the approval or disapproval of courses offered by an institution under contract. Revises approval requirements concerning the adequacy of student records. (Sec. 202) Eliminates the distinction between the pursuit of education by open circuit television and independent study for purposes of the computation of the educational assistance allowance provided. (Sec. 203) Authorizes the Secretary to approve the pursuit of flight training if, among other requirements, the individual possesses a valid private pilot's license and meets the medical requirements for a commercial pilot's license on the first day of such training and within 60 days after successfully completing such training. (Sec. 204) Repeals a provision limiting the monthly educational assistance allowance payable to an individual pursuing a cooperative program. Increases the monthly educational allowance provided to individuals pursuing training in a business or industrial establishment as part of a full-time education program. (Sec. 205) Extends through 1997 the authority of the Secretary to issue certificates or other securities evidencing an interest in a pool of veterans' mortgage loans guaranteed by the Department. (Sec. 206) Amends the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act to extend through FY 1999 the authority for veterans' reintegration projects. Title III: Other Matters - Authorizes the American Battle Monuments Commission to enter into arrangements for the repair and long-term maintenance of war memorials. Establishes in the Treasury a fund for such repair and maintenance expenses. (Sec. 302) Provides burial benefits when a veteran dies at an institution at which such veteran was receiving Department-authorized hospital or nursing home care.</summary>
</bill>
