<bill session="106" type="h" number="4053" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States-Southeastern Europe Democratization and Burdensharing Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize assistance to the countries of southeastern Europe for fiscal year 2001, to authorize assistance for democratization in Serbia and Montenegro, to require equitable burdensharing in multilateral assistance programs for southeastern Europe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="2000-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400610" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400439" joined="2000-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E379-380"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Education)"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Albania"/>
    <term name="Albanians"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Croatia"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Decision making in public administration"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Equality before the law"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="International labor activities"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Kosovo"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Macedonia"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Montenegro"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public administration"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Romania"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Serbia"/>
    <term name="Slovenia"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="War crime trials"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
    <term name="Yugoslavia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: United States Assistance for the Countries of Southeastern Europe Title II: Assistance for Democracy Building in the Republic of Serbia and the Republic of Montenegro Title III: Assistance to the Republic of Montenegro Title IV: Assistance to the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia Title V: Equitable Burdensharing Requirement for Assistance for Southeastern Europe Region Title VI: Policy Regarding Individuals Indicted by the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia United States-Southeastern Europe Democratization and Burdensharing Act of 2000 - Title I: United States Assistance for the Countries of Southeastern Europe - Authorizes the President to provide specified U.S. foreign assistance for political and economic reforms in the countries of southeastern Europe (Republic of Slovenia, the Republic of Croatia, Bosnia and Herzegovina, the Republic of Albania, the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia, the Republic of Bulgaria, and Romania) and the Kosovo region of the Republic of Serbia. Prohibits such assistance (except humanitarian assistance) to the Republic of Serbia, except if the President determines that such government has undertaken steps to become democratic and ensure equal rights for all of its citizens.Title II: Assistance for Democracy Building in the Republic of Serbia and the Republic of Montenegro - Declares that the United States supports the development of democracy in Serbia and Montenegro and those who are committed to the building of democratic institutions, defending human rights, promoting rule of law, and fostering tolerance in society.(Sec. 204) Earmarks certain U.S. foreign assistance funds for democracy building in all regions of the Republic of Serbia (with a separate availability for Kosovo) and in the Republic of Montenegro.(Sec. 205) Prohibits U.S. foreign assistance to: (1) rebuild the civilian infrastructure in the Republic of Serbia; and (2) the Government of the Republic of Serbia, the Government of the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (other than Montenegro), or individuals connected with these governments particularly if the governments are under the direction of Slobodan Milosevic, the Socialist Party of Serbia, or any other non-democratic party.(Sec. 206) Expresses the sense of Congress that political contacts between the U.S. officials and those who represent a genuine desire for democratic governance in the Republic of Serbia and the Republic of Montenegro should be developed through regular and well publicized meetings.Authorizes appropriations for a voluntary U.S. contribution to the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) and the OSCE Parliamentary Assembly.Title III: Assistance to the Republic of Montenegro - Declares that the United States supports the development in Montenegro of a market-based economy and a democratic government based on equal rights for all of its citizens, regardless of ethnic background. Earmarks a specified amount of U.S. foreign assistance funds for political and economic reforms in the republic of Montenegro.Title IV: Assistance to the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia - Earmarks a specified amount of U.S. foreign assistance funds for economic and political reforms in the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia.(Sec. 403) Earmarks specified amounts for: (1) the establishment and support of the faculty and programs of an American University for Southeastern Europe at Skopje, Macedonia, or at another suitable site there; (2) microenterprise credits and loans through existing programs funded by the United States in Macedonia; (3) the Trade and Development Agency for additional activities under the South Balkans Development Initiative and activities in support of related infrastructure projects in Macedonia, including those projects that, in cooperation with the Republic of Bulgaria and the Republic of Albania, would expedite completion of an East-West trade corridor across those countries; (4) foreign military assistance for the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia; and (5) international military education and training (IMET) for the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia.Title V: Equitable Burdensharing Requirement for Assistance for Southeastern Europe Region - Limits the total amount of U.S. foreign assistance to the countries of southeastern Europe, the Republic of Montenegro, and the Kosovo region of the Republic of Serbia to no more than 15 percent of the total amount of certain multilateral assistance provided to such countries and region.(Sec. 502) Urges the European Union member states to make a far greater effort to provide adequate numbers of personnel for the International Police in Kosovo so that the goal of an effective 4,700-officer International Police in Kosovo force is attained as soon as possible.Title VI: Policy Regarding Individuals Indicted by the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia - Declares that it is U.S. policy to assist the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia as fully as possible in its apprehension and prosecution of individuals indicted for war crimes (including Slobodan Milosevic), and to encourage other North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) countries and other interested countries to do the same.</summary>
</bill>
