<bill session="106" type="h" number="1827" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-08T14:24:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-03-08T14:24:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Government Waste Corrections bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Waste Corrections Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Government Waste Corrections Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Government Waste Corrections Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the economy and efficiency of Government operations by requiring the use of recovery audits by Federal agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1999-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1999-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1999-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1999-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400225" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1999-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1999-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400304" joined="1999-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="1999-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1999-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1999-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400410" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="1999-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-05-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E985-986"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-11-10">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17T10:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 106-474.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12142-12144" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-11-17T10:48:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="270">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 270.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-02-29T19:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 426 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1827 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. In lieu of the amendment recommended by the Committee on Government Reform now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T12:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 426 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T12:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 426.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H713-722" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T12:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1827 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. In lieu of the amendment recommended by the Committee on Government Reform now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T12:49:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 426 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T12:49:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Bill Barrett to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T12:50:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1827.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T13:29:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1827.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T13:30:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T13:30:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T13:31:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS ON FINAL PASSAGE - The Chair put the question on final passage and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Burton objected to the voice vote based upon the absence of a quorum and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the day. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T14:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-03-08T14:24:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="29" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 375 - 0 (Roll no. 29).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T14:24:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="426"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Public administration"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h588"/>
    <amendment number="h589"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/8/2000--Passed House amended.
Government Waste Corrections Act of 2000 - Requires each Federal executive agency to conduct recovery audits and recovery activity (audits and activity) with respect to payment activities totaling $500 million or more and allows each agency to conduct audits and activity with respect to activities totaling less than such amounts. Allows each agency to request that the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (Director) exempt an activity from such audit requirement when compliance with such requirement would impede the agency's mission or would not be cost- effective. Outlines audit and activity procedures. Permits such agencies to conduct such audits and activity internally, by contract, or by a combination thereof.Sets forth agency authorities with respect to audits and activity procured by contract. Authorizes the contractor, as part of a contract, to notify any person of possible overpayments made to such person and identified in the audit and to respond to questions concerning such overpayment. Outlines required contract terms and conditions, including confidentiality requirements and required periodic reports and notifications from the contractor concerning identified overpayments as well as the possibility of fraud or other criminal activity discovered during the audit. Requires the agency head to conduct a cost-comparison process to determine whether to conduct audits and activity in-house or by contract.Limits the disclosure by non-governmental entities of individually identifiable information obtained through the performance of an audit and activity. Requires such entities to destroy such information upon conclusion of the matter for which the audit or activity was undertaken.Requires audit and activity amounts recovered to be used for recovery audit costs and a management improvement program established under this Act, with the remainder to be deposited into the Treasury. Provides exceptions.Directs each agency which is required to conduct such audits and activity to conduct a management improvement program which shall address problems contributing to agency overpayments. Allows such program to seek to reduce errors and waste in other agency programs and operations by improving the agency's staff capacity, information technology, and financial management. Requires the Director to coordinate and oversee the implementation of such recovery audit provisions, including providing guidance for audit standards. Authorizes the Director to: (1) limit the amounts paid to contractors as a recovery fee; and (2) exempt an agency from the audit and activity requirements when compliance would impede the agency's mission or would not be cost-effective (requiring a report to Congress on any such exemption). Exempts Department of Defense major system acquisition programs from the audit and activity requirements of this Act. Requires three annual reports from the Director to the President and specified congressional committees on such implementation. Requires the Comptroller General, after each such report, to report to the Director and such committees.Requires each agency to begin such audit and activity within 18 months after the enactment of this Act.Requires the Director to study and report to Congress on the effects of recovery audits conducted by executive agencies.</summary>
</bill>
