<bill session="104" type="h" number="4188" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fort Peck Reservation Rural Water System Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the construction of the Fort Peck Reservation Rural Water System, Montana, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411677"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1700"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water supply engineering"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/1996--Introduced.
Fort Peck Reservation Rural Water System Act of 1995 (sic) - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to plan, design, construct, operate, maintain, and replace a municipal, rural, and industrial water system, to be known as the Fort Peck Reservation Rural Water System and to consist of specified facilities. Directs the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with the Fort Peck Tribal Executive Board with respect to all phases of the System. Provides construction requirements. Prohibits the obligation of construction funds until: (1) certain environmental mitigation requirements have been met; and (2) a final engineering report has been approved by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to issue a public notice finding that plans for the System include prudent and responsible water conservation measures which are economically and financially feasible. Requires the System to utilize power for its operation from the Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin Program. Authorizes appropriations for planning, design, construction, operation, and maintenance of the System.</summary>
</bill>
