<bill session="105" type="hr" number="581" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-08T15:13:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-08T15:13:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Impeachment Investigation resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Authorizing and directing the Committee on the Judiciary to investigate whether sufficient grounds exist for the impeachment of William Jefferson Clinton, President of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07T23:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Judiciary reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-795, by Mr. Hyde.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-10-07T23:01:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="272">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 272.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10015-10032, H10083-10119" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEEDINGS - Mr. Hyde asked unanimous consent that debate on the resolution be extended to two hours. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T10:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with two hours of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T11:55:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEEDINGS - Mr. Conyers asked unanimous consent that a motion to recommit the resolution, to be offered at the conclusion of debate, be debatable for ten minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T13:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T14:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Boucher moved to recommit with instructions to Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T14:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion to recommit the resolution to the Committee on the Judiciary with instructions to report the same back with an amendment to strike the first section and insert provisions to conduct an inquiry and if appropriate to act upon the Referral from the Independent Counsel; to review the constitutional standard for impeachment; and investigate whether sufficient grounds exist for the House to exercise its constitutional power to impeach the President. Following the conclusion of its inquiry the Committee shall consider any recommendation it may commend to the House including (1) one or more articles of impeachment; (2) alternative sanctions; or (3) no action. The Committee shall make its recommendations sufficiently in advance of December 31, 1998 so that the House may consider the recommendations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T14:39:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 198 - 236 (Roll No. 497).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10119" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-10-08T15:13:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="498" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 258 - 176 (Roll No. 498).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Clinton Administration"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House Judiciary"/>
    <term name="Impeachments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/1998--Introduced.
Authorizes the House Committee on the Judiciary, acting as a whole or by any subcommittee thereof appointed by the chairman for the purposes hereof and in accordance with the rules of the Committee, to investigate fully and completely whether sufficient grounds exist for the House to exercise its constitutional power to impeach President Clinton. Requires the Committee to report to the House such resolutions, articles of impeachment, or other recommendations as it deems proper.</summary>
</bill>
