<bill session="106" type="h" number="5099" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare+Choice Program Improvement Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to make improvements to the Medicare+Choice Program under part C of the Medicare Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="2000-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2000--Introduced.
Medicare+Choice Program Improvement Act of 2000 - Amends part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for: (1) increasing the national per capita Medicare+Choice growth percentage in 2001 and 2002; (2) increasing the minimum payment amount in 2002 for any of the 50 States and the District of Columbia; (3) allowing a Medicare+Choice organization to elect to apply an area-specific percentage of 50 percent and a national percentage of 50 percent for 2002 rather than the rate currently applicable for that year in determining the blended capitation rate used in determining the calculation of annual Medicare+Choice capitation rates; (4) increasing the update for payment areas with only one or no Medicare+Choice contracts; (5) permitting higher negotiated rates in certain Medicare+Choice payment areas below the national average; and (6) providing for a ten year phase-in of risk adjustment based on data from all settings.Delays from July to November 2000 the deadline for withdrawing the offer, or rescinding the withdrawal, of Medicare+Choice plans for 2001.</summary>
</bill>
