<bill session="104" type="h" number="4228" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States-Puerto Rico Political Status Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a process leading to full self-government for Puerto Rico.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="National self-determination"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Statehood (American politics)"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Introduced.
United States-Puerto Rico Political Status Act - Declares it is the policy of the Congress that: (1) English shall be the official language of the Federal government in the United States; and (2) if the referenda under this Act result in approval of sovereignty leading to Statehood for Puerto Rico, it is anticipated that English would become the official language of the Federal government in Puerto Rico. Requires a referendum to be held by December 31, 1998, on Puerto Rico's political status, either: (1) retention of its present Commonwealth status; (2) full self-government through separate sovereignty leading to independence or free association; or (3) full self-government through U.S. sovereignty leading to statehood. Requires the President to develop and submit to the Congress for approval legislation for: (1) a transition plan of at least ten years which leads to full self-government for Puerto Rico; and (2) a recommendation for the implementation of such self-government consistent with Puerto Rico's approval. Sets forth specified requirements with respect to the referendum and congressional procedures for consideration of legislation. Makes funds available for the referendum. Requires the Government of Puerto Rico to make grants to the State Elections Commission of Puerto Rico for referenda held under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
