<bill session="108" type="h" number="4564" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for reform relating to employment at the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400435"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2004-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Retirement age"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2004--Introduced.
Amend Federal retirement provisions relating to the Civil Service Retirement System and the Federal Employees' Retirement System to raise, from 60 to 65, the mandatory separation age for employees of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) who have been exempted, because it is in the public interest to do so, by the head of the agency from being retired at the earlier automatic separation age limit of 57. Sets forth provisions for payment of retention and relocation bonuses for the FBI. Authorizes the Director of the FBI to provide for the establishment and training of a Federal Bureau of Investigation Reserve Service (FBI Reserve Service) for temporary reemployment in the FBI of previously full-time employees of the FBI during emergencies. Limits the membership of the FBI Reserve Service to 500 members at any given time. Amends Federal law relating to Government organization and employees, to include, with regard to pay authority for critical positions, positions at the FBI, the primary duties and responsibilities of which relate to intelligence functions.</summary>
</bill>
