<bill session="108" type="h" number="1219" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Malpractice and Insurance Reform Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit frivolous medical malpractice lawsuits, to reform the medical malpractice insurance business in order to reduce the cost of medical malpractice insurance, to enhance patient access to medical care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2003-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2003-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400177" joined="2003-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2003-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contempt of court"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Gynecology"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Price fixing"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Surgeons"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2003--Introduced.
Medical Malpractice and Insurance Reform Act of 2003 - Declares that medical malpractice actions shall be barred unless the complaint is within three years after the right of action accrues. Sets forth criteria for determining the date on which the right of action accrues.Prohibits any individual from bringing a medical malpractice liability action unless it is accompanied by the affidavit of a qualified specialist attesting to the reasonableness of the filing. Requires the attorney of a person filing such an action, or the individual if there is no attorney, to sign a certificate of merit attesting to the justified nature of the action.Directs courts to impose sanctions for violations of the provisions pertaining to the certificate of merit, including to issue fines for multiple offenders.Requires mediation, to be made available by the State, before a trial for any medical malpractice liability action.Prohibits punitive damages from being awarded in a medical malpractice action except upon proof of gross negligence, reckless indifference to life, or one of various types of intentional acts.Requires medical malpractice liability insurance companies to implement a plan to dedicate at least 50 percent of the annual savings from carrying out this section to reducing malpractice premiums. Imposes a civil penalty on medical malpractice liability insurance companies that violate this section.Amends the Public Health Service Act to permit the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to award grants or contracts to geographic areas that have shortages of one or more types of health providers due to the cost of maintaining malpractice insurance.Establishes the Independent Advisory Commission on Medical Malpractice Insurance, which shall investigate the recent dramatic increases in medical malpractice insurance premiums and formulate proposals to reduce such premiums.</summary>
</bill>
