<bill session="105" type="h" number="2184" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Private Security Officer Quality Assurance Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit reviews of criminal records of applicants for private security officer employment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400549"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-08-19">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.103.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="103"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Trade associations"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/1997--Introduced.
Private Security Officer Quality Assurance Act of 1997 - Directs the Attorney General (AG) to designate an association of employers of private security officers, which must submit to the AG, at the request of an employer of officers, fingerprints or other methods of positive identification for background checks of such officers. Allows an employer to seek authorization from its employees for a background check. Directs the AG, upon receipt of fingerprints from an association, to: (1) search records of the Interstate Information Index of the National Crime Information Center and the Identification Division of the Federal Bureau of Investigation; and (2) provide any corresponding identification and criminal history records to the requesting association. Authorizes the AG to prescribe regulations to carry out this Act, including measures relating to the imposition of fees necessary for the recovery of costs. Directs the AG to report to specified congressional committees two years after enactment of this Act on the number of inquiries made by the association of employers and their disposition. Establishes criminal penalties for misuse of such background check information. Provides that employers shall not be held liable in any action for damages based on employment determinations that rely on such criminal history information from the AG. Authorizes the AG to collect a user fee for a request, under any applicable law, for an individual's criminal history information.</summary>
</bill>
