<bill session="105" type="h" number="270" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Reconciliation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part B of title IV of the Social Security Act to provide for a set-aside of funds for States that have enacted certain divorce laws, to amend the Legal Services Corporation Act to prohibit the use of funds made available under the Act to provide legal assistance in certain proceedings relating to divorces and legal separations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400533"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to the poor"/>
    <term name="Marriage counseling"/>
    <term name="Separation (Law)"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Wife abuse"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Family Reconciliation Act - Amends part B (Child-Welfare Services) of title IV of the Social Security Act with regard to family preservation and support services to create certain set-asides for States with approved family reconciliation plans which require a minimum 60-day waiting period and participation in counseling programs before final dissolution of a marriage involving one or more children under age 12. Amends the Legal Services Corporation Act to prohibit the use of funds under that Act for legal assistance in certain actions relating to divorces or separations except where there is court-determined spousal abuse.</summary>
</bill>
