<bill session="107" type="h" number="2347" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax Empowerment and Relief for Farmers and Fishermen (TERFF) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax relief for farmers and fishermen, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400207" joined="2001-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="2002-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="2002-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2002-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2002-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409888" joined="2002-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="2002-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural production"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cooperative societies"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy tax credits"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Livestock industry"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Preferred stocks"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Unrelated business income tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2001--Introduced.
Tax Empowerment and Relief for Farmers and Fishermen (TERFF) Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an eligible commercial farmer or commercial fisherman a deduction (up to 20 percent of taxable income attributable to such business) for the amount paid in cash into a Farm, Fishing, and Ranch Risk Management Account.Amends the Code and title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act to exclude net earnings from a lease agreement (currently, an arrangement) from income with respect to farmland.Treats conservation reserve program payments as real estate rentals for self-employment earnings purposes.Exempt certain small issue agriculture bonds from the State volume cap.Sets forth a rule for determining the allowable deduction for a charitable contribution of food inventory.Extends income averaging to income from the trade or business of catching, taking, or harvesting fish intended to enter commerce through sale, barter, or trade. Disregards income averaging for farmers and commercial fishermen in computing the regular alternative minimum tax.Declares, with respect to the treatment of S corporations and to the tax exemption for farmers' cooperatives, that cooperative marketing includes the value-added processing of the products of cooperative members and other producers through animals that is by: (1) feeding such products to cattle, hogs, fish, chickens, or other animals; and then (2) selling the resulting animals or animal products.Authorizes a U.S. district court to issue a declaratory judgment relating to the initial or continuing qualification of a farmers' cooperative as tax-exempt.Provides, with respect to the small ethanol producer credit, for: (1) authorizing credit allocation among a cooperative's patrons; (2) increasing the gallon capacity for eligible producers; (3) making the credit a non-passive income credit; and (4) removing the credit from the alcohol fuel credit gross income inclusion.</summary>
</bill>
