<bill session="106" type="h" number="1906" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-22">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">FY2000 Agriculture Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Livestock Mandatory Reporting Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2000, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400534"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-05-21T17:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-157, by Mr. Skeen.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-05-21T17:30:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="87">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 87.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 185 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1906 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. During consideration of the bill for amendment, the Chair may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whether the Member offering an amendment has caused it to be printed in the Congressional Record. Amendments so printed shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T13:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 185 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T13:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 185.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3540-3584" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T13:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1906 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. During consideration of the bill for amendment, the Chair may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whether the Member offering an amendment has caused it to be printed in the Congressional Record. Amendments so printed shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 185 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Edward A. Pease to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1906.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Coburn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Sanford and announced that by voice vote, the noes had prevailed. Mr. Coburn subsequently demanded a recorded vote. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 185, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T19:48:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Coburn and announced that by voice vote, the noes had prevailed. Mr. Coburn subsequently demanded a recorded vote and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 185, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed and the point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>PROCEEDINGS POSTPONED - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Coburn and announced that by voice vote, the noes had prevailed. Mr. Coburn subsequently demanded a recorded vote. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 185, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T20:16:00-04:00">
      <text>PROCEEDINGS RESUMED - The Chair proceeded to put the question on the 3 amendments which had been debated earlier and on which proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T21:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1906 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3614-3649" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26T10:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26T11:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Coburn by voice vote and announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Kaptur demanded a recorded vote, and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 185, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26T12:15:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Coburn by voice vote and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Coburn demanded a recorded vote, and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 185, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Sanford by voice vote and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sanford demanded a recorded vote, and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 185, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Coburn by voice vote and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Coburn demanded a recorded vote, and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 185, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26T14:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair announced that the proceedings will resume on amendments postponed earlier in the following order: The amendment offered by Mr. Coburn to reduce funding by $50,863,000 for agricultural research; the amendment offered by Mr. Coburn to reduce funding by $1,000,000 for climate change research; the amendment offered by Mr. Sanford to reduce funding by $5,136,000 for wood research; and the amendment offered by Mr. Coburn to reduce funding by $300,000 for peanut research.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26T15:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1906 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3780-3823" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Postponed Proceedings on De Fazio Amendment - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. DeFazio by voice vote. Mr. DeFazio objected to the voice vote pending the absence of a quorum. The Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Mr. Skeen asked unanimous consent that debate on the amendment offered by Mr. Coburn be completed in two hours. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T15:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Coburn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1906.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T18:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit the bill with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 207 - 220 (Roll no. 176).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3823" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-06-08T19:25:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="177" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 246 - 183 (Roll no. 177).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T19:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Agriculture, Rural Development. Approved for full committee consideration without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Senate Committee on Appropriations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10214" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 1233 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1999-08-04" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 1233 with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment asks for a conference, appoints conferees Cochran; Specter; Bond; Gorton; McConnell; Burns; Stevens; Kohl; Harkin; Dorgan; Feinstein; Durbin; Byrd.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10214" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Skeen asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T16:01:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8125-8126" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T16:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T16:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T16:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained in the motion require the managers on the part of the House to provide maximum funding, within the scope of conference, for food safety programs at the Department of Agriculture and the Food and Drug Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T16:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T16:04:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8126" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T16:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T16:06:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Skeen, Walsh, Dickey, Kingston, Nethercutt, Bonilla, Latham, Emerson, Young (FL), Kaptur, DeLauro, Hinchey, Farr, Boyd, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T22:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 106-354 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9141-9173" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T23:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 317 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 1906 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-01T11:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 317 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-01T11:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Skeen brought up conference report H. Rept. 106-354 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 317.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-01T11:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report on on H.R. 1906.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-01T12:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-01T12:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Kaptur moved to recommit to the conference committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-01T12:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit to conference committee was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-01T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit to conference committee Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 187 - 228 (Roll no. 468).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9236" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="1999-10-01T13:15:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="469" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 240 - 175 (Roll No. 469).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9217-9237" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-10-01T13:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-01">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-06">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement and official papers held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-07">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of the conference report to accompany H.R. 1906 agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12215" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-07">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-07">
      <text>Cloture motion on the conference report presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12216" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-08">
      <text>Second cloture motion on the conference report presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12316" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-12">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12405-12419" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-12">
      <text>Cloture on the conference report invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 79-20. Record Vote No: 322.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12419" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-12">
      <text>Second cloture motion on the conference report withdrawn by unanimous consent in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-13">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1999-10-13" how="roll" result="pass" roll="323" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 74-26. Record Vote No: 323.</text>
      <reference ref="CR  S12504" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-10-13">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1999-10-13">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1999-10-13">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1999-10-22">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1999-10-22" type="public" number="106-78">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-78.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP01" subcommittee="Agriculture, Rural Development, and Related Agencies" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="185"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="317"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="106" type="s" number="1233"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1233"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="106" type="s" number="1233"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Agricultural appropriations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural colleges"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural estimating and reporting"/>
    <term name="Agricultural experiment stations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agricultural industries"/>
    <term name="Agricultural innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pests"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Agricultural production"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural statistics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural surpluses"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Alternative Agricultural Research and Commercialization Corporation"/>
    <term name="Alternative agriculture"/>
    <term name="Alternative crops"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Apples"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Beef"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Chief financial officers"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining in government"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining unit"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Colonias"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Commodity Credit Corporation"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="Credit insurance"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Dairy products"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Export subsidies"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Farmland protection"/>
    <term name="Farms"/>
    <term name="Federal Crop Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to rural areas"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Food supply"/>
    <term name="Food supply insurance"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forestry"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Fruit trade"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Grain inspection"/>
    <term name="Grain trade"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Hunger"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import quotas"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infant formulas"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insect control"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International agricultural cooperation"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Legumes"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Livestock industry"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Market surveys"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Marketing orders"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Medical mycology"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Methyl bromide"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and the aged"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Oilseeds"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Orphan drugs"/>
    <term name="Oxygenates"/>
    <term name="Pacific area"/>
    <term name="Peanuts"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pesticide residues in food"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Plant diseases"/>
    <term name="Plant germplasm resources"/>
    <term name="Plant protection"/>
    <term name="Plant quarantine"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Pork"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Poultry industry"/>
    <term name="Poultry inspection"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="RU 486 (Drug)"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Radioactive contamination of food"/>
    <term name="Reformulated gasoline"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Revegetation"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rice"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="Rural electrification"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soybeans"/>
    <term name="Sparsely populated areas"/>
    <term name="Stock repurchasing"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Sustainable agriculture"/>
    <term name="Swine"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
    <term name="Tobacco settlement"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transgenic animals"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Vegetable trade"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
    <term name="Weed control"/>
    <term name="Welfare work participation"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wheat"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Year 2000 computer problem"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h120"/>
    <amendment number="h121"/>
    <amendment number="h122"/>
    <amendment number="h123"/>
    <amendment number="h124"/>
    <amendment number="h125"/>
    <amendment number="h126"/>
    <amendment number="h127"/>
    <amendment number="h128"/>
    <amendment number="h129"/>
    <amendment number="h130"/>
    <amendment number="h131"/>
    <amendment number="h132"/>
    <amendment number="h133"/>
    <amendment number="h136"/>
    <amendment number="h137"/>
    <amendment number="h138"/>
    <amendment number="h139"/>
    <amendment number="h140"/>
    <amendment number="h141"/>
    <amendment number="h142"/>
    <amendment number="h143"/>
    <amendment number="h144"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/30/1999--Conference report filed in House.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Agricultural Programs Title II: Conservation Programs Title III: Rural Economic and Community Development Programs Title IV: Domestic Food Programs Title V: Foreign Assistance and Related Programs Title VI: Related Agencies and Food and Drug Administration Title VII: General Provisions Title VIII: Emergency and Disaster Assistance for Producers Subtitle A: Crop and Market Loss Assistance Subtitle B: Other Assistance Subtitle C: Administration Title IX: Livestock Mandatory Reporting Subtitle A: Livestock Mandatory Reporting Subtitle B: Related Beef Reporting Provisions Subtitle C: Related Swine Reporting Provisions Subtitle D: Implementation Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000 - Title I: Agricultural Programs - Appropriates funds for FY 2000 for the following Department of Agriculture programs and services: (1) Office of the Secretary of Agriculture; (2) executive operations; (3) Office of the Chief Information Officer; (4) Office of the Chief Financial Officer; (5) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Administration; (6) Agriculture buildings and facilities and rental payments; (7) hazardous waste management; (8) departmental administration; (9) outreach for socially disadvantaged farmers; (10) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations; (11) Office of Communications; (12) Office of the Inspector General; (13) Office of the General Counsel; (14) Office of the Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics; (15) Economic Research Service; (16) National Agricultural Statistics Service; (17) Agricultural Research Service; (18) Cooperative State Research, Education, and Extension Service; ( Native American Institutions Endowment Fund); (19) Office of the Under Secretary for Marketing and Regulatory Programs; (20) Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service; (21) Agricultural Marketing Service; (22) Grain Inspection, Packers and Stockyards Administration; (23) Office of the Under Secretary for Food Safety; (24) Food Safety and Inspection Service; (25) Office of the Under Secretary for Farm and Foreign Agricultural Services; (26) Farm Service Agency; (27) Risk Management Agency; (28) Federal Crop Insurance Corporation Fund; and (29) Commodity Credit Corporation Fund.Title II: Conservation Programs - Appropriates funds for the: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Natural Resources and Environment; and (2) Natural Resources Conservation Service.Title III: Rural Economic and Community Development Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Rural Development; (2) Rural Housing Service; (3) Rural Business-Cooperative Service; and (4) Rural Utilities Service.Title IV: Domestic Food Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Food, Nutrition and Consumer Services; and (2) Food and Nutrition Service.Title V: Foreign Assistance and Related Programs - Appropriates funds for the Foreign Agricultural Service and General Sales Manager.Title VI: Related Agencies and Food and Drug Administration - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Food and Drug Administration; (2) Commodity Futures Trading Commission; and (3) Farm Credit Administration.Title VII: General Provisions - Specifies certain uses and limits on or prohibitions against the use of funds appropriated by this Act.(Sec. 713) States that appropriations for the rural housing insurance fund program account for FY 1994 through 1999 guaranteed and direct loans shall remain available until expended.(Sec. 714) Provides that FY 2000 obligations shall remain available until expended for the following accounts: (1) rural development loan fund program; (2) rural telephone bank program; (3) rural electrification and telecommunications loan program; (4) rural housing insurance fund program; and (5) rural economic development loan program.(Sec. 718) Prohibits fund use to retire more than five percent of rural telephone bank Class A stock.(Sec. 721) Prohibits more than 30-day intra-Department transfers without reimbursement.(Sec. 722) Prohibits any appropriation use to make certain appropriation hearings information available to non-Department personnel.(Sec. 723) Prohibits appropriations use to acquire new information technology systems for the Department without approval of the Chief Information Officer and concurrence of the Executive Information Technology Investment review Board.(Sec. 724) Sets forth certain Appropriations Acts reprogramming procedures.(Sec. 725) Prohibits fund use for the Fund for Rural America program.(Sec. 726) Caps funding for the environmental quality incentives program.(Sec. 727) Prohibits any fund use to pay producers under the Agricultural Market Transition Act unless contract payments are reduced for each acre planted to wild rice.(Sec. 728) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to enroll more than 150,000 acres in the FY 2000 wetlands reserve program.(Sec. 729) Prohibits any fund use for the Initiative for Future Agriculture and Food Systems.(Sec. 730) States that as of FY 2000, the definitions of rural areas for certain business programs and community facilities programs shall be those in effect prior to enactment of Public Law 104-127.(Sec. 731) Prohibits fund use for any commodity purchase program that excludes farmer-owned cooperatives.(Sec. 732) Prohibits fund use for the conservation farm option program.(Sec. 733) Prohibits fund use by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to: (1) relocate or close the Division of Drug Analysis, St. Louis, Missouri, or the District Office Laboratory, Detroit, Michigan; or (2) reduce staffing below a certain level at, or modify the status of, the Detroit, Michigan District Office.(Sec. 734) Prohibits any fund use for agricultural products inspections unless the Secretary of Agriculture has made certain processing equipment inspections and imposed a related fee.(Sec. 735) Prohibits any appropriations use for an agricultural submission to Congress that assumes reductions from the previous year's budget due to user fee proposals unless the submission also identifies spending reductions to occur if the user fees are not enacted.(Sec. 736) Prohibits fund use to establish an Office of Community Food Security or similar office within the Department without prior approval by the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations.(Sec. 737) Prohibits any fund use by the Agricultural Research Service to accept and administer the National Swine Research Center in Ames, Iowa.(Sec. 738) Prohibits fund use for the emergency food assistance program if such program exceeds $98 million.(Sec. 739) Prohibits appropriations use to implement the Kyoto Protocol.(Sec. 741) Prohibits fund use to declare excess, or transfer, Department facilities at Fort Reno, Oklahoma, without congressional authorization.(Sec. 742) Directs the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service to redistribute certain funds for a specified watershed project in Mississippi.(Sec. 743) Directs the Secretary to offer to enter into an agreement (similar to an existing California agreement) with the Governor of Hawaii for a pilot program to inspect the mail for prohibited plants, products, and pests.(Sec. 744) Directs the Secretary to provide guaranteed credit lines for health care facilities to address Year 2000 computer conversion issues.(Sec. 745) Directs the Secretary to compensate producers for any losses incurred in the seizure, quarantine, or destruction of karnal bunt-infested wheat.(Sec. 746) Appropriates specified funds for providing Bill Emerson and Mickey Leland Hunger Fellowships through the Congressional Hunger Center.(Sec. 747) Appropriates specified funds for the farmland protection program in New Hampshire.(Sec. 748) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act, with respect to temporary agricultural (H-2A) worker applications, to: (1) reduce the filing deadline from 60 days to 45 days; and (2) increase the certification issuance deadline from 20 days to 30 days.(Sec. 749) States that if the Secretary's exercise of authority under this Act causes changes in an existing bargaining unit, the affected parties shall attempt to reach a voluntary agreement on a new bargaining unit and representative. Sets forth related provisions.(Sec. 751) Sets forth limitations on HUBZone program contracts under the Small Business Act.(Sec. 752) Redesignates the National School Lunch Act as the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act.(Sec. 754) Amends the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 to redesignate the Stuttgart National Aquaculture Research Center (Arkansas) as the Harry K. Dupree Stuttgart National Aquaculture Research Center.(Sec. 755) Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 to extend within-State lease and transfer of burley tobacco quota authority to Kentucky, Ohio, and Indiana.Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 to authorize the Secretary to release tobacco production and marketing information to State trusts or similar organizations engaged in the distribution of national trust funds to tobacco producers and other related persons, to the extent that such release is: (1) in the interest of tobacco producers; and (2) to a State trust or other organization engaged in the distribution of funds to tobacco producers or other parties with an interest in tobacco production or farms under a national or State trust or settlement.Directs the Secretary, prior to release of such information, to allow at least 15 days for persons whose release consent would otherwise be required to elect to be exempt from such release.Requires a person obtaining released information to maintain records and not to use such information for other than permitted purposes. Provides penalties for knowing violations of the provisions of this Act.Exempts from the provisions of this section: (1) cigarette manufacturer production records; (2) tobacco quota purchase intention records; and (3) buyer aggregate purchase records.(Sec. 756) Makes Berlin, New Hampshire, eligible for a FY 2000 rural utilities loan or grant under the rural community advancement program.(Sec. 757) Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act to extend marketing order promotion authority (including paid advertising) to cranberries. Authorizes the Secretary to require cranberry handlers and importers to provide acquisition, inventory, and disposition data.(Sec. 758) Amends the Food Stamp Act, as of FY 2001, to include Native Alaskan villages within food stamp program administrative cost-sharing authority.(Sec. 759) Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to Alaska Native and Native Hawaiian serving institutions for education, applied research, and related community development programs. Authorizes FY 2001 through 2006 appropriations.(Sec. 760) Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act, reenacted with amendments by the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1937, to state that the price of milk paid by a handler at a plant in Clark County, Nevada, shall not be subject to Federal milk marketing orders.(Sec. 761) Makes Olean, New York, and Carolina, Puerto Rico, eligible for Rural Utilities Service grants and loans.(Sec. 764) Prohibits fund use to implement specified FSA Notices.(Sec. 766) Redesignates the U.S. Salinity Laboratory in Riverside, California, as the George E. Brown, Jr. Salinity Laboratory.(Sec. 768) States that the maximum income limits for single family housing in high cost areas of Alaska shall be 150 percent of the Alaska metropolitan income level.Title VIII: Emergency and Disaster Assistance for Producers - Subtitle A: Crop and Market Loss Assistance - Directs the Secretary to provide emergency assistance to producers who have disaster-caused 1999 losses (including livestock, fisheries, and trees from which a crop is harvested). States that producers with crop insurance shall not be discriminated against respecting such assistance.Authorizes: (1) rice loan deficiency payments; and (2) recourse loans for honey and mohair.(Sec. 802) Directs the Secretary to provide production loss assistance to producers who are eligible for final FY 1999 production flexibility payments. Makes such assistance available in proportion to amounts received under a producer's flexibility contract. Provides tenant and sharecropper protection (shared payments).(Sec. 803) Directs the Secretary to provide assistance to: (1) 1999 producers of quota and additional peanuts; and (2) tobacco producers in accordance with the National Tobacco Grower Settlement Trust.Permits, upon producer referendum approval, sale of flue-cured tobacco allotments or quotas to same-State farms.(Sec. 804) Directs the Secretary to provide assistance to 1999 producers of soybeans and oilseeds who are eligible for marketing assistance loans.(Sec. 805) Directs the Secretary to provide direct assistance to 1999 dairy and livestock producers.(Sec. 806) Amends the Agricultural Market Transition Act to revise the upland cotton import quota and marketing certificate programs.(Sec. 807) Extends the milk price support program through 2000.Subtitle B: Other Assistance - Amends the Agricultural Market Transition Act to extend through FY 2002 authority for advance production flexibility contract payments.(Sec. 812) Authorizes the Commodity Credit Corporation, in making in-kind payments respecting nonrecourse marketing assistance loans and loan deficiency payments, to: (1) acquire and use pledged commodities as loan collateral; (2) use other (owned) commodities; and (3) redeem negotiable marketing certificates for cash.(Sec. 813) Limits 1999 marketing loan gains and loan deficiency payments to $150,000 per person.(Sec. 814) Directs the Secretary to transfer specified Corporation funds to the Federal Crop Insurance Fund for the 2000 crop year.(Sec. 815) Directs the Secretary to forgive certain water and waste disposal loan and interest amounts owed by Stroud, Oklahoma.(Sec. 816) Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to permit the National Sheep Industry Improvement Center to make assistance available through intermediary financial institutions. Provides for privatization of the Center.(Sec. 817) Appropriates additional FY 2001 funds for emergency disaster assistance to: (1) the Department for persons or entities affected by the 1999 fisheries failure in the Norton Sound region of Alaska; and (2) the Department of Commerce for the commercial fishery failure with respect to Northeast multi-species fisheries.(Sec. 818) Expresses the sense of Congress: (1) that the President should request fast-track authority for future United States trade negotiations; and (2) respecting future World Trade Organization negotiations and agricultural commerce.Subtitle C: Administration - Obligates specified funds for livestock and dairy producers.Title IX: Livestock Mandatory Reporting - Livestock Mandatory Reporting Act of 1999 - Subtitle A: Livestock Mandatory Reporting - Amends the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 to define specified terms relating to livestock reporting, including cattle, lamb, and swine reporting.Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to establish mandatory price reporting programs for live cattle and swine that: (1) provide timely and accurate market information; (2) facilitate informed marketing decisions; and (3) promote competition in the slaughtering industry. Sets forth reporting provisions for the Secretary and packers.Requires mandatory packer reporting of boxed beef sales.Authorizes the Secretary to establish a reporting price information program for lamb.Sets forth enforcement provisions.Prohibits the Secretary from charging user or service fees.Requires the Secretary to encourage voluntary reporting by packers not subject to the mandatory requirements of this title.Requires the Secretary to publish at least monthly information on retail prices for food products made from beef, pork, chicken, turkey, veal, or lamb.Subtitle B: Related Beef Reporting Provisions - Amends the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to include beef within the agricultural export commodities subject to weekly reporting by the Secretary.(Sec. 922) Requires the Secretary to implement an electronic online system to issue and report on meat and meat product export certificates.(Sec. 923) Requires the Secretary publish information on imports of beef, beef variety meats, and cattle.(Sec. 924) Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle C: Related Swine Reporting Provisions - Requires the Secretary to publish on a monthly basis the Hogs and Pigs Inventory Report, including a separate category for gestating sows.(Sec. 932) Requires the Secretary to make available to swine producers, packers, and other market participants information on swine slaughter that reflects differences in numbers between barrows and gilts.(Sec. 933) Requires the Secretary to contract for a correlation study and report (and prepare subsequent reports) establishing a baseline and standards for determining and improving average trim loss measurements and processing techniques for swine slaughter.(Sec. 934) Amends the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 to require the Secretary to establish and maintain a library of each contract type offered by packers to swine producers for the purchase and slaughter of swine, including non-carcass premiums. Authorizes appropriations.Requires the Comptroller General to report on the Secretary's authority and jurisdiction over packers and others involved in procuring, slaughtering, or processing swine, pork, or pork products under specified Acts.(Sec. 935) Authorizes appropriations to carry out activities under this title.Subtitle D: Implementation - Sets forth implementing provisions. Terminates the provisions of this Act five years after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
