<bill session="106" type="h" number="5039" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Choice Preservation Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to revise and improve the Medicare+Choice Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400173"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Improvements In Payments Title II: Additional Improvements Medicare Choice Preservation Act of 2000 - Title I: Improvements in Payments - Amends part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for: (1) increasing the national per capita Medicare+Choice growth percentage in 2001 and 2002; (2) increasing the minimum payment amount in 2001 for any of the 50 States and the District of Columbia; (3) allowing a Medicare+Choice organization to elect to apply an area-specific percentage of 50 percent and a national percentage of 50 percent for 2002 rather than the rate currently applicable for that year in determining the blended capitation rate used in determining the calculation of annual Medicare+Choice capitation rates; (4) increasing the minimum percentage increase in 2001 under provisions for calculation of annual Medicare+Choice capitation rates; (5) increasing the update for payment areas with only one or no Medicare+Choice contracts; (6) eliminating the budget neutrality adjustment for 2001 and 2002 under blended capitation rate provisions; (7) revising calculation of area-specific and national percentage capitation rates; and (8) phasing-in over a ten year period of risk adjustment methodology based on data from all settings.Title II: Additional Improvements - Delays from July to November 2000 the deadline for withdrawing the offer, rescinding the withdrawal, of Medicare+Choice plans for 2001.Amends SSA title XVIII part C to revise data collection requirements under the Medicare+Choice program with regard to: (1) issuance of encounter data submission; (2) post-stabilization guidelines; (3) effectiveness of elections and changes of elections; (4) uniform premium and benefits; and (5) Medicare+Choice program compatibility with employer or union group health plans.</summary>
</bill>
