<bill session="106" type="h" number="3229" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Electronic Fund Transfer Fees Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to prohibit the imposition of certain additional fees on consumers in connection with any electronic fund transfer which is initiated by the consumer from an electronic terminal operated by a person other than the financial institution holding the consumer's account and which utilizes a national or regional communication network.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Automated teller machines"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/4/1999--Introduced.
Electronic Fund Transfer Fees Act of 1999 - Amends the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to prohibit the operator of the electronic terminal at which an electronic fund transfer is initiated from imposing a fee upon any such electronic fund transfer which: (1) is initiated by a consumer from an electronic terminal operated by a person other than the financial institution holding such consumer's account; and (2) utilizes a national or regional communication network to execute the transaction between such person and the financial institution holding such consumer's account.</summary>
</bill>
