<bill session="104" type="h" number="71" updated="2012-11-01T22:43:26-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce the Official Mail Allowance of Members of the House and to prohibit certain other mailing practices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1995-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="401547" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1995-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1995-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="405033" joined="1995-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1995-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="410887" joined="1995-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Postal Service"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional allowances"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Primaries"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>01/04/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991 to revise the formula for the Official Mail Allowance (thereby reducing the amount allowed) for Members of the House of Representatives. Repeals provisions authorizing a Member of the House from transferring amounts from his or her Official Expenses Allowance and Clerk Hire Allowance to his or her Official Mail Allowance. Prohibits any: (1) Member of Congress from sending any unsolicited franked mail postmarked fewer than 60 days immediately before any primary or general election in which such Member is a candidate; and (2) Representative who is a candidate for any other public office from sending unsolicited franked mail outside his or her congressional district. Defines "unsolicited mailing" as all mail other than mail that is: (1) in direct response to a communication from a person to whom the matter is mailed; (2) from a Member of Congress to other Members; (3) of a news release to the communications media; or (4) in furtherance of the administrative duties of the Members of Congress. Requires the Clerk of the House to include (by separate category) the costs relating to franked, first class mass mailings in the statement made available to the public concerning the costs charged against the Official Mail Allowance for each person entitled to use the congressional frank.</summary>
</bill>
