<bill session="105" type="h" number="4840" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Savings Provision Technical Amendment Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make certain technical amendments to the Act commonly known as the Clinger-Cohen Act of 1996, and to provide that certain cost accounting standards shall not be applied to the Federal Employees Health Benefit program until the Cost Accounting Standards Board Review Panel submits its report and recommendations to Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1998-10-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/1998--Introduced.
Savings Provision Technical Amendment Act of 1998 - Amends the Clinger-Cohen Act of 1996 relating to information technology management to make certain savings provisions inapplicable to any decision of the General Services Board of Contract Appeals (whether or not such decision is subsequently vacated) that: (1) is issued in a proceeding involving a protest; (2) is issued after February 10, 1996, and before the effective date of such Act; and (3) declares that a delegation of procurement authority from the Administrator of General Services or another source should have been obtained, and that a contract is void for lack of such a delegation. Declares that, in the case of any decision of the Board covered by this Act, the Administrator: (1) shall take necessary actions to vacate the decision; and (2) may not decide any further protest with respect to the contract it declared void. Requires the contracting activity that awarded the contract that was declared void by such decision to: (1) deem the contract valid and in full effect; (2) adhere to the contract's terms; and (3) require performance of the contract to begin 15 days after enactment of this Act and continue for the number of years prescribed by the contract when awarded. States that the contract declared void by such decision shall not be subject to any other protest.</summary>
</bill>
