<bill session="104" type="h" number="2476" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense Medicare Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for common sense reforms of the medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1995-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="402762" joined="1995-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1995-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1995-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="406082" joined="1996-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1995-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Baby boom generation"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grand jury"/>
    <term name="Health care fraud"/>
    <term name="Health care reform"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicaid fraud"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Preferred provider organizations (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Prosthesis"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Fraud and Abuse Subtitle A: Provisions Relating to Durable Medical Equipment Subtitle B: Anti-Fraud Provisions Subtitle C: Health Care Fraud Abuse Account Title II: Medicare Plus Pilot Program Title III: Commission on the Effect of the Baby Boom Generation on the Medicare Program Title IV: Development of Single Medicare Administrative System Title V: Lock-Box Provision Common Sense Medicare Reform Act of 1995 - Title I: Fraud and Abuse - Subtitle A: Provisions Relating to Durable Medical Equipment - Revises the payment methodology under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) for durable medical equipment to provide for: (1) the use of competitive pricing to determine payment amounts; and (2) a permanent freeze in updates for covered items (starting in 1996) and orthotics and prosthetics (starting in 1995). Subtitle B: Anti-Fraud Provisions - Amends the Federal criminal code to provide for: (1) various specified sanctions for certain health care-related violations involving illegal remuneration in the form of kickbacks and other arrangements in connection with specified health care benefit programs; and (2) other specified changes relating to health care fraud and abuse and such matters as disclosure of grand jury information and investigations of acts or activities constituting or involving health care fraud. Subtitle C: Health Care Fraud Abuse Account - Establishes in the Treasury the HHS Fraud and Abuse Control Fund, consisting of deposits of penalties and other specified payments made pursuant to a court or administrative order or voluntary settlement agreement, in order to support various specified anti-fraud and abuse activities under the Medicare and Medicaid programs. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Medicare Plus Pilot Program - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a pilot program under which provider-sponsored networks, Taft-Hartley plans, association plans, and high-deductible health plans (with contributions to medical savings accounts) may qualify for payments to health maintenance organizations and competitive medical plans. Requires certain studies in conjunction with such program for a report to the Congress. Title III: Commission on the Effect of the Baby Boom Generation on the Medicare Program - Establishes the Commission on the Effect of the Baby Boom Generation on the Medicare Program to examine the financial impact on Medicare of the increase in Medicare-eligible individuals from approximately 2010 to 2035 for a report to the Congress, including specific recommendations for preserving Medicare. Authorizes appropriations. Title IV: Development of Single Medicare Administrative System - Directs the Secretary to take necessary steps to provide for improved Medicare efficiency through a common payment form for all Medicare payments and consolidated administration of Medicare parts A and B. Title V: Lock-Box Provision - Provides that all savings resulting from the enactment of this Act shall be transferred to the credit of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under Medicare part A and may not be used to offset revenue losses from a tax cut.</summary>
</bill>
