<bill session="108" type="h" number="2769" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Save Our Seniors Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit commercial importation of prescription drugs from Canada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400121"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2003-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400294" joined="2003-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2003-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Product counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2003--Introduced.
Save Our Seniors Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to permit pharmacists and wholesalers to import prescription drugs from Canada. Allows the Secretary to permit importation from European Union countries in three years if the Secretary finds that drugs imported from Canada have proven safe and effective. Requires: (1) safeguards to ensure that each prescription drug imported is safe and effective; (2) importers to submit to the Secretary detailed information about the drug and shipment; (3) Canadian distributors to register with the Secretary; (4) immediate suspension of importation of a drug or by an importer if a pattern of counterfeiting or violations of this Act are discovered; and (5) manufacturers to authorize the use of the approved labeling for the drug. Prohibits discrimination by manufacturers against wholesalers or pharmacists who distribute prescription drugs. Declares that the Secretary should waive the prohibition against importation of a drug when it is clearly for personal use and does not present an unreasonable risk to the individual. Requires the Secretary to grant such waivers under certain circumstances and to publish guidance as to when the Secretary will grant these waivers. Requires a study and report from: (1) the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences on importation under this Act; and (2) the Comptroller General on the effect this section has on the retail price of prescription drugs.</summary>
</bill>
