<bill session="104" type="hr" number="478" updated="2012-11-01T22:43:21-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide public access to committee documents over the Internet, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1996-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1996-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1996-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1996-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404332" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1996-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="1996-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1996-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1996-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1996-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1996-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="411214" joined="1996-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on House Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSRU" name="House Rules"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional allowances"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee membership"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee staffing"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Congressional witnesses"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative reference services"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>07/16/1996--Introduced.
Amends rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require the following information to be made available electronically on the Internet: (1) reports filed by committees, including the Committee on Rules; (2) committee approved measures; (3) committee rules; (4) committee roll call votes otherwise made available for public inspection; (5) copies of a committee authorizations for payment or reimbursement of travel expenses to be incurred by its members or staff; (6) committee amendments offered by committee members to measures under consideration; (7) any committee print or chairman's mark that is generally made available to members of the committee; (8) committee oversight plans submitted to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight and to the Committee on House Oversight; and (9) up-to-date directories of committee membership and staff, schedules and notices of committee activities, and any advance written statements submitted to a committee of proposed testimony unless it is to be presented in executive session, and transcripts of committee meetings or hearings within five calendar days. Provides an exception for the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence. Requires the Clerk of the House of Representatives to: (1) establish a central electronic data base of official documents to which committees may have access; (2) establish universal data elements respecting such official documents; and (3) implement standards established by the Committee on House Oversight with respect to the content of such data bases. Directs the Committee to establish standards to provide guidance to the Clerk and committees respecting electronic data bases which may be accessed by committees to effectuate the electronic document reform necessary to enable committees to carry out amendments to the Rules of the House pursuant to this Act. Encourages the Committee to develop such standards in consultation with the Senate so that identical standards can be implemented in both Chambers.</summary>
</bill>
