<bill session="107" type="h" number="4734" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Alaska Federal Lands Management Demonstration Project Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Alaska Federal Lands Management Demonstration Project Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand Alaska Native contracting of Federal land management functions and activities and to promote hiring of Alaska Natives by the Federal Government within the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2002-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E787-788"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-05">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Received from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-10-11T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-745.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-10-11T12:03:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="465">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 465.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/2002--Reported to House amended.
Alaska Federal Lands Management Demonstration Project Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct an Alaska Federal Lands Management Demonstration Project under which up to 12 Indian tribes or tribal organizations may contract to perform construction, maintenance, data collection, biological research, and harvest monitoring on conservation system units in Alaska.Requires the Secretary to select no fewer than six eligible, geographically representative tribes or tribal organizations per year to participate in the Project.Specifies eligibility requirements and priority selection criteria.Requires selected tribes and tribal organizations to complete a planning phase before contracting with the Secretary to perform specified services or functions related to conservation and allocation actions by regional Federal subsistence advisory councils.Permits the inclusion in a contract, at the tribe or tribal organization's request, of benefits, privileges, terms, and conditions of agreements entered under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act.Excludes from authorized contracts: (1) revenue-producing visitor services unless agreed to by the Alaska Native corporations most directly affected; and (2) authority to administer, manage, or oversee permits, licenses, or contracts related to sport hunting and fishing guiding activities. Declares that Denali National Park shall not be subject to this Act.Provides for planning grants, as funds permit.Authorizes appropriations.Directs the Secretary to establish a demonstration project with the Koyukuk River Basin Moose Co-Management Team, Inc., for the provision of services at the Koyukuk and Kanuti National Wildlife Refuges.Authorizes the use of intergovernmental personnel actions to assign Federal employees to the contractor while retaining their Federal employment status.</summary>
</bill>
