<bill session="106" type="hc" number="299" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing fragile X as the most common inherited cause of mental retardation and as a powerful research model for other disorders, urging increased funding for research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400540"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2000-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Genetic screening"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Hereditary diseases"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental retardation"/>
    <term name="Mentally disabled children"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/5/2000--Introduced.
States that the Congress: (1) recognizes the devastating impact of fragile X on thousands of Americans; (2) recognizes the leadership of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, the National Institute of Mental Health, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in research efforts to find a cure for fragile X and related disorders; (3) calls on these and other sources of Federal and private research funds to enhance and increase their efforts and commitments to fragile X research; and (4) calls on medical schools and other health educators, medical societies and associations, and Federal, State, and local health care facilities to learn, teach, and promote awareness of the incidence, causes, symptoms, effects, and treatment of fragile X and support screening of newborns for fragile X to permit early intervention and treatment.</summary>
</bill>
