<bill session="106" type="h" number="2117" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require any amounts appropriated for Members' Representational Allowances for the House of Representatives for a session of Congress that remain after all payments are made from such Allowances for the session to be deposited in the Treasury and used for deficit reduction or to reduce the Federal debt.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1200"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional allowances"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/1999--Introduced.
Requires any amounts appropriated for a representational allowance for a Member of the House of Representatives which remain after all payments are made under such allowance to be deposited in the Treasury and used for deficit reduction or, for a session of Congress or other period for which there is no Federal budget deficit, to reduce the Federal debt. Requires the Committee on Appropriations of the House to include in its report accompanying the annual appropriations bill for the legislative branch a statement of such amount deposited for the preceding calendar year with respect to each Member of the House and the total deposited with respect to all Members.</summary>
</bill>
