<bill session="104" type="hj" number="134" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-01-06">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Continuing Appropriation (ninth)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406863"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T19:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 317 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 134 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the joint resolution in the House. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit, whch may include instructions only if offered by the Minority Leader or his designee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T20:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 317 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T20:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 317.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15295-15308" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T20:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 134 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the joint resolution in the House. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit, which may include instructions only if offered by the Minority Leader or his designee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T20:33:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T21:46:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T21:51:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T21:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T21:52:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T21:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Livingston raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Livingston stated that the content of the amendment contained in the motion dealt with funding and authorizing activities outside the Department of Veterans Affairs and was, therefore, not germane to the underlying resolution. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T21:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T21:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T21:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Livingston moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T22:17:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair Agreed to by recorded vote: 236 - 176 (Roll no. 872).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T22:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T22:19:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Obey motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T22:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T22:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Livingston raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Livingston stated that the amendment contained in the motion dealt with funding and authorizing activities outside the Department of Veterans Affairs and was therefore not germane to the underlying resolution. Sustained by the Chair. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T22:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T22:23:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Obey motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T22:27:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T22:43:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 178 - 234 (Roll no. 873).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15307" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-12-20T22:59:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="874" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 411 - 1 (Roll no. 874).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20T22:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-12-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="298">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 298.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S19197-19205" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 3110 proposed by Senator Lott for Senator Hatfield.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 3110 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1995-12-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05T14:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 336 Reported to House. Providing for the disposition of the Senate amendment to H.J. Res. 134 in the House. Upon adoption of this resolution the House shall be considered to have taken from the Spearker's table the joint resolution H.J. Res. 134, with the Senate amendment thereto, and to have concurred in the Senate amendment with an amendment consisting of the text printed in the report accompanying this resolution. The House shall also be considered to have adopted H. Con. Res. 131.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05T18:08:00-05:00">
      <text>House agreed to Senate amendment with amendment pursuant to H. Res. 336.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H240" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-01-05" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendment to the Senate amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S86" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-01-05">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1996-01-06">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-01-06">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-01-06" type="public" number="104-94">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-94.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hc" number="131"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="317"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hr" number="336"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="336"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hr" number="336"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Gay marriage"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homosexuality"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Lesbians"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Support of dependents"/>
    <term name="Unmarried couples"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3110"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>1/5/1996--House agreed to Senate amendment with amendment.
Makes continuing appropriations, in any case during FY 1996 in which appropriations are not otherwise available for the programs and activities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to ensure payment of the following: (1) existing veterans' benefits; and (2) Veterans Health Administration contractors when due for services provided that relate directly to patient health and safety. Defines existing benefits as those that have been adjudicated and authorized for payment as of: (1) December 15, 1995; or (2) if appropriations for such benefits are available (other than as provided for above) after December 15, 1995, the last day on which appropriations for payment of such benefits are available.</summary>
</bill>
