<bill session="104" type="hc" number="171" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Condemning the proposed relocation to the site of the Jasenovac death camp in Croatia of the remains of individuals who were not killed there, including soldiers of the Croatian Ustashe regime who participated during the Holocaust in the mass murder of Jews and others.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1996-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1996-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400334" joined="1996-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1996-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Concentration camps"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Croatia"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="National socialism"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/1996--Introduced.
Condemns the proposed relocation to the site of the Jasenovac death camp in Croatia of the remains of individuals who were not killed there, including soldiers of the Croatian Ustashe regime who participated in mass murders during the Holocaust. Calls on: (1) the Secretary of State to condemn strongly this proposed relocation, to demand that President Tudjman disavow it, and, in conjunction with our allies, to express unified opposition to such relocation and to demand its disavowal; and (2) the Chairman of the United States Holocaust Memorial Council to study such relocation, to educate the public about the dangers of denial and revisionism relating to the Holocaust, and to report to the Congress on such activities.</summary>
</bill>
