<bill session="108" type="h" number="835" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clearwater Basin Project Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for enhanced collaborative forest stewardship management within the Clearwater and Nez Perce National Forests in Idaho, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2003-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E251"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Weeds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife reintroduction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2003--Introduced.
Clearwater Basin Project Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish and maintain the Clearwater Advisory Panel (CAP), which shall provide advice and recommendations to the Forest Service regarding the Clearwater Basin pilot project (the Project) within the Clearwater and Nez Perce National Forests, Idaho. States that the CAP shall: (1) make recommendations regarding activities for high priority implementation; (2) provide early and continuous coordination with Federal officials; and (3) provide for public input into its proceedings.Directs the CAP, in consultation with and receiving technical assistance from the applicable Forest Supervisor, to develop and submit for approval from the Forest Supervisor five-year schedules of high priority activities for the Project (with separate schedules for each Forest). Requires that the activities included in such schedules have funding authorized and appropriated under this Act or other law and that they be consistent with the applicable forest land and resource management plan. Directs the Forest Service to complete any applicable National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) procedures for the approval of the activities at the site-specific, project level. Directs the CAP to consult with the Nez Perce Tribe in developing and recommending each schedule.Directs the Forest Supervisor to issue a project or activity decision document regarding approval of the recommended schedule in accordance with NEPA and other applicable procedures.Provides for the schedules and activities authorized under this section to supplement certain other schedules, plans, and projects or other activities authorized and implemented under other law.</summary>
</bill>
