<bill session="105" type="h" number="4550" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-16T20:06:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-09-16T20:06:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Drug Demand Reduction bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drug Demand Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Antiaddiction Medication Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Media Campaign Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free National Clearinghouse Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Parents Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Prisons and Jails Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Schools Quality Assurance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Teenage Drivers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Workplace Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Drug Demand Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Antiaddiction Medication Development Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Media Campaign Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free National Clearinghouse Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Parents Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Prisons and Jails Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Schools Quality Assurance Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Teenage Drivers Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Drug-Free Workplace Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for programs to facilitate a significant reduction in the incidence and prevalence of substance abuse through reducing the demand for illegal drugs and the inappropriate use of legal drugs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404587" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400169" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1998-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1998-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1998-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1998-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Government Reform and Oversight, Small Business, Transportation and Infrastructure, the Judiciary, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Security, International Affairs and Criminal Justice.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15T20:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 538 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4550 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule for a period not to exceed three hours. Before consideration of any other amendment it shall be in order to consider the amendment printed in House Report 105-721, the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying the resolution if offered by a Member designated in the report. After disposition of the amendment, the provisions of the bill as then perfected shall be considered as original test for futher amendment under the five-minute rule. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. The Chairman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whethe...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 538 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 538.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7863-7888" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4550 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule for a period not to exceed three hours. Before consideration of any other amendment it shall be in order to consider the amendment printed in House Report 105-721, the report of the Committee on Rule accompanying the resolution if offered by a Member designated in the report. After disposition of the amendment, the provisions of the bill as then perfected shall be considered as original test for futher amendment under the five-minute rule. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. The Chairman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whethe...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 538 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Scott McInnis to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T18:48:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the completion of debate the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment by voice vote and announced that that ayes had prevailed. Mr. Barrett of Wisconsin demanded a recorded vote pending the absence of a quorum. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 538, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment and the point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T19:21:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business of the Committee was the postponed recorded vote on the Taylor of Mississippi amendment debated earlier.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T19:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4550.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T19:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T19:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the remaining amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-09-16T20:06:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="444" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 396 - 9 (Roll No. 444).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T20:06:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 4550.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T20:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-21">
      <text>See H.R.4328.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO06" subcommittee="National Security, International Affairs and Criminal Justice" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="538"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="4328"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism treatment"/>
    <term name="Automobile insurance"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Driver tests"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug addiction"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drug legalization"/>
    <term name="Drug policy"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Drugs and crime"/>
    <term name="Drugs and employment"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Employee assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to substance abuse programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smoking and youth"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h891"/>
    <amendment number="h892"/>
    <amendment number="h893"/>
    <amendment number="h894"/>
    <amendment number="h895"/>
    <amendment number="h896"/>
    <amendment number="h897"/>
    <amendment number="h898"/>
    <amendment number="h899"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/16/1998--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Targeted Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Programs Subtitle A: National Youth Anti-Drug Media Campaign Subtitle B: Drug-Free Workplace Act Subtitle C: Drug-Free Teen Drivers Subtitle D: Drug-Free Prisons and Jails Subtitle E: Drug-Free Schools Quality Assurance Subtitle F: Drug-Free National Clearinghouse Subtitle G: Drug-Free Parents Empowerment Title II: Private Sector Anti-Drug Partnerships Subtitle A: Antiaddiction Medications Subtitle B: Commission on Role of Medication Education in Reducing Substance Abuse Title III: Statement of National Antidrug Policy Subtitle A: Congressional Leadership in Community Coalitions Subtitle B: Rejection of Legalization of Drugs Subtitle C: Report on Streamlining Federal Prevention and Treatment Efforts Drug Demand Reduction Act - Title I: Targeted Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Programs - Subtitle A: National Youth Anti-Drug Media Campaign - Drug-Free Media Campaign Act of 1998 - Requires the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy to: (1) conduct a national media campaign for the purpose of reducing and preventing drug abuse among young people in the United States; and (2) use appropriated funds for media that focuses on, or that includes specific information on, prevention or treatment resources for consumers within specific local areas. (Sec. 103) Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) authorized and prohibited uses of funds; and (2) matching and reporting requirements. (Sec. 105) Authorizes appropriations. Subtitle B: Drug-Free Workplace Act - Drug-Free Workplace Act of 1998 - Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) businesses should adopt drug-free workplace programs; and (2) States should consider financial incentives, such as reductions in workers' compensation premiums, to encourage businesses to adopt drug-free workplace programs. (Sec. 114) Amends the Small Business Act to establish a drug-free workplace demonstration program, under which the Small Business Administration may make grants to eligible intermediaries for the purpose of providing financial and technical assistance to small business concerns seeking to start a drug-free workplace program. Sets forth provisions regarding eligibility for participation and program requirements, including requirements for: (1) employee drug testing by a laboratory certified by the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration or the College of American Pathologists, with each positive test result reviewed by a Licensed Medical Review Officer; and (2) employee access to an employee assistance program, including treatment. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 115) Amends the Act to require the services to be provided by small business development centers to include providing information and assistance to small business concerns with respect to developing drug-free workplace programs. (Sec. 116) Authorizes the Small Business Administrator to contract with and compensate Government and private agencies or persons for services related to carrying out this subtitle. Subtitle C: Drug-Free Teen Drivers - Drug-Free Teenage Drivers Act - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a model program to provide for the voluntary drug testing of all teenage applicants for a driver's license and, if a State adopting the program so elects, other first time applicants regardless of age. Sets forth minimum program requirements, including: (1) that information about an applicant's choice not to take a drug test or about the result of a test on the applicant be made available to the applicant's automobile insurance company, if any, or the parent of a teenage applicant, or both; and (2) if an applicant tests positive, that the State will not issue a license to the applicant and will require the applicant to complete a State-approved drug treatment program and not test positive in a drug test before reapplying for a license. Authorizes the States to adopt and implement the model program and, if they do so, to provide treatment to low-income individuals who apply for licenses. (Sec. 123) Requires the Secretary to establish an incentive grant program to assist States in improving their laws relating to controlled substances and driving. Sets forth grant requirements, including provisions regarding the use of grant funds and a formula for determining grant amounts. (Sec. 124) Directs the Secretary to provide specified technical assistance. (Sec. 125) Authorizes appropriations. Subtitle D: Drug-Free Prisons and Jails - Drug-Free Prisons and Jails Act of 1998 - Requires the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to establish a model substance abuse treatment program for substance-involved offenders by providing financial assistance to grant recipients and evaluating the success of programs conducted pursuant to this subtitle. Limits grant awards and administrative costs. (Sec. 134) Sets forth requirements for grant applications, review and approval of awards, permissible uses of funds, and evaluation and reporting requirements. Requires the Director to establish minimum criteria for program evaluation. (Sec. 138) Authorizes appropriations from the Violent Crime Reduction Trust Fund. Subtitle E: Drug-Free Schools Quality Assurance - Drug-Free Schools Quality Assurance Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require the chief executive officer of each State or other entity designated to be responsible for education activities to: (1) establish a standard of quality for drug prevention programs implemented in public schools in the State in accordance with specified criteria (including a comparison of the rate of illegal use of alcohol, tobacco, and drugs by students enrolled over a specified period, the rate of suspensions or expulsions, program effectiveness, parental and community involvement, and the extent of review of existing community drug prevention programs before implementation); and (2) identify and designate (upon application by a school) any public school that achieves such standard as a quality program school. Sets forth provisions regarding requests for a quality program designation and public notification. Subtitle F: Drug-Free National Clearinghouse - Drug-Free National Clearinghouse Act of 1998 - Establishes in the Office the Drug-Free National Clearinghouse, which shall: (1) consolidate and assume the drug prevention and drug treatment information clearinghouse roles currently performed by National Drug Control Program agencies; and (2) ensure that such information is effectively disseminated. (Sec. 163) Requires that the Clearinghouse be headed by a director to be appointed by the Director of the Office. Sets forth the director's duties. (Sec. 164) Requires each National Drug Control Program agency to cooperate with the Clearinghouse director. Subtitle G: Drug-Free Parents Empowerment - Drug-Free Parents Empowerment Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to support the efforts of parent organizations to develop and promote efforts to reduce illegal drug use among children in their communities. Sets forth requirements for parent organizations to receive grants, application procedures, and a grant amount limitation. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Private Sector Anti-Drug Partnerships - Subtitle A: Antiaddiction Medications - Antiaddiction Medication Development Act - Requires the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and the Attorney General of the United States to provide to the Director of the National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA) a response to specified requests to facilitate the approval for commercial distribution of antiaddiction drugs developed by NIDA. Sets forth provisions regarding the submission of, and responses to, such requests. (Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a study to determine whether there is a need to establish particularized incentives for the development of drugs to treat dependence on alcohol or on any controlled substance (qualifying antiaddiction drugs). Sets forth requirements regarding Federal agency collaboration, study elements, and reporting requirements. Subtitle B: Commission on Role of Medication Education in Reducing Substance Abuse - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish the National Commission on the Role of Medical Education in Reducing Substance Abuse, which shall conduct a study to determine the manner in which programs of initial and continuing medical education can be modified to improve the efforts of health professionals in preventing, diagnosing, and treating substance abuse cases. Sets forth reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Statement of National Antidrug Policy - Subtitle A: Congressional Leadership in Community Coalitions - Expresses the sense of the Congress that the individual Members of the House of Representatives should establish community-based anti-drug coalitions in their congressional districts or should actively support such coalitions that already exist. Subtitle B: Rejection of Legalization of Drugs - Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the States and their citizens should reject drug legalization; and (2) every State should make efforts to be drug-free. Subtitle C: Report on Streamlining Federal Prevention and Treatment Efforts - Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) Federal Government efforts to reduce the demand for illegal drugs in the United States are frustrated by the fragmentation of those efforts across multiple departments and agencies; and (2) improvement of those efforts can best be achieved through consolidation and coordination. Requires the Director of National Drug Control Policy to prepare and submit to specified congressional committees a report evaluating options for increasing the efficacy of Federal drug prevention and treatment programs and activities. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
