<bill session="105" type="h" number="467" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commodity Exchange Act Amendments of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Commodity Exchange Act to provide a conditional exemption for certain transactions involving professional markets, to clarify the effect of the designation of a board of trade as a contract market, to simplify the process for implementing contract market rules, to regulate audit trail requirements, to establish cost-benefit analysis requirements, to combat fraud in transactions in or involving foreign currency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400581"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E131"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Risk Management and Specialty Crops.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commodity Futures Trading Com.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-18">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received from Commodity Futures Trading Com.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSAG24" subcommittee="Risk Management and Specialty Crops" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Chambers of commerce"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange futures"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Options (Contract)"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Administration of Commodity Exchange Act Title II: Treasury Amendment Clarification Commodity Exchange Act Amendments of 1997 - Title I: Administration of Commodity Exchange Act - Amends the Commodity Exchange Act (CEA) to provide a conditional exemption for certain transactions involving professional markets. Revises requirements for the designation of a board of trade as a contract market. Revises the process for the submission and disapproval of contract market rules. Revises provisions for regulation of audit trail requirements. Requires the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to prescribe an objective standard or methodology for establishing whether a contract market meets certain requirements for being able to determine, with reasonable accuracy, the time of contract execution, in increments of at most one minute in length. Sets forth criteria for the trade recordation data (including time stamps) that an audit trail system for a contract market shall rely on. Establishes requirements for use of cost-benefit analysis. Repeals specified provisions relating to Commodity Futures Trading Commission oversight and deficiency orders. Title II: Treasury Amendment Clarification - Amends CEA to define board of trade, as it applies to transactions in or involving foreign currency, as any facility whereby standardized contracts are systematically marketed to retail investors.</summary>
</bill>
