<bill session="104" type="h" number="1297" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">New Urban Agenda Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote a new urban agenda, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1995-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1995-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="407226" joined="1995-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="408976" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1995-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Banking and Financial Services, Science, Commerce, Transportation and Infrastructure, Government Reform and Oversight, and International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-22">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-22">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-22">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-22">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-22">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-22">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-22">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Buildings and Economic Development.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW08" subcommittee="Public Buildings and Economic Development" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Convention facilities"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy consumption"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Farms"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Household moving"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Industrial development bonds"/>
    <term name="Industrial parks"/>
    <term name="Industry"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports facilities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban economic development"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Federal Commitment to Urban Economic Development Title II: Tax Incentives to Stimulate Urban Economic Development Title III: Community-Based Housing Development Title IV: Response to Urban Environmental Challenges Subtitle A: Environmental Cleanup Subtitle B: Environmental-Economic Recovery New Urban Agenda Act of 1995 - Title I: Federal Commitment to Urban Economic Development - Amends the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to require executive agencies to expend not less than 15 percent in a fiscal year for the purchase of goods from businesses located in empowerment zones, enterprise communities, or enterprise zones. Requires agencies, to the maximum extent practicable, to purchase recycled products from businesses located in such zones. (Sec. 102) Requires not less than 15 percent of foreign assistance provided in a fiscal year to be in the form of credits for the purchase of U.S. goods produced, manufactured, or assembled in such zones. (Sec. 103) Directs the Secretary of Commerce, in designating and providing financial assistance to Manufacturing Technology Outreach Centers, to give preference to centers located in such zones. (Sec. 104) Establishes a preference for the construction, improvement, or relocation of Federal facilities in distressed urban areas. Title II: Tax Incentives to Stimulate Urban Economic Development - Amends the Internal Revenue Code with respect to the offset for rental real estate activities under passive activity rules to increase the rehabilitation credit under such rules. (Sec. 202) Allows the rehabilitation investment credit to offset a portion of tentative minimum tax. (Sec. 203) Allows the issuance of tax-exempt facility bonds for sports facilities, convention or trade show facilities, freestanding parking facilities, air or water pollution control facilities, or industrial parks. Makes termination dates on such tax-exempt bonds inapplicable to bonds issued to finance manufacturing facilities. (Sec. 204) Increases the permitted amount of qualified small issue bonds for facilities to be used by related persons. (Sec. 205) Provides an exception to arbitrage interest rebate provisions if 100 percent of available construction proceeds are spent for governmental purposes within three years of the issuance of the tax-exempt bonds. Title III: Community-Based Housing Development - Provides, subject to the approval of both the unit of general local government and the local public housing agency, for the reconstruction of public housing dwelling units on the same property on which such units were demolished or disposed, and for the relocation of displaced tenants to such new units. Title IV: Response to Urban Environmental Challenges - Subtitle A: Environmental Cleanup - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to exclude local governments that are owners or operators of facilities in distressed urban areas from liability under such Act. Requires the President to establish standards for the degree of cleanup of hazardous substances, pollutants, and contaminants released into the environment for facilities located in distressed urban areas. Subtitle B: Environmental-Economic Recovery - Authorizes the Secretary of Energy to make no more than three loans to units of local government for distressed urban areas for the establishment of facilities to dispose of, and obtain inexpensive electrical power and steam from, solid waste. Requires a report to the Congress on the results of financing such facilities.</summary>
</bill>
