<bill session="107" type="hc" number="511" updated="2013-07-14T18:59:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Congratulating the people and Government of the Republic of Kazakhstan on the eleventh anniversary of the independence of the Republic of Kazakhstan and praising longstanding and growing friendship between the United States and Kazakhstan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2002-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-16">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Antiamerican demonstrations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Emigration"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Kazakhstan"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/16/2002--Introduced.
Congratulates the people and Government of the Republic of Kazakhstan on the 11th anniversary of its independence and the establishment of diplomatic relations with the United States and for its achievements in economic development. Calls upon the Government of Kazakhstan to further carry out democratic reforms. Expresses gratitude for the support and assistance of the people of Kazakhstan in the antiterrorist campaign. Applauds the decision of Kazakhstan's leadership to renounce the deployment of its inherited nuclear weapons.Calls on the President to expand: (1) assistance for environmental rehabilitation programs in Semipalatinsk and the Aral Sea region; and (2) cultural and educational exchange programs with the Central Asian countries, particularly Kazakhstan.Welcomes the agreement with Kazakhstan (the Houston Initiative) aimed at maintaining and developing relations between small and medium sized businesses in the two countries. Recognizes the need to terminate the application of the Jackson-Vanik amendment and provide permanent normal trade relations status to Kazakhstan. Praises President Nazarbayev's initiative to convene the Conference on Interaction and Confidence Building Measures in Asia. Urges further strengthening of strategically important relations between Kazakhstan and the United States.</summary>
</bill>
