<bill session="105" type="h" number="4224" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Schools Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure safety in public schools by increasing police presence.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400143"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="1998-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="401033" joined="1998-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1998-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400578" joined="1998-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1998-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1998-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1998-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1998-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1998-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1998-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1998-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1998-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1998-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="1998-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1998-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Black police"/>
    <term name="Community policing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Police-community relations"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="School violence"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/1998--Introduced.
Safe Schools Act of 1998 - Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) make grants to States, local governments, Indian tribal governments, and other public and private entities and multijurisdictional or regional consortia thereof, to increase police presence, and expand and improve cooperative efforts between law enforcement agencies and members of the community, to address crime and disorder problems in and around schools; (2) give preferential consideration for such grants to applications for hiring and rehiring additional career law enforcement officers that involve a non-Federal contribution exceeding a 25 percent minimum; and (3) provide technical assistance to further the purposes of this Act. Limits the costs of a program, project, or activity provided by such a grant to 75 percent, unless the Attorney General waives the requirement of a non-Federal contribution. Directs that the Federal share decrease from year to year for up to five years, in relation to a grant for a period exceeding one year for hiring or rehiring career law enforcement officers, looking toward the continuation of the increased hiring level using State or local sources of funding following the conclusion of Federal support. Terminates authority for grants to hire officers after six years. Directs the Attorney General, prior to the expiration of such authority, to report to the Congress. Authorizes the use of grants under this Act to: (1) rehire law enforcement officers who have been laid off as a result of State and local budget reductions for deployment in school-based policing; and (2) hire and train new, additional career law enforcement officers for deployment in school-based policing across the Nation. Sets forth application requirements, including requirements that applications demonstrate a specific public safety need and specify plans for obtaining necessary support and continuing the proposed activity following the conclusion of Federal support. Authorizes the Attorney General to waive specified requirements and make special provisions to facilitate the expedited submission, processing, and approval of applications of local government or law enforcement agencies having jurisdiction over areas with populations of less than 50,000. Sets forth provisions regarding monitoring and evaluation of activities funded under this Act and revocation or suspension of funding. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
