<bill session="107" type="h" number="5521" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-02T15:36:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-02T15:36:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the government of the District of Columbia and other activities chargeable in whole or in part against the revenues of said District for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400225"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 107-716, by Mr. Knollenberg.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-10-02T15:36:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="446">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 446.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="2809"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism treatment"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Asbestos abatement"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Baseball"/>
    <term name="Boycott"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Capital budgets"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Chief financial officers"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="City councils"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining in government"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Community policing"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional delegations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Contraceptives"/>
    <term name="Convention facilities"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug legalization"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disabled students"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee-management relations in government"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to adult education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to disability services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to substance abuse programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Forensic medicine"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Halfway houses"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Kindergarten"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to the poor"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Lotteries"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marijuana"/>
    <term name="Mayors"/>
    <term name="Medicinal plants"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Mentally disabled"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Military civic action"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Municipal buildings"/>
    <term name="Municipal employees"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Municipal home rule"/>
    <term name="Municipal politics and government"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Municipal taxation"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Needle exchange programs"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Public defenders"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Rating of teachers"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Sexual abstinence"/>
    <term name="Sick leave"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports facilities"/>
    <term name="Statehood (American politics)"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tobacco settlement"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Unmarried couples"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban economic development"/>
    <term name="Urban transportation"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Waterfronts"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2002--Reported to House without amendment.
District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2003 - Makes appropriations to the District of Columbia for FY 2003, including amounts for the Federal payments: (1) for District of Columbia Resident Tuition Support; (2) for emergency planning and security costs in the District; (3) to District of Columbia Courts; (4) for Defender Services in District of Columbia Courts; (5) to the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia (including transfer of funds); (6) to the Department of Transportation in the District; (7) to the Chief Financial Officer of the District; (8) to continue improvements on the Potomac Southwest Waterfront; (9) to reimburse Fairfax County, Virginia, for asbestos remediation on the former site of the Lorton Correctional Complex; (10) to the D.C. Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department to repair, renovate, and rehabilitate fire stations in need of capital improvements; (11) to the D.C. Public Education System for special education transportation services and satellite facilities; (12) to the Credit Enhancement Revolving Fund; (13) for the Family Literacy Program; (14) to the D.C. Water and Sewer Authority to begin implementing the Combined Sewer Overflow Long-Term Plan; and (15) for capital infrastructure development.Appropriates specified sums out of the District's general fund and/or other funds for the current fiscal year for: (1) operating expenses (with limitations); (2) governmental direction and support; (3) economic development and regulation; (4) public safety and justice; (5) the public education system (including transfer of funds); (6) human support services (including transfer of funds); (7) public works; (8) the Reserve; (9) the Emergency and Contingency Reserve Fund; (10) repayment of certain loans and interest; (11) repayment of General Fund Recovery Debt; (12) payment of interest on short-term borrowing; (13) for principal and interest payments on the District's Certificates of Participation, issued to finance the ground lease underlying the building located at One Judiciary Square; (14) refunds and for the payment of legal settlements or judgments that have been entered against the District government; (15) the John A. Wilson Building; (16) workforce investments; (17) the Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund; (18) for certain non-departmental agency costs; (19) pay-as-you-go capital in lieu of capital financing; (20) for the District's costs of public safety expenses related to National Special Security Events and for the costs of providing support to respond to immediate and specific terrorist threats or attacks in the District or surrounding jurisdictions; (21) the Water and Sewer Authority; (22) the Washington Aqueduct; (23) the Stormwater Permit Compliance Enterprise Fund; (24) the Lottery and Charitable Games Enterprise Fund; (25) the Sports and Entertainment Commission; (26) the District of Columbia Retirement Board; (27) the Washington Convention Center Enterprise Fund; (28) the National Capital Revitalization Corporation; and (29) capital outlay (including rescissions).Sets forth authorized or prohibited uses of funds appropriated by this Act identical or similar to corresponding provisions of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2002.(Sec. 117) Prohibits the expenditure of funds appropriated under this Act for abortions except where the mother's life would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term or in cases of rape or incest.(Sec. 118) Bars the use of funds under this Act to implement or enforce: (1) the District of Columbia Health Care Benefits Expansion Act of 1992 (also known as the District Domestic Partner Act); or (2) any system of registration of unmarried, cohabiting couples for purposes of extending them benefits on the same basis as such benefits are extended to legally married couples.(Sec. 123) Prohibits the use of Federal funds contained in this Act: (1) by the District of Columbia Corporation Counsel or any other District government officer or entity to provide assistance for any petition drive or civil action which seeks to require Congress to provide for voting representation in Congress for the District; (2) for any program of distributing sterile needles or syringes for the hypodermic injection of any illegal drug (requires individuals or entities who do so to account for all funds used for such program separately from any funds contained in this Act); (3) 60 days after its enactment to pay the salary of any chief financial officer of any District government office who has not filed a certification with the Mayor and Chief Financial Officer that the officer understands the duties and restrictions applicable, including reports required as a result of this Act or its amendments; or (4) to enact or carry out any law, rule, or regulation to legalize or otherwise reduce penalties associated with the possession, use, or distribution of any schedule I substance under the Controlled Substances Act or any tetrahydrocannabinols (THC) derivative.(Sec. 126) Provides that the Legalization of Marijuana for Medical Treatment Initiative of 1998, also known as Initiative 59, approved by the electors of the District on November 3, 1998, shall not take effect.(Sec. 127) Provides that nothing in this Act may be construed to prevent the Council or the Mayor of the District of Columbia from addressing the issue of the provision of contraceptive coverage by health insurance plans. Expresses the intent of Congress that any legislation enacted on such issue should include a "conscience clause" which provides exceptions for religious beliefs and moral convictions.(Sec. 128) Requires the Superior Court of the District of Columbia or the District of Columbia Court of Appeals to assign interest on a voucher submitted by a court-appointed attorney for payment if the voucher is not paid within 45 days of its submission.(Sec. 129) Requires the Mayor to report quarterly to specified congressional committees on the following District issues: (1) crime; (2) access to drug abuse treatment; (3) management of parolees and pre-trial violent offenders; (4) education; (5) improvement in basic District services, including rat control and abatement; (6) application for and management of Federal grants; and (7) indicators of child well-being.(Sec. 130) Postpones from October 1 to February 15 of each fiscal year the deadline by which the Mayor must deposit in cash into the contingency reserve fund the amount required to maintain a fund balance of at least three percent of the total budget appropriated for operating expenditures for such fiscal year which is derived from local funds.(Sec. 132) Prohibits the funds contained in this Act from being used to issue, administer, or enforce any order by the District of Columbia Commission on Human Rights relating to docket numbers 93-030-(PA) and 93-031-(PA) (In The Matter Of: Roland D. Pool and Michael S. Geller (Boy Scouts' Policy of Excluding Homosexuals)).(Sec. 133) Prohibits the transfer of any Federal funds to any Federal department, agency, or instrumentality, except pursuant to a transfer made by, or transfer authority provided in, this Act or any other appropriation Act.(Sec. 134) Requires that all funds from the Crime Victims Compensation Fund designated for outreach activities be deposited in the Crime Victims Assistance Fund for such purposes.(Sec. 135) Requires the District of Columbia Courts to transfer to the D.C. Treasury all fines levied and collected by the Courts in cases charging Driving Under the Influence and Driving While Impaired. Requires the Office of the Corporation Counsel to use such funds for enforcement and prosecution of District traffic alcohol laws.(Sec. 136) Prohibits any reprogramming of amounts in the annual budget adopted for a non-control fiscal year, unless: (1) the Mayor submits a request for reprogramming to the Chief Financial Officer (CFO); (2) the CFO certifies to the Council the availability of the funds for such reprogramming; and (3) the Council approves.(Sec. 137) Allows funds appropriated in this Act to any agency to be transferred to the Office of Labor Relations and Collective Bargaining (OLRCB) to pay for OLRCB representation in third-party cases, grievances, and dispute resolution.(Sec. 138) Requires the District of Columbia to submit to Congress a revised financial plan and budget for the District Government FY 2003 that will ensure a balanced budget.</summary>
</bill>
