<bill session="105" type="h" number="190" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Act entitled "An Act to provide for the establishment of the Everglades National Park in the State of Florida and for other purposes", approved May 30, 1934, to clarify certain rights of the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1997-01-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Indian hunting and fishing rights"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Amends Federal law relating to the Everglades National Park to allow the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida to use the Permit Area (property described in the Special Use Permit issued by the National Park Service (NPS) to the Tribe, approved by the Secretary of the Interior on February 1, 1973), in accordance with such Permit, except that: (1) specified conditions of the Permit which relate to removal of improvements or revocation of the Permit shall not apply; (2) notwithstanding any condition of the Permit, the approval of, the consent of, or a permit from the NPS Director and the Superintendent of the Everglades National Park shall not be required if the Tribe has met all other requirements of Federal law related to such approval, consent, or permit; and (3) the Tribe may exercise jurisdiction over such Permit Area to the same extent as it exercises jurisdiction over its Indian Reservation.</summary>
</bill>
