<bill session="107" type="h" number="2603" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-09-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States-Jordan Free Trade Area Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">United States-Jordan Free Trade Area Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">United States-Jordan Free Trade Area Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">United States-Jordan Free Trade Area Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To implement the agreement establishing a United States-Jordan free trade area.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-07-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31T10:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 107-176, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31T10:01:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 31, 2001.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31T10:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-07-31T10:03:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="105">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 105.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31T10:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31T10:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4871-4881" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31T10:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2603.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-07-31T11:05:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4871-4873" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24">
      <text>Senate Committee on Finance discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9679-9693" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2001-09-24" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2001-09-24">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2001-09-25">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2001-09-28">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2001-09-28" type="public" number="107-43">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 107-43.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="1484"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="643"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Dyes and dyeing"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Jordan"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="U.S. International Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2001--Passed House amended.
United States-Jordan Free Trade Area Implementation Act - Title I: Tariff Modifications; Rules of Origin - Authorizes the President to proclaim such modifications or continuation of duty, continuation of duty-free or excise treatment, or additional duties as are deemed necessary or appropriate to carry out the Agreement between the United States of America and the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan on the Establishment of a Free Trade Area (Agreement), entered into on October 24, 2000. Sets forth certain rules of origin with respect to the reduction or elimination of any duty imposed by the United States on Jordanian textile, fabric, or apparel articles as provided in such Agreement.Title II: Relief From Imports - Subtitle A: General Provisions - Defines specified terms.Subtitle B: Relief From Imports Benefitting From the Agreement - Directs the International Trade Commission (ITC), upon the filing of a petition by an entity (including a trade association, firm, certified or recognized union, or group of workers representative of an industry) requesting trade relief from U.S. obligations under the Agreement (or alleging that critical circumstances exist), to initiate an investigation to determine whether, as a result of the reduction or elimination of a duty provided for under the Agreement, a Jordanian article is being imported into the United States in such increased quantities and under such conditions that such imports alone constitute a substantial cause of serious injury or threat thereof to the domestic industry producing an article that is like, or directly competitive with, the imported article. Prescribes a procedure for ITC action on such a petition. Requires the President, upon an affirmative determination by the ITC, to provide necessary import relief (including suspension of any further duty reduction, or an increase in the rate duty, on imported Jordanian articles under the Agreement) and facilitate domestic industry efforts to make a positive adjustment to import competition, unless the provision of such relief is not in the U.S. national economic interest, or in extraordinary circumstances, the provision of relief would cause serious harm to U.S. national security.Subtitle C: Cases Under Title II of the Trade Act of 1974 - Requires the ITC, if an affirmative determination about import competition has been made under the Trade Act of 1974, also to find whether imports of Jordanian articles are a substantial cause of serious injury or threat. Requires the President to review such a determination, and authorizes exclusion of such Jordanian imports from remedial action if the final determination is negative.Title III: Temporary Entry - Authorizes a Jordanian national (including any spouse or child, if accompanying or following to join such national) to enter the United States pursuant to the Agreement as a nonimmigrant if such entrance is solely to carry on substantial trade, or solely to develop the operations of an enterprise in which he has invested a substantial amount of capital.Title IV: General Provisions - Declares that U.S. law shall supercede any inconsistent Agreement provisions.(Sec. 402) Authorizes appropriations for each fiscal year after FY 2001 to the Department of Commerce for the payment of the U.S. share of expenses incurred in dispute settlement proceedings under the Agreement.</summary>
</bill>
