<bill session="104" type="h" number="507" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Long-Term Care Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of expanded nursing facility and in-home services for dependent individuals under the medicare program, to provide for coverage of outpatient prescription drugs under part B of such program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data transmission systems"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Drugstores"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Emblems"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/13/1995--Introduced.
Comprehensive Long-Term Care Act of 1995 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) extend Medicare part A (Hospital Insurance) coverage of extended care services to chronically dependent individuals; and (2) provide for coverage of home care services and outpatient prescription drugs under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance). Provides for application of a deductible in determining the amount of an individual's payment for covered prescription drugs. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish a program for assuring appropriate prescribing and dispensing practices for covered prescription drugs; (2) develop, and update annually, an information guide for physicians on wholesale drug prices; and (3) report to the Congress on the prices of prescription drugs and their use by individuals eligible for Medicare part B benefits. Requires pharmacies to enter into an agreement with the Secretary in order to receive payment for prescription drugs dispensed to such individuals. Requires the Secretary to establish a point-of-sale electronic system for use by carriers and pharmacies in the submission of information on prescription drugs dispensed. Authorizes sanctions against pharmacies that violate their agreement with the Secretary. Limits the length of prescriptions. Requires the Director of the Office of Technology Assessment to provide for a Prescription Drug Payment Review Commission. Requires the Commission to report annually to the Congress on methods of determining payment for covered prescription drugs. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Secretary to develop a standard prescription drugs claims form for use under Medicare and by other third-party payors.</summary>
</bill>
