<bill session="108" type="h" number="2686" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure the safety of recreational fishermen and other persons who use motor vehicles to access beaches adjacent to the Brigantine Wilderness Area in the Edwin B. Forsythe National Wildlife Refuge, New Jersey, by providing a narrow transition zone above the mean high tide line where motor vehicles can be safely driven and parked.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animal breeding"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Beaches"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2003--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to revise the boundaries of a specified portion of the Brigantine Wilderness Area (in the Edwin B. Forsythe National Wildlife Refuge, formerly known as the Brigantine National Wildlife Refuge) located on Long Beach Island in Ocean County, New Jersey, to provide a narrow transition zone between the mean high tide line and the wilderness boundaries to permit vehicles to safely access and park on the beach without inadvertently entering the wilderness area. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to alter the Secretary's authority to prohibit or restrict public access to such area during the breeding season of the piping plover.</summary>
</bill>
