<bill session="104" type="h" number="3105" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to exempt certain State and local redevelopment boards or commissions, and fresh start users of facilities purchased from those boards or commissions, from the liability under that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400435"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E383-384"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative responsibility"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Factories"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Local officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1996--Introduced.
Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to exempt from liability for costs or damages under the Act any State or local board, commission, or other entity (or its members) established by law to plan for or implement the redevelopment or reuse of a facility with respect to a hazardous substance release from the facility to the extent the liability is based solely on the entity's status as an owner of the facility if the entity: (1) has not engaged in a response action or the generation of hazardous substance at the facility; or (2) is the owner of the facility only on a temporary basis prior to transfer. Revises the definition of "contractual relationship," for purposes of liability under CERCLA, to exclude transfers of property from an exempt redevelopment entity described in this Act after the disposal or placement of a hazardous substance if the defendant has not engaged in: (1) a response action or disposal of a hazardous substance at the facility; or (2) the generation of a hazardous substance disposed of at the facility.</summary>
</bill>
