<bill session="107" type="hr" number="405" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the moral requirement to end violence and terrorism in the Middle East.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400300"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2002-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2002-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2002-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="2002-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2067-2068" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Suicide"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="West Bank"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2002--Introduced.
Declares that the House of Representatives: (1) stands in solidarity with Israel's right to take military action to end terrorist attacks, dismantle the terrorist infrastructure, and provide security for its people; (2) remains committed to Israel's right to self-defense and to assisting Israel in exercising that right; and (3) will continue to assist Israel in strengthening its homeland defenses.Condemns Palestinian suicide bombings and the support and coordination of terror by Yassir Arafat and other members of the Palestinian leadership. Calls for the Palestinian Authority to fulfill its commitment to dismantle the terrorist infrastructure in the Palestinian areas.Urges: (1) all Arab states to declare their unqualified opposition to all forms of terrorism and to act in concert with the United States to stop the violence; (2) Israel to make clear its willingness to withdraw from occupied territories in the context of a full settlement; and (3) all parties in the region to pursue efforts to establish a, lasting peace in the Middle East.</summary>
</bill>
