<bill session="105" type="h" number="1324" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Telecommunications Trade and Foreign Investment Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to clarify the authority of the Federal Communications Commission to authorize foreign investment in United States broadcast and common carrier radio licenses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1997-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="1997-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1997-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-04-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E668"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/1997--Introduced.
Telecommunications Trade and Foreign Investment Act of 1997 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit any broadcast radio station license from being granted to or held by: (1) an alien or a foreign corporation; (2) any corporation of which more than one-fifth of the capital stock is owned or voted by a foreign government; (3) any corporation organized under the laws of a foreign country; or (4) any corporation directly or indirectly controlled by another corporation of which more than one-fourth of the capital stock is owned or voted by aliens, a foreign corporation, or any corporation organized under the laws of a foreign country. Provides a similar prohibition with respect to the granting of licenses for a common carrier or aeronautical en route or fixed radio station, unless the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) finds that the public interest will be served by the granting of such license. Requires the FCC, in making such public interest determination, to consider whether competitive opportunities are available to U.S. nationals or corporations in the applicant's market.</summary>
</bill>
