<bill session="105" type="hr" number="147" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-20T16:08:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-05-20T16:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the House of Representatives should participate in and support activities to provide decent homes for the people of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400239"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="1997-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404587" joined="1997-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1997-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1997-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1997-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="410407" joined="1997-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-05-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2494"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-20T13:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lazio moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-20T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2941-2946, H2960" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-20T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-20T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-20T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Solomon asked unanimous consent that the demand for a recorded vote on H. Res. 147 be vacated. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-20T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1997-05-20T16:08:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-05-20T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-20T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Politicians' families"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special weeks"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban housing"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/1997--Passed House amended.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the Members of the House of Representatives and Habitat for Humanity, with support from the National Partners in Homeownership, should sponsor and construct, commencing on June 5, 1997, two homes in the Anacostia neighborhood of the District of Columbia, each to be known as a "House That Congress Built"; (2) each house should be constructed primarily by Members and their families and staffs with the participation of the family that will own the home, involving and symbolizing the partnership of the public, private, and nonprofit sectors of society; (3) upon completion and initial occupancy of the homes in the fall of 1997, the Members, their families and staffs, each family that will own each house, and local and national leaders from the public and private nonprofit sectors of society should participate in an event to celebrate the occasion; (4) the Members and their families and staff should participate in similar house building activities of Habitat for Humanity in their own districts as part of National Homeownership Week; and (5) these occasions should be used to emphasize the importance of providing safe, clean, and healthy homes for all of the people in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
