<bill session="104" type="h" number="2684" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-05T18:14:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-12-05T18:14:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Senior Citizens' Right to Work Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Senior Citizens' Right to Work Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide for increases in the amounts of allowable earnings under the social security earnings limit for individuals who have attained retirement age, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300014"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400567" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="401547" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="402010" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="402657" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403864" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404068" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400583" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404332" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404367" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404869" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="405033" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400169" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="405317" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400225" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="406625" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="407400" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400510" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="408092" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="409618" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="410067" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="410887" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="411178" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1995-11-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-11-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 31 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-11-30T15:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Dreier asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Ways and Means have until midnight on Dec. 1 to file a report on H.R. 2684. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-04T12:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Bass asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Ways and Means have until midnight on Dec. 4 to file a report on H.R. 2684. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-04T17:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 104-379.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-12-04T17:26:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="191">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 191.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05T16:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Bunning moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05T16:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13962-13971, H13974" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05T16:39:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05T17:20:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05T18:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-12-05T18:14:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="837" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays (2/3 required): 411 - 4 (Roll No. 837).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05T18:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.3136.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2668"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3136"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3136"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1432"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1470"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Black lung"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Clergy"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to alcoholism programs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Retirement income"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security beneficiaries"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Stepfamilies"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Support of dependents"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/1995--Passed House amended.
Senior Citizens' Right to Work Act of 1995 - Amends title II (Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Benefits) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to provide, through adjustments in the monthly exempt amount, for increases in the amounts of allowable earnings under the Social Security earnings limit for individuals who have attained retirement age. Retains the current limit on substantial gainful activity earnings applicable to individuals under age 65 who are eligible for disability benefits based on blindness. (Sec. 3) Establishes a Continuing Disability Review Administration Revolving Account for OASDI disability benefits in the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund. Directs the Chief Actuary of the Social Security Administration (SSA) to estimate annually the present value of savings to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund, and the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund which will accrue for all years as a result of cessation of benefit payments resulting from continuing disability reviews carried out pursuant to specified requirements during the fiscal year. Directs the Managing Trustee to: (1) transfer to the Account from amounts otherwise in the Trust Fund an amount equal to the estimated savings certified by the Chief Actuary; and (2) make available to the Commissioner of Social Security from funds in the Account an amount certified by the Chief Actuary as currently required to meet expenditures necessary to provide for required continuing disability reviews (including expenditures for the cost of staffing, training, purchase of medical and other evidence, and processing related to appeals and overpayments and related indirect costs). Includes under required information in a specified annual report a final accounting of amounts transferred to the Continuing Disability Review Administration Revolving Account in the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund during the year, the amount made available from such Account during such year pursuant to certifications made by the Chief Actuary of the SSA and expenditures made by the Commissioner of Social Security for the specified purposes during the year, including a comparison of the number of continuing disability reviews conducted during the year with the estimated number of continuing disability reviews upon which the estimate of such expenditures was made. Terminates the Continuing Disability Review Administration Revolving Account at the end of FY 2002, and provides that any balance in such Account shall revert to funds otherwise available in the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund. Provides for appointment by the Commissioner of a Chief Actuary in the SSA. (Sec. 4) Bases entitlement of stepchildren to child's insurance benefits solely on their actual dependency on stepparent support. Repeals the requirement that the stepchild actually be living with the stepparent. Requires termination of any child's insurance benefits based on the wages and self-employment income of the stepparent six months after the Commissioner is formally notified of the natural parent's divorce from the stepparent. (Sec. 5) Extends the length of time required for recomputation of benefits after normal retirement age. (Sec. 6) Eliminates the role of the SSA in processing attorney's fees. Prohibits any person, agent, or attorney from charging in excess of $4,000 (or, if the Commissioner approves, a higher fee) for services performed in connection with any claim before the Commissioner. Directs a court, in determining a reasonable fee, to take into consideration the amount of the fee, if any, that an attorney may charge the claimant for services (eliminating the current limitation of such fee to 25 percent of the total past-due benefits to which a judgment entitles the claimant). (Sec. 7) Provides that an individual shall not be considered to be disabled for OASDI purposes, or for supplemental security income (SSI) purposes under title XVI of the Act (thus denying them benefits), if alcoholism or drug addiction would be a contributing factor material to the determination of disability. (Continues disability benefits based on a separate disabling condition to individuals also disabled by drug addiction or alcoholism.) Requires the payment of OASDI or SSI benefits based on disability to a representative payee if such payment would serve the interest of an individual who also has an alcoholism or drug addiction condition that prevents the individual from managing such benefits. Requires the Commissioner to refer such individual to the appropriate State agency administering the approved State plan for substance abuse treatment services. Appropriates additional specified amounts to supplement State and Tribal alcohol and substance abuse treatment programs funded under the Public Health Service Act. Requires State or Tribal governments receiving such an allotment to consider as priorities activities relating to the treatment of the abuse of alcohol and other drugs. (Sec. 8) Permits members of the clergy to file to revoke their exemption from social security tax coverage under the Internal Revenue Code. (Sec. 9) Directs the Commissioner to: (1) conduct a pilot study of the efficacy of providing certain individualized information to recipients of monthly OASDI insurance benefits, designed to promote better understanding of their contributions and benefits under the social security system; (2) provide to each of the beneficiaries involved in the study one annualized statement, setting forth specified information; and (3) report to the Congress on the results of such study. States that the study shall involve solely beneficiaries whose benefit entitlement first occurred in or after 1984 and who have remained entitled for a continuous period of at least five years.</summary>
</bill>
