<bill session="104" type="h" number="4244" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to waive the 3-day prior hospitalization requirement for coverage of skilled nursing facility services in the case of individuals classified within certain diagnosis-related groups.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="1996-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1797"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Extended care facilities"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for coverage under part A (Hospital Insurance) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act of extended care services for individuals with a condition classifiable within a select diagnosis-related group (DRG). (Waives the three-day prior hospitalization requirement for coverage of skilled nursing facility services for such DRGs.) Requires the Secretary to select at least five DRGs beginning in FY 1998, and additional qualified groups for subsequent fiscal years. Provides for recovery of excessive expenditures by: (1) reductions in payable amounts for post-hospital extended care services in the following fiscal year; and (2) rescission of the selection of any DRG.</summary>
</bill>
