<bill session="108" type="h" number="1538" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-09-11T11:03:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-09-11T11:03:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">True American Heroes Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">True American Heroes Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To posthumously award congressional gold medals to government workers and others who responded to the attacks on the World Trade Center and the Pentagon and perished and to people aboard United Airlines Flight 93 who helped resist the hijackers and caused the plane to crash, to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in commemoration of the Spirit of America, recognizing the tragic events of September 11, 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2003-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2003-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2003-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2003-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11T10:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated pursuant to a previous order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11T10:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered pursuant to a previous order.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8201-8207" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11T10:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 1538.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11T11:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-09-11T11:03:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8201-8203" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11T11:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional gold medals"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Flags"/>
    <term name="Flight crews"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Mayors"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Port authorities"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Silver"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2003--Passed House without amendment.
True American Heroes Act of 2003 - Title I: Medals for Responders and Resisters - Directs the Speaker of the House and the President pro tempore of the Senate to make arrangements for the posthumous award of congressional gold medals to: (1) the emergency workers, government employees, and others who responded to the attacks on the World Trade Center in New York City and perished in the tragic events of September 11, 2001; (2) each passenger and crew member on board United Airlines Flight 93 who is identified by the Attorney General as having helped resist the hijackers before the crash; and (3) officers, emergency workers, and other Federal employees who responded to the attacks on the Pentagon and perished that day. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to strike such medals and to strike gold duplicates of the first medal for presentation to the Governor of New York, the Mayor of New York City, and other specified police, fire, medical, and Port Authority officials and stations in New York and New Jersey. Authorizes the Secretary to strike and sell duplicate bronze medals. Title II: Spirit of America Commemorative Coins - Directs the Secretary to mint and issue $50-dollar gold coins, one-dollar silver coins, and half-dollar clad coins emblematic of the tragic events that occurred at the Pentagon, in New York City, and in Pennsylvania, on September 11, 2001. Sets forth surcharges for the coins minted under this title (not less than $100 per $50 coin, ten dollars per dollar coin, and five dollars per half-dollar coin), with the proceeds in excess of the cost of producing the gold coins to be used to cover the costs of producing the gold medals under title I not recovered from the sale of duplicate bronze medals, with any amount remaining to be transferred to a victims fund determined to be appropriate.</summary>
</bill>
