<bill session="105" type="h" number="1160" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Reserve Audit and Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote accountability and the public interest in the operation of the Federal Reserve System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404634"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1997-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1997-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1997-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank directors"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Depository libraries"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Open market operations"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/1997--Introduced.
Federal Reserve Audit and Accountability Act - Amends the Federal Reserve Act to declare that the president and first vice-president of each Federal reserve bank shall be appointed by the President, with the consent of the Senate. (Currently such appointment authority is exercised by each Federal reserve bank's board of directors.) Amends Federal law to remove specified limitations placed upon General Accounting Office audits of the Federal Reserve Board and Federal reserve banks. Directs the Comptroller General to audit at least triennially the vault facilities of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (the Board). Requires the Board and all Federal reserve banks to transmit their estimated receipts and proposed expenditures to the Congress during the first 15 days of each regular session. Mandates prompt public disclosure of Federal Open Market Committee meetings and actions, including policy actions and prior transcripts. Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to establish for the Board an Office of the Inspector General, with the Inspector General appointed by the President, subject to Senate advice and consent. Permits the Chairman of the Board to delegate authority for general supervision of the Inspector General to the Vice Chairman, but to no one else. Declares that the Inspector General's authority extends to the conditions, operations, and all facilities of the Federal reserve banks.</summary>
</bill>
