<bill session="105" type="h" number="2652" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-19T13:38:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-05-19T13:38:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Collections of Information Antipiracy Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Collections of Information Antipiracy Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Collections of Information Antipiracy Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 17, United States Code, to prevent the misappropriation of collections of information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1997-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="1998-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1998-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="1998-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1998-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-10-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2000"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12T13:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 105-525.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-05-12T13:34:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="297">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 297.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Coble moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3398-3404" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-05-19T13:38:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T13:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Business intelligence"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Product counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Stock exchanges"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/1998--Passed House amended.
Collections of Information Antipiracy Act - Amends Federal copyright law to make persons who extract, or use in commerce, a substantial part of a collection of information gathered or maintained by another person through the investment of substantial resources, so as to harm the other person's (or a successor's) actual or potential market for a product or service that incorporates such information and is offered or intended to be offered in commerce liable to the person (or a successor) for remedies under this Act. Exempts certain activities from this Act, including the extraction or use of individual items of information or extraction or use of information for verification, nonprofit educational, scientific, or research, or news reporting purposes. Provides that protection shall not extend to information gathered or maintained by or for a government entity or to computer programs. Protects information required to be collected and disseminated by a national securities exchange, a registered security association, or a registered securities information processor under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 or a contract market under the Commodity Exchange Act. Provides that information otherwise subject to protection is not disqualified from protection solely because it is incorporated into a computer program. Requires all rights specified in this Act to be governed exclusively by Federal law, thus preempting State law. Declares that protection under this Act is independent of, and does not affect or enlarge, any copyright protection in any work that is contained in or consists of a collection of information. Authorizes civil actions to be brought for violations of this Act. Provides for injunctions to prevent violations and authorizes impoundment of all copies of information extracted or used in violation. Entitles plaintiffs to specified monetary relief. Reduces or remits monetary relief for nonprofit educational, scientific, or research institutions in cases where an employee believed conduct to be permissible. Makes provisions regarding injunctions and impoundment inapplicable to actions against the U.S. Government. Provides for relief against State entities. Prescribes criminal penalties for certain willful violations. Provides for a three-year statute of limitations on civil and criminal actions. Bars the maintenance of actions for the extraction or use of a collection of information that occurs more than 15 years after the investment of resources that qualified the information for protection.</summary>
</bill>
