<bill session="104" type="h" number="1285" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Innocent Landowner Defense Amendment of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to provide a specific definition of the requirement that a purchaser of real property make all appropriate inquiry into the previous ownership and uses of the real property in order to qualify for the "innocent landowner" defense.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400428"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1995-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E648"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/1995--Introduced.
Innocent Landowner Defense Amendment of 1995 - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act to create a rebuttable presumption that a defendant who has acquired real property has made all appropriate inquiry into previous ownership and uses of the property if he establishes that, immediately prior to or at the time of acquisition, he obtained a Phase I Environmental Audit (i.e., an investigation of the property, conducted by environmental professionals, to determine the obviousness of the presence or likely presence of a release or threatened release of hazardous substances, including a review of specified records of the previous ownership and use of such property). Specifies that no such presumption shall arise: (1) unless the defendant has maintained a compilation of the information reviewed in the course of the Audit; and (2) if the Audit discloses the presence or likely presence of a release or threatened release of hazardous substances on the property to be acquired, unless the defendant has taken reasonable steps to confirm the absence of such release or threatened release.</summary>
</bill>
