<bill session="106" type="h" number="1867" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campaign Integrity Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to reform the financing of campaigns for elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1999-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="1999-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400577" joined="1999-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="1999-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400190" joined="1999-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="1999-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1999-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-08-02">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported Without Recommendation by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05T12:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 106-294.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-08-05T12:55:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="174">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 174.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8139"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Soft Money and Contributions and Expenditures of Political Parties Title II: Indexing Contribution Limits Title III: Expanding Disclosure of Campaign Finance Information Title IV: Effective Date Campaign Integrity Act of 1999 - Title I: Soft Money and Contributions and Expenditures of Political Parties - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to prohibit any national committee of a political party, including the national congressional campaign committees of a political party, and any party committee officers or agents, from soliciting, receiving, or directing any contributions, donations, or transfers of funds, or spending any funds, which are not subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of such Act. Declares that no candidate for Federal office, individual holding Federal office, or any agent of such candidate or officeholder may solicit, receive, or direct: (1) any funds in connection with any Federal election unless they are subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of such Act; (2) any funds that are to be expended in connection with any non-Federal election unless they are not in excess of the amounts permitted contributions to Federal candidates and political committees, and are not from prohibited sources; or (3) any funds on behalf of any person which are not subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of such Act if such funds are for the purpose of financing any activity on behalf of a candidate for election to Federal office or any communication which refers to a clearly identified candidate for election to Federal office. Exempts from the prohibitions of this Act: (1) the solicitation or receipt of funds by a candidate for a non-Federal office if such activity is permitted under State law; or (2) the attendance by a Federal office-holder or a candidate for election to Federal office at a fundraising event for a State or local committee of a political party of the State which the individual represents or seeks to represent as a Federal officeholder, if the event is held in that State. Prohibits a State committee of a political party from transferring any funds to a State committee of a political party of another State, except according to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of such Act. (Sec. 102) Increases the aggregate annual limit on contributions by individuals to political parties from $20,000 to $25,000. (Sec. 103) Repeals limitations on the amount of coordinated expenditures by the national and State committees of political parties. (Sec. 104) Increases from $15,000 to $20,000 the limit on contributions by multicandidate political committees (PACs) to national political parties. Title II: Indexing Contribution Limits - Amends FECA to mandate indexing of contribution limits, according to a specified formula involving the Consumer Price Index, beginning calendar 2001. Title III: Expanding Disclosure of Campaign Finance Information - Prescribes reporting requirements for expenditures for radio or television broadcast communications regarding a candidate for the Senate or the House of Representatives. Applies such requirements to any person who expends an aggregate amount of more than $25,000 during a calendar year for such communications relating to a single candidate for election to Federal office (or an aggregate amount of more than $100,000 during a calendar year for all such communications relating to all such candidates). Establishes civil fines for violations of such requirements. (Sec. 302) Amends FECA to require the principal campaign committees of candidates for the Senate or the House, and all political committees other than authorized committees of such a candidate, to file monthly reports (instead of quarterly reports, as currently), by specified deadlines. (Sec. 303) Directs the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to require electronic filing of campaign finance reports, unless the aggregate amount of contributions or expenditures (as the case may be) reported by the committee in all reports filed with respect to the election involved (taking into account the period covered by the report) is less than $50,000. Requires the FEC to make available without charge a standardized package of software to enable persons filing reports by electronic means to meet such requirements. (Sec. 304) Revises the waiver of strict compliance with FECA reporting requirements where a political committee's treasurer shows that best efforts have been used to obtain, maintain, and submit the information required. Denies such a waiver with respect to information regarding the occupation or the name of the employer of any individual who makes a contribution or contributions aggregating more than $200 during a calendar year. Title IV: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
