<bill session="106" type="h" number="4127" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Classroom Safety Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to provide increased authority for school personnel to discipline children with disabilities who engage in certain dangerous behavior.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="2000-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled children"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disabled students"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to disability services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Public schools"/>
    <term name="School discipline"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School violence"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2000--Introduced.
Classroom Safety Act of 2000 - Amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) to authorize school personnel to discipline (including expel or suspend), in the same manner in which such personnel may discipline a child without a disability, a child with a disability who commits specified school-related weapon or drug offenses. (Thus provides an exception to current IDEA procedural safeguards that require placement in an alternative educational setting.)Authorizes such personnel to modify the disciplinary action on a case-by-case basis. Permits assertion of a defense that the offense was committed unintentionally or innocently.Allows the local educational agency (LEA) responsible for providing educational services to a child with a disability who is expelled or suspended under this Act to choose to continue to provide educational services to such child, but specifies that an LEA that so chooses to continue to provide services: (1) is not required by IDEA to provide such child with a free appropriate public education, or any particular level of service; and (2) has discretion as to the location where it provides the services.</summary>
</bill>
