<bill session="105" type="h" number="1150" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Real Estate Investment Trust Tax Simplification Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to simplify certain provisions applicable to real estate investment trusts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="1997-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1997-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E559-561"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Debt"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Real estate investment"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Removal of Tax Traps for the Unwary Title II: Conformity with Regulated Investment Company Rules Title III: Other Simplification Real Estate Investment Trust Tax Simplification Act of 1997 - Title I: Removal of Tax Traps for the Unwary - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose monetary penalties for the failure of a real estate investment trust (REIT) to comply with regulations regarding ascertaining the actual ownership of the outstanding shares, or certificates of beneficial interest, of the REIT. Requires treating a complying REIT as if it had met a requirement to not be closely held if it does not know, or exercising reasonable diligence would not have known, whether it was closely held. (Sec. 102) Revises the definition of "rents from real property" with regard to impermissible tenant service income and constructive ownership of stock. Title II: Conformity with Regulated Investment Company Rules - Provides for the treatment by shareholders of undistributed capital gains. Title III: Other Simplification - Revises requirements concerning the treatment of earnings and profits with regard to certain distributions. (Sec. 302) Modifies the grace period regarding foreclosure property. Allows one extension (currently, one or more extensions). Allows a REIT to revoke an election to treat property as foreclosure property. Changes requirements concerning termination of the grace period. (Sec. 303) Sets forth special foreclosure rules for health care properties. (Sec. 304) Revises: (1) the treatment of certain interest rate agreements; (2) the formula for determining the amount of excess noncash income; and (3) the circumstances in which a sale of property that is a real estate asset is not a prohibited transaction. (Sec. 307) Provides for the circumstances in which sale of secured property by a REIT will be treated as if the REIT had held the property for at least four years. (Sec. 308) Removes a requirement that, in order to be a qualified REIT subsidiary, the stock of a corporation must have been held by the REIT at all times the corporation was in existence.</summary>
</bill>
