<bill session="104" type="h" number="251" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">House Ethics Protection Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 to prevent any action to dissolve, diminish the scope of the mission of, or limit the activities of, the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct during certain investigations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400163"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Legislative and Budget Process.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU02" subcommittee="Legislative Process" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional caucuses"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee membership"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional leadership"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
House Ethics Protection Act of 1995 - Amends the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 to provide that if any Member of the House of Representatives who was the subject of an investigation during the previous Congress also serves in the current Congress, the following actions are prohibited: (1) action to disband the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct; (2) action to shift such Committee's jurisdiction to any other committee; (3) action to combine such Committee with any other committee or subcommittee; (4) action making such Committee a subcommittee; or (5) action to change the number of members nominated by either party caucus to such Committee. Prohibits a House Member from participating in the procedure nominating members to the Committee if the Member was a subject of an investigation by such Committee during the current or previous congressional session. Bars the Speaker of the House from taking any action regarding the appointment of members to the Committee if the Speaker is or has been the subject of such an investigation. Requires the Committee to report to the House on each investigation conducted and matters heard during the previous Congress for which final actions were postponed or unresolved.</summary>
</bill>
