<bill session="106" type="h" number="4706" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">WTO Dispute Settlement Review Commission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a commission to review the dispute settlement reports of the World Trade Organization, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2000-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="2000-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2000-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2000-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2000-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="2000-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Veto"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2000--Introduced.
WTO Dispute Settlement Review Commission Act - Establishes the WTO Dispute Settlement Review Commission to review: (1) all adverse reports of dispute settlement panels and the Appellate Body of the World Trade Organization (WTO) which are adopted by the Dispute Settlement Body and the result of a proceeding initiated against the United States by a WTO member; and (2) upon the request of the United States Trade Representative (USTR), any adverse report of a dispute settlement panel or the Appellate Body which is adopted by the Dispute Settlement Body and in which the United States is a complaining party.Requires the Commission to determine whether, with respect to an adverse finding, the panel or the Appellate Body exceeded its authority, acted arbitrarily or capriciously, deviated from applicable standards, and added to the obligations, or diminished the rights, of the United States under the Uruguay Round Agreement.Urges the President to undertake negotiations to amend or modify the Uruguay Round Agreement upon enactment of a joint resolution requesting such negotiations.</summary>
</bill>
