<bill session="108" type="h" number="2304" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-17T14:34:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-11-17T14:34:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To resolve boundary conflicts in the vicinity of the Mark Twain National Forest in Barry and Stone Counties, Missouri, that resulted from private landowner reliance on a subsequent Federal survey, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400034"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17T14:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gutknecht moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17T14:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11169-11170" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17T14:32:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2304.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-11-17T14:34:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11169-11170" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17T14:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="1167"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2003--Passed House amended.
Establishes procedures for resolving the status of Federal land in Barry and Stone County, Missouri, claimed by private property owners based on land surveys subsequent to the Public Land Survey System land surveys upon which the original land patents were issued. Requires claimants to submit notice to the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of Agriculture (as appropriate) within 15 years of enactment of this Act and to establish their qualifications for a remedy. Authorizes the appropriate Secretary, upon receiving notice from a qualifying claimant, to take any or a combination of the following actions to resolve boundary conflicts: (1) convey and quitclaim all right, title, and interest of the United States in the disputed land; (2) if there are Federal interests in such land, confirm Federal title to it and retain it in Federal management; and (3) compensate the qualifying claimant where title is confirmed and retained pursuant to item (2). Requires conveyance of land under this Act without consideration, if the appropriate Secretary determines that the boundary conflict was the result of innocent detrimental reliance by the qualifying claimant on a subsequent land survey. Requires the appropriate Secretary to pay costs associated with the resolution of boundary disputes pursuant to this Act and to reimburse qualifying claimants for survey costs necessary to establish a claim. Establishes rules for the treatment of preexisting conditions, existing reservations, and existing rights and uses.</summary>
</bill>
