<bill session="105" type="h" number="4285" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Subchapter S Revision Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for S corporation reform, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1998-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1998-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1998-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1998-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1998-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400540" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1998-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-07-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1365"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate liquidations"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Debt"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employee ownership"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Preferred stocks"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific instruments and apparatus"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax treaties"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Subchapter S Expansion Subtitle A: Eligible Shareholders of an S Corporation Subtitle B: Qualification and Eligibility Requirements of S Corporations Subtitle C: Taxation of S Corporation Shareholders Subtitle D: Effective Date Title II: Sense of the House of Representatives Resolution Subchapter S Revision Act of 1998 - Title I: Subchapter S Expansion - Subtitle A: Eligible Shareholders of an S Corporation - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow certain members of a family to be treated as one shareholder of an S corporation (electing small business corporation). Permits nonresident aliens to be S corporation shareholders if the corporation is engaged in a U.S. trade or business. Subjects such aliens' effectively-connected U.S. income to withholding tax. Subtitle B: Qualification and Eligibility Requirements of S Corporations - Prohibits, with respect to S corporations, treating: (1) qualified preferred stock as a second class of stock; and (2) a person as a shareholder by reason of holding such stock. (Sec. 112) Permits financial institutions to hold convertible (safe harbor) debt. (Sec. 113) Repeals: (1) the characterization of excessive passive investment income as a termination event; and (2) the passive income capital gain category. (Sec. 115) Permits: (1) an S corporation to make charitable contributions of inventory and scientific property used to care for the ill, the needy, or infants; and (2) S corporation shareholders to increase the basis of their stock by the excess of the charitable contribution over the property's basis. (Sec. 116) Makes other-than health insurance fringe benefits nontaxable for S corporation two-percent shareholders. Subtitle C: Taxation of S Corporation Shareholders - States that a loss recognized by a shareholder in a complete liquidation of an S corporation shall be treated as an ordinary loss to the extent the shareholder's stock basis is attributable to ordinary income from such liquidation. Subtitle D: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date for provisions of this Act. Title II: Sense of the House of Representatives Resolution - Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives against treating the conversion of certain large C corporations to S corporations as taxable liquidations.</summary>
</bill>
