<bill session="105" type="h" number="3221" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Employees Health Benefits Children's Equity Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 89 of title 5, United States Code, concerning the Federal Employees Health Benefits (FEHB) Program, to enable the Federal Government to enroll an employee and his or her family in the FEHB Program when a State court orders the employee to provide health insurance coverage for a child of the employee but the employee fails to provide the coverage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400090"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child support enforcement"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/1998--Introduced.
Federal Employees Health Benefits Children's Equity Act of 1997 - Amends Federal law concerning the Federal Employees Health Benefits (FEHB) Program to direct the agency of an unenrolled employee who is required by a court or administrative order to provide health insurance coverage for a child who meets FEHB requirements to enroll the employee in a self and family enrollment option which provides the lower level of coverage under the Service Benefit Plan, if such employee fails to enroll for self and family coverage in a health benefits plan that provides full benefits and services in the location in which the child resides and does not provide documentation showing that such coverage has been provided through other health insurance.</summary>
</bill>
