<bill session="107" type="h" number="3468" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Terrorist Military Tribunal Authorization Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the President to convene military tribunals for the trial outside the United States of persons other than United States citizens and lawful resident aliens who are apprehended in connection with the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks against the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400166"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2002-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2001-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2002-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2284-2285"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-01-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Courts-martial and courts of inquiry"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2001--Introduced.
Foreign Terrorist Military Tribunal Authorization Act of 2001- Authorizes the President to convene military tribunals for the trial of individuals who are charged with offenses arising from the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks on the United States. Permits such a trial to be held only at a location outside the United States.Makes this Act applicable to an individual who is not a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence and who is apprehended outside the United States.Treats as an offense arising from such attacks an offense relating to: (1) planning, authorizing, committing, or aiding those attacks; and (2) harboring any organization or individual that planned, authorized, committed, or aided those attacks.Bars any military order, executive order, regulation, or other directive of the executive branch from limiting the rights or privileges of any individual under provisions relating to habeas corpus. Allows the privilege of the writ of habeas corpus to be suspended only in cases of rebellion or invasion and only by law.</summary>
</bill>
