<bill session="104" type="h" number="2797" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ethics Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To abolish the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct in the House of Representatives, establish an Independent Commission on Congressional Ethics, and provide for the transfer of the duties and functions of the Committee to the Independent Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411166"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-12-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14933"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Legislative and Budget Process.</text>
      <committee name="House Rules"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU02" subcommittee="Legislative Process" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Termination of Committee on Standards of Official Conduct in the House of Representatives Title II: Establishment of Commission Title III: Discharge of Commission Report from Committee on Rules in the House of Representatives Ethics Reform Act of 1995 - Title I: Termination of Committee on Standards of Official Conduct in the House of Representatives - Amends: (1) rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives to terminate the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct; and (2) the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 to repeal provisions regarding that Committee. Makes conforming amendments to the Rules, the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, and other Federal law. Title II: Establishment of Commission - Establishes within the legislative branch the Independent Commission on Congressional Ethics. Sets forth provisions regarding membership and staff of, and procedural rules with respect to, the Commission. Sets forth duties of the Commission, including: (1) recommending to the House appropriate administrative actions to establish or enforce standards of official conduct for Members, officers, and employees of the House; (2) investigating alleged violations and reporting to the House its findings and recommendations; (3) reporting to appropriate Federal or State authorities, with House approval, any substantial evidence of violations; (4) considering requests of any House Member, officer, or employee for an advisory opinion; and (5) providing information and guidance to House Members, officers, and employees regarding laws, rules, regulations, and other standards of conduct applicable to such individuals in their official capacities. Title III: Discharge of Commission Report from Committee on Rules in the House of Representatives - Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) discharging the Committee from further consideration of a Commission's report or any resolution introduced with respect to a Commission report, recommendation, or advisory opinion; and (2) floor consideration of such a resolution.</summary>
</bill>
