<bill session="106" type="h" number="5533" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GAINS Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Action and Investments for New Success for Women and Girls Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the United States financial and programmatic contributions to advancing the status of women and girls in low-income countries around the world, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2000-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1889-1890"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Alien smuggling"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Birth control"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cooperative societies"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Eastern Europe"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial crises"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to women"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Poor women"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate Foreign Relations"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination against women"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in education"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
    <term name="Wife abuse"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Women's shelters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/24/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Integration of Women into National Economics of Developing Countries Title II: Impact of Trade Agreements on Women Title III: Ensuring Opportunities for Women in Developing Countries Title IV: Promotion of Health of Women and Girls In Developing Countries Title V: Human Rights of Women Global Action and Investments for New Success for Women and Girls Act of 2000 (GAINS Act of 2000) - Title I: Integration of Women Into National Economies of Developing Countries - Amends the Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989 and the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 to require such Acts to be administered so as to give particular attention to those programs, projects, and activities which tend to integrate women into the national economies of developing countries.(Sec. 104) Authorizes appropriations for the Office of Women in Development of the Agency for International Development (AID).(Sec. 105) Authorizes the President to make a voluntary contribution to the United Nations Development Fund for Women.Title II: Impact of Trade Agreements On Women - Directs the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) to: (1) establish an Advisory Committee for Trade, Gender, and Development Policy; and (2) appoint to the Advisory Committee on Trade Policy two additional members, one with expertise in gender issues and one with expertise in international development issues.(Sec. 204) Directs the USTR, the Secretaries of Labor and of Health and Human Services, and the Administrator of AID to review: (1) the impact of U.S. trade agreements on the employment of women, women's health, and educational opportunities; and (2) the relationship between U.S. development assistance policies and U.S. trade policies, including the extent to which issues relating to gender are integrated into U.S. negotiation positions relating to trade agreements.(Sec. 205) Directs the Administrator of AID and the Secretary of State to conduct periodically time use surveys of unremunerated work performed in foreign countries, including surveys to determine the approximate monetary value of such work.Title III: Ensuring Opportunities for Women in Developing Countries - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to revise education and human resources development provisions to reaffirm the goals established by the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development and the United Nations (UN) of achieving global gender equity in education by 2005 and universal access to basic education by 2015.(Sec. 302) Authorizes the President to provide grant assistance for programs to increase the availability of credit and other services to microenterprises lacking full access to capital, training, technical assistance, and business development (with 50 percent of all assistance to be targeted to very poor entrepreneurs).(Sec. 303) Establishes a U.S. Microfinance Loan Facility to pool and manage risk from natural disasters, war or civil conflict, national financial crisis, or short-term financial movements that threaten the long-term development of U.S.-supported microfinance institutions.Title IV: Promotion of Health of Women and Girls in Developing Countries - Authorizes appropriations for the U.S. voluntary contribution to the UN Population Fund.(Sec. 402) Provides for: (1) AID programs to provide maternal health assistance to individuals in need in developing countries; (2) AID programs to prevent and treat HIV/AIDS in developing countries; (3) assistance for the prevention, treatment, and control of tuberculosis; and (4) the establishment by AID of an index to measure the impact of its programs, projects, and activities on the health of children in developing countries.Title V: Human Rights of Women - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to direct the Administrator of AID to carry out programs to assist governments of developing countries to eliminate de jure discrimination against women.(Sec. 502) Directs the President to carry out programs in the United States and in foreign countries to prevent the trafficking of women and children.(Sec. 503) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) a specified congressional committee should hold hearings on the Convention on the Elimination of all Forms of Discrimination Against Women (CEDAW); and (2) the Senate should give its advice and consent to the ratification of CEDAW.</summary>
</bill>
