<bill session="108" type="hr" number="327" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-22T10:55:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-07-22T10:55:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2800) making appropriations for foreign operations, export financing, and related programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2004, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400107"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-21T22:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 108-227, by Mr. Diaz-Balart, L..</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-21T22:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Provides one hour of general debate equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. Rule waives points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI (prohibiting unauthorized appropriations or legislative provisions in an appropriations bill), except as specified in the resolution. Authorizes the Chair to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-07-21T22:05:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="92">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 92.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22T10:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7237-7241" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22T10:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 327.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22T10:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2003-07-22T10:55:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7237" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22T10:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="h" number="2800"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2003--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 2800 (FY 2004 foreign operations, export financing, and related programs appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
