<bill session="106" type="h" number="2932" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-02T18:38:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-05-02T18:38:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Golden Spike/Crossroads of the West National Heritage Area Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Golden Spike/Crossroads of the West National Heritage Area.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study of the Golden Spike/Crossroads of the West National Heritage Area Study Area and to establish the Crossroads of the West Historic District in the State of Utah.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-04-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13T17:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-584.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-04-13T17:34:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="318">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 318.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-05-02T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-02T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2357-2358" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-02T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2932.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-02T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-02T18:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2375-2376" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-05-02T18:38:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="132" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 400 - 9 (Roll no. 132).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2357-2358" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-05-02T18:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-06-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 106-321.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-06-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="639">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 639.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Architecture"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad terminals"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/2000--Passed House amended.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study of the Golden Spike/Crossroads of the West National Heritage Area Study Area to determine whether such Study Area meets specified criteria for inclusion as a national heritage area. Requires the Study Area to be comprised of sites relating to the completion in the State of Utah of the first transcontinental railroad. Requires a report from the Secretary to specified congressional committees on study results and a recommendation on its inclusion as a national heritage area. Authorizes appropriations.Establishes in the city of Ogden, Utah, the Crossroads of the West Historic District. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants and enter into cooperative agreements with the State of Utah, local governments, and nonprofit entities under which the Secretary agrees to pay not more than 50 percent of the costs of: (1) a plan for the development of historic, architectural, natural, cultural, and interpretive resources within the District; (2) implementation of projects approved under the development plan; and (3) an analysis of measures that could be taken to encourage economic development and revitalization within the District in a manner consistent with the District's historic character. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements to pay up to 50 percent of the costs of the restoration, preservation, and interpretation of properties within the District, together with appropriate technical assistance. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
