<bill session="105" type="h" number="4650" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Senior Citizen Protection Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to extend the authority of State Medicaid fraud control units to investigate and prosecute fraud in connection with Federal health care programs and abuse of residents of board and care facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400169" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400605" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1998-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Elder abuse"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Group homes"/>
    <term name="Health care fraud"/>
    <term name="Long-term care facilities"/>
    <term name="Medicaid fraud"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1998--Introduced.
Senior Citizen Protection Act of 1998 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to extend the authority of State Medicaid fraud control units, upon the approval of the Inspector General (IG) of the relevant Federal agency in a particular case or investigation, to investigate and prosecute: (1) fraud in connection with other Federal health care programs (if the suspected fraud or law violation in such case or investigation is primarily related to the State Medicaid plan); and (2) abuse of residents of non-Medicaid board and care facilities, if their assistance is requested by State and local agencies. Provides that when the IG grants such approval, he or she retains continuing authority to join the case or investigation, or after consultation with the unit, to replace it as the primary agency assigned to the case or investigation. Provides that overpayments collected by a State Medicaid fraud control unit shall be credited exclusively to, and be available for expenditure under, the Federal health care program that was subject to the activity that was the basis for the collection.</summary>
</bill>
