<bill session="105" type="h" number="1884" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Voluntary Environmental Self-Evaluation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish limited privileges and immunities for certain information relating to compliance with environmental laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="1997-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1998-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, Transportation and Infrastructure, Agriculture, and Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry, Resource Conservation and Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW09" subcommittee="Railroads" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG26" subcommittee="Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG27" subcommittee="Forestry, Resource Conservation and Research" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Privileges and immunities"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Self-incrimination"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/1997--Introduced.
Voluntary Environmental Self-Evaluation Act - Provides that information contained in, and testimony relating to, voluntary environmental self-evaluations shall not be admissible evidence or subject to discovery in Federal or State administrative or judicial proceedings under Federal environmental laws. Authorizes waivers of such privilege by the entity concerned. Permits persons seeking disclosure of such information, in cases where an entity invokes the nondisclosure privilege, to request an administrative law judge or the court, as appropriate, to convene an in camera proceeding to determine applicability of the privilege. Makes the privilege inapplicable in civil proceedings if an administrative law judge or the court determines that: (1) the document or testimony indicates non-compliance with an environmental law by such entity and the entity failed to achieve compliance within a reasonable time period; (2) such entity is asserting the privilege for a fraudulent purpose; or (3) the report was prepared for purposes of avoiding disclosure of information required for a pending or imminent investigative, administrative, or judicial proceeding of which the entity had knowledge. Provides for appeals of such determinations. Makes the nondisclosure privilege inapplicable in criminal proceedings brought by Federal or State agencies if the court makes any of the determinations described above for civil proceedings. Authorizes seizures of reports believed to constitute evidence of criminal offenses but limits use of the information to review by such agencies until the court determines it subject to disclosure. Provides immunity from Federal or State prosecution to entities making voluntary disclosures of violations of environmental laws as a result of making self-evaluations or using environmental management systems and makes such disclosures inadmissible in courts or administrative proceedings if the entity: (1) meets certain conditions regarding promptness of disclosure, efforts to achieve compliance, and availability of information; and (2) is not disclosing information for fraudulent purposes or to avoid penalties. Makes immunity inapplicable if the violation concerned is part of a pattern of significant violations that has occurred within the past three years in cases where the senior management had knowledge and failed to take corrective action.</summary>
</bill>
