<bill session="104" type="h" number="3773" updated="2012-11-01T22:45:22-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent Members of the House of Representatives from making mass mailings during an election year, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="401547" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="408476" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="411214" joined="1996-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Postal Service"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>07/10/1996--Introduced.
Prohibits a Member of, or Member-elect to, the House of Representatives from making any franked mass mailing if it would be postmarked during any session that begins in an even-numbered election year. Provides that this Act shall not preclude the mailing of: (1) any mass mailing by chairmen of congressional committees, subcommittees thereof, or commissions, the Democratic caucus, or the House or Senate Republican conference which relates to the normal and regular business of the organization; (2) a town meeting notice if it is made more than 90 days before the date of any primary or general election (whether regular, special, or runoff) for any Federal, State, or local office in which such Member is a candidate; or (3) any mail matter which relates to an emergency or disaster declared by the President if the mailing is sent within 60 days after the declaration, the recipients of the mailing are located in a congressional district any portion of which is within (or adjacent to) an area included in such declaration, and the mailing relates solely to the emergency or disaster.</summary>
</bill>
