<bill session="105" type="h" number="1562" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Adult Basic Education and Literacy Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide assistance to States and local communities to improve adult education and literacy, to help achieve the National Educational Goals for all citizens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1997-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="994"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Career education"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to adult education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Leadership"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School-to-work transition"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Amendment to the Adult Education Act Title II: Effective Date; Transition Title III: Repeals of Other Acts Title I: Amendment to the Adult Education Act - Adult Basic Education and Literacy Act - Amends the Adult Education Act to revise and rename it the Adult Basic Education and Literacy Act. Authorizes appropriations for national leadership activities and for State grants for adult education and literacy, including technical assistance in developing performance goals and uniform national performance data. Sets forth authority and priorities for Adult Education and Literacy programs, including: (1) State grants, leadership activities, administration, and plans; (2) State awarding of subgrants and contracts to eligible applicants; (3) performance goals and indicators; (4) evaluation, improvement, and accountability reports; and (5) allotments and reallotment of funds. Provides for national leadership and evaluation activities. Authorizes use of reserved funds for specified purposes, including research and development, demonstration programs, information dissemination, assessments, support for State and local capacity building, data collection, professional development, and technical assistance for distance learning and use of technology in the classroom. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make awards for national excellence to States for specified types of program achievements. Revises provisions for the National Institute for Literacy. Sets forth conditions for waivers of certain program requirements. Title II: Effective Date; Transition - Sets forth effective date and transition provisions. Title III: Repeals of Other Acts - Repeals: (1) the National Literacy Act of 1991; and (2) specified provisions of the Higher Education Act of 1965 for grants to States for workplace and community training for incarcerated youth offenders.</summary>
</bill>
