<bill session="104" type="hr" number="109" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-09T12:12:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-03-09T12:12:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 956) to establish legal standards and procedures for product liability litigation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-08T20:39:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-72, by Mr. Linder.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-08T20:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 956. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of H.R. 1075. No amendment to the substitute shall be in order except those printed in the report accompanying this resolution, if offered in the order and manner specified. Said amendments shall not be subject to further amendment, or subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-03-08T20:40:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="30">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 30.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-03-09T10:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2901-2912" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-09T10:32:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-09T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>ORDERING THE PREVIOUS QUESTION - At the conclusion of debate on the resolution, Mr. Linder moved the previous question on both the pending amendment and on the resolution. The Chair put the question on the motion and by voice vote declared that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Frost objected to the voice vote based on the absence of a quorum and the Yeas and Nays were automatically ordered.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-09T12:03:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 191 (Roll no. 217).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-03-09T12:12:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="218" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 247 - 181 (Roll no. 218).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-03-09T12:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="956"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h276"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/9/1995--Passed House amended.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 956 (establishing legal standards and procedures for product liability litigation).</summary>
</bill>
