<bill session="106" type="h" number="4054" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Building, Renovating, Improving, and Constructing Kids' Schools Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide States with loans to enable State entities or local governments within the States to make interest payments on qualified school construction bonds issued by the State entities or local governments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="2000-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E373"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2000--Introduced.
Building, Renovating, Improving, and Constructing Kids' Schools Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, from specified amounts in a stabilization fund, to make available funds to States for loans to enable State entities or local governments to make annual interest payments on certain qualified school construction bonds (with terms up to 20 years) they issue. Bases such State allotments on relative shares of funds received under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 as part A basic local program grants under title I provisions for helping disadvantaged children meet high standards. Reserves specified funds for Indian tribes for loans to enable them to pay interest on such bonds they issue.Sets forth requirements for loan repayment and interest rate. Exempts a State entity or local government from such repayment and interest rate accrual prior to January 1, 2008, unless the amount appropriated to carry out assistance for education of all children with disabilities under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act for any fiscal year before FY 2009 is sufficient to fully fund such assistance for the fiscal year at the originally promised level, which promised level would provide to each State 40 percent of the average per-pupil expenditure for providing special education and related services for each child with a disability in the State.Directs the Secretary to: (1) ensure that funds provided under this Act are properly distributed, and are used to pay the interest on qualified school construction bonds; and (2) notify each State of the amount of funds it may borrow under this Act. Provides that the Secretary shall not have authority to approve or disapprove school construction plans assisted pursuant to this Act, except to ensure that funds made available under this Act are used only to supplement, and not supplant, the amount of school construction, rehabilitation, and repair in the State that would have occurred in the absence of such funds.</summary>
</bill>
