<bill session="107" type="h" number="4990" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-26T21:13:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-06-26T21:13:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish requirements with respect to the sale of, or the offer to sell, prescription drugs through the Internet, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400397"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T21:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 107-546.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-06-26T21:13:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="327">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 327.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health care fraud"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2002--Reported to House without amendment.
Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require each interstate Internet seller to comply with requirements of this Act with respect to the sale or offer of prescription drugs. Requires the seller to: (1) post visibly on its web site home page its street address, the States in which it is authorized as a pharmacy, certain prescriber information, and a statement it will dispense prescription drugs only upon a valid prescription; and (2) disclose such information to State licensing boards.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) engage in activities to educate the public about the dangers of purchasing prescription drugs from unlawful Internet sources; and (2) recommend to Congress the coordination of activities of Federal agencies regarding Internet sellers that operate from foreign countries with the activities of such foreign governments.</summary>
</bill>
