<bill session="105" type="h" number="4803" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Electronic Duck Stamp Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize electronic issuance and recognition of migratory bird hunting and conservation stamps.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400397"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/1998--Introduced.
Electronic Duck Stamp Act of 1998 - Amends Federal law to allow the Department of the Interior, the Postal Service, or a State or person authorized to sell Federal Migratory Bird Hunting and Conservation Stamps to issue the stamps, or representations of such stamps, electronically by endorsement affixed to licenses issued at points of sale or through other electronic media. Prohibits such States or persons from participating in the electronic issuance of such a stamp unless the Secretary of the Interior has received a plan submitted by the party in question which provides for a satisfactory accounting process for the collection and transfer of revenue, distribution, and law enforcement verification of the electronic transaction, and the subsequent distribution of the actual stamp. Requires such States or persons, not later than 14 days after the issuance of an electronic stamp, to transfer to the Department or designated agent the revenue collected from the issuance by means of an electronic fund transfer method approved by, and compatible with, the Department's or the designated agent's accounting system.</summary>
</bill>
