<bill session="105" type="h" number="2189" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Uniform Child Support Enforcement Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Social Security Act to repeal provisions relating to the State enforcement of child support obligations and to require the Internal Revenue Service to collect child support through wage withholding and other means, and to authorize the Social Security Administration to distribute child support collections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1997-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1997-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1998-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1997-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1997-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1998-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1997-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="1997-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="1998-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1997-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1997-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1997-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1997-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Abandonment of family"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Child support enforcement"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Garnishment"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Paternity"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/1997--Introduced.
Uniform Child Support Enforcement Act of 1997 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to deem any individual with the right to collect child support to have assigned to the Internal Revenue Service the right to collect the support (unless the individual elects to retain the right). Requires States to transmit abstracts of child support orders to the Federal Case Registry of Child Support Orders. (Sec. 3) Requires employees to notify their employers of their child support obligations and requires employers to withhold that amount from wages. Requires that an individual's child support obligations that are not covered by the withholding be paid with the individual's tax return. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to collect any past due amount. Provides for penalties and interest. Requires that child support amounts (and related penalties and interest) received by the Secretary be paid to the Commissioner of Social Security. Provides for the application of estimated tax provisions. Mandates criminal penalties for willful false statements by employees to employers regarding child support obligations. Removes provisions relating to offset of past-due support against overpayments. (Sec. 4) Amends the Social Security Act to direct the Commissioner to distribute child support amounts collected to the family and, if the family does or did receive certain types of assistance, to the State. (Sec. 5) Removes and revises numerous provisions to remove references to State enforcement of child support (but retain references to State enforcement of medical child support) obligations. Revises auditing requirements regarding certain State activities. Modifies: (1) the contents of an annual report to the Congress regarding activities under provisions relating to child support and establishment of paternity; and (2) financial recordkeeping requirements. Removes or repeals provisions relating to: (1) State case registries; (2) direct payments to Indian tribes or tribal organizations that have child support enforcement plans; (3) incentive payments to States; and (4) the collection of past-due support from Federal tax refunds.</summary>
</bill>
