<bill session="106" type="h" number="995" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Direct Check for Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a direct check for education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400121"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1999-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="2000-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400190" joined="1999-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2000-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1999-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E459"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="School-to-work transition"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/1999--Introduced.
Direct Check for Education Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make direct awards to local educational agencies (LEAs) to support programs or activities, that the LEA deems appropriate, for students in kindergarten through grade 12. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to use funds under this Act to continue to make payments to eligible recipients pursuant to, and for the duration of, any multiyear award made prior to enactment of this Act. Repeals the Goals 2000: Educate America Act. Repeals certain provisions of the Department of Education Appropriations Act,1999, which vested in the National Assessment Governing Board exclusive authority for developing voluntary national tests pursuant to a specified contract. Repeals the following programs under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA): (1) the Technology for Education program, including national programs, State and local programs for school technology resources, Star Schools, Ready-to-Learn Television, telecommunications demonstration project for mathematics, elementary mathematics and science equipment, and elementary and secondary school library media resources; (2) the State programs component of Innovative Education Program Strategies; and (3) the Fund for the Improvement of Education. Repeals the School-to-Work Opportunities Act of 1994. Directs the Secretary to determine a per-child amount to be awarded to each LEA. Authorizes the Secretary to conduct audits of LEA expenditures under this Act, and to enforce certain sanctions and penalties if such funds are not used in accordance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
