<bill session="106" type="h" number="3664" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Illegal Alien Prosecution Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for the deferral of removal and detention of certain aliens awaiting trial on Federal or State criminal charges, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400606"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E139-140"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Bail"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2000--Introduced.
Illegal Alien Prosecution Act of 2000 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to direct the Attorney General, at Federal or State request, to defer removal of a previously deported alien awaiting trial for a serious violent felony pending conclusion of prosecution, and to detain such alien if released on bail or personal recognizance until taken into Federal or State custody.Authorizes the Attorney General, at Federal or State request, to defer removal of a similarly situated alien awaiting trial for other than a serious violent felony, and to detain (nondiscretionary) such alien until taken into Federal or State custody.Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) detain, at Federal or State request, an alien seeking U.S. admission who is subject to Federal or State arrest and prosecution, and release such alien into Federal or State custody; and (2) stay the removal of an alien subject to Federal or State arrest.</summary>
</bill>
