<bill session="107" type="h" number="2987" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TRICARE Benefits Modernization Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to fully integrate the beneficiaries of the Individual Case Management Program into the TRICARE program, to provide long-term health care benefits under the TRICARE program and otherwise to improve the benefits provided under the TRICARE program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="2002-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-01-22">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="1402"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Deafness"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hearing aids"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Occupational therapy"/>
    <term name="Paralysis"/>
    <term name="Physical therapy"/>
    <term name="Prosthesis"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Respiratory diseases"/>
    <term name="Respite care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2001--Introduced.
TRICARE Benefits Modernization Act of 2001 - Directs the Secretary of Defense to: (1) terminate the individual case management program under the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services (CHAMPUS); and (2) integrate its beneficiaries and services into the TRICARE program (a Department of Defense managed care program).Makes limits on custodial care under the case management program inapplicable to domiciliary or custodial care incident to other authorized health care.Requires the Secretary to provide long-term health care benefits under TRICARE so as to integrate such benefits with those provided under TRICARE on a less than long-term basis. Allows post-hospital extended care services in a skilled nursing facility to continue for as long as is medically necessary and appropriate.Provides extended health care benefits for military dependents who have a serious physical disability or any extraordinary physical or psychological condition (currently limited to moderately or severely mentally retarded dependents). Outlines benefits provided and copayment requirements.Allows a dependent, in order to receive outpatient mental health services under a TRICARE contract in excess of the amount available in that year, to convert any unused period of inpatient mental health benefit still available.Makes a physician's determination that a service or supply is medically or psychologically necessary for a TRICARE patient conclusive, unless clearly erroneous. Prohibits such determinations from being subject to peer review.Includes orthotic devices, hearing aids, and rehabilitative therapy among the TRICARE services authorized for military dependents. Outlines types of durable medical equipment authorized to be provided.</summary>
</bill>
