<bill session="104" type="h" number="1132" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nonpoint Source Water Pollution Prevention Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to establish requirements and provide assistance to prevent nonpoint sources of water pollution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E510-511"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Eutrophication"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Fertilizers"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nonpoint source pollution"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Nonpoint Source Management Programs Title II: Nonpoint Source Prevention on Federal Lands Title III: Water Quality Criteria; Standards; Antidegradation; New Sources Title IV: Citizen Watershed Monitoring Program Nonpoint Source Water Pollution Prevention Act of 1995 - Title I: Nonpoint Source Management Programs - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require State Governors to revise nonpoint source management programs for purposes of achieving full restoration and protection of target watersheds. Directs State Governors to: (1) identify and prioritize target watersheds into five groups based on the severity of nonpoint source pollution problems; and (2) notify landowners and operators who conduct nonpoint source activities in first priority group watersheds that they will be required to implement site-level programs. Establishes requirements for site-level programs. Authorizes exemptions from requirements for site-level programs in cases of insignificant environmental degradation or severe economic hardship. Requires State watershed management programs to be approved by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and to achieve full restoration and protection of watersheds within eight years of implementation. Withholds nonpoint source pollution management grants from, and approval of specified discharge permits for, States that fail to comply with watershed management requirements. Requires additional management measures to be taken in watersheds that have not achieved the required goal by the end of the eight-year period. Makes water quality standards enforceable against nonpoint sources of pollution in target watersheds after the expiration of the eight-year period, with exceptions for individuals meeting requirements for an extended compliance period. Extends the authorization of appropriations for nonpoint source pollution management and groundwater quality grants through FY 2000. Title II: Nonpoint Source Prevention on Federal Lands - Requires the President to issue regulations for the prevention and control of nonpoint sources of pollution on Federal lands to provide for full restoration and protection of watersheds within eight years of issuance. Revises existing licenses or operational authorities to comply with regulations. Directs the President to prevent pollution resulting from federally assisted highway construction projects. Prohibits approval of specified highway projects unless they comply with pollution prevention measures promulgated by the President. Title III: Water Quality Criteria; Standards; Antidegradation; New Sources - Directs the Administrator to revise specified water quality criteria triennially and include numerical pollution concentration limits or biological monitoring and assessment methods. Requires States to provide specific numerical criteria for nonpoint source pollutants in water quality standards. Directs the Administrator to issue: (1) antidegradation regulations to apply to nonpoint source pollutants in the same manner that such policies extend to point sources; and (2) guidance for identifying new nonpoint sources. Title IV: Citizen Watershed Monitoring Program - Requires States to establish citizen watershed monitoring programs. Allocates funding for such programs.</summary>
</bill>
