<bill session="104" type="h" number="4302" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Meat, Poultry, and Seafood Inspection Reform Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To consolidate within the Department of Agriculture all inspection activities regarding livestock and poultry carcasses, seafood, meat products, poultry products, and seafood products to provide for the improved inspection of those articles and products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404869"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Business intelligence"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Extortion"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fish inspection"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
    <term name="Food contamination"/>
    <term name="Food handling"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food irradiation"/>
    <term name="Food poisoning"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foodborne diseases"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Libel and slander"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Livestock industry"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Microbiology"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Municipal officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Poultry industry"/>
    <term name="Poultry inspection"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Inspection and Labeling of Livestock, Poultry, Seafood, and Their Products Subtitle A: Inspection Requirements Subtitle B: Labeling Requirements Subtitle C: International Commerce Subtitle D: Miscellaneous Title II: Related Industries Title III: Federal and State Cooperation Title IV: Auxiliary Provisions Title V: Public Education Title VI: Miscellaneous Provisions Title VII: Repeal of Superseded Laws Title VIII: Effective Date Meat, Poultry, and Seafood Inspection Reform Act of 1996 - Transfers seafood inspection jurisdiction from the Food and Drug Administration to the Food Safety and Inspection Service of the Department of Agriculture (Department). Title I: Inspection and Labeling of Livestock, Poultry, Seafood, and Their Products - Subtitle A: Inspection Requirements - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary) to provide for: (1) slaughtering facility ante- and post- mortem inspection and verification of livestock, poultry, and seafood; and (2) inspection and verification of processing facility meat, poultry, and seafood products. Authorizes facility self-inspection. Provides for facility sanitation and night inspections. (Sec. 106) Sets forth prohibited and exempt activities (personal or custom slaughtering or processing). (Sec. 108) Authorizes appropriate microbiological testing. Subtitle B: Labeling Requirements - Requires receptacle, carcass, and product labeling, including derivation labeling where appropriate. (Sec. 123) Sets forth prohibited acts of misbranding. Subtitle C: International Commerce - Subjects imported meat, poultry, and seafood to domestic inspection and verification requirements or their equivalents. Provides for enforcement through inspection and sampling, or certification by the Secretary of foreign standards. Provides exceptions for: (1) Canada and Mexico under specified conditions; and (2) personal use. (Sec. 132) Requires: (1) disease examination of all U.S. (live) export livestock, poultry, and seafood; and (2) review and certification of all U.S. exports of meat, poultry, and seafood carcasses and products. Subtitle D: Miscellaneous - Establishes in the Department the Safe Meat, Poultry, and Seafood Inspection Advisory Panel. (Sec. 145) Establishes criminal penalties for bribery or attempted bribery under this Act. (Sec. 147) Authorizes the Secretary to require (pre-slaughter) source identification of livestock, poultry, and seafood. (Sec. 148) Directs the Secretary to perform health-related monitoring of seafood growing areas and fishing grounds in certain Federal jurisdiction waters. Authorizes harvest restrictions or closure, including State waters, for public health reasons. Title II: Related Industries - Prohibits inspection as provided for under title I for meat, poultry, or seafood products not intended for human consumption. Requires denaturation or other identification of such products prior to commercial distribution. (Sec. 203) Provides for the registration and commercial regulation of persons who are involved in the trade of dead, dying, disabled, or diseased livestock, poultry, or seafood. Title III: Federal and State Cooperation - Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) cooperate with State agencies to protect the public from adulterated and misbranded livestock, poultry, and seafood products; and (2) apply Federal inspection standards to a State that has not promulgated its own standards. Permits a State with a qualifying (State) inspection program to distribute products in interstate commerce. Title IV: Auxiliary Provisions - Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) inspection services; (2) administrative detention of carcasses and meat, poultry, and seafood products; (3) seizure and condemnation; (4) Federal and State jurisdiction; and (5) criminal acts and violations. Title V: Public Education - Directs the Secretary to design and implement a national public education program on meat, poultry, and seafood products. Title VI: Miscellaneous Provisions - Authorizes the Secretary to conduct related research programs. (Sec. 603) Authorizes appropriations to carry out the provisions of this Act. Title VII: Repeal of Superseded Laws - Repeals: (1) the Federal Meat Inspection Act; (2) the Poultry Products Inspection Act; and (3) specified provisions of other Federal law. Makes conforming amendments to: (1) the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990; (2) the Consumer Product Safety Act; (3) the Toxic Substances Control Act; (4) the Endangered Species Act of 1973; (5) the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; and (6) other Federal law. Title VIII: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date for amendments made by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
