<bill session="108" type="h" number="4053" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-23T16:29:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-06-23T16:29:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States International Leadership Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">United States International Leadership Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the workings of international organizations and multilateral institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="2004-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400214" joined="2004-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2004-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-03-31">
      <text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T12:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Ros-Lehtinen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T12:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4785-4789" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T12:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4053.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T16:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4823" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-06-23T16:29:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="289" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 365 - 56 (Roll no. 289).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4785-4787" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T16:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="1590"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Emblems"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leadership"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations structure"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2004--Passed House without amendment.
United States International Leadership Act of 2004 - Title I: United States International Leadership - (Sec. 102) Directs the President, through the Secretary of State and the relevant U.S. chiefs of mission, to seek to establish a democracy caucus at the United Nations (UN), the UN Human Rights Commission, the UN Conference on Disarmament, and at other broad-based international organizations. States that a democracy caucus at an international organization should: (1) forge common positions on matters of concern before the organization and work within and across regional lines to promote agreed positions; (2) work to revise an increasingly outmoded system of regional voting and decision making; and (3) set up a rotational leadership scheme to provide member states an opportunity, for a set period of time, to serve as the designated president of the caucus, responsible for serving as its voice in each organization. (Sec. 103) Requires the Secretary to ensure that a high-level Government delegation is sent annually to consult with key foreign governments to promote the U.S. agenda at international fora. (Sec. 104) Directs the President, through the Secretary and the relevant U.S. chiefs of mission, to use U.S. influence to reform the criteria for leadership and, in appropriate cases for membership, at all UN bodies and at other international organizations and multilateral institutions so as to exclude nations that violate organization principles, or are subject to organization sanctions. (Sec. 105) Amends the Foreign Service Act to direct the Secretary to establish training courses for Foreign Service officers, including appropriate chiefs of mission, and for Department of State civilian employees on the conduct of diplomacy at international organizations and other multilateral institutions and at broad-based multilateral negotiations of international instruments. (Sec. 106) Declares that selection boards responsible for recommending Senior Foreign Service promotions shall consider whether the Service member has served in a position whose primary responsibility is to formulate policy towards or represent the United States at an international organization, a multilateral institution, or a broad-based multilateral negotiation of an international instrument. Makes such provision effective as of January 1, 2011. States that Congress finds that: (1) the Department maintains a number of U.S. missions both within the United States and abroad that are dedicated to representing the United States to international organizations and multilateral institutions; and (2) the Department may be well served in developing persons with specialized skills necessary to become experts in this unique form of diplomacy. Directs the Secretary to report on: (1) establishment of a new Foreign Service cone concentrating on service at international organizations and multilateral institutions or participation in multilateral negotiations of international instruments; and (2) alternative mechanisms for developing a core group of U.S. diplomats and other government employees experienced in conducting multilateral diplomacy. (Sec. 107) Authorizes the Secretary to establish within the Bureau of International Organizational Affairs an Office on Multilateral Negotiations whose primary responsibility shall be to assist in the organization of, and preparation for, U.S. participation in multilateral negotiations, including the advocacy efforts undertaken by the Department and other U.S. agencies. Title II: Miscellaneous Provisions - (Sec. 201) Amends the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003 to require the Secretary to report annually on U.S. and international efforts to obtain full membership for the Magen David Adom of Israel in the International Red Cross Movement. (Sec. 202) Authorizes appropriations to: (1) combat the piracy of U.S. copyrighted materials; and (2) make a voluntary contribution to the Organization of American States for the Inter-American Committee Against Terrorism to develop a port in the Latin American-Caribbean region as a model of best security practices.</summary>
</bill>
