<bill session="107" type="h" number="3257" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Give Fans a Chance Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Act of September 30, 1961, to limit the antitrust exemption applicable to broadcasting agreements made by leagues of professional sports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="2001-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-11-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2045-2046"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Baseball"/>
    <term name="Basketball"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Corporate management"/>
    <term name="Football"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ownership"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hockey"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Location of industries"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and state"/>
    <term name="Sports facilities"/>
    <term name="Stadiums"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax preferences"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting of sports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/2001--Introduced.
Give Fans a Chance Act of 2001 - Provides that the antitrust exemption applicable to broadcasting agreements made by professional sports leagues shall not apply to a league for any period during which any member club is: (1) subject to a league's requirement or to an agreement made by two or more member clubs that forbids any of such clubs to transfer an ownership interest to any governmental entity or to members of the general public; or (2) not in compliance with the following relocation or elimination requirements.Requires a member club or a league to furnish notice of a proposed relocation of a club out of its home territory or of club elimination not later than 180 days before the commencement of the new season. Provides that, during the notice period: (1) a local government, stadium, arena authority, person, or any combination thereof (local government) may prepare and present a proposal to purchase the club to retain it in the home community; and (2) the club and the league shall give a local government the opportunity to present a proposal to induce the club to remain. Directs the league to make a determination, before the expiration of the notice period, regarding the relocation or elimination. Sets forth criteria for relocation or elimination decisions, including the extent to which fan loyalty to and support for the club has been demonstrated.</summary>
</bill>
