<bill session="105" type="h" number="3012" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dakota Water Resources Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend Public Law 89-108 to increase authorization levels for State and Indian tribal, municipal, rural, and industrial water supplies, to meet current and future water quantity and quality needs of the Red River Valley, to deauthorize certain project features and irrigation service areas, to enhance natural resources and fish and wildlife habitat, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400323"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2320-2322"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Bur Reclamation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="1515"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Freshwater ecology"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grassland ecology"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Multipurpose projects"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water rates"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/1997--Introduced.
Dakota Water Resources Act of 1997 - Amends Federal provisions relating to the Garrison water diversion unit, North Dakota (part of the Missouri River Basin Project), to include within the authorized purposes of such unit the development of municipal, rural, and industrial water systems, groundwater recharge, augmented stream flows, irrigation, and enhanced fish and wildlife habitat and other natural resources. (Currently, only irrigation is authorized.) Authorizes the State of North Dakota (currently, only the Secretary of the Interior) to plan and construct within North Dakota a multipurpose water resource development irrigation project. Makes nonreimbursable all features constructed by the Secretary before the enactment of this Act. Directs the Secretary to enter into an agreement with North Dakota for the operation and maintenance of the completed unit facilities and the design and construction by the State of new unit facilities. Makes the Secretary responsible for mitigation and enhancement measures associated with features so constructed. (Sec. 3) Repeals a provision prohibiting the Secretary from altering the status of Sheyenne Lake National Wildlife Refuge prior to the completion of construction of Lonetree Dam and Reservoir. (Sec. 4) Excludes certain areas in North Dakota within which the Secretary is authorized to develop irrigation facilities. (Sec. 5) Prohibits irrigation costs from resulting in any reallocation of project costs or increased rates to Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin customers. (Sec. 6) Revises provisions authorizing the construction of municipal, rural, and industrial water systems in North Dakota to: (1) reduce from 25 to 15 percent the non-Federal share of construction costs; (2) authorize the State to use Federal and non-Federal funds for grants or loans for such systems; (3) make additional projects eligible for such funding; (4) direct the Secretary and the State to jointly submit to the Congress a report on the comprehensive water quality and quantity needs of the Red River Valley and the options for meeting those needs; (5) direct the Secretary to prepare and complete a draft environmental impact statement with respect to such needs; (6) direct the State to select one or more options for meeting such needs; (7) authorize the State to develop and implement a State water conservation program; and (8) make nonreimbursable the cost of certain water system features constructed on the Missouri River by the Secretary of the Army before the enactment of this Act. (Sec. 7) Authorizes and directs the Secretary to construct a feature or features to deliver water to the Sheyenne River water supply and release facility or such other feature(s) as selected by the State. Deauthorizes the Lonetree Dam and Reservoir. Authorizes and directs the Secretary to contract with the State for the operation and maintenance of the Lonetree wildlife conservation area. (Sec. 8) Prohibits authorized Federal funds from being used to subsidize the irrigation of any crop at the Oakes Test Area after one year after the enactment of this Act. (Sec. 9) Authorizes additional appropriations to carry out provisions added by this Act. (Sec. 10) Renames the Wetlands Trust (as established under the prior Federal provisions) the Natural Resources Trust and provides additional Federal contributions to such Trust. (Sec. 11) Directs the Secretary to cause to be performed a review of the options for bank stabilization of the Missouri River downstream of the Garrison Dam in North Dakota.</summary>
</bill>
