<bill session="104" type="h" number="1916" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Civil Asset Forfeiture Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform certain statutes regarding civil asset forfeiture.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1996-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="401310" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1996-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1996-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1995-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="1996-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1996-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407669" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="408976" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400398" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="411214" joined="1996-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-22">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to the poor"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/1995--Introduced.
Civil Asset Forfeiture Reform Act - Amends the Federal judicial code to exclude from the customs and tax exemption under tort claims procedures any claim based on the negligent destruction, injury, or loss of goods or merchandise (including real property) while in the possession of any customs or other law enforcement officer. Extends the period for filing claims in certain in rem proceedings. Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to provide that: (1) in all suits or actions brought for the forfeiture of any vessel, vehicle, aircraft, merchandise, or baggage seized under the provisions of any law relating to the collection of duties on imports or tonnage, with exceptions, and for the recovery of the value of any forfeited property because of violation of any such law, the burden of proof is on the Government to establish by clear and convincing evidence that the property was subject to forfeiture; (2) any person claiming such property may at any time within 30 days from the date of the first publication of the notice of seizure file a claim with the appropriate customs officer, who shall transmit such claim to the U.S. attorney for the district in which seizure was made; and (3) if the person filing such claim (or a claim regarding seized property under any other provision of law that incorporates by reference the seizure, forfeiture, and condemnation procedures of the customs laws) is financially unable to obtain representation, the court may appoint counsel, subject to specified requirements. Specifies that a claimant is entitled to immediate release of seized property if continued possession by the Government would cause the claimant substantial hardship, such as preventing the functioning of a business, preventing an individual from working, or leaving an individual homeless. Sets forth procedures regarding the request for release, return of property, and time for decision by the court on a complaint for such return. Makes sums in the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund available for the payment of court-awarded compensation for representation of claimants under the Tariff Act, with respect to seizure claims by individuals financially unable to obtain representation of counsel. Amends the Controlled Substances Act to provide that no conveyance shall be forfeited to the extent of an interest of an owner by reason of any act or omission established by that owner to have been committed or omitted either without the knowledge or without the consent of that owner. Specifies that property shall not be considered to have been used for a proscribed use without the knowledge or consent of the owner of an interest in that property if that owner was wilfully blind to, or has failed to take reasonable steps to prevent, the proscribed use.</summary>
</bill>
