<bill session="104" type="h" number="2754" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-13T13:43:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-06-13T13:43:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Shipbuilding Trade Agreement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Shipbuilding Trade Agreement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Shipbuilding Trade Agreement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To approve and implement the OECD Shipbuilding Trade Agreement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400085"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1995-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1995-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="404520" joined="1995-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1995-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1995-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="408976" joined="1995-12-21" withdrawn="1996-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2333"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on National Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-03-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 4.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-04-18T15:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 104-524, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-18T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on National Security Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than May 30, 1996.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-05-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-05-30T21:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on National Security. H. Rept. 104-524, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-05-30T21:51:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="299">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 299.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-06T15:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 448 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2754 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in part 1 of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-12T23:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 448 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13T10:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 448.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6293-6325" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13T10:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2754 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in part 1 of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13T10:48:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 448 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13T10:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Gil Gutknecht to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13T10:48:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13T11:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 448, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Bateman amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2754.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-06-13T13:43:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="238" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 325 - 100 (Roll no. 238).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="448"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Antidumping"/>
    <term name="Business intelligence"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Ice breaking operations"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International arbitration"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="International corporations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding subsidies"/>
    <term name="Shipping agreements"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tugboats"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1154"/>
    <amendment number="h1155"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/13/1996--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Injurious Pricing and Countermeasures Title II: Other Provisions Title III: Revenue Offset Shipbuilding Trade Agreement Act - Declares that the Congress approves the Agreement Respecting Normal Competitive Conditions in the Commercial Shipbuilding and Repair Industry (Shipbuilding Agreement), a reciprocal trade agreement resulting from negotiations under the auspices of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, entered into on December 21, 1994. Title I: Injurious Pricing and Countermeasures - Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to impose an injurious pricing charge upon the foreign producer of a vessel sold to U.S. buyers at less than fair value if the U.S. International Trade Commission determines that as a result of the sale an industry in the United States: (1) has been materially injured, or is threatened with material injury; or (2) the establishment of an industry in the United States is or has been materially retarded. (Sec. 101) Prescribes procedural guidelines for: (1) an injurious pricing investigation by an administering authority (Secretary of Commerce, or any other Federal officer to whom such responsibilities are transferred); (2) collection of such an injurious pricing charge; and (3) imposition of countermeasures. Prescribes guidelines for: (1) injurious pricing petitions by third countries, and by interested parties with respect to a sale by a foreign producer in a Shipbuilding Agreement Party to a buyer in a third country that is a Shipbuilding Agreement Party; (2) a comparison between export price and normal value in order to determine whether a subject vessel has been sold at less than fair value; (3) determinations on the basis of available facts; and (4) conduct of investigations. Authorizes the U.S. Trade Representative to request the Commission to issue an advisory report, and to notify certain congressional committees, if a dispute settlement panel finds that a Commission action is not in conformity with U.S. obligations under the Shipbuilding Agreement. (Sec. 102) Directs the Customs Service to deny any request, with certain exceptions, for a permit to lade or unlade passengers, merchandise, or baggage from or onto vessels appearing on a countermeasures list pursuant to this Act. (Sec. 103) Provides for judicial review in injurious pricing and countermeasure proceedings. Title II: Other Provisions - Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to exempt certain Shipbuilding Agreement Party vessels from the customs duty on equipment purchased for, and repairs made in a foreign country, upon a vessel documented under U.S. law to engage in the foreign or coastwise trade. Specifies as so exempt: (1) self-propelled seagoing vessels of 100 gross tons or more used for transportation of goods or persons or for performance of a specialized service (including, but not limited to, ice breakers and dredges); and (2) tugs of 365 kilowatts or more. (Sec. 202) Precludes any private right of action under the Shipbuilding Agreement. (Sec. 204) Amends the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 to include a Shipbuilding Agreement vessel within its eligibility guidelines on construction-differential and operating-differential subsidies. Revises guidelines for Federal loans and guaranteed loans for shipbuilding. (Sec. 205) Provides, with respect to the Shipbuilding Agreement, for: (1) Party withdrawal; (2) non-effect on specified other laws; and (3) protection of U.S. interests. Title III: Revenue Offset - Amends Internal Revenue Code provisions which allow a taxpayer to exclude from gross income any such income derived from the international operation of a ship, provided the taxpayer takes the position and discloses on the tax return that such income is not includible in his or her gross income. Sets forth penalties for failure to disclose such position on the tax return, with an exception for failure due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect.</summary>
</bill>
