<bill session="108" type="hc" number="431" updated="2013-07-14T19:03:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Urging the Government of Vietnam to provide to the United States all information in the possession of Vietnam regarding Americans unaccounted for from the Vietnam War, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2004-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2004-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="2004-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2004-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2004-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400254" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2004-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2004-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2004-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2004-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Laos"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military relations"/>
    <term name="Missing in action"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Warships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2004--Introduced.
States that Congress: (1) urges the Government of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam to immediately provide to the United States all information relating to Americans unaccounted for from the Vietnam War, including documents relating to Americans unaccounted for in areas of Laos and Cambodia that were under wartime Vietnamese control; (2) welcomes the improvement in military ties between the United States and Vietnam, including the port call of the U.S.S. Vandergrift in November 2003, and urges the Government of Vietnam to respond positively by the end of 2004 to requests to permit a United States Navy vessel to conduct humanitarian underwater recovery missions along the coastline of Vietnam; and (3) will consider statements by President George W. Bush and the response of the Government of Vietnam to the U.S. request to use a United States Navy vessel to conduct humanitarian underwater recovery missions along the coast of Vietnam before taking further steps beneficial to the economic and political objectives of the Government of Vietnam.</summary>
</bill>
