<bill session="105" type="hr" number="383" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-11T12:12:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-03-11T12:12:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1432) to authorize a new trade and investment policy for sub-Saharan Africa.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-03-10T19:31:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-431, by Mr. Linder.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-10T19:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1432 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill and modified by the amendments printed in part 1 of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. Only those amendments printed in part II of the report accompanying this resolution (H. Rpt. 105-431) shall be in order.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-10T19:31:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="153">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 153.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11T10:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1027-1037" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11T10:40:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11T11:47:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-03-11T12:12:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="43" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 190 (Roll no. 43).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11T12:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="1432"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/1998--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (modified closed) for the consideration of H.R. 1432 (trade and investment policy for sub-Saharan Africa).</summary>
</bill>
