<bill session="108" type="h" number="2243" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the participation of the United States in the thirteenth replenishment of the resources of the International Development Association, the seventh replenishment of the resources of the Asian Development Fund, and the ninth replenishment of the resources of the African Development Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2003-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2003--Introduced.
Amends specified Federal laws to authorize appropriations for: (1) the U.S. contribution to the thirteenth replenishment of the International Development Association; (2) the U.S. contribution to the seventh replenishment of the Asian Development Fund; and (3) the U.S. contribution to the ninth replenishment of the African Development Fund. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. Executive Director at each multilateral development institution to inform such institution of specified U.S. policy goals (and to work toward achieving such goals at the institution before June 30, 2005). Requires each institution to: (1) post on its website an electronic version of Board of Directors meeting minutes within 60 days after any such meeting, with material deemed too sensitive for public distribution redacted; (2) keep a written transcript or electronic recording of each Board meeting and preserve it for at least ten years; (3) make available to the public 15 days before Board consideration (or if not then available, when the documents are distributed to the Board) all public sector loan documents, country assistance strategies, sector strategies, and sector policies prepared by the institution and presented for Board endorsement or approval; (4) post on its website an annual report of statistical summaries and case studies of fraud and corruption cases pursued by its investigations unit; and (5) require any health, education, or poverty-focused loan, credit, grant, document, policy, or strategy prepared by it to include specific outcome and output indicators to measure results, and that such indicators and results be published periodically during execution, and at the completion, of the project or program. Urges the Secretary no later than 60 days after a meeting of the Board of a multilateral development institution to provide for publication on the Department of the Treasury's website of the institution's written statements regarding inspection mechanism claims and cases.</summary>
</bill>
