<bill session="107" type="h" number="1169" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 39, United States Code, with respect to "cooperative mailings".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2001-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2001-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="2001-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2001-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2001-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="2001-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2001-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="2001-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2001-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-03-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E438"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2001--Introduced.
Amends Federal law to declare that, in the case of mail matter (cooperative mailings) sent (or proposed to be sent) by or on behalf of an organization authorized to mail at non-profit postage rates, which also has a contractual or any other business relationship with an entity not so authorized, non-profit postage rates shall apply if those rates would apply in the case of identical mail matter sent by an authorized organization without such a relationship with an unauthorized organization.Declares that an unauthorized organization is not authorized by this Act to advertise, promote, offer, or, for a fee or consideration, recommend, describe, or announce the availability of any of its products or services at such non-profit postage rates.Declares that it is the sense of the Congress that nothing in this Act should be considered to alter the authority of the U.S. Postal Service to: (1) to apply regular postage rates, rather than non-profit rates, to specified other mail matter; or (2) enforce any criminal law within its jurisdiction.</summary>
</bill>
