<bill session="106" type="h" number="2178" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate as wilderness certain lands within the Rocky Mountain National Park in the State of Colorado.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1999-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1210-1211"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-28">
      <text>Referred to Department of the Interior for comments.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1999--Introduced.
Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness Act of 1999 - Designates certain lands in Rocky Mountain National Park, Colorado, as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, which shall be known as the Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness. Allows the continuation of: (1) activities on, under, or affecting the lands designated as wilderness by this Act relating to the monitoring, operating, maintenance, repair, replacement, and use of the Colorado- Big Thompson Project (Project) and its facilities which were allowed as of June 1, 1998; and (2) any other activities that because of emergencies or catastrophic events become necessary for continued use of such Project and its facilities, subject only to reasonable restrictions established by the Secretary of the Interior to protect the wilderness values of such lands. Prohibits any restrictions on such activities that would prevent their occurrence or that would reduce the water supply provided by the Project or the Windy Gap Project.</summary>
</bill>
