<bill session="107" type="h" number="4758" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Restore Fiscal Discipline and Safeguard Social Security Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a responsible increase in the debt limit, restore fiscal discipline, and safeguard Social Security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400282"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="2002-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2002-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400177" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2002-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2002-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2002-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2002-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="2002-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="2002-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="2002-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2002-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400410" joined="2002-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Business cycles"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debt limit"/>
    <term name="Economic forecasting"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="War"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/2002--Introduced.
Restore Fiscal Discipline and Safeguard Social Security Act of 2002 - Amends Federal money and finance law to increase the statutory debt limit to $6.1 trillion.Makes it out of order for the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any bill or amendment that increases the public debt limit above the new one established by this Act by more than $100 billion, except in specified circumstances.Directs the President to submit to Congress a proposal to bring the budget of the Government (excluding the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund) into balance or surplus by FY 2007.Makes it out of order for the House or the Senate, whenever the most recent CBO report projects an on-budget deficit for any fiscal year, to consider any concurrent resolution on the budget that: (1) sets forth or assumes an on-budget deficit for any such fiscal year larger than such projection; (2) sets forth or assumes a budget that is not in on-budget balance or surplus within four fiscal years, and is not in on-budget balance or surplus for any covered subsequent fiscal year; or (3) contains any reduction in social security benefits.Makes it out of order for the House or the Senate, whenever the most recent CBO report projects both on-budget surpluses (or a balanced budget) and deficits for the fiscal years concerned, to consider any concurrent resolution on the budget that: (1) sets forth or assumes an on-budget deficit for any fiscal year for which the CBO projection is for an on-budget surplus or balance; or (2) contains any reduction in social security benefits.Suspends such requirements during war or low economic growth.</summary>
</bill>
