<bill session="104" type="h" number="2942" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Railroad Retirement Amendment Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 to prevent the canceling of annuities to certain divorced spouses of workers whose widows elect to receive lump sum payments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1996-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW09" subcommittee="Railroads" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="1552"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1552"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Divorcees"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/1996--Introduced.
Railroad Retirement Amendment Act of 1996 - Amends the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 to prevent the canceling of annuities to certain divorced wives of workers if, through an administrative error, they received such benefits otherwise precluded by the making of a lump sum payment to a widow. Requires such survivor benefits to be paid to such a divorced wife who elects to repay the lump sum payment to the Railroad Retirement Board. Authorizes the Board to: (1) withhold up to ten percent of each benefit amount paid after the date of the enactment of this Act toward such reimbursement; and (2) waive such repayment to the extent it would cause an unjust financial hardship for the beneficiary. Makes such amendment applicable to such benefits paid in the past, present, or future.</summary>
</bill>
