<bill session="106" type="h" number="1646" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Case Management Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for an extra payment amount under the Medicare Program to rural providers of services who furnish case manager services to Medicare beneficiaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="1999-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E808"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/1999--Introduced.
Rural Case Management Act of 1999 - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for an additional payment under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to rural service providers or physicians who furnish rural case manager services to Medicare beneficiaries. Prohibits any payment for such case manager services furnished to a Medicare beneficiary unless the provider or physician establishes and periodically reviews a rural case management plan for the treatment of such beneficiary. Requires the Secretary to establish the necessary standards for effective and efficient development and oversight of rural case manager services and management plans to: (1) ensure the health and safety of Medicare beneficiaries furnished plan services; and (2) provide guidance on the process or processes that may be used to timely develop such plans. Provides that Medicare limitations on certain physician referrals shall apply to a referral by a rural case manager to a rural agency in the same manner as such limitations apply to a referral by a physician to an entity with which the physician has a financial relationship.</summary>
</bill>
