<bill session="104" type="hj" number="154" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making further continuing appropriations for the District of Columbia for fiscal year 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Municipal officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/3/1996--Introduced.
Appropriates funds for FY 1996 for such amounts as may be necessary under the authority and conditions provided in the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1995 (the Act) for continuing the operations of the District of Columbia (D.C.) government and other activities chargeable against D.C. revenues that were conducted in FY 1995 and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority would be available in the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1996. Prohibits the making of any obligations or expenditures until the Mayor of D.C. has provided to the D.C. Council, the D.C. Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority, the President, and the House and Senate Appropriations Committees prior written notification and a description of the effect of such obligations or expenditures on the current spending plans. Appropriates such amounts as necessary under the authority and conditions provided in the Act for continuing the Federal payment to D.C. and the Federal contribution to retirement funds for FY 1996. Requires the pertinent project or activity to be continued at a rate not exceeding the lowest of the current rate, the rate under the 1996 Act as passed by the House or Representatives, or the rate under the 1996 Act as passed by the Senate. (Sec. 2) Provides that appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this Act shall be available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) the enactment of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this Act; (2) the enactment of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1996 without any provision for such project or activity; or (3) September 30, 1996. (Sec. 3) Specifies additional requirements and limitations regarding appropriations made available or authority granted under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
