<bill session="107" type="hr" number="544" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-25T19:42:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-09-25T19:42:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives on permanency of pension reform provisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400392"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 547 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 540, H. Res. 544 and H. Res. 543. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-25T17:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 547 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-25T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 547.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6678-6681" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-25T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 540, H. Res. 543 and H. Res. 544.  Measure will be considered read.  Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-25T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 544.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-25T19:07:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-25T19:07:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL VOTE - At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. The Yeas and Nays were demanded and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-25T19:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6681-6682" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2002-09-25T19:42:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="415" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 291 - 118 (Roll no. 415).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6678" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-09-25T19:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="hr" number="547"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="107" type="hr" number="547"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2002--Passed House without amendment.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the Congress should complete action in the 107th Congress on the Retirement Security Savings Act of 2002 and should present such legislation to the President for his signature prior to adjournment, so that workers can be assured that certain pension reforms under current law, which are permanently extended by such Act, will not be eliminated.</summary>
</bill>
