<bill session="106" type="h" number="1780" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the settlement of claims of the Menominee Indian Tribe of Wisconsin.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400159"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-05-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E933"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="606"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1021"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/1999--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to pay to the Menominee Indian Tribe of Wisconsin a specified amount for damages sustained by the Tribe by reason of the: (1) enactment and implementation of an Act to provide for a per capita distribution of Menominee tribal funds and authorize the withdrawal of the Menominee Tribe from Federal jurisdiction; and (2) mismanagement by the United States of the Tribe's assets held in trust by the United States before April 30, 1961. Provides that payment of such amount shall be in full satisfaction of any claims that the Tribe may have against the United States with respect to such damages. States that such payment shall: (1) have the status of a judgment of the U.S. Court of Federal Claims for the purposes of the Indian Tribal Judgment Funds Use or Distribution Act; (2) be made in accordance with that Act's requirements on the condition that after payment of attorney's fees and litigation expenses, of the remaining amount, not less than 30 percent shall be distributed on a per capita basis and not more than 70 percent shall be set aside and programmed to serve tribal needs; and (3) not be used to purchase land for the purpose of having such land taken into trust for the Tribe's benefit.</summary>
</bill>
