<bill session="104" type="hc" number="87" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Condemning the refusal of the Indonesian officials organizing the World Archery Championships in Jakarta, Indonesia, in August 1995 to permit a team from Israel to participate in the competition under the name of Israel and under the flag of Israel, and urging the government of Indonesia to join in condemning this manifestation of racism and anti-Semitism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400231"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Antisemitism"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Flags"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Racism"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/1995--Introduced.
Condemns the Indonesian officials organizing the World Archery Championships in Jakarta, Indonesia, for their refusal to permit a team representing Israel to participate under the name and flag of their country. Calls upon the Government of Indonesia to: (1) repudiate this refusal publicly; and (2) urge the inclusion of the Israeli team under the name and flag of Israel. Condemns all manifestations of racism and anti-Semitism wherever they may appear in Indonesia and elsewhere throughout the world. Directs specified congressional officials to convey copies of this Resolution to the Presidents of Indonesia and of the International Archery Federation.</summary>
</bill>
