<bill session="104" type="h" number="547" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Poverty Data Correction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 13, United States Code, to require that any data relating to the incidence of poverty produced or published by the Secretary of Commerce for subnational areas be corrected for differences in the cost of living in those areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Security, International Affairs and Criminal Justice.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO06" subcommittee="National Security, International Affairs and Criminal Justice" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer price indexes"/>
    <term name="Cost of living"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/17/1995--Introduced.
Poverty Data Correction Act - Requires any data relating to the incidence of poverty produced or published by or for the Secretary of Commerce for subnational areas to be corrected for differences in the cost of living, and data produced for State and sub-State areas to be corrected for differences in the cost of living for at least all States of the United States. Requires such corrected data to be published in 1997 and biennially thereafter. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop or cause to be developed a State cost-of-living index which ranks and assigns an index value to each State using data on wage, housing, and other costs relevant to the cost of living; and (2) multiply the Federal Government's statistical poverty thresholds by the index value for each State's cost of living to produce State poverty thresholds for each State. Requires the State cost-of-living index and resulting State poverty thresholds to be published before September 30, 1996, for calendar year 1995 and to be updated annually thereafter.</summary>
</bill>
