<amendment session="107" chamber="h" number="285" updated="2013-07-17T08:15:54-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2505" sequence="3"/>
  <status datetime="2001-07-31T17:49:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="400161"/>
  <offered datetime="2001-07-31"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to ban the use of human somatic cell nuclear transfer technology to initiate a pregnancy but allow the use of somatic cell nuclear transfer technology to clone molecules, DNA, cells, or tissues; require each individual who intends to perform human somatic cell nuclear transfer technology to register with the Secretary of Health and Human Services; sunset the ban ten years after enactment; require those who break the law to forfeit equipment, other property, and any monetary gains; and require a study by the Institute of Medicine on the properties of embryonic, fetal and adult stem cells.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute numbered 2 printed in House Report 107-172 to make it a criminal act, subject to criminal and civil penalties, to use somatic cell nuclear transfer, or the products from this technology, to initiate a pregnancy or with the intent to initiate a pregnancy; to make it illegal to ship, mail, transport, or receive the products of somatic cell nuclear transfer if the products will be used to initiate a pregnancy; to protect other uses of somatic cell nuclear transfer, including therapeutic cloning; to require all individuals or companies who plan to perform somatic cell nuclear transfer to register with the Secretary and attest that they know that initiating a pregnancy through such means is illegal; to provide that such registration is deemed confidential, following the same fashion as the FDA's treatment of trade secrets when a company files an Investigational New Drug application; to preempt future state laws that are different from federal cloning law or prohibit protected types of research; to sunset the ban ten years after enactment; to require those who break the law to forfeit equipment, other property, and any monetary gains; and to require a study by the Institute of Medicine on the properties of embryonic, fetal and adult stem cells.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Greenwood.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4931-4943" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4931" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31T17:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A003) and on the bill pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2001-07-31T17:49:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="302">
      <text>On agreeing to the Greenwood amendment (A003) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 178 - 249 (Roll no. 302).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
