<bill session="108" type="hr" number="310" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-09T12:10:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-07-09T12:10:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2211) to reauthorize title II of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-08T21:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 108-190, by Mrs. Myrick.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-08T21:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and the Workforce now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule. Makes in order only those amendments printed in House Report 108-190. Provides that the amendments printed in the report shall be considered only in the order printed, offered only by a Member designated in the report, considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified, equally divided and controlled, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand fora division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole. Waives all points of order against the amendments printed</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-07-08T21:10:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="77">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 77.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-07-09T10:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6353-6356" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-09T10:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 310.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-09T10:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-09T10:47:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - The Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern asked for the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-09T12:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6363-6364" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2003-07-09T12:10:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="338" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 252 - 170 (Roll no. 338).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6353" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-09T12:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="h" number="2211"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2003--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 2211 (reauthorization of title II (Teacher Quality Enhancement) of the Higher Education Act of 1965).</summary>
</bill>
