<bill session="105" type="h" number="2096" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States-Caribbean Basin Trade Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote the growth of free enterprise and economic opportunity in the Caribbean Basin region, increase trade and investment between the Caribbean Basin region and the United States, and encourage the adoption by Caribbean Basin countries of policies necessary for participation in the free trade area of the Americas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="984"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alternative crops"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Clothing industry"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Import quotas"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Opium"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Textile industry"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/1997--Introduced.
United States-Caribbean Basin Trade Enhancement Act - Amends the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act to accord, for a specified transition period, the same tariff and quota treatment (lower tariffs or duty-free treatment) given certain textile and apparel articles imported from North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) countries to such articles from U.S.-Caribbean Basin Trade Enhancement Act (CBTEA) beneficiary countries planning to become parties to the Free Trade Area of the Americas, or countries which have undertaken their obligations under the World Trade Organization on or ahead of schedule. Authorizes any interested U.S. person during such transition period to request the President to proclaim lower tariff and quota treatment with respect to certain nonoriginating CBTEA textile and apparel articles. Directs the President to report periodically to the Congress concerning CBTEA beneficiary countries. Directs the United States International Trade Commission to report biennially to the Congress and the President on the economic impact of this Act on U.S. industries and consumers, including its effectiveness in promoting drug-related crop eradication and crop substitution efforts of the CBTEA beneficiary countries. Authorizes the President to determine that a country is not providing adequate protection of intellectual property rights under its laws, even if it is in compliance with the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights under the Uruguay Round Agreements Act.</summary>
</bill>
