<bill session="107" type="h" number="3480" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-04-09T15:05:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-04-09T15:05:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Upper Mississippi River Basin Protection Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Upper Mississippi River Basin Protection Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote Department of the Interior efforts to provide a scientific basis for the management of sediment and nutrient loss in the Upper Mississippi River Basin.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400214" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400519" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2001-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Received from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-03-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T14:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-388.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-04-09T14:11:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="226">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 226.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1101-1104" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T14:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3480.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-04-09T15:05:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1101-1103" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T15:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-04-25">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Jeffords without amendment. With written report No. 107-169.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-06-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="433">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 433.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer simulation"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Estuarine pollution"/>
    <term name="Eutrophication"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Sedimentation"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2002--Passed House without amendment.
Upper Mississippi River Basin Protection Act of 2001 - Declares that it is the policy of Congress that Federal investments in the Upper Mississippi River Basin must be guided by sound science.Title I: Sediment and Nutrient Monitoring Network - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, through the United States Geological Survey, to establish a nutrient and sediment monitoring network for the River Basin to: (1) identify and evaluate sources of sediments and nutrients; (2) quantify the processes affecting mobilization, transport, and fate of those sediments and nutrients on land and in water; (3) quantify their transport to and through the Basin; (4) record changes to sediment and nutrient loss; (5) provide coordinated data to be used in computer modeling of the Basin; and (6) identify major sources for targeting resources to reduce sediment and nutrient loss. States that such information shall be headquartered at the Upper Midwest Environmental Sciences Center in La Crosse, Wisconsin.(Sec. 102) Directs the Secretary to establish guidelines for related data collection and storage activities. Requires such data to be released to the public using generic station identifiers and hydrologic codes. Prohibits information regarding the location of a monitoring station on private lands from being disseminated without the landowner's permission.(Sec. 103) Directs the Secretary to inventory the sediment and monitoring efforts of governmental and nongovernmental entities for the purpose of creating a baseline understanding of overlap, data gaps, and redundancies, and based on such inventory, to integrate them into the monitoring network. Requires that such activities be carried out in coordination with the Lower Estuary Assessment Group as authorized under the Estuaries and Clean Waters Act of 2000.(Sec. 104) Directs the Secretary to collaborate with other public and private monitoring efforts in establishing the monitoring program.(Sec. 105) Makes the non-Federal sponsors of the monitoring network responsible for not less than 25 percent of the costs of maintaining it. Permits up to 80 percent of the non-Federal share to be provided through in-kind contributions. Deems a State or local monitoring effort that is adhering to the guidelines specified above to satisfy all such cost-share requirements.(Sec. 106) Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the development of such network.(Sec. 107) Directs the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a water resources assessment of the Basin.Title II: Computer Modeling and Research - Requires the Director of the United States Geological Survey to establish a computer modeling program of nutrient and sediment sources in the Basin. Requires such modeling to be used to identify subwatersheds that are significant sources of sediment and nutrient loss and to be made available for targeting public and private sediment and nutrient reduction efforts. Requires sediment and nutrient models to include models to: (1) relate nutrient and sediment loss to landscape, land use, and land management practices; and (2) define river channel nutrient transformation processes. Requires the collection of ancillary information in a GIS format to support modeling and management use of such results. States that such information shall be headquartered at the Center in La Crosse, Wisconsin.(Sec. 202) Requires the Director to establish an Internet-based system to distribute information about nutrient and sediment loss reduction projects and nutrient and sediment levels in the Upper Mississippi River and its tributaries.(Sec. 203) Requires the Director to provide to Congress and the public: (1) annual reports regarding monitoring activities conducted in the Basin; and (2) a progress report regarding modeling activities every three years.Title III: Authorization of Appropriations - Authorizes appropriations to: (1) the Secretary to carry out this Act; and (2) allow the National Research Council to perform the water resources assessment.</summary>
</bill>
