<bill session="104" type="h" number="1646" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reserve Forces Revitalization Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To revise and reform the statutes governing the organization and management of the reserve components of the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406625"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400569" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="401774" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="402750" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="404068" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404503" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400169" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="405258" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400547" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400590" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="408476" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1995-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1996-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-22">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29">
      <text>Favorable Executive Comment Received from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House National Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Marine corps"/>
    <term name="Military civic action"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military construction operations"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Military leave"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military posture"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax incentives"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Findings and Purposes Title II: Reserve Component Structure Title III: Reserve Component Accessibility Title IV: Reserve Component Resources Title V: Reserve Forces Sustainment Reserve Forces Revitalization Act of 1995 - Title I: Findings and Purposes - States that the purpose of this Act is to revise statutory authorities governing the reserve components of the armed forces in order to recognize the realities of reserve component partnership in the Total Force and to better prepare the American citizen-soldier in peace for duties in war. Title II: Reserve Component Structure - Establishes within the appropriate military departments the Army, Naval, and Air Force Reserve Command, as well as the Marine Forces Reserve. Provides for a commander and deputy commander within each of the Commands and Reserve. Requires the Secretary of each military department (Commandant, with respect to the Marine Corps) to assign to the Command or Reserve all of their reserve forces (specified portions with respect to the Marine Corps). Requires an implementation report and schedule. Establishes in each military department an Office of Army, Naval, Marine Forces, and Air Force Reserve, as well as a Chief of each such Reserve. Outlines administrative provisions with respect to each such office, including terms of office, budgets, and a required annual report to the Congress. (Sec. 203) Requires the Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau to serve in the grade of lieutenant general (currently, major general). (Sec. 204) Provides the grades of the commanders of the reserve personnel centers. (Sec. 205) Exempts from annual active-duty officer end strength limitations general officers responsible for reserve affairs within the military departments. (Sec. 206) Limits the total reduction in the number of positions authorized for military (civilian) technicians of the Army and Air National Guard and the Army and Air Force Reserve. Title III: Reserve Component Accessibility - Authorizes the President to order to active duty members of the Ready Reserve: (1) in time of national emergency declared by the Congress; (2) when necessary to provide Federal disaster relief to a State upon request; and (3) when otherwise authorized by law. Requires 48 hours' prior notification to the Congress before exercising such authority. Provides time limitations with respect to such activations. Requires quarterly reports to the Congress by the President with respect to the exercise of such authority and the necessity for retention of the reserves on active duty. Limits to one million the total number of personnel authorized to be on such duty at any one time without their consent. Directs the Secretary of Defense to prescribe policies and procedures for the release of such members from such duty. Prohibits any member of the Ready Reserve from being ordered to such duty more than once in any 24-month period, with a waiver by the President when it is determined that such service is urgently required and not otherwise available. (Sec. 302) Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress concerning possible legislation: (1) providing tax incentives to employers of reserve personnel to compensate for employee absences due to the performance of involuntary training or required or involuntary active duty; (2) to establish an income insurance program to provide replacement income to reserve personnel called to active duty or active Federal service; and (3) to establish a small business loan program to provide to reserve personnel ordered to active duty or active Federal service during a contingency operation low-cost loans to assist such members in retaining or rebuilding businesses affected by such service. Title IV: Reserve Component Resources - Directs the Secretary to include in the annual budget report to the Congress a report on any actual or anticipated shortfall in funding for reserve component personnel, operations and maintenance, equipment, or military construction in the budget for that fiscal year. (Sec. 402) Requires funds appropriated to the reserve components to be allocated by the Secretary to the use of that component for the purposes provided by the Congress. Requires amounts intended for military or civilian active personnel performing service in support of the reserves to be shown separately in budget justification documents. Title V: Reserve Forces Sustainment - Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress concerning possible legislation to restore the tax deductibility of nonreimbursable expenses incurred by reserve personnel in connection with military service. (Sec. 502) Authorizes the Secretary to pay transient housing charges for reserve personnel performing active duty for training at locations which are more than 50 miles from their current residence. (Currently, such authority is limited to annual training duty performed at such locations.) (Sec. 503) Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the United States should continue to pay reserve personnel appropriate quarters allowances during periods of service on active duty for training; and (2) current reserve component military leave policies should not be changed. (Sec. 505) Directs the Secretary to seek to arrange for the establishment by a private insurance carrier of a group dental plan for members of the Selected Reserve and their dependents which would enable such individuals to obtain dental care at a low cost. (Sec. 506) Directs the Secretary to seek to enter into an agreement with a national organization representing retail merchants under which such organization would sponsor a program for the provision of price discounts by participating retail merchants to members of the armed forces. (Sec. 507) Commends the Reserve Forces Policy Board for its past work as an independent source of advice to the Secretary on all matters pertaining to the reserves. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Board and the reserve forces policy committees for the individual military departments should continue to perform the vital role of providing the civilian leadership of the Department of Defense with independent advice on such matters.</summary>
</bill>
