<bill session="108" type="hc" number="453" updated="2013-07-14T19:03:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Celebrating the establishment of democracy in Iraq and urging the people of the United States and of other countries in all communities and congregations to ring bells on June 30, 2004, to commemorate the restoration of freedom to the people of Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400145"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2004--Introduced.
States that Congress: (1) celebrates the establishment of democracy in Iraq; (2) recognizes the importance of the freedoms that are being restored to the Iraqi people; (3) supports the five-step plan outlined by President Bush for the restoration of Iraqi sovereignty; (4) expresses gratitude to the members of the U.S. Armed Forces who are participating in Operation Iraqi Freedom to end the regime of Saddam Hussein and bring democracy and freedom to Iraq; (5) encourages all the people of Iraq to work together to create a new Iraq; and (6) urges the people of the United States and of other countries in all communities and congregations to ring bells on June 30, 2004, in recognition of the establishment of democracy in Iraq and the restoration of freedom to the people of Iraq.</summary>
</bill>
