<bill session="104" type="h" number="85" updated="2012-11-01T22:43:26-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Travel Disclosure Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for greater disclosure of and accountability for Federal Government travel.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400210"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on House Oversight, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>01/04/1995--Introduced.
Federal Travel Disclosure Act of 1995 - Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of Federal funds for: (1) Government travel other than from amounts specifically appropriated by law for such purpose; or (2) travel expenses paid by one Federal entity for an individual employed by another Federal entity without reimbursement by the individual or the travel account of the individual's employer. (Sec. 3) Directs the head of each executive department to designate a travel supervisor. Specifies the travel supervisors for the legislative and judicial branches. (Sec. 4) Requires all Government travel to be: (1) approved in advance by the appropriate travel supervisor; (2) accomplished by the most economical means conveniently possible; and (3) accomplished by U.S. commercial carrier wherever possible. Requires all legislative branch foreign travel, with specified exceptions, to be approved in advance by recorded vote of the committee (in the case of travel by a committee member or committee staff) or by the appropriate travel supervisor. (Sec. 5) Requires each travel supervisor to establish written guidelines for Government travel and to submit quarterly reports with respect to such travel to the Administrator of General Services (for executive branch or independent agency travel), the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate (for legislative branch travel), and the Director of the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts (for judicial branch travel). Requires such reports to be made available for public inspection.</summary>
</bill>
