<bill session="106" type="h" number="2909" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-06">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Intercountry Adoption Convention Implementation bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Intercountry Adoption Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for implementation by the United States of the Hague Convention on Protection of Children and Cooperation in Respect of Intercountry Adoption, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400568" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="2000-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2000-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2000-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1999-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1999-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2000-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1999-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1999-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1999-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2000-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1999-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2000-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="1999-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2000-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="1999-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1930"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-14">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-22T23:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on International Relations. H. Rept. 106-691, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-22">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Ways and Means for a period ending not later than June 22, 2000 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(s), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-22T23:23:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 22, 2000.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-22T23:24:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Education and the Workforce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 22, 2000.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-22T23:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-22T23:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Education and the Workforce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-06-22T23:28:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="387">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 387.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-22T23:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6389-6399" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18T12:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2909.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-07-18T13:03:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6389-6394" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18T13:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="692">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 692.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7751-7752" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-07-27" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-18T18:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman asked unanimous consent that the House agree with an amendment to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-18T18:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with debate under a reservation of objection. At the conclusion of debate, the reservation was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-09-18T18:54:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree with an amendment to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7690-7695" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7690-7694" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-09-18T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-19">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-09-20" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendment to Senate amendment by Unanimous Consent Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8866" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8866" label="text as Senate agreed to House amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2000-09-21">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-09-26">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-10-06">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-10-06" type="public" number="106-279">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-279.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="h" number="2342"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="682"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="682"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Adopted children"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Adoptive parents"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emigration"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4023"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/18/2000--House agreed to Senate amendment with amendment.
Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000 - Title I: United States Central Authority - Requires the Department of State, through the Secretary of State, to serve as the central authority of the United States with respect to implementation of the Convention on Protection of Children and Co-operation in Respect of Intercountry Adoption done at the Hague on May 29, 1993. Outlines responsibilities of the Secretary, including liaison, information exchange, accreditation and approval, and other coordination activities relating to the Convention.(Sec. 103) Requires the Attorney General to be responsible for the filing of applications by prospective adoptive parents to the central authority of their country of residence.(Sec. 104) Requires annual reports from the Secretary to specified congressional committees describing activities of the U.S. central authority during the previous year.Title II: Provisions Relating to Accreditation and Approval - Prohibits any person from offering or providing adoption services, with specified exceptions, in connection with a Convention adoption in the United States unless that person is accredited under this title, or is providing such services through or under the supervision and responsibility of an accredited agency or approved person.(Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary to enter into agreements with one or more qualified entities that will provide for the accreditation of agencies, and approval of persons, to provide adoption services in the United States in cases subject to the Convention. Requires such entities to undertake related oversight, enforcement, and information collection activities. Sets forth procedures for an agency or person to reapply for accreditation after an adverse action by an accrediting entity. Provides for the judicial review of such actions. Subjects to approval by the Secretary any fees assessed by accrediting entities against agencies or persons seeking accreditation for Convention intercountry adoptions. Outlines accreditation standards and procedures.(Sec. 204) Directs the Secretary to: (1) monitor each entity's performance of accrediting duties and compliance with the Convention and other applicable laws and regulations; and (2) suspend or cancel the accreditation of an agency or person found to be substantially out of compliance with applicable requirements, if the accrediting entity has failed or refused to take appropriate corrective action. Authorizes the Secretary to debar an agency or person from accreditation, under certain conditions. Provides judicial review of the Secretary's decisions under this section.Declares that willful, grossly negligent, or repeated failure by an agency to ensure the completion and transmission of a background report (home study) on prospective adoptive parents that fully complies with the Convention and applicable Federal and State requirements shall constitute substantial noncompliance with such requirements.(Sec. 205) Amends part B (Child and Family Services) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require State plans for child welfare services to include among other things: (1) a description of the activities that the State has undertaken for children adopted from other countries, including adoption and post-adoption services; and (2) a requirement that the State collect and report information on children who are adopted from other countries, and who enter into State custody as a result of the disruption of a placement for adoption or the dissolution of an adoption, including the number of children, the agencies that handled the placement or adoption, the plans for the child, and the reasons for the disruption or dissolution.Title III: Recognition of Convention Adoptions in the United States - Directs the Secretary, with respect to each Convention adoption, to issue a certificate to the adoptive citizen parent domiciled in the United States recognizing the legal effect, for purposes of emigration and adoption, of a Convention adoption, as long as the Secretary has received appropriate documentation from the central authority of the child's country of origin, and has verified that other requirements of the Convention and this Act have been met with respect to adoption. Provides for U.S. recognition of adoptions finalized in other Convention countries.(Sec. 302) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to include: (1) under its definition of "child" a child adopted through the Convention; and (2) under its immigration approval procedures a child for whom the Secretary has certified that a U.S. citizen has effected final adoption under the Convention. Authorizes the Attorney General, in determining whether the purpose of a particular adoption under this Act is to form a bona fide parent-child relationship, and the parent-child relationship of the child and the natural parents has been terminated, to consider whether there is a petition pending to confer immigrant status on one or both of such natural parents.(Sec. 303) Outlines procedures for the adoption in any other Convention country of a child residing in the United States, requiring certain duties to be performed by an accredited agency or approved person or the prospective parents acting on their own behalf (if so permitted in such country). Prohibits a State court from entering an order declaring such adoption to be final or granting custody for adoption, unless such court: (1) has received and verified that such duties have been performed, as well as evidence that other Convention requirements have been met; and (2) has determined that the adoptive placement is in the child's best interests.Title IV: Administration and Enforcement - Provides for: (1) the preservation of Convention adoption records; (2) disclosure and access of Convention records (to the extent necessary to administer the Convention or this Act) and of non-Convention records (including records of adoption proceedings conducted in the United States); and (3) recognition of Convention documents of other countries. Makes unlawful the disclosure of all or part of a Convention record.(Sec. 403) Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 404) Provides civil penalties and other enforcement procedures for violations of this Act.Title V: General Provisions - Sets forth provisions with respect to the recognition of Convention adoptions.(Sec. 502) Authorizes the Secretary to establish by regulation alternative procedures for the adoption of children by individuals related to them by blood, marriage, or adoption in cases subject to the Convention.(Sec. 503) States that the Convention and this Act shall have no effect on: (1) State law; or (2) provisions of the Indian Child Welfare Act.</summary>
</bill>
