<bill session="108" type="hr" number="165" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-10T12:47:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-04-10T12:47:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing support for a renewed effort to find a peaceful, just, and lasting settlement to the Cyprus problem.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="2003-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2003-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2003-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2003-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-09T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bereuter moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-09T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H3009-3014" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-09T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 165.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-09T19:37:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10T12:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H3077" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2003-04-10T12:47:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="129" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 422 - 0 (Roll no. 129).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR 4/09/2003 H3009-3010" label="text as passed House"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10T12:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSFA14" subcommittee="Europe" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Cyprus"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Greece"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="Turks"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations officials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2003--Passed House amended.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced on March 27, 2003. The summary of that version is repeated here.)Expresses the appreciation of the House of Representatives for the efforts of the United Nations Secretary General to seek a peaceful, just, and lasting settlement of the Cyprus problem for the benefit of the people of Cyprus and the region.Expresses its strong disappointment that the Secretary General's efforts to bring his plan for a comprehensive settlement to a referenda by the people of Cyprus has been rejected.Expresses its very strong regret that Turkish Cypriot leader, Mr. Denktash, rejected the comprehensive settlement offered by the Secretary General and denied the Turkish Cypriot people the opportunity to determine their own future by refusing to offer the settlement proposal to referenda.Declares that the House remains committed, despite the recent setback, to giving any assistance necessary for finding a just and durable settlement for the Cyprus problem and urges the maximum effort by the U.S. Government and others to redouble their efforts to seek a just and lasting settlement to the Cyprus problem.Encourages both Greek and Turkish Cypriot leaders to renew their efforts to find a settlement to the Cyprus problem on the basis of the Secretary General's framework.Urges the Governments of Turkey and Greece to do everything possible to support the search for a settlement, including actions by the Government of Turkey helping to persuade the Turkish Cypriot leader to reach an agreement which would reunite the island and which would serve the interests of both Cypriot communities.Encourages both sides, upon completion of a comprehensive settlement, to consider putting it to referenda, if necessary, in order that the will of the people of Cyprus can be democratically expressed.</summary>
</bill>
