<bill session="106" type="h" number="3824" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Support for Children Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To simplify and improve the rules governing the distribution of child support collected by States pursuant to part D of title IV of the Social Security Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2000-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="2000-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2000-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E221"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Child support enforcement"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Prenatal care"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2000--Introduced.
Child Support for Children Act - Amends parts A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) and D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) of the Social Security Act (SSA) with respect to: (1) mandatory pass-through to families of current child support payments to the extent that the amount of such payment does not exceed the amount required to be paid to the family for the month in which collected; (2) payment rules in connection with child support collected by the State on behalf of families receiving assistance under SSA title IV parts A and E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) in determining the family's TANF eligibility; (3) maintenance of effort; (4) State part A plan requirements to ensure timely TANF payments when child support payments are delayed; (5) payment rules in connection with child support arrearages; and (6) State part D requirements to ban the use of child support enforcement to collect certain Medicaid (SSA title XIX) expenses from noncustodial parents.</summary>
</bill>
