<bill session="106" type="h" number="3671" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-11-01">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs Improvement Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs Improvement Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs Improvement Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Fish and Wildlife Programs Improvement and National Wildlife Refuge System Centennial Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act Amendments of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">National Wildlife Refuge System Centennial Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs Improvement Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Fish and Wildlife Programs Improvement and National Wildlife Refuge System Centennial Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act Amendments of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">National Wildlife Refuge System Centennial Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs Improvement Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Acts popularly known as the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act and the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act to enhance the funds available for grants to States for fish and wildlife conservation projects and increase opportunities for recreational hunting, bow hunting, trapping, archery, and fishing, by eliminating opportunities for waste, fraud, abuse, maladministration, and unauthorized expenditures for administration and execution of those Acts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">A bill to amend the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act and the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act to enhance the funds available for grants to States for fish and wildlife conservation projects, to reauthorize and amend the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act, to commemorate the centennial of the establishment of the first national wildlife refuge in the United States on March 14, 1903, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2000-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2000-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400603" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="2000-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400353" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400372" joined="2000-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400374" joined="2000-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2000-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2000-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="2000-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-02-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E156"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-22">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-03-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 36 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-03-30T15:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-554.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-03-30T15:42:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="301">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 301.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-04-03T20:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 455 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3671 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 4(a) of rule XIII are waived. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Resources now printe in the bill. Points of order against the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute for failure to comply with clause 4 of rule XXI are waived. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 455 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 455.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1806-1821" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3671 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 4(a) of rule XIII are waived. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Resources now printed in the bill. Points of order against the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute for failure to comply with clause 4 of rule XXI are waived. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 455 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Richard Burr to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3671.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3671.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05T17:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1815-1818" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05T17:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-04-05T17:27:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="105" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 423 - 2 (Roll no. 105).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E555-557"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-10-10">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Smith, of NH with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 106-495. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-10-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="945">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 945.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-10-12">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10491-10498" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10491-10494" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-12">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-10-12" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-17T17:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10017-10026" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-17T17:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-17T17:52:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Udall (NM) objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed until Oct. 18. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-10-18T18:50:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10082" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 10/17/2000 H10017-10023" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-18T18:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-18">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-11-01">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-11-01" type="public" number="106-408">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-408.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="455"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to territories"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Interstate commissions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Relocation of employees"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special years"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trapping"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h652"/>
    <amendment number="h653"/>
    <amendment number="h654"/>
    <amendment number="s4312"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/12/2000--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs Subtitle A: Wildlife Restoration Subtitle B: Sport Fish Restoration Subtitle C: Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs Title II: National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Title III: National Wildlife Refuge System Centennial Fish and Wildlife Programs Improvement and National Wildlife Refuge System Centennial Act of 2000 - Title I: Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs - Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs Improvement Act of 2000 - Subtitle A: Wildlife Restoration - Amends the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (Federal Aid in Wildlife Restoration Act) to specify the amounts authorized to be set aside for FY 2001 and thereafter for administrative expenses of the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) in implementing such Act. Authorizes any administrative portions remaining in a fiscal year to be apportioned among the States for purposes of such Act.Adds Puerto Rico to the list of territories to which revenues from taxes imposed on pistols, revolvers, bows, and arrows shall be apportioned.Specifies authorized administrative uses of amounts set aside for administration. Prohibits the Secretary from using such amounts to supplement any function for which general appropriations are made for the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) or any other entity of the Department of the Interior (Department). Requires the Department's Inspector General to procure the performance of biennial audits of such expenditures.(Sec. 112) Earmarks funds under such Act for grants to States that: (1) have not used all funds apportioned from taxes on pistols, revolvers, bows, and arrows for the enhancement of hunter education programs, hunter and sporting firearm safety programs, hunter development programs and construction or development of firearm shooting and archery ranges; and (2) have used such tax funds for any use authorized by the Act. Limits to 75 percent the Federal share of any grant activity.(Sec. 113) Earmarks funds under such Act for multi-State conservation project grants under which the Secretary makes grants that will benefit at least 26 States for wildlife restoration projects submitted each fiscal year by State fish and game departments acting through the International Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies (Association). Requires nongovernmental organizations that apply for such grants to certify that grant funds will not be used for activities that promote or encourage opposition to regulated hunting or trapping of wildlife.Subtitle B: Sport Fish Restoration - Amends the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act (Federal Aid in Fish Restoration Act) to specify the amounts authorized to be set aside for FY 2001 and thereafter for administrative expenses of the Secretary in implementing such Act. Authorizes remaining administrative portions in a fiscal year to be apportioned among the States for purposes of such Act. Specifies authorized administrative uses of such amounts. Prohibits the Secretary from using such amounts to supplement any function for which general appropriations are made for the USFWS or another Department entity. Requires the Department's Inspector General to procure the performance of biennial audits of such expenditures.(Sec. 122) Makes amounts under such Act available each fiscal year to the Secretary for making multi-State (at least 26 States benefitting) project conservation grants for sport fish restoration projects prepared and submitted by State fish and game departments acting through the Association. Requires nongovernmental organizations that apply for such grants to certify that grant funds will not be used for activities that promote or encourage opposition to the regulated taking of fish. Earmarks fiscal year grant amounts for specified marine fisheries commissions and the Sport Fishing and Boating Partnership Council.(Sec. 123) Extends the availability of funds made available under such Act to carry out the Coastal Wetlands, Planning, Protection, and Restoration Act through FY 2009.Subtitle C: Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs - Designates the programs established under the amended Acts as the Federal Assistance Program for State Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration (Program).(Sec. 132) Establishes within the USFWS an Assistant Director for Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs to administer, manage, and oversee the Program.(Sec. 133) Requires the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees on the steps taken to comply with this title, including the extent to which compliance has required a reduction in personnel assigned to administer, manage, and oversee the Program.Provides for spending certifications by the Secretary to specified congressional committees on amounts used under such Acts as well as spending certifications by States to the Secretary.Title II: National Fish and Wildlife Foundation - National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act Amendments of 2000 - Amends the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (the Act) to increase the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation's Board of Directors from 15 to 25 members, including the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.(Sec. 204) Authorizes the Foundation to have its principal offices in Washington, D.C. (as currently provided), or in the bordering counties of Maryland or Virginia.Sets forth conditions for the Foundation to: (1) acquire and convey property, including agency approval; and (2) invest and deposit Federal funds.Revises provisions relating to agency approval of acquisitions of property and of conveyances and grants. Sets forth limitations relating to the Foundation's: (1) reconveyance of real property; and (2) expenditures for printing services or capital equipment.(Sec. 206) Bars the Foundation from making a grant unless it provides notice within a prescribed time frame to the Member of Congress for the congressional district in which the funded project will be carried out.(Sec. 207) Authorizes appropriations for FY 2001 through 2003 for the Departments of Commerce and the Interior to carry out activities under the Act (conservation or management of fish, wildlife, plants, and other natural resources). Authorizes the Foundation to accept funds from a Federal agency under any other Federal law to further its conservation and management activities. Sets forth matching funds requirements.Prohibits Foundation grants from being used for litigation expenses or for lobbying Congress.(Sec. 208) Declares that nothing in this Act authorizes the Foundation to perform any function for which authority is provided to the National Park Foundation by specified Federal law.Title III: National Wildlife Refuge System Centennial - National Wildlife Refuge System Centennial Act - Establishes the National Wildlife Refuge System Centennial Commission to, among other things: (1) prepare a plan to commemorate the centennial of the System beginning on March 14, 2003; and (2) plan and host a conference on the System.(Sec. 304) Directs the Secretary to: (1) prepare and submit to Congress and the President a long-term plan to address priority operation, maintenance, and construction needs of the System; and (2) prepare and submit annually to Congress an assessment of expenditures to meet the identified operation and maintenance backlog, a specification of transition costs, as identified in the analysis of newly acquired refuge land, and a description of the method used to determine the priority status of such costs.(Sec. 305) Declares that Congress finds that designation of the year 2003 as the Year of the Wildlife Refuge would promote the goal of increasing public appreciation of the System.(Sec. 306) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
