<bill session="104" type="hr" number="121" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-30T12:31:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-03-30T12:31:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 831) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permanently extend the deduction for the health insurance costs of self-employed individuals, to repeal the provision permitting nonrecognition of gain on sales and exchanges effectuating policies of the Federal Communications Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408976"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T21:49:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-93, by Mr. Quillen.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T21:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 831. Waiving all points of order against the conference report and against its consideration. The conference report shall be considered read when called up.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-03-29T21:49:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="36">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 36.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30T10:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3986-3994" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30T10:56:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30T12:22:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 201 (Roll No. 278).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-03-30T12:31:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="279" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 244 - 178 (Roll No. 279).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30T12:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="831"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/1995--Introduced.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the conference report on H.R. 831 (amending the Internal Revenue Code to permanently extend the deduction for the health insurance costs of self-employed individuals and repealing the provision permitting nonrecognition of gain on sales and exchanges effectuating policies of the Federal Communications Commission).</summary>
</bill>
