<bill session="104" type="h" number="3106" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rail Safety Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve rail transportation safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400438"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1996-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1996-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1996-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1996-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1996-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1996-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1996-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW09" subcommittee="Railroads" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fuel storage"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lighting"/>
    <term name="Locomotives"/>
    <term name="Navigation satellites"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad equipment"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad research"/>
    <term name="Railroad rolling stock"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1996--Introduced.
Rail Safety Act of 1996 - Amends Federal transportation law to direct the Secretary of Transportation to promulgate regulations concerning limitations on duty hours of train employees that are no less stringent than those under specified existing Federal transportation law. Directs the Secretary to study and report to the Congress on: (1) the feasibility of requiring satellite-based positive train control systems in the United States by January 1, 2001; and (2) the technical, structural, and economic feasibility of installing in rail passenger cars devices which, in the event of a collision, would automatically provide passenger escape access. Directs the Secretary, to the extent feasibility is determined, to promulgate regulations requiring installation of such control systems and train escape devices by specified dates. Directs the Secretary to: (1) determine what regulations are necessary to increase the ability of passengers to escape from a rail car in the event of an emergency; and (2) if necessary, promulgate them, to take effect as soon as practicable. Directs the Secretary to establish, by regulation, minimum safety standards for fuel tanks of locomotives of rail passenger trains that take into consideration environmental protection and public safety. Directs the Secretary to determine, and report to the appropriate congressional committees, whether to promulgate regulations for public safety purposes to: (1) require crash posts at the corners of rail passenger cars; (2) require safety locomotives on rail passenger trains; (3) establish minimum crash-worthiness standards for passenger cab cars; or (4) carry out any combination of the above. Directs the Secretary to: (1) study whether to promulgate regulations requiring placement of rail signals along railways in specified positions; and (2) promulgate such regulations if the requirement is determined necessary. Requires a report to the Congress if such placement is determined unnecessary.</summary>
</bill>
