<bill session="105" type="h" number="4124" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">E-Mail User Protection Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote online commerce and communications, to protect consumers and service providers from the misuse of computer facilities by others sending unsolicited commercial electronic mail over such facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400577"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Direct mail advertising"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Mailing lists"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/1998--Introduced.
E-Mail User Protection Act of 1998 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit any person from: (1) intentionally soliciting the transmission of unsolicited commercial e-mail from an unregistered or fictitious Internet domain or e-mail address in order to prevent reply through standard reply mechanisms; (2) intentionally using or distributing a computer program or other mechanism or procedure to disguise the source of unsolicited commercial e-mail; (3) intentionally distributing a collection or list of e-mail addresses knowing that persons on such list have previously requested removal from the list; (4) intentionally registering or creating an Internet e-mail account for the sole or primary purpose of disguising the source of unsolicited e-mail messages; (5) directing an unsolicited commercial e-mail message to subscribers of an interactive computer service (service), knowing such to be in contravention to the rules of such service with respect to unsolicited commercial e-mail messages; or (6) accessing the server of a service and using a computer program to collect e-mail addresses of service subscribers in order to send such subscribers unsolicited commercial e-mail or to sell or distribute a list of such subscribers. Considers each transmission received by an individual to be a separate violation for purposes of this Act. Provides appropriate relief for both individuals and service providers. Authorizes a State, through its Attorney General, to bring an action on behalf of its residents for appropriate relief.</summary>
</bill>
