<bill session="105" type="h" number="3145" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Arlington National Cemetery Integrity Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to enact into law eligibility requirements for interment in Arlington National Cemetery.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1998-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-02-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H109-110, E68-69"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Medal of Honor"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Disability retirement"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Ex-presidents"/>
    <term name="Ex-prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medals, decorations, etc."/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court justices"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/1998--Introduced.
Arlington National Cemetery Integrity Act of 1998 - Allows the remains of the following persons to be interred at Arlington National Cemetery: (1) any member of the armed forces who dies while on active duty; (2) any retired member who served on active duty, was carried on a retired list, and was entitled to retired pay; (3) any former member who was separated for physical disability before October 1, 1949, who served on active duty, and who would have been eligible for disability retirement if such provisions had been in effect on such date; (4) any former member whose last active military service was terminated honorably and who has been awarded one of a number of specified military decorations; (5) any former prisoner of war who while such a prisoner served honorably, whose last active military service terminated honorably, and who died on or after November 30, 1993; (6) any former member whose last active military service terminated honorably and who has held one of a number of specified positions in the Federal Government, the Supreme Court, or the State Department; (7) the President or any former President; (8) the spouse, surviving spouse, minor child, and, in the discretion of the Cemetery's Superintendent, unmarried adult child of an interred member; and (9) the parents of a minor child or unmarried adult child whose remains, based on the parent's eligibility, are already buried in the Cemetery. Authorizes: (1) burial in another part of the Cemetery in the case of the remains of a spouse who cannot be buried at the gravesite of the related spouse due to the encroachment of tree roots, shrubs, plants, or similar events; and (2) Cemetery burial for the remains of disabled adult unmarried children of individuals eligible for Cemetery burial. Authorizes the cremated remains of the following persons to be placed in the Cemetery columbarium: (1) a veteran whose last period of active duty ended honorably; and (2) the spouse, surviving spouse, minor child, or unmarried adult child (discretionary) of such a veteran.</summary>
</bill>
