<bill session="107" type="hj" number="61" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-09-13T01:08:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-09-13T01:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Senate and House of Representatives regarding the terrorist attacks launched against the United States on September 11, 2001.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="2001-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-09-12T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Armey asked unanimous consent that the joint resolution be debatable for 3 hours, equally divided and controlled; that the previous question be ordered on the joint resolution without intervening motion; and that after passage of the joint resolution when the House receives a message from the Senate announcing passage of a similar joint resolution, the House shall be considered to have adopted the Senate joint resolution. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-12T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5503-5590" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5503" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-12T14:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order, the House proceeded with 3 hours of debate on H.J. Res. 61.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-12T17:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House continued with debate on H.J. Res. 61.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-12T19:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE EXENSION - By unanimous consent, debate on H.J. Res. 61 was extended for an additional 2 hours.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-12T21:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE EXTENSION - By unanimous consent, the debate on H.J. Res. 61 was extended for 2 additional hours.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-12T23:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE EXTENSION - By unanimous consent, debate on H.J. Res. 61 was extended for an additional 30 minutes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-12T23:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE EXTENSION - By unanimous consent, debate on H.J. Res. 61 was extended for an additional 30 minutes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-13T00:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE EXTENSION - By unanimous consent, debate on H.J. Res. 61 was extended for 30 additional minutes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-13T00:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-09-13T01:08:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="338" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 408 - 0 (Roll no. 338).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-09-13T01:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-13T01:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Laid on the table. See S.J. Res. 22 for further action.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="sj" number="22"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="sj" number="22"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special days"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2001--Passed House without amendment.
Condemns the terrorists who planned and carried out the September 11, 2001, attacks against the United States, as well as their sponsors. Extends condolences to the victims and their families, friends, and loved ones.Declares that Congress is certain that the people of the United States will stand united as our Nation begins the process of recovering and rebuilding in the aftermath of these attacks.Commends the heroic actions of the rescue workers, volunteers, and State and local officials who responded to these tragic events.Declares that these premeditated attacks struck not only at the people of America, but also at the symbols and structures of our economic and military strength, and that the United States is entitled to respond under international law.Expresses: (1) thanks to those foreign leaders and individuals who have expressed solidarity with the United States in the aftermath of the attacks and asks them to continue to stand with the United States in the war against international terrorism; (2) a commitment to support increased resources in the war to eradicate terrorism; and (3) support for the determination of the President to bring to justice and punish the perpetrators of these attacks and their sponsors.Declares September 12, 2001, to be a National Day of Unity and Mourning.</summary>
</bill>
