<bill session="106" type="h" number="1651" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-11-07">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fishermen's Protective Act Amendments of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Fisheries Survey Vessel Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Fishermen's Protective Act Amendments of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Yukon River Salmon Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Fisheries Survey Vessel Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Fishermen's Protective Act Amendments of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Yukon River Salmon Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Fishermen's Protective Act Amendments of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Fisheries Survey Vessel Authorization Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Yukon River Salmon Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fishermen's Protective Act of 1967 to extend the period during which reimbursement may be provided to owners of United States fishing vessels for costs incurred when such a vessel is seized and detained by a foreign country.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1999-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1999-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-06-23T17:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-197.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-06-23T17:42:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="112">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 112.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Saxton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8113-8115" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1651.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-09-13T14:54:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8113-8115" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T14:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13T14:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported to Senate by Senator McCain with an amendment. With written report No. 106-302.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-05-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="569">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 569.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-26">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent. (consideration: CR S5769-5771; text of measure as reported in Senate: CR S5769-5770)&#13;)</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-06-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-06-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Saxton moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T15:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the Senate amendment to H.R. 1651.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:PINGPONGFAIL" datetime="2000-07-25T17:42:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="433" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 265 - 154 (Roll no. 433).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H6855-6856, H6884-6885" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H6855" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T17:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-18T14:13:00-04:00">
      <text>House agreed to Senate amendment with an amendment pursuant to H. Res. 579.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-19">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-10-25" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendment  by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11019" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11019" label="text as Senate agreed to House amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-25">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2000-10-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-27">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-11-07">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-11-07" type="public" number="106-450">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-450.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="hr" number="579"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="hr" number="579"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International fishery management"/>
    <term name="International rivers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research ships"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Salmon fisheries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seizure of vessels and cargoes"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tuna fisheries"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3621"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/26/2000--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Extension of Period for Reimbursement under Fishermen's Protective Act of 1967 Title II: Yukon River Salmon Title III: Fishery Information Acquisition Title IV: Miscellaneous Title I: Extension of Period for Reimbursement under Fishermen's Protective Act of 1967 - Fishermen's Protective Act Amendments of 1999 - Amends the Fishermen's Protective Act of 1967 to extend the effective period of provisions authorizing reimbursement to owners of U.S. commercial fishing vessels for certain costs incurred when such a vessel is seized and detained by a foreign country.Title II: Yukon River Salmon - Yukon River Salmon Act of 1999 - Establishes the Yukon River Salmon Panel. Includes among its duties: (1) advising the Secretary of State on the negotiation of any international agreement with Canada regarding management of salmon stocks originating from the Yukon River in Canada; and (2) advising the Secretary of the Interior on restoration and enhancement of those stocks. Authorizes the Secretary of State to designate Panel members to be the U.S. representatives on any successor to the panel established by a specified interim agreement between the United States and Canada for the conservation of salmon stocks, if authorized by any agreement establishing the successor.(Sec. 203) Authorizes the Governor of Alaska to establish and appoint an advisory committee of individuals knowledgeable regarding the Yukon River salmon fisheries. Allows committee members to attend all Panel meetings and requires that they be given the opportunity to examine and be heard on any Panel matter.(Sec. 205) Makes the State of Alaska Department of Fish and Game the responsible U.S. management entity for the purposes of any agreement with Canada regarding management of salmon stocks originating from the Yukon River.(Sec. 207) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to carry out projects to restore or enhance such salmon stocks.(Sec. 208) Authorizes appropriations.Title III: Fishery Information Acquisition - Fisheries Survey Vessel Authorization Act of 1999 - Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to acquire and equip up to six fishery survey vessels. Authorizes appropriations.Title IV: Miscellaneous - Amends the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975 to make it unlawful for any person, other than a person holding a purse seine permit, to: (1) use an aircraft to locate or otherwise assist in fishing for, catching, or retaining Atlantic bluefin tuna; or (2) catch, possess, or retain Atlantic bluefin tuna located by use of an aircraft.(Sec. 402) Directs the Secretary of Commerce, notwithstanding specified provisions of the Small Business Act relating to awards or contracts and notwithstanding specified Federal regulations, to seek to procure Fisheries Research Vessels through full and open competition from United States shipbuilding companies irrespective of size. Requires, as an award criterion, that at least 40 percent of the value of the total construction and outfitting contract be obtained from small business concerns either directly or through subcontracting.</summary>
</bill>
