<bill session="106" type="h" number="4032" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Neighborhood Schools Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a loan guarantee program under which the Federal government shall guarantee payment of loans made by lending institutions for capital projects for public charter schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400434"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="2000-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="2000-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2000--Introduced.
Neighborhood Schools Act - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish a program to award loan guarantees to eligible public charter schools to guarantee to lending institutions payment of principal and interest on loans made to such schools for capital projects.Makes a school eligible to receive a loan guarantee if it submits an application with: (1) certifications that it is a public charter school as defined by the jurisdiction where it is located, and that it does not have access to funding for the project involved through the financing methods available to other public schools in the jurisdiction; (2) assurances that it will be unable to obtain financing for the project at a reasonably affordable rate of interest unless it is awarded such a loan guarantee; and (3) a business plan for the school including reasonable assurances that it will repay the loan for which the guarantee will be made.Limits the cumulative total of the principal of the loans outstanding at any time for which loan guarantees have been made under the program.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
