<bill session="104" type="h" number="1971" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Aviation Noise Limit Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for aviation noise management and reduction in residential areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1995-11-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/1995--Introduced.
Aviation Noise Limit Act of 1995 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to develop a staged plan to reduce by at least 75 percent on or before January 1, 2001, the number of individuals residing in residential areas in the vicinity of an airport who are exposed to a yearly day-night average sound level of 60 decibels or above. Requires the Secretary in developing such plan to consider various methods for aviation noise reduction, including soundproofing, relocation incentives, use of quieter aircraft, operations restrictions, and revision of air routes. Authorizes the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to make airspace traffic changes in residential areas only if they will not result in an increase in aviation noise. Makes the Secretary responsible for all non-military activity, within and outside controlled airspace, regulating such activity to ensure compliance with the requirements of this Act in normal circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
