<bill session="104" type="h" number="2573" updated="2012-11-01T22:44:46-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Campaign and Administrative Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to eliminate PAC contributions to individual House of Representatives candidates, to provide a tax credit and tax deduction for contributions to such candidates, to provide for voluntary expenditure limitations in House of Representatives elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400334"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSIF" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" name="House Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>11/01/1995--Introduced.
Congressional Campaign and Administrative Reform Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Election Reform Act of 1971 (Act) to prohibit multicandidate political committee contributions to House of Representatives (House) candidates. (Sec. 3) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit an individual income tax credit ($50 or $100 for a joint return) or deduction ($250 or $500 for a joint return) for an House campaign contribution. (Sec. 5) Amends the Act to provide for free radio and television broadcast time in House elections for candidates who agree to voluntary expenditure limits. (Sec. 6) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to subject broadcast station licensees to free broadcast requirements. Sets forth broadcast allocation provisions. (Sec. 7) Provides for a ban on soft money. Repeals the building fund exception to the definition of "contribution." (Sec. 8) Requires at least 80 percent of House candidate contributions to be from in-State individual residents. Sets forth noncompliance penalties. (Sec. 9) Subjects certain State political committees to the same $20,000 contribution limit as national political committees. (Sec. 10) Subjects corporations, labor organizations, and nonprofit organizations to certain election activity disclosure requirements. (Sec. 11) Prohibits a nonparty multicandidate political committee or lobbyist from acting as a conduit or intermediary for contributions to a candidate for Federal office (bundling). (Sec. 12) Prohibits leadership committees.</summary>
</bill>
