<bill session="108" type="h" number="1413" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Smallpox Emergency Personnel Protection Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide benefits for certain individuals with injuries resulting from administration of a smallpox vaccine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="2003-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2003-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2003-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="2003-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2003-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2003-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Border Security, and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="1770"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Smallpox"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2003--Introduced.
Smallpox Emergency Personnel Protection Act of 2003 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish procedures for determining whether an individual is an eligible individual under this Act who qualifies for compensation for a covered injury or injuries.Defines a covered injury as an injury, disability, illness, condition, or death arising in a specified time period from the administration of a smallpox vaccine or arising in specified circumstances from an accidental smallpox inoculation. Defines a covered individual as an individual from one of certain professions who is functioning as part of a Federally approved smallpox emergency response plan. Defines an eligible individual as a covered individual who sustains a covered injury from a smallpox vaccine or as an individual who is accidentally inoculated and sustains a covered injury.Directs the Secretary to create a smallpox vaccine injury table identifying adverse effects that shall be presumed to result from the administration of (or exposure to) a smallpox vaccine and the time period in which the first symptom of each such adverse effect must occur for such presumption to apply.Requires the Secretary to make payments for medical items and services as reasonable and necessary to treat a covered injury of an eligible individual. Directs the Secretary to provide compensation according to a specified formula to an eligible individual for the loss of employment income incurred due to a covered injury. Provides separately for benefits for permanent and total disability and death.Amends Public Health Service Act provisions regarding: (1) tort liability for the administration of smallpox countermeasures; and (2) the administration of smallpox countermeasures by health professionals, including to modify the definitions of covered countermeasure, covered person, and qualified person.</summary>
</bill>
