<bill session="105" type="h" number="512" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-19T15:31:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-05-19T15:31:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">New Wildlife Refuge Authorization Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">New Wildlife Refuge Authorization Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">New Wildlife Refuge Authorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the expenditure of funds from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for the creation of new National Wildlife Refuges without specific authorization from Congress pursuant to a recommendation from the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to create the refuge.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1997-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-31">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-31">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 25 - 9.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-09-29T12:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-276.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-09-29T12:49:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="156">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 156.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12T19:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 427 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 512 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed as amendment No. 1 in the Congressional Record of May 12, 1998. Points of order against the substitute for failure to comply with clause 7 of rule XVI shall be waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pombo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3420-3423" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-05-19T15:31:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="427"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/1998--Passed House amended.
New Wildlife Refuge Authorization Act - Prohibits funds from being authorized from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for designation of a National Wildlife Refuge System (NWRS) unit, unless the Secretary of the Interior has: (1) completed all actions pertaining to environmental review that are required for that designation; (2) notified each Member of, and each Delegate and Resident Commissioner to, the Congress that represents an area included in the boundaries of the proposed unit, upon the completion of the preliminary project proposal for such designation; and (3) provided a copy of each final environmental assessment resulting from such review and a summary of all public comments received by the Secretary to specified congressional committees and to each Member of or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress elected to represent an area included in the boundaries of the proposed unit. Makes the above provisions inapplicable to NWRS units that are designated or specifically authorized to be designated by law. Excludes land located within the boundaries (or proposed boundaries) of a NWRS unit designated after the enactment of this Act from Federal land use restrictions based solely on a determination of the boundaries until an interest in the land has been acquired by the United States.</summary>
</bill>
