<bill session="104" type="h" number="3180" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Amber Hagerman Child Protection Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase penalties for sex offenses against children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400143"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1996-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="1996-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1996-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="402454" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403308" joined="1996-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1996-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404503" joined="1996-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1996-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1996-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1996-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1996-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1996-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1996-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1996-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1996-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407838" joined="1996-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1996-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1996-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.2974.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2974"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child molesting"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/28/1996--Introduced.
Amber Hagerman Child Protection Act of 1996 - Amends the Federal criminal code to apply prohibitions and penalties for aggravated sexual abuse of a person under age 12 and for sexual abuse of a person between the ages of 12 and 16 to any person who: (1) crosses a State line with intent to engage in a sexual act with such minor; or (2) knowingly engages, or attempts to engage, in such an act in interstate or foreign commerce. Authorizes imposition of the death penalty if the defendant kills the victim. Directs that a defendant previously convicted of another Federal offense of sexual abuse or aggravated sexual abuse of a minor or of a State offense that would have been such an offense had it occurred in a Federal prison be sentenced to life imprisonment, unless the death penalty is imposed. Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 (VCCLEA) to provide that, in order not to reduce the funds available under the drug control and system improvement grant program under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 by ten percent, a State shall have in effect a law which requires a court to sentence a defendant in a State prosecution who is convicted of an offense that would have been aggravated sexual abuse or sexual abuse of a minor if it occurred in a Federal prison, and who has previously been convicted for such an offense, to life in prison without the possibility of parole. Revises VCCLEA provisions under subtitle A of title XVII (the Jacob Wetterling Crimes Against Children and Sexually Violent Offender Registration Act) to: (1) provide for the transfer of information from the State law enforcement agency to the Federal Bureau of Information (FBI); (2) require the information collected under a State registration program to be transmitted to the FBI and to be released to law enforcement agencies and government agencies conducting background checks under specified circumstances; and (3) direct the FBI to maintain a separate data base for information submitted to it under this Act, to make such data base accessible to appropriate State law enforcement officials, and to inform appropriate local law enforcement officials on each occasion that a person registered changes registration to that locality.</summary>
</bill>
