<bill session="104" type="h" number="193" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Equitable Health Care for Severe Mental Illnesses Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a comprehensive policy with respect to the provision of health care coverage and services to individuals with severe mental illnesses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400533"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1995-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1995-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1995-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="298"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health policy"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mentally ill"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Equitable Health Care for Severe Mental Illnesses Act of 1995 - Declares that it is the policy of the United States that: (1) persons with severe mental illnesses must not be discriminated against in health care; and (2) health care coverage, provided through any financing, must provide for the treatment of severe mental illnesses in a way that is equitable and commensurate with that provided for other major illnesses. Requires health care coverage, in order to be considered nondiscriminatory and equitable under this Act, to cover services that are essential to the effective treatment of severe mental illnesses in a manner that: (1) is not more restrictive than coverage provided for other major physical illnesses; (2) provides adequate financial protection to the person requiring the medical treatment for a severe mental illness; and (3) is consistent with effective and common methods of controlling health care costs for other major physical illnesses.</summary>
</bill>
