<bill session="104" type="h" number="4109" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Export Programs Extension Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend the authority for certain export programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409423"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1639-1640"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Overseas Private Investment Corporation Title II: Trade and Development Agency Title III: Export Promotion Programs Export Programs Extension Act of 1996 - Title I: Overseas Private Investment Corporation - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to increase the ceilings on the maximum contingent liabilities outstanding at any one time for investment insurance and for the financing of investment guarantees issued by the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) as well as of direct U.S. investment loans. Extends OPIC's authority to issue such insurance and guarantees through FY 1997. Title II: Trade and Development Agency - Authorizes appropriations for the Trade and Development Agency for FY 1997. Title III: Export Promotion Program - Amends the Export Administration Amendments Act of 1985 to authorize appropriations for the Department of Commerce export promotion programs for FY 1997.</summary>
</bill>
