<bill session="106" type="hc" number="222" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-16T14:16:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-16T14:16:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Condemning the assassination of Armenian Prime Minister Vazgen Sargsian and other officials of the Armenian Government and expressing the sense of the Congress in mourning this tragic loss of the duly elected leadership of Armenia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T12:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T12:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12010-12015, H12018-12019" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T12:52:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 222.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T13:13:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T14:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-11-16T14:16:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="588" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 399 - 0 (Roll no. 588).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T14:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="sc" number="63"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armenia"/>
    <term name="Assassination"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Legislators"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/1999--Introduced.
Declares that Congress: (1) deplores the slaying of the Prime Minister of Armenia, Vazgen Sargsian, the Chairman of the Armenian Parliament, Karen Demirchian, the Deputy Chairman of the Armenian Parliament, Yuri Bakhshian, the Minister of Operative Issues, Leonard Petrossian, and other members of the Armenian Government; (2) strongly shares the determination of the Armenian people that the perpetrators will be swiftly brought to justice so that Armenia may demonstrate its resolute opposition to acts of terror; (3) commends the efforts of the late Prime Minister and the Armenian Government for their commitment to democracy and the rule of law and for supporting free market movements internationally; and (4) continues to cherish the strong friendship between Armenia and the United States.</summary>
</bill>
