<bill session="108" type="h" number="4360" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Country of Origin Healthcare Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for continuing Federal reimbursement of emergency health services furnished to illegal aliens through foreign aid funds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400095"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2004--Introduced.
Country of Origin Healthcare Accountability Act - Requires that $250 million of foreign aid funds appropriated under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 be made available to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make allotments to States for eligible providers for unreimbursable costs incurred by providing emergency health care services to: (1) undocumented aliens; (2) aliens who have been paroled into the United States at a U.S. port of entry for the purpose of receiving eligible services; and (3) Mexican citizens permitted to enter the United States for not more than 72 hours under the authority of biometric machine readable border crossing identification card.</summary>
</bill>
