<bill session="108" type="h" number="1720" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-10-29T17:23:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-10-29T17:23:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Health Care Facilities Capital Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Veterans Health Care Facilities Capital Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans Health Care Facilities Capital Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out construction projects for the purpose of improving, renovating, establishing, and updating patient care facilities at Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out construction projects for the purpose of improving, renovating, establishing, and updating patient care facilities at Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400324" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2003-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E758-759"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T19:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 108-210.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-07-15T19:44:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="116">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 116.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29T12:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29T12:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9996-10008" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29T12:38:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1720.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29T13:23:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29T17:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10079-10080" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-10-29T17:23:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="576" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 417 - 0 (Roll no. 576).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9996-9999" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29T17:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29T17:23:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="116"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="1585"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="1832"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="1908"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2307"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2349"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Architecture and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Brain"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Earth movements and building"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Head injuries"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Pain"/>
    <term name="Prosthesis"/>
    <term name="Protection of animals"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research ethics"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Spinal cord injuries"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women veterans"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/29/2003--Passed House amended.
Veterans Health Care Facilities Capital Improvement Act - (Sec. 2) Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out major medical facility projects, using funds appropriated for FY 2004 and 2005. Allows such projects to be carried out to improve, replace, renovate, update, or establish a new patient care facility, or to improve, replace, renovate, or update, a research facility, in order to improve: (1) seismic protection related to patient safety; (2) fire safety; (3) utility systems and ancillary patient care facilities; (4) accommodation for persons with disabilities; and (5) patient care facilities to specialized programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs. Requires: (1) each project to be reviewed by a board independent of the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) of the Department; and (2) each board's recommendations to be considered by the Secretary prior to selection. Authorizes appropriations for such fiscal years. Directs the Comptroller General to report to the congressional veterans' committees: (1) evaluating advantages and disadvantages of congressional authorization for such projects over specific authorization by law; and (2) describing specific actions of the Secretary during FY 2004 with respect to such projects. Requires the Secretary to report to such committees on the project authorization process. (Sec. 3) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out specified major medical facility projects for current or future Department medical facilities in: (1) Chicago, Illinois; (2) San Diego, California; (3) West Haven, Connecticut; (4) Columbus, Ohio; and (5) Pensacola, Florida. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 for such projects. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into major medical facilities leases for Department outpatient clinics in Charlotte, North Carolina, Clark County, Nevada, and at the site of the former Fitzsimons Army Medical Center in Aurora, Colorado. (Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out major medical facility projects at the site of the former Fitzsimons Center, including inpatient and outpatient facilities providing acute, sub-acute, primary, and long-term care services. Requires consultation between the Secretary and the Secretary of Defense, which shall include consideration of establishing a Department of Veterans Affairs-Department of Defense joint health-care venture at the site. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 through 2006. Directs the Secretary to report to the veterans' and appropriations committees on the exercise of such authority. (Sec. 5) Prohibits the Secretary from making a final disposal of the Lakeside Division facility in Chicago, Illinois, until the Secretary has entered into a contract for the project for such facility. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to develop a plan: (1) to establish an inpatient facility to meet veterans' hospital care needs in southern New Jersey; and (2) for hospital care needs of veterans who reside in far south Texas. Requires reports on each plan from the Secretary to the veterans' committees. (Sec. 7) Increases from $4 million to $6 million the threshold cost of a major medical facility project above which funds for such project must be specifically authorized by law. (Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary to: (1) examine the feasibility of Department coordination of its needs for veterans' inpatient hospital, medical, and long-term care services with the pending construction of a new university medical center at the Medical University of South Carolina in Charleston, South Carolina; and (2) report results to the veterans' committees. (Sec. 9) Designates the Department: (1) health care facility on South Damen Avenue in Chicago, Illinois, as the Jesse Brown Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center; and (2) outpatient clinic in New London, Connecticut, as the John J. McGuirk Department of Veterans Affairs Outpatient Clinic. (Sec. 11) Establishes in the VHA an Office of Research Oversight to advise the Under Secretary for Health on matters of compliance and assurance in human subjects protections, animal welfare, research safety, and research impropriety and misconduct. Requires the Office to function independently of VHA offices responsible for the conduct of medical research programs. Establishes an Office Director to conduct investigations and report to the Under Secretary with respect to the above matters, including appropriate recommendations for the termination, suspension, or limitation of Department research activities. Requires the Director to report: (1) to the Under Secretary, Secretary, and veterans' committees on any suspected lapse of protecting the safety of human subjects and others, including employees, in medical research programs; and (2) annually to the veterans' committees on prior-year activities. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to the veterans' committees on the effects of the establishment of the Office, the actions taken, and improvements in the conduct of ethical medical research in the VHA. Requires the Secretary to report to the veterans' committees on the implementation of this section.</summary>
</bill>
