<bill session="107" type="h" number="2851" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-09-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Western Shoshone Claims Distribution Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the use and distribution of the funds awarded to the Western Shoshone identifiable group under Indian Claims Commission Docket Numbers 326-A-1, 326-A-3, 326-K, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2001-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/6/2001--Introduced.
Western Shoshone Claims Distribution Act - Provides for the distribution of specified funds appropriated in satisfaction of a judgment award granted to the Western Shoshone Indians in Docket Number 326-K before the Indian Claims Commission to U.S. citizens who have at least 1/4 Western Shoshone blood and who are enrolled on a Western Shoshone Judgment Roll to be established by the Secretary of the Interior.Requires that such funds and specified funds appropriated in satisfaction of the judgment awards granted to such Indians in Docket Numbers 326-A-1 and 326-A-3 before the U.S. Court of Claims be credited to and distributed from a Western Shoshone Educational Trust Fund to be established by the Secretary for educational grants and other forms of educational assistance to individual Western Shoshone members and to pay reasonable and necessary expenses of an Administrative Committee established by this Act to oversee the distribution of such educational grants and assistance.</summary>
</bill>
