<bill session="104" type="h" number="1244" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Theatrical Motion Picture Authorship Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 17, United States Code, to identify the author of a theatrical motion picture as a physical person for purposes of noneconomic interests in that work.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401947"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1995-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1995-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E615-616"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Copyright infringement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/1995--Introduced.
Theatrical Motion Picture Authorship Act of 1995 - Declares that the principal director, screenwriter, and cinematographer of a theatrical motion picture have the noneconomic interests in such picture. Describes such interests as the right of the director, screenwriter, or cinematographer to: (1) claim that he or she was the director, screenwriter, or cinematographer of the picture; (2) prevent the use of his or her name as the director, screenwriter, or cinematographer of pictures of which he or she was not the director, screenwriter, or cinematographer; and (3) prevent any intentional distortion, mutilation, or other modification of the picture which would be prejudicial to his or her honor or reputation. Permits the exercise of such rights whether or not the person is the copyright owner. Requires the duration of such interests to be coextensive with (and expire at the same time as) exclusive copyright rights in the picture. Prohibits the transfer of such interests, but authorizes the exercise of such interests by heirs. Authorizes the waiver of such rights, but prohibits: (1) the execution of the written instrument containing the waiver before the first public performance of the motion picture; and (2) consideration exceeding one dollar to be given for the grant of the waiver. Revises copyright ownership provisions to provide that the principal director, screenwriter, and cinematographer shall be considered authors with respect to ownership of noneconomic interests in theatrical motion pictures. Considers violations of rights granted by this Act to be infringements.</summary>
</bill>
