<bill session="106" type="h" number="1802" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-19">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foster Care Independence Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Foster Care Independence Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Foster Care Independence Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Foster Care Independence Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to provide States with more funding and greater flexibility in carrying out programs designed to help children make the transition from foster care to self-sufficiency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1999-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-20">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-05-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-06-10T21:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 106-182, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-10T21:38:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 25, 1999.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-24T17:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 221 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1802 with 1 hour and 20 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. General debate shall be equally divided and controlled by The Chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Ways and Means for 60 minutes and the Chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Commerce for 20 minutes. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill, the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and means. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment shall be in order except those amendments printed in H. Rept. 106-199.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T09:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-06-25T09:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="113">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 113.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T09:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 221 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T09:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 221.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4959-4987" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T09:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1802 with 1 hour and 20 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. General debate shall be equally divided and controlled by The Chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Ways and Means for 60 minutes and the Chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Commerce for 20 minutes. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill, the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and means. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment shall be in order except those amendments printed in H. Rept. 106-199.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T09:37:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 221 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T09:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ray LaHood to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T09:37:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 80 minutes of general debate on H.R. 1802.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1802.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-06-25T11:38:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="256" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 380 - 6 (Roll no. 256).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T11:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-25T11:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1802.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Senate Committee on Finance discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15201-15205" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Amendment SP 2797 proposed by Senator Collins.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Amendment SP 2797 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1999-11-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="221"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="26"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="26"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="3443"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asians"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Child support enforcement"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Computer matching"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled children"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Foster parents"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Guerrilla warfare"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Paternity"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="School-to-work transition"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social security beneficiaries"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare fraud"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h240"/>
    <amendment number="h241"/>
    <amendment number="h242"/>
    <amendment number="s2797"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/19/1999--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Improved Independent Living Program Subtitle A: Improved Independent Living Program Subtitle B: Related Foster Care Provision Subtitle C: Medicaid Amendments Subtitle D: Adoption Incentive Payments Title II: SSI Fraud Prevention Subtitle A: Fraud Prevention and Related Provisions Subtitle B: Benefits for Certain World War II Veterans Subtitle C: Study Title III: Child Support Title IV: Technical Corrections Foster Care Independence Act of 1999 - Title I: Improved Independent Living Program - Subtitle A: Improved Independent Living Program - Amends title IV part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to revise the program of grants to States for independent living programs providing education, training, employment services, and financial support for individuals between ages 16 and 18 leaving foster care for independent living. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) develop outcome measures to assess State performance in operating such programs; (2) identify data elements needed to track such performance, services, and the individuals served; and (3) develop and implement a plan to collect such data.(Sec. 101) Authorizes appropriations.Expresses the sense of Congress that States should provide medical assistance under the State plan approved under SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to 18-, 19-, and 20-year-olds who have been emancipated from foster care.Subtitle B: Related Foster Care Provision - Increases the amount of assets allowable for children in foster care in determining assistance eligibility under SSA title IV part E.(Sec. 112) Mandates that State plans for foster care and adoption assistance include a certification that prior to foster care placement the prospective parents will be adequately prepared to provide for the needs of the child, and that such preparation will continue, as necessary, after placement of the child.Subtitle C: Medicaid Amendments - Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to authorize a State to limit the eligibility of independent foster care adolescents to individuals for whom foster care maintenance payments or independent living services were furnished under the Improved Independent Living Program.(Sec. 121) Provides for contingent coordination of this Act with the Ticket to Work and Work Incentives Improvement Act of 1999, if the latter is enacted.Subtitle D: Adoption Incentive Payments - Instructs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make supplemental grants to adoption incentive-eligible States. Increases the appropriations authorized for FY 2000 through 2003.Title II: SSI Fraud Prevention - Subtitle A: Fraud Prevention and Related Provisions - Amends SSA title II (Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) and title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) to subject a representative payee to liability for overpayments made after the death of the individual on whose behalf the payments were made. Instructs the Commissioner of Social Security (the Commissioner) to establish an overpayment control record under the representative payee's social security account number.(Sec. 202) Provides for recovery of overpayments of SSI benefits from lump sum SSI benefit payments.(Sec. 203) Authorizes the Commissioner to employ certain statutory debt collection practices to collect delinquent accounts. (Sec. 204) Changes from discretionary to mandatory the authority of States to provide State prisoner information to Federal and federally assisted benefit programs.(Sec. 205) Sets forth a statutory mechanism for the treatment of assets held in trust for an individual in connection with eligibility for SSI benefits.(Sec. 206) Revamps guidelines governing eligibility criteria in connection with disposal of resources for less than fair market value under the SSI program.(Sec. 207) Prescribes administrative procedures for: (1) imposing penalties for false or misleading statements; and (2) excluding representatives and health care providers convicted of violations from participation in social security programs.(Sec. 210) Directs the Commissioner to: (1) study and report to certain congressional committees on possible measures to improve fraud prevention and administrative processing; (2) include in the annual budget an itemization of the amount of funds required to support efforts to combat fraud committed by applicants and beneficiaries; and (3) conduct periodic computer matches with Medicare and Medicaid institutionalization data.(Sec. 213) Authorizes the Commissioner to require applicants or beneficiaries to authorize access to information held by their financial institutions in order to ascertain benefits eligibility.Subtitle B: Benefits for Certain World War II Veterans - Amends the Social Security Act to add a new title VIII (Special Benefits for Certain World War II Veterans) to provide monthly benefits to certain qualified World War II veterans for each month such an individual resides outside the United States. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle C: Study - Directs the Commissioner to: (1) study and report to certain congressional committees on the reasons why family farmers with resources of less than $100,000 are denied SSI benefits, including whether the deeming process unduly burdens and discriminates against family farmers who do not institutionalize a disabled dependent; and (2) determine the number of such farmers who have been denied such benefits during each of the preceding ten years.Title III: Child Support - Cites circumstances under which the State share of distribution of collected child support shall be increased by statutory formula. Repeals such formula, and the entire hold harmless provision for the State share of the distribution of collected child support, as of October 1, 2001.Title IV: Technical Corrections - Sets forth technical corrections relating to amendments made by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996.</summary>
</bill>
