<bill session="108" type="h" number="316" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To eliminate certain restrictions on the availability of credits under title III of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 for the use of biodiesel fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2003-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400207" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="2003-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-01-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Renewable natural resources"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/8/2003--Introduced.
Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 with respect to the allocation of biodiesel fuel use credits to a fleet or covered person for qualifying volumes of the biodiesel component of fuel containing at least 20 percent biodiesel by volume purchased for use by the fleet or covered person in vehicles that weigh more than 8,500 pounds gross vehicle weight rating.Repeals the limitation of such allocations to a maximum of 50 percent of the alternative fueled vehicle requirements of a fleet or covered person. (Thus makes such credits available for 100 percent of such requirements.)Repeals the current denial that such a credit may be considered a specified kind of alternative fueled vehicle credit (thus allowing such consideration).Directs the Secretary of Energy to study and report to Congress on the availability and cost of: (1) light duty motor vehicles that qualify under such Act as alternative fueled vehicles; and (2) fuels that qualify as alternative fuels.</summary>
</bill>
