<bill session="106" type="h" number="605" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve retirement authorities applicable to judges of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400504"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1999-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1999-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial tenure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Retirement"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/1999--Introduced.
Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims Act of 1999 - Amends Federal provisions relating to the authority and administration of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims to authorize a retired judge to be recalled for further Court service if such judge, at the time of his or her retirement, provided written notice of his or her availability for further service. Prohibits such a judge from being recalled for more than 90 days without the judge's consent or for more than 180 days during any calendar year. Requires the removal of a judge from recall-eligible status if such judge declines to perform such further service. (Sec. 4) Disregards, for purposes of the calculation of years of service as a judge, any fractional part of a year that is less than 183 days, but credits as a full year any fractional part consisting of 183 days or more. (Sec. 5) Revises generally provisions concerning the calculation of retired pay of recall-eligible judges, judges who did not make themselves available for recall, and judges who are removed from the recall-eligible list. Provides cost-of-living adjustments to such pay. (Sec. 6) Requires a retired judge who represents a client in any claim against the United States relating to veterans' benefits to forfeit all retired pay rights for one year after such representation begins. (Sec. 7) Provides early retirement authority for Court judges in order to provide for staggered terms of such judges.</summary>
</bill>
