<bill session="107" type="h" number="4129" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-12-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Central Utah Project Completion Act to clarify the responsibilities of the Secretary of the Interior with respect to the Central Utah Project, to redirect unexpended budget authority for the Central Utah Project for wastewater treatment and reuse and other purposes, to provide for prepayment of repayment contracts for municipal and industrial water delivery facilities, and to eliminate a deadline for such prepayment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="2002-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2002-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-08T17:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-554.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-07-08T17:56:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="333">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 333.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6875-6876" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4129.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-10-01T18:34:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6875-6876" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2002-11-20" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/19/2002 S11652-11655" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-11-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2002-11-20">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2002-12-09">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2002-12-19">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2002-12-19" type="public" number="107-366">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 107-366.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="2565"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="4031"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="1361"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="2475"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Mountains"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water supply engineering"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2002--Passed House amended.
(Sec. 1) Amends the Central Utah Project Completion Act to require all amounts previously expended in planning and developing specified Utah reclamation projects and features, including amounts previously expended for investigation of power features in the Bonneville Unit, to be considered non-reimbursable and non-returnable; (2) require the Secretary of the Interior to carry out responsibilities identified in such Act and the Colorado River Storage Project Act relating to the Bonneville Unit of Central Utah Project, including oversight for all phases of the Unit, administration of prior and future contracts, and operation and maintenance of previously constructed facilities; (3) authorize a pilot management program that shall provide a mechanism for the Secretary and the Central Utah Water Conservancy District to create an organization within the Bureau of Reclamation to assist the Secretary in long-term management responsibilities of the Bonneville Unit; and (4) authorize the Secretary to use Bureau technical services for engineering and construction work on any project features.Authorizes the Secretary to utilize up to $300,000 of all unexpended budget authority for Project units. Deauthorizes the balance in excess of this amount. Allows such amount to be used to provide 65 percent of the Federal share pursuant to the Act to acquire water and water rights for project purposes (including instream flows), to complete specified project facilities, to implement water conservation measures relating to the Project (including the use of reverse osmosis membrane technologies, water recycling, and conjunctive use), to stabilize high mountain lakes and appurtenant facilities, and to develop power.Directs the Secretary to allow for prepayment of any additional or supplemental contracts providing for repayment of Project municipal and industrial water delivery facilities. Repeals a requirement that the District exercise of its prepayment rights by the end of FY 2002.(Sec. 2) Authorizes the Secretary to enter into contracts with the Provo River Water Users Association or any of its member unit contractors for water from Provo River in Utah for: (1) the impounding, storage, and carriage of nonproject water for domestic, municipal, industrial, and other beneficial purposes, using facilities associated with the Provo River Project; and (2) the exchange of water among Provo River Project contractors for such purposes using those facilities.</summary>
</bill>
