<bill session="106" type="h" number="3523" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Expedited Rescissions Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to provide for expedited rescissions of budget authority and of limited tax benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Presidential messages"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax preferences"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2000--Introduced.
Expedited Rescissions Act of 1999 - Amends the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to authorize the President, in addition to the existing method of proposing rescissions under such Act, to propose the expedited rescission of any budget authority provided in an appropriation Act or of any limited tax benefit set forth in any revenue Act.Authorizes the President to transmit a draft bill to Congress with such a proposal that clearly identifies the budget authority proposed to be rescinded from each program, project, or activity funded by that Act. Authorizes submission of a draft bill that would rescind limited tax benefits as well.Sets forth procedures for the identification of limited tax benefits.Establishes expedited procedures in the Senate and the House of Representatives for consideration of the draft bill.Authorizes the President to defer the obligation of budget authority subject to rescission or the implementation of any limited tax benefit subject to rescission but only if a special message requesting such rescission has been transmitted to Congress.Sets forth deadlines for the release of deferred obligations. Bars any budget authority or limited tax benefit proposed for rescission from being proposed for rescission under the Act more than once.</summary>
</bill>
