<bill session="108" type="h" number="4681" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prescription Drug Price Comparison for Savings Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish and maintain an Internet website that is designed to allow consumers to compare the usual and customary prices for covered outpatient drugs sold by retail pharmacies that participate in the Medicaid Program for each postal Zip Code, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2004-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="2597"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Zip code"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2004--Introduced.
Prescription Drug Price Comparison for Savings Act of 2004 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish and maintain an Internet website using the information supplied by participating pharmacies to allow an individual to compare for each zip code the usual and customary prices for a range of strengths and quantities of covered outpatient drugs sold by retail pharmacies that receive Medicaid payments. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to direct States to: (1) require a participating pharmacy, concurrent with filling a prescription for an individual receiving assistance under Medicaid, to report to the State its zip code and the usual and customary price for the covered outpatient drug as of the date the prescription is filled; and (2) submit this information to the Secretary to enable the Secretary to post monthly updates on the website.</summary>
</bill>
