<bill session="106" type="h" number="3333" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Indian Tribal Justice Technical and Legal Assistance Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide technical and legal assistance to tribal justice systems and members of Indian tribes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1999-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2365"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Indian courts"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Indian youth"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to the poor"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Training and Technical Assistance, Civil and Criminal Legal Assistance Grants Title II: Indian Tribal Courts Indian Tribal Justice Technical and Legal Assistance Act of 1999 - Title I: Training and Technical Assistance, Civil and Criminal Legal Assistance Grants - Directs the Attorney General, in consultation with the Office of Tribal Justice of the Department of Justice, to award grants to: (1) national and regional membership organizations and associations whose membership consists of judicial system personnel within tribal justice systems, to provide training and technical assistance for the development, enrichment, and enhancement of such systems; and (2) non-profit entities that provide legal assistance services for Indian tribes, members of Indian tribes, or tribal justice systems pursuant to federal poverty guidelines, for the provision of civil or criminal legal assistance to members of tribes and tribal justice systems. Authorizes appropriations.Title II: Indian Tribal Courts - Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants and provide technical assistance to Indian tribes to enable such tribes to carry out programs supporting the development, enhancement, and continuing operation of tribal justice systems and the development and implementation of: (1) tribal codes and sentencing guidelines; (2) inter-tribal courts and appellate systems; (3) tribal probation services, diversion programs, and alternative sentencing provisions; (4) tribal juvenile services and multi-disciplinary protocols for child physical and sexual abuse; and (5) traditional tribal judicial practices, traditional tribal justice systems, and traditional methods of dispute resolution.Authorizes appropriations.Amends the Indian Tribal Justice Act to extend through FY 2007 the authorization of appropriations for: (1) the Office of Tribal Justice Support; (2) base support funding for tribal justice systems; (3) administration of the Office; and (4) the administration of tribal judicial conferences.</summary>
</bill>
