<bill session="108" type="h" number="1623" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Presidential Gifts Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 44, United States Code, to direct the Archivist of the United States to maintain an inventory of all gifts received from domestic sources for the President, the Executive Residence at the White House, or a Presidential archival depository.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400304"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E684"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and the Census.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO20" subcommittee="Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and the Census" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Presidential ethics"/>
    <term name="Presidential families"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="White House (Washington, D.C.)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2003--Introduced.
Presidential Gifts Accountability Act - Directs the Archivist of the United States to maintain a current inventory of all presidential gifts.Requires the head of a Federal office or agency to report to the Archivist any information regarding a presidential gift.Requires the Archivist to: (1) make inventory information available to the public; (2) disclose to the public additional information regarding each gift from any person who makes presidential gifts in a year having a cumulative value of $100 or more; and (3) report to specified congressional committees on each disposition of a gift other than a gift from a relative or a gift having a value of less than $100.Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to prohibit the President and any spouse from: (1) accepting any gift of stock in a corporation or any gift certificate; (2) accepting gifts from a single source in a year having a cumulative value greater than $1,000, except a personalized, honorific award; (3) accepting any gift beginning on the date of a presidential election occurring during the President's term and ending on the date of the beginning of the next presidential term, unless the President is reelected for that next term; or (4) soliciting or coordinating, or seeking another to solicit or coordinate, the making of any gift to the President or spouse. Requires any gift wrongfully accepted to be returned or to become property of the United States and not deposited in a presidential archival depository. Makes this section inapplicable with respect to gifts from a foreign government or a relative.</summary>
</bill>
