<bill session="104" type="h" number="3847" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drug Abuse Prevention and Treatment Consolidation and Reorganization Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Drug Abuse Prevention and Treatment Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to alcoholism programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Homeless children"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Runaway children"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Drug Abuse Prevention and Treatment Administration Title II: Programs and Functions of Administration Subtitle A: Transfers from Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration; Transfer from Other Agencies Subtitle B: Additional Provisions Regarding Prevention and Treatment of Substance Abuse Subtitle C: Funding Title III: Advisory Council; Peer Review Title IV: Miscellaneous Authorities Title V: Disposition of Remaining Programs and Functions of Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration Title VI: General Provisions Drug Abuse Prevention and Treatment Consolidation and Reorganization Act of 1996 - Title I: Drug Abuse Prevention and Treatment Administration - Establishes as an independent agency in the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) the Drug Abuse Prevention and Treatment Administration, to be headed by an Administrator appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Title II: Programs and Functions of Administration - Subtitle A: Transfers from Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration; Transfer from Other Agencies - Transfers to the Administration programs and functions: (1) relating to the Center for Substance Abuse Treatment, Public Health Service Act substance abuse block grants, or the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA); (2) under the Safe and Drug-Free Schools and Communities Act of 1994; (3) under specified provisions of the Anti-Drug Abuse Act of 1988 administered by the HHS' Administration for Children and Families (relating to drug abuse and youth gangs and or runaway and homeless youth); (4) under the Public and Assisted Housing Drug Elimination Act of 1990; and (5) under the Drug-Free Public Housing Act of 1988. Subtitle B: Additional Provisions Regarding Prevention and Treatment of Substance Abuse - Mandates a program to coordinate public and nonprofit private entity activities to provide for a nationwide network for substance abuse prevention. Authorizes grants to assist communities in coordinating substance abuse prevention services. (Sec. 212) Mandates coordination of Administration and Office of National Drug Control Policy activities. Subtitle C: Funding - Authorizes appropriations for the Administration. Title III: Advisory Council; Peer Review - Mandates an advisory council and peer review of grants and cooperative agreements. Title IV: Miscellaneous Authorities - Sets forth miscellaneous authorities of the Secretary of HHS and the Administrator, including regarding facilities (acquiring, constructing, improving, etc.) and the use of personnel, consultants, experts, and volunteers. Title V: Disposition of Remaining Programs and Functions of Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration - Transfers to the HHS' Health Resources and Services Administration all functions of SAMHSA not transferred under title II of this Act. Terminates SAMHSA. Title VI: General Provisions - Sets forth transitional and savings provisions and makes conforming amendments.</summary>
</bill>
