<bill session="106" type="h" number="5024" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Information Policy Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the coordination of Federal information policy through the establishment of a Federal Chief Information Officer and an Office of Information Policy in the Executive Office of the President, and to otherwise strengthen Federal information resources management.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1355-1357"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Management information systems"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Official secrets"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2000--Introduced.
Federal Information Policy Act of 2000 - Amends Federal law to revise provisions regarding Federal information policy. Removes a provision which excludes the General Accounting Office from the definition of "agency" for purposes of applying such policy.Establishes an Office of Information Policy in the Executive Office of the President to be headed by a Chief Information Officer (Officer) of the United States who shall be the principal adviser to the President on matters relating to the efficient and effective development, use, and management of information technology and resources by the Federal Government. Outlines the Officer's duties and grants the Officer certain authorities and duties currently given to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) under existing law.Incorporates certain provisions of the Government Paperwork Elimination Act concerning the use and acceptance of electronic signatures by executive agencies. Grants the Officer duties under such provisions currently given to the Director.Requires the Officer to monitor the implementation of electronic signature requirements of this Act and related laws to ensure that the Federal Government: (1) maintains an efficient and effective information infrastructure for undertaking Government operations using electronic information processes; (2) provides efficient and effective means for the public to interact with the Government by means other than such processes; and (3) manages its increasing reliance on information technology in a manner consistent with this Act.Directs the Officer to review the Federal information systems standards setting process and report to the President on its efficiency and effectiveness and any recommendations for improvement.Requires the Officer to establish minimum evaluation criteria to be used for independent evaluations of: (1) agency implementation of information technology management processes and capabilities; (2) cost, schedule, risk, and return status of major information management and technology initiatives; and (3) results of major information technology investments and programs in achieving progress toward improvements in mission performance and programmatic outcomes. Requires annual submissions of agency evaluations to the Officer, Director, and Congress.Establishes a Chief Information Officers Council in the executive branch to assist and advise in, and carry out other related activities with respect to, Federal information resource management.Requires the Officer to report annually to Congress on: (1) efforts undertaken to improve the development, application, and management of information resources; and (2) results of major activities undertaken by the Council.Authorizes appropriations to carry out Federal information policy provisions for FY 2001 through 2005.(Sec. 4) Incorporates provisions similar to those under existing law with respect to paperwork reduction.Requires the Director to extend the annual Governmentwide goal for the reduction of information collection burdens by at least five percent through FY 2005.Requires the Director to encourage the use of the Government Information Locator Service to provide information regarding agency information collection activities and opportunities to maximize the efficiency and effectiveness of agency collections of information and the reduction of paperwork burdens on the public.Authorizes appropriations to carry out paperwork reduction activities for FY 2001 through 2005.(Sec. 5) Establishes an Office of Information Security and Technical Protection in the Office of Information Policy (established by this Act).Requires the Officer to establish Government-wide policies for the management of programs that: (1) support the cost-effective security of Federal information systems by promoting security as an integral component of each agency's business operations; and (2) include information technology architectures(integrated frameworks for evolving or maintaining existing information technology and acquiring new technology to achieve strategic goals and information resources management goals). Requires such policies to: (1) be founded on a continuous risk management cycle; (2) implement controls that adequately address the risk; (3) promote continuing awareness of information security risks; (4) continually monitor and evaluate information security policy; and (5) control effectiveness of information security practices. Outlines information security responsibilities of each agency, including the development and implementation of an agency-wide security program for the operations and assets of such agency. Makes each program subject to Officer approval and annual review by agency program officials.Requires each agency to annually undergo an independent evaluation of its information security program and practices. Requires related reports.Authorizes appropriations for FY 2001 through 2005 to carry out information security provisions.(Sec. 6) Requires the: (1) Secretary of Commerce to develop, issue, review, and update standards and guidance for the security of Federal information systems; (2) Secretary of Defense and Director of the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) to develop and issue more stringent information security policies for mission critical systems of such entities and ensure the implementation of such policies; (3) Department of Justice to review and update guidance to agencies on legal remedies regarding security incidents and coordination with law enforcement agencies concerning such incidents; (4) General Services Administration to review and update guidance on addressing security considerations relating to the acquisition of information technology; and (5) Office of Personnel Management to review and update regulations concerning computer security training for Federal civilian employees.Allows mission critical information security policies developed by the Department of Defense, CIA, and other agencies to be adopted by the Officer and heads of other Federal agencies with respect to mission critical systems of such agencies. Allows agencies to develop and implement more stringent information security policies than those required under this Act.(Sec. 7) Incorporates provisions of the Clinger-Cohen Act with respect to management of information technology. Grants the Officer certain authorities currently granted to the Director. Makes certain information technology provisions inapplicable to national security systems.(Sec. 8) Makes conforming amendments to specified Acts.</summary>
</bill>
