<bill session="104" type="h" number="1795" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Acquisition Improvement Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve Government procurement procedures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402763"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on National Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Business intelligence"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate corruption"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Value engineering"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/1995--Introduced.
Federal Acquisition Improvement Reform Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 and other Federal law, with respect to Federal military and civilian agency procurement, to provide for: (1) a conference on a specific procurement for anyone interested in submitting a bid or proposal in response to the procurement solicitation; (2) a description of the agency's source selection plan in the solicitation; (3) a preliminary assessment of competitive proposals; and (4) special simplified procedures for purchases of commercial items and for property and services in amounts not exceeding the simplified acquisition threshold. Revises procurement integrity provisions under the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act, repealing specific prohibitions against bribery (including offers of future employment) and limiting civil and criminal penalties to certain unauthorized exchanges of contractor bid or proposal information (with increased penalties if information is exchanged for anything of value, or if competitive advantage results). Repeals the exemption from procurement integrity requirements of military and civilian personnel whose contracting authority does not exceed $2,500 (the micro-purchase threshold), and whose duties make it unlikely the individual's total procurements in any 12-month period will exceed $20,000. Outlines specified requirements relating to agency value engineering, among other things: (1) applying such engineering to identify and implement opportunities to reduce capital and operation costs and improve and maintain optimum quality of construction, administrative, program, acquisition, and grant projects; and (2) requiring senior managers to establish appropriate procedures and processes for using qualified personnel, the most cost-effective arrangement for agency work, and sound reporting of agency accomplishments, with any reported savings audited periodically by the agency's Inspector General and split for use between the following year's program and deposit into the Treasury to reduce the Federal debt. Requires the OMB Director to review the policies in this paragraph after a certain period after enactment of this Act for a report to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
