<bill session="106" type="hr" number="504" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-18T13:21:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-05-18T13:21:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 4205) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2001 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal year 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-05-17T23:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-624, by Mrs. Myrick.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-17T23:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4205 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Specified amendments are in order. No further amendment shall be in order except those printed in H.Rept. 106-624. Amendments shall be debatable only in the order printed in the report, for the time specified, equally controlled and divided. All points of order are waived against the amendments. Allows the Chairman to consider any amendment out of the order printed no sooner than one hour after the Chairman of the Committee on Armed Services or a designee announces from the floor a request to this effect.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-05-17T23:45:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="224">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 224.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-05-18T11:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3321-3346" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-18T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 504.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-18T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 200 (Roll no. 200).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3330-3345" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2000-05-18T13:21:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="201" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 254 - 169 (Roll no. 201).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3321-3322" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-05-18T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="4205"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2000--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (modified closed) for the consideration of H.R. 4205 (Department of Defense funding authorization).</summary>
</bill>
