<bill session="108" type="h" number="5408" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business and Farm Energy Emergency Relief Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide emergency relief to small businesses affected by significant increases in the prices of electricity, heating oil, natural gas, propane, and kerosene, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400233"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/20/2004 E2111-2112"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Rural Development and Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Credit, Rural Development, and Research" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural wastes"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Cogeneration of electric power and heat"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Propane"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Small farms"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2004--Introduced.
Small Business and Farm Energy Emergency Relief Act of 2004 - Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make disaster loans to assist small businesses that have suffered or are likely to suffer substantial economic injury as the result of a sharp and significant increase in the price of heating fuel or electricity. Prohibits any such loan from being made if the total amount outstanding and committed to the borrower would exceed $1.5 million, unless the applicant is a major source of employment in its surrounding area. Requires, for such assistance: (1) a declaration by the President or the SBA Administrator that an area is affected by a sharp and significant increase in such price; or (2) a certification from the governor of the State that its small businesses have suffered such economic injury and are in need of assistance which is not otherwise available. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to make loans to farm operations that qualify as a small business and have or are likely to suffer substantial economic injury from a sharp and significant increase in energy costs or input costs from energy sources occurring on or after November 1, 2004, in connection with an energy emergency declared by the President or the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
