<bill session="106" type="h" number="948" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Debt Downpayment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 31 of title 31, United States Code, to establish lower statutory limits for debt held by the public for each of fiscal years 2000 through 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="1999-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="1999-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H885-886"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1253-1254"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Debt limit"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/1999--Introduced.
Debt Downpayment Act - Amends Federal law to establish limits, for FY 2000 through 2009, on the face amounts of publicly-held obligations subject to the public debt limit and those whose principal and interest are guaranteed by the U.S. Government, except those issued directly to a Federal fund. Defines a "Federal fund" as a Federal trust fund or Government account to which the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to issue obligations in respect of public money, money otherwise required to be deposited in the Treasury, or amounts appropriated. Describes the face amount for obligations issued on a discount basis based on whether the obligation is redeemable before or after maturity. Waives these provisions for: (1) any fiscal year in which a declaration of war is in effect; or (2) for the budget year and the next fiscal year, if real economic growth has been negative for two consecutive calendar quarters. Excludes the receipts and disbursements totals of the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program under title II of the Social Security Act (including the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance and Disability Insurance Trust Funds) from: (1) any official statement issued by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) or the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) of surplus or deficit totals of the Federal or congressional budgets; and (2) OMB or CBO displays of Federal budgetary aggregates.</summary>
</bill>
