<bill session="106" type="h" number="238" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-03T18:11:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-03T18:11:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 274 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to impose mandatory minimum sentences, and increase certain sentences, for bringing in and harboring certain aliens and to amend title 18, United States Code, to provide enhanced penalties for persons committing such offenses while armed.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E13"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-07-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-14T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 106-850.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-14T17:18:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="505">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 505.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogan moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8694-8697" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 238.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-10-03T18:11:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8694" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Reporting" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Alien smuggling"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal negligence"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Pleas (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Undercover operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2000--Passed House amended.
(Sec. 1) Directs the Attorney General to increase by 50 for each of FY 2001 through 2005 the number of Immigration and Naturalization Service (full-time) personnel assigned to investigate and combat alien smuggling.(Sec. 2) Directs the United States Sentencing Commission to promulgate revised sentencing guidelines for alien smuggling-related activities so as to: (1) double specified minimum prison terms for smuggling, transporting, harboring, or inducement; (2) increase minimum fines; and (3) increase by at least two offense levels sentencing for intentionally or recklessly creating a substantial risk of serious bodily injury or causing bodily injury or death. Exempts from such provisions offenses: (1) committed other than for profit; or (2) involving a defendant's spouse, child, or both.(Sec. 3) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (Act) to exempt from specified alien smuggling or harboring criminal penalties persons rendering life threatening emergency assistance to an alien in the United States.(Sec. 4) Directs the Commission to revise Federal sentencing guidelines to provide that plea bargaining and other prosecutorial policies, and district policy differences, are not a ground for sentence imposition outside applicable guidelines.(Sec. 5) Amends Federal criminal law to subject specified alien smuggling and harboring crimes under the Act committed by an armed person to enhanced penalties.(Sec. 6) Authorizes Service appropriations for alien smuggling-related undercover and enforcement activities.(Sec. 7) Defines alien smuggling for certain purposes of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
