<bill session="105" type="h" number="3990" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Cramming bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Anti-Cramming Protection Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Telephone Disclosure and Dispute Resolution Act to prevent unfair and deceptive practices in telephone billing for miscellaneous products or services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="1998-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="1998-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1998-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="1998-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-06-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1027"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Telephone rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/1998--Introduced.
Anti-Cramming Protection Act of 1998 - Amends the Telephone Disclosure and Dispute Resolution Act to direct the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to prescribe rules to protect consumers from unfair and deceptive acts in the billing of miscellaneous product or service charges. Prohibits any person from submitting for billing on telephone bills miscellaneous product or service charges which have not been authorized by the subscriber. Outlines further requirements with respect to the identification, and notification to the subscriber, of such miscellaneous charges. Authorizes a subscriber to instruct its common carrier not to bill for any miscellaneous product or service charges or for certain subcategories of such products or services. Directs the FTC to adopt rules for dispute resolution between a subscriber and a provider of miscellaneous products or services. Authorizes a common carrier to discontinue customer billing if it reasonably believes that charges are being submitted to such carrier for billing in violation of this section. Provides for enforcement of FTC rules adopted pursuant to this Act. Recognizes any applicable State law not inconsistent with this Act. Directs the FTC to enforce the requirements of this Act. Authorizes the attorney general of a State, or other authorized State officials, to bring a civil action on behalf of its residents for violations of this Act, after prior written notice to the FTC.</summary>
</bill>
