<bill session="104" type="h" number="1095" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Check Cashing Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a State system of licensing or registering persons engaged in a business which regularly and primarily charges fees for cashing checks, and to provide for insured financial depository institutions to cash checks issued by States of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404067"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2402"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development banking"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Debit cards"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/1995--Introduced.
Check Cashing Act of 1995 - Requires any person other than a depository institution to obtain a State license or registration as a prerequisite to conducting a check cashing business. Prescribes guidelines under which the Federal Trade Commission may approve a State check cashing business licensing or registration system. Cites circumstances under which an insured depository institution or (with respect to its members) credit union may not refuse to cash a government check presented by a payee. Declares that the National Credit Union Administration Board may not prohibit any federally chartered (community development) credit union from dispensing benefits under a Federal or State assistance program that are authorized to be dispensed by a check cashing service. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to the Congress on: (1) the effectiveness of the dispensation of benefits under Federal and State assistance programs through federally chartered credit unions; and (2) the effects of requiring the use of a debit card system for making all federal benefit payments, as well as other innovative ways to upgrade current methods by which the Federal Government delivers benefit payment checks.</summary>
</bill>
