<bill session="104" type="hr" number="224" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-20T12:57:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-09-20T12:57:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2274) to amend title 23, United States Code, to designate the National Highway System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408976"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-09-19T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-252, by Mr. Quillen.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-19T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2274 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. In lieu of the amendmment recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of H.R. 2349. The amendment shall be considered by title rather than by section. The first two sections and each titlte shall be considered as read. Specified points of order shall be waived. Before consideration of any other amendment, it shall be in order to consider the amendment printed in the report accompanying this rule, debatable for 10 minutes. All points of order against the amendment...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-09-19T18:25:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="91">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 91.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-09-20T11:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9257-9264" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-20T11:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-20T12:48:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 173 (Roll no. 674).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-09-20T12:57:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="675" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 375 - 39, 1 Present (Roll no. 675).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-09-20T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="2274"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the open rule for the consideration of H.R. 2274 (designating the National Highway System).</summary>
</bill>
