<bill session="108" type="hc" number="466" updated="2013-07-14T19:03:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Urging the Government of India to conduct a thorough and transparent investigation of the scope of abusive child labor in circuses throughout India and to pursue immediate and effective remedies to end such abuse, and to provide immediate and continuous police protection to secure the personal safety of Kailash Satyarthi, his family, and his colleagues in the South Asian Coalition Against Child Servitude.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2004-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Children's rights"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights workers"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2004--Introduced.
States that Congress: (1) urges the Government of India, the provincial government in Uttar Pradesh, and the local government in the Gonda District to take immediate action to secure the release of the children being held by the owners and operators of the Great Roman Circus; (2) urges the Government of India, the provincial government of Uttar Pradesh, and the local government in Gonda District to provide police protection for Kailash Satyarthi, his family, and his colleagues in the South Asian Coalition Against Child Servitude who were brutally attacked on June 15, 2004, and to prevent any future attacks; (3) urges the Government of India and the provincial government of Uttar Pradesh to investigate such attack and to arrest and prosecute the responsible individuals; and (4) urges the Government of India to conduct a thorough and transparent investigation of the scope of abusive child labor in Indian circuses and to pursue remedies to end such abuse.</summary>
</bill>
