<bill session="106" type="h" number="874" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Individual Social Security Retirement Accounts Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform Social Security by creating individual Social Security retirement accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400604"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1999-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="1999-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400607" joined="1999-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1999-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="1999-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E291"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Retirement age"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security beneficiaries"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/1999--Introduced.
Individual Social Security Retirement Accounts Act of 1999 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to reduce social security taxes for eligible individuals, whether employed by others or self-employed, who elect to participate in the Individual Retirement Program (IRP) created under a new part B of title II (Old-Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) (part B eligible individual). Reduces the employers' tax for employers of such individuals. Leaves the respective tax rates at their current levels with respect to individuals who remain covered under the current OASDI program (redesignated as part A of SSA title II).(Sec. 3) Amends SSA title II to require, under new part B, that employers have in effect a social security payroll deduction plan for eligible employees who elect to enroll under it. Requires the plan to provide for employers to deduct five percent of the employee's wages, together with an employer contribution also equal to five percent of the employee's wages, for transfer to the employee's individual social security retirement (ISSR) account.Requires self-employed individuals to contribute ten percent of their income to such accounts.Makes employees between ages 18 and 61 who are not entitled to OASDI disability benefits eligible to elect to enroll under new part B. Entitles eligible individuals who attain age 62 to a supplemental minimum benefit payment to their ISSR accounts. Requires a trustee of an ISSR account to purchase, from amounts available in the account, disability insurance and preretirement survivor benefits for each account holder.Sets forth penalties for failure to establish and maintain a social security payroll deduction plan.Amends the IRC to require amounts deducted from employee wages to be shown on their wage receipts.Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to exempt social security payroll deduction plans from certain requirements for employee benefit plans.(Sec. 4) Amends the IRC to exclude from an individual's gross income: (1) any amount paid to an ISSR account as the employer's contribution; or (2) half of the amount paid to such an account of a self-employed individual. Exempts such accounts from taxation (except the excise tax on certain prohibited transactions). Provides for taxation of account distributions, to the extent they are includible in gross income, in the same manner as social security benefits. Imposes an excise tax on excess contributions to an account.(Sec. 5) Amends SSA title II to declares that eligible individuals who have elected to establish ISSR accounts shall be deemed not entitled to OASDI benefits.(Sec. 6) Directs the Commissioner of Social Security to certify to the Secretary of the Treasury whether an eligible individual was credited with wages and self-employment income under SSA title II part A immediately before the first calendar year for which the individual may distribute amounts from an ISSR account. Provides that, immediately upon receipt of such certification, the Secretary shall issue a contribution recognition bond to the trustee of the ISSR account held by such individual. Defines a contribution recognition bond as consisting of an obligation of the United States to make monthly payments into an ISSR account in an amount equal to the individual's primary insurance amount.(Sec. 7) Provides for a phased-in increase in the social security retirement age, eventually to age 70 with respect to an individual who attains early retirement age after December 31, 2028.(Sec. 8) Amends SSA title II to provide for the application of adjusted percentages to average indexed monthly earnings in determining primary insurance amounts.(Sec. 9) Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to provide for off-budget treatment for specified social security reforms.(Sec. 10) Directs the Office of Personnel Management to study and report to the President and Congress on the most appropriate and feasible means of providing for the application of this Act with respect to Federal civilian and military personnel.</summary>
</bill>
