<bill session="104" type="h" number="1676" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 to clarify that the expenses of administering the Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance programs are not included in the budget of the United States Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405939"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1995-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-05-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1075-1076"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-18">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-18">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Legislative and Budget Process.</text>
      <committee name="House Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU02" subcommittee="Legislative Process" name="House Rules"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 to exclude the administrative expenses of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund under title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act from Federal budget calculations. Exempts expenses of administering the old age, survivors and disability insurance programs from sequestration under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman Hollings Act). Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the congressional budget resolution to set forth separately an estimate of benefit payments under the OASDI programs for the fiscal year and each of the two ensuing fiscal years. Amends the Budget Enforcement Act of 1990 to make it out of order in the House of Representatives to consider any bill or joint resolution which would appropriate funds for a fiscal year which exceeds 1.5 percent of the estimate of benefit payments for such OASDI programs for the fiscal year set forth in the most recently agreed to congressional budget resolution.</summary>
</bill>
