<bill session="106" type="h" number="4402" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Training and Education for American Workers Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Training and Education for American Workers Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the American Competitiveness and Workforce Improvement Act of 1998 to improve the use of amounts deposited into the H-1B Nonimmigrant Petitioner Account for demonstration programs and projects to provide technical skills training for occupations for which there is a high demand for skilled workers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="2000-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2000-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400135" joined="2000-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="2000-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2000-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2000-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2000-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2000-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-05-10">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-05-25T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 106-642.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-05-25T15:53:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="352">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 352.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Biomedical engineering"/>
    <term name="Biotechnology"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer industry"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disabled students"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="High technology industries"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Working poor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2000--Reported to House amended.
Training and Education for American Workers Act of 2000 - Amends the American Competitiveness and Workforce Improvement Act of 1998 (as contained in title IV of division C of the Omnibus Consolidated and Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1999 (Public Law 105-277)) to revise provisions for the use of amounts deposited into the H-1B Nonimmigrant Petitioner Account for demonstration programs and projects to provide technical skills training for employed and unemployed workers.Directs the Secretary of Labor to: (1) use 75 percent of such funds to award grants to provide such training for any skill shortage related to a specialty occupation, as defined under the Immigration and Nationality Act; and (2) transfer 25 percent of such funds to the Secretary of Education for a student loan forgiveness program for mathematics, science, and reading teachers.Revises such training grant eligibility provisions. Requires certain eligible local, regional, or multi-State consortia to act in conjunction with, and with the active participation of, eligible local workforce investment boards. Requires 25 percent matching funds from grantees.Gives priority for such training grants to programs or projects that train employed and unemployed workers in skills that are in shortage in the high technology, information technology, and biotechnology fields, including software and communications services, telecommunications, systems installation and integration, computers and communications hardware, health care technology, biotechnology, and biomedical research, manufacturing, and innovation services.Requires grantees to make active efforts to recruit and train individuals traditionally underrepresented in information technology occupations, such as minorities, women, low-wage workers, workers residing in empowerment zones and enterprise communities, and individuals with a disability.Establishes such student loan forgiveness program, for specified loans made under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA), for new borrowers after October 1, 1998, who have been employed as full-time teachers of mathematics, science, or a related field, or have been full-time teachers responsible for providing reading instruction in any of grades kindergarten through third grade, for three consecutive complete school years.Sets forth various qualifications which loan forgiveness applicants must demonstrate with respect to their being fully qualified teachers in: (1) public elementary or secondary schools; or (2) nonprofit private elementary or secondary schools or charter schools.</summary>
</bill>
