<bill session="104" type="h" number="3520" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Retirement Savings and Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Pension Audit Improvement Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for retirement savings and security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400146"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1996-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404520" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404634" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="1996-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1996-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="406284" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1996-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1996-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1996-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400300" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1996-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="410821" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411677" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1996-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1996-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Economic and Educational Opportunities, Government Reform and Oversight, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW09" subcommittee="Railroads" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disability retirement"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Divorcees"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Embezzlement"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Employee leasing"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Heart diseases"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Hypertension"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Local officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Quality control"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
    <term name="Retirement age"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Widowers"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Revenue Provisions Subtitle A: Expanded Pension Coverage and Simplification Subtitle B: Expanded Individual Retirement Accounts to Increase Coverage and Portability Subtitle C: Other Expansions of Pension Portability Subtitle D: Conforming Amendments Title II: ERISA Provisions Subtitle A: Expanded Pension Coverage and Simplification Subtitle B: Portability Subtitle C: Enhanced Security Title III: Additional Retirement Participation and Payment Options for Federal Employees Title IV: Conforming Railroad Retirement Benefits with Social Security Retirement Savings and Security Act - Title I: Revenue Provisions - Subtitle A: Expanded Pension Coverage and Simplification - Chapter 1: The NEST and Other Coverage Expansion - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish national employee savings trusts (NESTS), 401 (k)-type plans, for employees of small employers. (Sec. 1102) Makes tax-exempt organizations and Indian governmental instrumentalities eligible section 401(k) pension plan employers. (Sec. 1103) Sets forth alternative methods for satisfying section 401(k) nondiscrimination tests. (Sec. 1104) Revises "highly compensated employee" provisions. (Sec. 1106) Repeals the limitation in the case of an employee with defined benefit and a defined contribution plans from the same employer. (Sec. 1107) Makes certain defined contribution plan provisions applicable to all permanently disabled employees. (Sec. 1108) Revises deferred payment provisions with respect to: (1) owner-employee contributions; (2) State and local plan trust requirements; and (3) certain disability payments to former police officers or fire fighters. Chapter 2: Simplification and Cost Savings - Sets forth a special compensation limitation rule with respect to governmental and multiemployer deferred payment plans. States that a governmental plan's eligibility shall not be affected by its excess benefit arrangement. (Sec. 1204) Provides special rules for treatment of governmental and tax-exempt organization deferred compensation plans. (Sec. 1206) Establishes a simplified method for annuity distribution taxation for certain employer plans. (Sec. 1207) Eliminates five-year income averaging for lump-sum distributions. (Sec. 1208) Reduces from 59.5 years old to 59 years old the age at which a recipient may receive certain retirement and annuity distributions penalty-free. (Sec. 1209) Provides a special rule for certain rural cooperative plan distributions. (Sec. 1211) Treats the social security retirement age as the uniform retirement age for purposes of pension plan non-discrimination requirements. (Sec. 1214) Eliminates partial termination rules with respect to multiemployer plans. (Sec. 1217) Increases the tax on prohibited transactions. Subtitle B: Expanded Individual Retirement Accounts to Increase Coverage and Portability - Chapter 1: Retirement Savings Incentives - Subchapter A: IRA Deduction - Increases individual retirement account (IRA) income limitations. Provides inflation adjustments for deductible amounts and income limitations. Subchapter B: Nondeductible Tax-Free IRAs - Establishes nondeductible tax-free IRAs. Chapter 2: Distributions and Investments - Authorizes IRA distributions to be used without the additional ten-percent tax for first home purchases, higher education, financially devastating medical costs, and by the unemployed. (Sec. 1323) Sets forth provisions with respect to the use of IRA funds to purchase qualifying State prepaid tuition instruments. Chapter 3: Termination of Certain Provisions - Sets forth IRA-related termination provisions with respect to: (1) inflation adjustments; (2) contributions to special IRA accounts; (3) early withdrawal tax; and (4) increases in specified limitations. Subtitle C: Other Expansions of Pension Portability - Establishes alternative nondiscrimination rules for certain plans that provide for early participation. (Sec. 1402) Establishes special rules for certain veterans' reemployment rights, including provisions regarding: (1) contributions; (2) elective deferrals; (3) retroactive adjustments; (4) loan repayment suspensions; and (5) compensation. (Sec. 1403) Eliminates the special vesting rule for multiemployer plans. Subtitle D: Conforming Amendments - Makes specified conforming amendments. Title II: ERISA Provisions - Subtitle A: Expanded Pension Coverage and Simplification - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to establish reporting and fiduciary requirements relating to NESTs designed to ensure participation by low- and moderate-wage workers, who will be able to save up to $5,000 per year tax-deferred, plus receive employer contributions toward retirement). (Sec. 2002) Eliminates specified ERISA requirements relating to employee benefit plan descriptions and filing of summary plan descriptions and descriptions of material modifications to a plan. Requires filing of annual plan reports by plan administrators. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to request any documents relating to such plans. (Sec. 2003) Includes under ERISA purchases of qualified State prepaid tuition program instruments to which specified IRC provisions apply. Subtitle B: Portability - Directs the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) to prescribe specified types of payment rules relating to missing participants for terminated multiemployer plans. (Sec. 2011) Allows the administrator of a plan not otherwise subject to ERISA plan termination insurance provisions to elect to transfer a missing participant's benefits to the PBGC upon plan termination. Requires such administrator to provide the PBGC with specified information. Directs the PBGC, if such a missing participant's benefits are transferred to it, to pay the appropriate amount to the participant or beneficiary. (Sec. 2012) Eliminates a special vesting rule for multiemployer plans. (Sec. 2013) Provides for treatment of certain loans during military service. Subtitle C: Enhanced Security - Increases the amounts of guarantees for multiemployer plan benefits. (Sec. 2022) Directs the Secretary of Labor, as chairman of the PBGC board, to transmit to the President and the Congress an annual reversion report providing information on plans from which residual assets were distributed to employers. (Sec. 2023) Sets forth a full funding limitation for multiemployer plans. Requires a valuation every three years in the case of multiemployer plans. (Sec. 2024) Increases the maximum civil penalty for certain prohibited transactions. (Sec. 2025) Revises provisions relating to substantial owner benefits to modify: (1) a phase-in of guarantee; and (2) allocation of assets. Pension Audit Improvement Act of 1996 - Amends ERISA to repeal certain provisions for limited scope audits. (Sec. 2033) Requires certain notifications by plan administrators and accountants regarding: (1) irregularities that may have occurred with respect to plans; and (2) termination of an accountant's engagement for auditing services. Sets forth civil penalties for failures to provide the Secretary of Labor with such notifications. (Sec. 2034) Prescribes additional requirements for qualified public accountants. (Sec. 2035) Revises certain fiduciary penalties. Modifies a prohibition of assignment or alienation. Changes from mandatory to discretionary: (1) the imposition and the amount of civil penalties for breach of fiduciary responsibility; and (2) certain provisions relating to an applicable recovery amount. Title III: Additional Retirement Participation and Payment Options for Federal Employees - Requires the Executive Director of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board to prescribe regulations to allow Federal employees to be afforded a reasonable opportunity to make an election to make contributions under the Thrift Savings Plan on the date of commencing service or beginning on the earliest date thereafter that such an election becomes administratively feasible. (Sec. 3002) Provides for a deferred annuity for a surviving former spouse of a deceased former Federal employee who separated from the service with title to a deferred annuity if such individuals were married to one another prior to the date of separation. Provides for a surviving spouse to elect to receive a certain deferred annuity if a former employee dies after having separated from the service with title to a deferred annuity but before having established a valid claim for annuity. (Sec. 3003) Provides for the payment of a lump-sum credit for a former spouse of a Federal employee. Title IV: Conforming Railroad Retirement Benefits with Social Security - Amends the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 (RRA) with respect to eligibility for and amount of a child's annuity. (Sec. 4002) Provides for entitlement to spousal annuities despite certain age requirements. Repeals the age requirement for divorced spouses, and provides for entitlement of the divorced spouse where the worker's annuity is not payable. (Sec. 4003) Provides for RRA benefits equivalent to those under the Social Security Act, with respect to: (1) amounts of continued payment to survivors of waived lump sum benefits; (2) lump sum death benefits; and (3) benefits with respect to service for which certain railroad retirement annuities are not payable.</summary>
</bill>
