<bill session="106" type="h" number="1143" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-17">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Microenterprise for Self-Reliance Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Microenterprise for Self-Reliance Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Microenterprise for Self-Reliance and International Anti-Corruption Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">International Academic Opportunity Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">International Anti-Corruption and Good Governance Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Microenterprise for Self-Reliance Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Paul D. Coverdell Fellows Program Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Support for Overseas Cooperative Development Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Microenterprise for Self-Reliance and International Anti-Corruption Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">International Academic Opportunity Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">International Anti-Corruption and Good Governance Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Microenterprise for Self-Reliance Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program to provide assistance for programs of credit and other financial services for microenterprises in developing countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="1999-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-03-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-04-12T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on International Relations. H. Rept. 106-82.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-04-12T16:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="44">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 44.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-04-12T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 136 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1143 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 4(a) of rule XIII are waived. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13T12:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 136 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13T12:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 136.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1888-1896" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13T12:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1143 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 4(a) of rule XIII are waived. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13T12:11:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 136 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13T12:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Thomas W. Ewing to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13T12:12:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1143.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13T12:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The House proceeded with debate on the amendment offered by Mr. Smith of New Jersey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13T12:44:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1143.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13T12:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-04-13T12:46:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13T12:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9681-9682" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-10-03" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-05T13:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-10-05T13:05:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8886-8893" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8886-8892" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-05T13:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-05">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-06">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-10-17">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-10-17" type="public" number="106-309">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-309.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="136"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2844"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Capital movements"/>
    <term name="Central banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Cooperative societies"/>
    <term name="Corporate corruption"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal incorporation"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial crises"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="International agricultural cooperation"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International economic relations"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Peace Corps"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Poor women"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Rural electrification"/>
    <term name="Rural poverty"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations delegations"/>
    <term name="United Nations economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban poverty"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h43"/>
    <amendment number="s4287"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/3/2000--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Microenterprise for Self-Reliance Act of 2000 Title II: International Anti-Corruption and Good Governance Act of 2000 Title III: International Academic Opportunity Act of 2000 Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions Microenterprise for Self-Reliance and International Anti-Corruption Act of 2000 - Title I: Microenterprise for Self-Reliance Act of 2000 - Microenterprise for Self-Reliance Act of 2000 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to set forth congressional findings and policy, including that: (1) the development of microenterprise (including micro- and small enterprises) is a vital factor in the growth of developing countries and in the development of free, open, and equitable international economic systems; (2) it is in the best interest of the United States to assist the development of microenterprises and of enterprises of the poor in developing countries; and (3) the support of microenterprise can be served by programs that provide credit, savings, training, technical assistance, and business development services.(Sec. 105) Authorizes the President to provide grants and other assistance for programs to increase the availability of credit and other services to microenterprises (including micro- and small enterprises) lacking full access to capital training, technical assistance, and business development services through: (1) grants to microfinance institutions; (2) loans and guarantees to credit institutions (with a limit of $30 million per borrower); (3) grants to microenterprise institutions for training, technical assistance, and business development services; and (3) policy and regulatory programs at the country level.Directs the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (AID) to establish: (1) a monitoring system that provides, among other things, for performance goals for microenterprise development grant assistance; (2) eligibility criteria for determining which entities shall carry out activities receiving credit assistance; and (3) a U.S. Microfinance Loan Facility to prevent the bankruptcy of microfinance institutions caused by natural disasters, war or civil conflict, national financial crisis, or other short-term financial movements that threaten the long-term development of such institutions. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 108) Directs the President to report to the appropriate congressional committees on the most cost-effective methods and measurements for increasing the access of poor people overseas to credit, other financial services, and related training.(Sec. 109) Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the administrator of AID and the Secretary of State should seek to support and strengthen the effectiveness of microfinance activities in United Nations (UN) agencies, such as the UN Development Program, which have provided key leadership in developing the microenterprise sector; and (2) the Secretary of the Treasury should instruct each U.S. Executive Director of the multilateral development banks to advocate the development of a coherent and coordinated strategy to support the microenterprise sector, including an increase of multilateral resource flows for building microenterprise retail and wholesale intermediaries.(Sec. 110) Expresses the sense of Congress that the AID should consider Mexico as a key priority in its microenterprise funding allocations.Title II: International Anti-Corruption and Good Governance Act of 2000 - International Anti-Corruption and Good Governance Act of 2000 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to revise U.S. development cooperation policy to urge emphasis on (among other things) the promotion of good governance through combating corruption and improving transparency and accountability. Revises U.S. policy with respect to the provision of development assistance to foreign countries to require the President, in assessing the commitment and progress of a country to use such assistance to help satisfy basic human needs of its poor, to utilize certain criteria, including progress in combating corruption and improving transparency and accountability in the public and private sector.(Sec. 204) Requires technical assistance provided by a certain Department of the Treasury program to foreign governments and foreign central banks of developing or transitional countries to include elements designed to combat anti-competitive, unethical, and corrupt activities, including protection against actions that may distort or inhibit transparency in market mechanisms and, to the extent applicable, privatization procedures.(Sec. 205) Authorizes the President to establish programs that combat corruption, improve transparency and accountability, and promote other forms of good governance in developing countries or countries eligible to receive assistance under the Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989. Requires the President to give priority to establishing programs in countries that received a significant amount of U.S. foreign assistance for the prior fiscal year, or in which the United States has a significant economic interest, and that continue to have the most persistent problems with public and private corruption. Requires the Secretary of State to report to specified congressional committees with respect to such programs. Authorizes appropriations.Title III: International Academic Opportunity Act of 2000 - International Academic Opportunity Act of 2000 - Directs the Secretary of State, subject to the availability of appropriations, to establish a Benjamin A. Gilman International Scholarships program of grants of up to $5,000 each to American college students of limited financial means for foreign study. Authorizes appropriations.Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions - Support for Overseas Cooperative Development Act - Declares that Congress supports the development and expansion of economic assistance programs that fully utilize cooperatives and credit unions, particularly those programs committed to: (1) international cooperative principles, democratic governance and involvement of women and ethnic minorities for economic and social development; (2) market-oriented and value-added activities with the potential to reach large numbers of low-income people and help them enter into mainstream economy; (3) strengthened participation of rural and urban poor to contribute to their country's economic development; and (4) utilization of technical assistance and training to better serve the member-owners.(Sec. 401) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 with respect to the goal of strengthening the participation of the rural and urban poor in their country's development through the use of development funds for technical and capital assistance in the development and use of cooperatives in less developed countries. Requires that priority be given to: (1) technical assistance to low-income farmers who form and develop member-owned cooperatives for farm supplies, marketing, and value-added processing; (2) the promotion of national credit union technical assistance that strengthens the ability of low-income people and micro-entrepreneurs to save and to have access to credit for their own economic advancement; (3) the support of rural electric and telecommunication cooperatives for access for rural people and villages that lack reliable electric and telecommunications services; and (4) the promotion of community-based cooperatives which provide employment opportunities and important services such as health clinics, self-help shelter, environmental improvements, group-owned businesses, and other activities.(Sec. 402) Authorizes appropriations for development assistance to carry out activities of the Global Environment Center of the AID. Earmarks amounts for water and coastal resources activities.(Sec. 403) Directs the Administrator of AID, in processing applications for the transportation of humanitarian assistance abroad, to give priority to applications for the transportation of disaster relief assistance.(Sec. 404) Establishes a working capital fund for the AID for expenses of personal and nonpersonal services, equipment, and supplies for: (1) International Cooperative Administrative Support Services; and (2) rebates from the use of U.S. Government credit cards.(Sec. 405) Amends the United Nations Participation Act of 1945 to increase the number of foreign service employees of the staff of the U.S. Mission to the UN who are provided living quarters in New York City, New York.(Sec. 406) Amends Federal law to extend the availability to the Linguistic Data Consortium of the University of Pennsylvania Voice of America (VOA) and Radio Marti computer readable multilingual text and recorded speech in various languages.(Sec. 407) Authorizes the Broadcasting Board of Governors to make available, upon request, to the Institute for Media Development previously broadcast audio and video materials produced by the Africa Division of the VOA.Paul D. Coverdell Fellows Program Act of 2000 - Renames the Peace Corps Fellows-USA Program the Paul D. Coverdell Fellows Program.</summary>
</bill>
