<bill session="106" type="h" number="2158" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Generation-Skipping Transfer Tax Amendments Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the tax on generation-skipping transfers to eliminate certain traps for the unwary and otherwise improve the fairness of such tax.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400261"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1975"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Inheritance tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1999--Introduced.
Generation-Skipping Transfer Tax Amendments Act of 1999 - Amends Internal Revenue Code provisions concerning the special rules for allocation of the generation-skipping tax (GST) exemption to provide, as a general rule, that: (1) if any individual makes an indirect skip during such individual's lifetime, any unused portion of such individual's GST exemption shall be allocated to the property transferred to the extent necessary to make the inclusion ratio for such property zero; and (2) if the amount of the indirect skip exceeds such unused portion, the entire unused portion shall be allocated to the property transferred.Requires the trusts resulting from a qualified severance to be treated as separate trusts.Revises valuation rules concerning gifts for which a gift tax return was filed or a deemed allocation was made.Requires regulations permitting the granting of extensions of time to make an allocation of a GST exemption.</summary>
</bill>
