<bill session="106" type="h" number="3378" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-12T22:45:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-09-12T22:45:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tijuana River Valley Estuary and Beach Sewage Cleanup Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Tijuana River Valley Estuary and Beach Sewage Cleanup Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Tijuana River Valley Estuary and Beach Sewage Cleanup Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize certain actions to address the comprehensive treatment of sewage emanating from the Tijuana River in order to substantially reduce river and ocean pollution in the San Diego border region.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1999-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-26">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-07-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-07">
      <text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 106-842, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on International Relations Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 12, 2000.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on International Relations discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-12T16:46:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="499">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 499.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T22:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. LaTourette moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T22:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7470-7475" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T22:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3378.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-09-12T22:45:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7470-7471" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T22:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International rivers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewage sludge"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in rivers, lakes, etc."/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2000--Passed House amended.
Tijuana River Valley Estuary and Beach Sewage Cleanup Act of 2000 - Authorizes and directs the U.S. section of the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico, subject to the negotiation and conclusion of a new Treaty Minute pursuant to the Treaty for the Utilization of Waters of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande or the amendment of Treaty Minute 283, to provide for the secondary treatment of up to 50 million gallons per day (mgd) in Mexico of: (1) effluent from the South Bay International Wastewater Treatment Plant (IWTP) if such treatment is not provided for at a U.S. facility; and (2) additional sewage emanating from the Tijuana River area, Mexico.Authorizes the Commission, subject to the results of the comprehensive plan developed under this Act revealing a need for additional secondary treatment capacity in the San Diego-Tijuana border region (border region) and recommending the provision of such capacity in Mexico, to provide up to an additional 25 mgd of such capacity for the above-described treatment.Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to develop a comprehensive plan with stakeholder involvement to address the transborder sanitation problems in the border region.Permits the Commission, upon conclusion of a new Treaty Minute or the amendment of Treaty Minute 283, to enter into a fee-for-services contract with the owner of the Mexican Facility (proposed wastewater treatment facility to be constructed within Mexico for treating sewage flows generated within Mexico, which flows impact U.S. and Mexican surface waters, health, and safety) to carry out the secondary treatment requirements of this Act. Requires the Inspector General of the Department of State to monitor and report to Congress on such contract.Requests the Secretary of State to give the highest priority to the negotiation and execution of a new Treaty Minute or a modification of Treaty Minute 283 in order that the other provisions of this Act to address river and ocean pollution in the border region may be implemented as soon as possible. Requests the Secretary to initiate such negotiations with Mexico. Requires the new or modified Treaty Minute to be subject to the provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
