<bill session="105" type="h" number="4874" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Military Training Transparency and Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the provision of defense services and training under the Arms Export Control Act or any other Act to foreign countries that are prohibited from receiving international military education and training or any other military assistance or arms transfers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1998-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/21/1998--Introduced.
International Military Training Transparency and Accountability Act - Amends the Arms Export Control Act to prohibit the sale, lease, loan, or grant of defense services or training (including Joint Combined Exchange Training (JCET)) to any foreign country that is prohibited or restricted from receiving international military education and training (IMET), or other military assistance or arms transfers. Permits a foreign country that is eligible to receive only expanded IMET, and is not prohibited from receiving any other military assistance or arms transfers, to receive defense services and training if it provides for training of civilian officials and military officers of the armed forces on military justice, international human rights standards, and the proper role of such forces in a democratic society. Permits a foreign country otherwise prohibited or restricted from receiving IMET or any other military assistance or arms transfers to receive defense services and training substantially unrelated to the prohibited military assistance or arms transfers, provided the President makes a specified certification to the Congress. Authorizes the President to waive any prohibition under this Act with respect to a foreign country upon certification to the Congress that it is important to the national security of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
