<bill session="108" type="h" number="1645" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a research, development, and demonstration program in genetics, protein science, and computational biology of microbes and plants to support the energy and environmental mission of the Department of Energy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400035"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Bacteria"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Heavy metals"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Plants"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Proteins"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2003--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish a research, development, and demonstration program in genetics, protein science, and computational biology of microbes and plants to support the energy and environmental mission of the Department. Provides that the program shall support individual investigators and multidisciplinary teams of investigators through competitive, merit-reviewed grants.Establishes as the program goal developing technologies and methods, based on the biological functions of microbes and plants, that: (1) can facilitate the production of fuels; (2) convert carbon dioxide to organic carbon; and (3) detoxify soils and water at DOE facilities contaminated with heavy metals and radiological materials. Requires the Secretary to: (1) transmit to Congress a research plan describing how the program will accomplish that goal; (2) contract with the National Academy of Sciences to review the plan; and (3) transmit the review to Congress along with the Secretary's response to recommendations.Prohibits the Secretary from conducting biomedical research in carrying out such program.</summary>
</bill>
