<bill session="104" type="h" number="1628" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Defense Nuclear Programs Agency Organization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Defense Nuclear Programs Agency to carry out all defense nuclear programs matters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405560"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-05-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1021"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-22">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD, DOE.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Procurement.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS20" subcommittee="Military Procurement" name="House National Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/1995--Introduced.
Defense Nuclear Programs Agency Organization Act - Establishes the Defense Nuclear Programs Agency, headed by an Administrator, who shall serve as the principal adviser to the President and the Secretary of Defense on all defense nuclear programs matters. Requires the appointment by the President of a Deputy Agency Administrator, as well as four Assistant Administrators, an Inspector General, and a General Counsel of the Agency. Requires the Administrator to be the Staff Director of the Nuclear Weapons Council. Transfers to the Administrator specified functions currently held by the Department of Energy, the Department of Defense, and the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board (Board) with respect to national security functions, as well as the oversight of defense and nondefense functions and budgets of specified national laboratories. (Sec. 7) Prohibits the transfer to another account of amounts appropriated to the Agency unless specifically authorized by law. Provides transition and savings provisions. (Sec. 11) Provides effective dates for specified provisions of this Act. Requires the Secretaries of Defense and Energy, the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Atomic Energy, and the Board to plan for the orderly establishment of, and transfer of functions to, the Agency.</summary>
</bill>
