<bill session="104" type="hr" number="311" updated="2012-11-01T22:43:19-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-19T12:27:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-12-19T12:27:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the provisional approval of regulations applicable to the House of Representatives and employees of the House of Representatives and to be issued by the Office of Compliance before January 23, 1996.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19T11:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19T11:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (CR H15111-15116)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15111-15116" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19T11:50:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-12-19T12:27:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19T12:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>12/19/1995--Introduced.
Approves, on a provisional basis until approved in accordance with the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, the regulations to be issued by the Office of Compliance before January 23, 1996, applicable to the House of Representatives and its employees.</summary>
</bill>
