<bill session="105" type="h" number="3209" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">On-Line Copyright Infringement Liability Limitation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 17, United States Code, to limit liability for copyright infringement for on-line material.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="1998-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E160-161"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2180"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Copyright infringement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Internet service providers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/1998--Introduced.
On-Line Copyright Infringement Liability Limitation Act - Amends Federal copyright law to exempt an on-line material provider from liability for direct infringement, based solely on the intermediate storage and transmission of material over such provider's network, if: (1) the transmission was initiated by another person; (2) the storage and transmission is carried out through an automatic technological process, without any selection of that material by the provider; and (3) any copy of such material is not retained longer than necessary to carry out that transmission. Exempts such a provider from liability for monetary relief for contributory infringement or vicarious liability based solely on the above conduct or on the transmission or provision of access to such material over the provider's system or network if the provider: (1) does not know of information indicating that the material is infringing; and (2) does not receive a financial benefit directly attributable to the infringing activity. Exempts a provider from any claim based on such provider's removing or disabling on-line access to material in response to knowledge or information that such material is infringing, whether or not such material is in fact an infringement. Makes liable for damages any person who knowingly materially misrepresents that on-line material is an infringement.</summary>
</bill>
