<bill session="104" type="h" number="4324" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Welfare to Work Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Population growth"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare recipients"/>
    <term name="Welfare reform"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1996--Introduced.
Welfare to Work Act of 1996 - Revises various provisions of the recently enacted Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996's Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) Program under new part A of title IV of the Social Security Act. Includes among such revisions: (1) new program purposes, such as helping low income families attain work and economic self-sufficiency and breaking the cycle of dependency of needy parents on government benefits by requiring job preparation and work; (2) renaming the program as the Assistance for Needy Families Program; (3) requiring work activities after three months of receiving program assistance, with certain good cause exceptions; (4) requiring cash benefits to be provided for recipients engaging in required work activities; (5) increasing child care funding; (6) eliminating the five year limit on program assistance; (7) establishing a supplemental grant for operation of work programs; (8) repealing Federal loans for State Welfare programs; (9) making mandatory the currently optional domestic violence certification with regard to State plans; and (10) requiring States to make an initial assessment of recipients of assistance.</summary>
</bill>
