<bill session="104" type="h" number="190" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Equal Employment Opportunity Commission Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen the authority of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission to enforce nondiscrimination policies in Federal employment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402763"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Affirmative action programs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in the civil service"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Equal Employment Opportunity Commission Amendments of 1995 - Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to authorize the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission to request a head of a Federal agency, department, or unit to appear before the Commission and explain the reason for failing to submit an equal employment opportunity plan. Directs the Commission, after an opportunity for a hearing, to order submission of a plan. Requires the Commission to enforce compliance with such order. Authorizes the Commission to initiate disciplinary action, including the withholding of pay, against any officer or employee responsible for failure to comply with an order. States that equal employment opportunity plans shall include the numerical employment goals established by an agency in its minority recruitment program and that each agency should establish numerical employment goals for the purpose of complying with affirmative action plans.</summary>
</bill>
