<bill session="108" type="h" number="5178" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Driver's License Improvement and Security Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to carry out a pilot program to improve the security of State drivers' licenses and identification cards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1759-1760"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Computer matching"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Encryption"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2004--Introduced.
Driver's License Improvement and Security Act of 2004 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to carry out a pilot program to assist States in developing and implementing a driver's license and identification card program that meets certain requirements. Requires a State to: (1) embed computer chips in licenses and cards it issues; (2) obtain biometric data for the identification of individuals to whom the State issues a new or renewed driver's license or identification card; (3) participate in a program to link State motor vehicle databases in order to provide electronic access by a State to information contained in the motor vehicle databases of other States; (4) include on each new or renewed driver's license or identification card multiple tamper-resistant security features or optical image layers, such as biometric scans, barcodes, 3D, flip, or motion imaging; and (5) adopt and implement procedures to document accurately the identity and residence of an individual before issuing him or her a driver's license or identification card. Authorizes the Secretary to make a grant to assist a State in developing and implementing a driver's license and identification card program that meets the requirements of this Act. Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to study and report to the Secretary of Transportation on which on-card biometric technology is most effective and usable for the pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
