<bill session="104" type="h" number="879" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide grants for projects that demonstrate technologies and methods for reducing discharges from combined sewer overflows into navigable waters of interstate significance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400301"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1995-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. Opportunities, and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental engineering"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to make grants to State, interstate, regional, and local entities for projects that demonstrate innovative and cost-effective technologies and methods for reducing discharges from combined sewer overflows into navigable waters of interstate significance. Requires the Administrator, in awarding such grants, to give priority consideration to projects that provide for the transfer of technologies to other areas of the United States. Sets the maximum Federal share of project costs at: (1) 100 percent of the cost of a feasibility study; (2) 80 percent of the cost of engineering and design; and (3) 80 percent of the cost of construction. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
