<bill session="105" type="h" number="2446" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disaster Streamlining and Costs Reduction Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to reduce the costs of disaster relief and emergency assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1997-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1997-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1997-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-09-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1726"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-01-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-01-28">
      <text>See H.R.3869.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3869"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Beaches"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marinas"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Prefabricated buildings"/>
    <term name="Property insurance"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports facilities"/>
    <term name="Stadiums"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/1997--Introduced.
Disaster Streamlining and Costs Reduction Act of 1997 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to: (1) establish a predisaster mitigation program to assist State and local governments to reduce injuries, loss of life, and damage or destruction of property from disasters; (2) use incentives and other mitigation measures to reduce the cost of disasters to Federal, State, and local governments, particularly damages to public facilities, and to the private sector; and (3) make predisaster mitigation grants to States and local governments and eligible private nonprofit organizations of not less than 75 percent of the cost of hazard mitigation measures. Requires the Director to: (1) establish grant standards, incentives, and criteria; and (2) establish a National Predisaster Mitigation Fund. Authorizes appropriations to the Fund. Directs the President to establish management cost rates for grant recipients. Authorizes the President to provide incentives for Federal shares of assistance for mitigation measures for applicants that have implemented the standards, incentives, and criteria established by the Director. Authorizes the President to make grants not to exceed 75 (currently 50) percent of the cost of improving, maintaining, and updating State disaster assistance plans. Amends provisions of the Act relating to the repair, restoration, and replacement of damaged facilities to: (1) require a facility owner or operator to have first applied for a Small Business Administration disaster loan before being eligible for contributions for the repair or replacement of a facility damaged or destroyed by a major disaster; (2) revise the cost-sharing authority for such assistance to authorize the President to provide up to 90 percent of repair or restoration costs for States and local governments that have implemented hazard mitigation measures in advance of major disasters and to reduce such assistance for entities unable or unwilling to take such steps; and (3) allow States, local governments, and owners of private nonprofit facilities to receive in-lieu contributions for repairing, restoring, or expanding other eligible facilities. Authorizes the President to provide financial assistance and direct services to disaster victims who have necessary expenses and serious needs, with a limit of $25,000 per individual or household. Allows such assistance to be used for: (1) housing needs, including new housing construction; or (2) medical, dental, and funeral expenses, personal property needs, and transportation expenses. Repeals provisions of the Act which: (1) authorize the President to make community disaster loans following a major disaster; and (2) provide simplified procedures for the provision of disaster assistance when the Federal estimate of repair, restoration, or replacement costs is less than $35,000.</summary>
</bill>
