<bill session="106" type="h" number="97" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Personal Privacy Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide protection from personal intrusion for commercial purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1999-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E8"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Press"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Stalking"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
Personal Privacy Protection Act - Amends the Federal criminal code to provide that whoever, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce and for commercial purposes, persistently follows or chases a person in a manner that causes that person to have a reasonable fear of bodily injury, in order to capture by a visual or auditory recording instrument any type of visual image, sound recording, or other physical impression of that person, shall: (1) if death or serious bodily injury results, be fined, imprisoned, or both; and (2) be liable in a civil action for appropriate relief.Provides for civil liability of anyone who, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce and for commercial purposes, engages in a tortious invasion of the privacy of another person in order to capture by a visual or auditory recording instrument any type of visual image, sound recording, or other physical impression of that person.Specifies that: (1) it shall not be a defense to a prosecution or civil action that no image or recording was captured or sold; and (2) only a person physically present at the time of, and engaging or assisting another in engaging in, a violation is subject to criminal charge or civil liability under this Act.Makes this Act's prohibitions inapplicable to official law enforcement activities.</summary>
</bill>
