<bill session="107" type="h" number="5575" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles 10 and 18, United States Code, and the Revised Statutes to remove the uncertainty regarding the authority of the Department of Defense to permit buildings located on military installations and reserve component facilities to be used as polling places in Federal, State, and local elections for public office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400222"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="2002-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2002-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2002-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2002-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400501" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400375" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="2002-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-08">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2002--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of a military department to make a building located on a military installation available for use as a polling place in any Federal, State, or local election for public office provided such use is limited to eligible voters who reside on that installation. Requires such building to continue to be made available for such use unless the Secretary notifies the appropriate State or local election officials of the reasons for discontinuing such availability. Authorizes a State to make a facility of the reserves available for such purpose, with the same continuation or notification requirement.Amends the Revised Statutes to deem the use of military installations or reserve facilities for polling purposes to be consistent with Federal voting rights law.</summary>
</bill>
