<bill session="108" type="h" number="4475" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Endangered Species Recovery Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to focus conservation efforts under that Act on the 109 species most in danger of extinction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2004-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-09">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax incentives"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/1/2004--Introduced.
Endangered Species Recovery Act of 2004 - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to redefine "endangered species" as any species in danger of extinction throughout all of its global range, subject to existing exceptions. Requires the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to identify from among endangered or threatened species the 109 species in greatest danger of extinction and to publish a list of such species (in lieu of listing all endangered or threatened species). Limits the Secretary of Commerce's requested listings to the 109 species. Prohibits the Secretary from listing species absent approval by majority vote of a panel comprised of the Secretary, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Secretary of Defense. Limits the listing period to five years. Eliminates the requirement that the Secretary identify endangered and threatened species "solely" on the basis of the best scientific and commercial data available. Requires prior notification to landowners if a species to be listed occurs on private land. Limits prohibitions regarding endangered species to the 109 species identified under this Act. Requires the Secretary to complete review of habitat conservation plans seeking permission for otherwise prohibited takings within 180 days. Requires the Secretary to: (1) implement a species conservation reserve program under which eligible land is enrolled through the use of contracts to assist owners and operators in conserving endangered species; (2 bear the cost of conservation measures set forth in such contracts; and (3) pay rent to compensate for the loss in agricultural value of subject property.</summary>
</bill>
