<bill session="107" type="h" number="3400" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-12-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Networking and Information Technology Research Advancement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Networking and Information Technology Research Advancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the High-Performance Computing Act of 1991 to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2003 through 2007 for the coordinated Federal program on networking and information technology research and development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2001-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2001-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2001-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2001-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8847"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-12-06">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-01-29T14:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Weldon (FL) asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Science, Space and Technology have until midnight on Jan. 31 to file a report on H.R. 3400. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18T12:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 107-511.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-06-18T12:34:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="306">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 306.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer simulation"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee stock options"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in science"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Meteorological research"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Pollution"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space exploration"/>
    <term name="Supercomputers"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
    <term name="Weights and measures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2002--Reported to House amended.
Networking and Information Technology Research Advancement Act - Amends the High-Performance Computing Act of 1991 to rename the National High-Performance Computing Program the Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Program, expanding its focus beyond Federal high-performance computing research and coordination to include all Federal networking and information technology activities.(Sec. 4) Requires such program to address the issues of network information systems security as well as more general research goals, including network stability and the social and economic consequences of such technology.Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy's annual report to include a detailed description of the Program Component Areas, including changes and activities contributing to network security improvement.Expands the role of the advisory commission to include program evaluation.Repeals provisions concerning the National Research and Education Network and the Next Generation Internet Program.(Sec. 5) Revises research activities of the National Science Foundation (NSF), the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Departments of Energy and Commerce (including the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration), and the Environmental Protection Agency to incorporate networking and information technology. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2003 through 2007.(Sec. 6) Requires the Director of the NSF to: (1) arrange for an assessment of the state of research on networking and information technology in the United States; and (2) continually collect and arrange for the analysis of data on the information technology workforce, including size, occupation category, education, training, compensation, and the role of foreign workers. Requires the results of the assessment and data analysis to be reported to Congress as specified.(Sec. 7) Directs the NSF to establish a center for research on information technology questions related to crisis management as part of the National High-Performance Computing Program. Authorizes the use of funds for human-computer interface technologies, network-based collaboration tools, network compatibility and reliability, wireless networks, and software and simulation.Authorizes appropriations for FY 2003 through 2007.</summary>
</bill>
