<bill session="106" type="h" number="2753" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Abandoned Mine Restoration Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Army to carry out a program for the restoration of abandoned mine sites.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400265" joined="2000-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Acid mine drainage"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Mine wastes"/>
    <term name="Mine water"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution of water"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
Abandoned Mine Restoration Act of 1999 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to carry out a program, managed by the head of the Sacramento District Office of the Corps of Engineers, to assist stewards of lands owned by the United States and non-Federal entities to address environmental and water quality problems caused by drainage and related activities from abandoned, inactive, and post-production noncoal mines.Permits the Secretary to provide technical, planning, design, restoration, remediation, and construction assistance to Federal and non-Federal entities for carrying out projects to address such environmental and water quality problems, but only if the Secretary determines that such a project will improve environmental quality, is in the public interest, and is cost-effective.Requires that the Federal share of the cost of a project to be 100 percent for projects carried out on Federal land and 65 percent for other projects. Sets forth provisions governing Federal cost share credits and reimbursements to non-Federal entities for project resources, services, and work.Requires that the non-Federal share of operation and maintenance costs for a project to be 100 percent, except that in the case of a project undertaken on Federal lands, the Federal agency with management responsibility for the lands shall be responsible for all operation and maintenance costs.Prohibits more than $10 million from being allotted for projects in a single locality, but permits the Secretary to accept funds voluntarily contributed by the non-Federal or Federal entity for expanding the scope of services requested.Prohibits the Secretary or any State or political subdivision which implements any remedial action which is consistent with a State and Environmental Protection Agency approved remediation plan at an abandoned mine site and adjacent lands to provide water quality protection from being treated, based on actions taken consistent with the plan, as being: (1) the site owner or operator or the arranger or transporter for disposal; (2) responsible for any discharge or release of pollutants, contaminants, or hazardous substances on or from the abandoned mine site or adjacent lands; or (3) subject to any enforcement action pursuant to Federal law, except for violations involving gross negligence.Authorizes the Secretary to provide assistance to the Western Universities Mine-Land Reclamation and Restoration Consortium for carrying out the purposes of the program.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
