<bill session="106" type="h" number="2704" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Farmer Owned Reserve Restoration Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Agricultural Act of 1949 to restore and improve the farmer owned reserve program, to extend the term of marketing assistance loans made under the Agricultural Market Transition Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400599"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities, Resource Conservation and Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG23" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Resource Conservation and Credit" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Feed grain program"/>
    <term name="Feed grains"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Grain storage"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Oilseeds"/>
    <term name="Rice"/>
    <term name="Soybeans"/>
    <term name="Wheat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Farmer Owner Reserve Program Title II: Other Provisions Farmer Owned Reserve Restoration Act of 1999 - Title I: Farmer Owner Reserve Program - Amends the Agricultural Market Transition Act to restore the wheat and feed grain (and oilseeds) farmer owned reserve program. (Eliminates the provision suspending the program for such producers through crop or calendar year 2002.) (Sec. 102) Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 with respect to the program to: (1) include oilseeds; (2) revise extended price support loan interest charge provisions; (3) permit advance storage payments and revise storage loan termination provisions; (4) reduce maximum wheat and feed grain amounts and establish oilseed amounts; and (5) set forth prices (compared to loan rates) at which, and conditions under which, a producer may withdraw stored commodities. Title II: Other Provisions - Amends the Agricultural Market Transition Act to increase the term of marketing assistance loans. (Sec. 202) Directs the Commodity Credit Corporation to make loans for construction or remodeling of storage facilities for: (1) dry or high moisture grain, soybeans, and rice; and (2) high moisture forage and silage.</summary>
</bill>
