<bill session="108" type="hr" number="258" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-05T15:26:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-05T15:26:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (S. 222) to approve the settlement of the water rights claims of the Zuni Indian Tribe in Apache County, Arizona, and for other purposes, and for consideration of the bill (S. 273) to provide for the expeditious completion of the acquisition of land owned by the State of Wyoming within the boundaries of Grand Teton National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T21:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 108-140, by Mr. Hastings (WA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T21:25:00-04:00">
      <text>S. 222 shall be debatable 40 minutes equally divided between the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Resources. Waives all points of order against consideration of S.222. Provides one motion to recommit, with or without instructions, for S. 222. The rule further provides that S. 273 shall be debatable for 40 minutes equally divided between the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Resources. Waives all points of order against consideration of S. 273. Finally, the rule provides one motion to recommit,</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-06-04T21:26:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="57">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 57.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5012-5022" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T13:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 258.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 194 (Roll no. 244).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2003-06-05T15:26:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="245" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 229 - 175 (Roll no. 245).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5012" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="222"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="s" number="222"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="s" number="273"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2003--Passed House without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced on June 4, 2003. The summary of that version is repeated here.)Sets forth the rule for the consideration of S. 222 (Zuni Indian Tribe water rights settlement) and S.273 (Grand Teton National Park Land acquisition).</summary>
</bill>
