<bill session="104" type="h" number="3293" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Drinking Water Estrogenic Substances Screening Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XIV of the Public Health Service Act (commonly known as the Safe Drinking Water Act) to establish a screening program for estrogenic substances.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1996-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1996-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1996-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1996-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1996-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1996-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1996-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1996-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1996-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1996-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1996-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1996-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental estrogens"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estrogen"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Pesticide pollution"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/1996--Introduced.
Safe Drinking Water Estrogenic Substances Screening Program Act - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to develop and, under specified conditions, implement a screening program, using appropriate validated test systems, to determine whether certain substances (including all active and inert ingredients used in registered pesticides) may have an effect in humans that is similar to an effect produced by a naturally occurring estrogen, or such other endocrine effect as the Administrator may designate. Allows the Administrator to exempt a biologic or other substance if the Administrator determines that the substance does not have any effect in humans similar to an effect produced by a naturally occurring estrogen. Requires the Administrator to order a manufacturer of a substance for which such testing is required to conduct such testing and submit results within a certain time period. Provides for suspension of the sale or distribution of the substance if the manufacturer fails to submit required information. Requires the Administrator to: (1) take such action as is necessary to ensure the protection of public health in the case of any substance that is found to have a potential adverse effect on humans; and (2) report findings and recommendations to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
