<bill session="106" type="hr" number="309" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding strategies to better protect millions of Americans with food allergies from potentially fatal allergic reactions, and to further assure the safety of manufactured food from inadvertent allergen contamination.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2000-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="2000-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1999-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1979"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9238-9239"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer organizations"/>
    <term name="Dairy products"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Food additives"/>
    <term name="Food allergies"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Peanuts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1999--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) major commercial food processors and producers should resolve to produce products containing key life-threatening allergens on separate, dedicated manufacturing lines; (2) labeled ingredient listings should specify their allergenic ingredients clearly by name if those ingredients are key allergens; (3) allergens should be identified in terms understandable to average citizens; (4) foods which are common, life-threatening allergens should not be added gratuitously to products where their contribution to taste is negligible and where their presence would not reasonably be expected; (5) industry, consumer, and scientific groups should voluntarily work together for the purpose of better educating food industry workers and the public on the issues of food allergy safety; and (6) an assessment of the impact and success of these initiatives should be made not later than one year after the date of adoption of this resolution and reported to the resolution's sponsors.</summary>
</bill>
