<bill session="107" type="h" number="5109" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-24T15:31:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-09-24T15:31:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Energy to convey a parcel of land at the facility of the Southwestern Power Administration in Tupelo, Oklahoma.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400540"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-673.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-09-24T12:03:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="415">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 415.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6493-6494" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5109.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-09-24T15:31:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6493" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Power marketing administrations"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Telegraph"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2002--Passed House amended.
Directs the Secretary of Energy to convey to Rural Enterprises of Oklahoma, Incorporated, (Rural Enterprises), all right, title, and interest of the United States to specified land, consisting of approximately 6.3 acres of the facility of the Southwestern Power Administration in Tupelo, Oklahoma, for use in economic development within the service area of the Tri-County Indian Nations Community Development Corporation.States that exact acreage and description of the parcel to be conveyed shall be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Secretary and to Rural Enterprises..Sets forth conditions of the conveyance that require Rural Enterprises to agree to: (1) honor the terms of any lease of the parcel in existence on the date of the conveyance; and (2) bear the costs of the conveyance and attendant survey.Retains a Federal easement to the parcel, including telephone and telegraph rights, in order to maintain a sewage connection to the electrical substation and lagoon facility located adjacent to the parcel.Authorizes the Southwestern Power Administration to remove the undepreciated value of the conveyed facilities from its repayable investment obligation.States that the fair market value of the land to be conveyed shall be determined by an appraisal acceptable to the Secretary that is conducted by an appraiser agreed upon by the Secretary and Rural Enterprises.</summary>
</bill>
