<bill session="104" type="h" number="3365" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Black Canyon National Park Complex Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To redesignate the Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Monument as a national park, to establish the Gunnison Gorge National Conservation Area, to establish the Curecanti National Recreation Area, to establish the Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Park Complex, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400265"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="1424"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="All terrain vehicles"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trapping"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/1996--Introduced.
Black Canyon National Park Complex Act of 1996 - Establishes the Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Park in Colorado. Abolishes the Black Canyon National Monument and incorporates all lands and interests therein as part of the Park. Establishes in Colorado: (1) the Gunnison Gorge National Conservation Area (conservation area); (2) the Curecanti National Recreation Area (recreation area); (3) the Denver and Rio Grande National Historic Site (consisting of the Denver and Rio Grande rolling stock and train trestle at Cimarron) and the Curecanti Archeological District located within the recreation area; and (4) the Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Park Complex (consisting of the Park, the conservation area, the recreation area, and portions of the Gunnison National Forest). Requires the Secretary of the Interior to transmit to specified congressional committees: (1) a comprehensive plan for the long-range protection and management of the conservation area; and (2) a comprehensive list of authorizing documents issued by the Bureau of Reclamation, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Forest Service for the use of lands within the recreation area. Directs the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior, with respect to areas within their jurisdictions, to: (1) provide for appropriate general recreation and multiple use activities, including swimming, fishing, boating, rafting, hiking, horseback riding, camping, and picnicking and, subject to valid existing rights, grazing and hay harvesting and the maintenance of roads, stock driveways, and utility rights-of-way; (2) permit limited off-road vehicle use within the recreation area; and (3) permit hunting, fishing, noncommercial taking of fresh-water crustaceans, and trapping (except that hunting and trapping are prohibited within the Park and in such zones and periods as the Secretaries may designate). Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
