<bill session="107" type="h" number="1070" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-11-27">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-11-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Great Lakes Legacy Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Great Lakes Legacy Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Great Lakes Legacy Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Great Lakes and Lake Champlain Program Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Daniel Patrick Moynihan Lake Champlain Basin Program Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Great Lakes Legacy Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Great Lakes and Lake Champlain Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Daniel Patrick Moynihan Lake Champlain Basin Program Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Great Lakes Legacy Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Great Lakes and Lake Champlain Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Daniel Patrick Moynihan Lake Champlain Basin Program Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Great Lakes Legacy Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to make grants for remediation of sediment contamination in areas of concern and to authorize assistance for research and development of innovative technologies for such purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out projects and conduct research for remediation of sediment contamination in areas of concern in the Great Lakes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An Act to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide assistance for remediation of sediment contamination in areas of concern, to authorize assistance for research and development of innovative technologies for such remediation, and to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act and the Water Resources Development Act of 2000 to modify provisions relating to the Lake Champlain basin, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400119"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="2001-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="2001-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2001-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2002-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2001-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2001-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2001-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="2001-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2001-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2001-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2001-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2001-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2001-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2001-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2001-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2001-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2001-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="2001-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2001-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2001-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="2002-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Technology, and Standards.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-25">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-06-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18T14:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 107-587, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Science Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 18, 2002.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Science discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-07-18T14:35:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="351">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 351.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T14:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Duncan moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T14:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6009-6012" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T14:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1070.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-09-04T15:11:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6009" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-09-26">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-10-15">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Jeffords with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 107-312.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-10-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="704">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 704.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-10-17">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10739-10742" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10740" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2002-10-17" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10740-19742" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-21">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-12T14:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Duncan moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-12T14:55:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1070.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2002-11-12T15:21:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8079-8083" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8079-8080" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-11-12T15:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2002-11-12">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2002-11-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2002-11-27">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2002-11-27" type="public" number="107-303">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 107-303.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Environment, Technology, and Standards" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="2544"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Brownfields"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Dredging spoil"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sedimentation"/>
    <term name="Soil remediation"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in rivers, lakes, etc."/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Weather"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4892"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/17/2002--Passed Senate amended.
Great Lakes and Lake Champlain Program Act of 2002 - Title I: Great Lakes - Great Lakes Legacy Act of 2002 - (Sec. 102) Amends Great Lakes management provisions of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to report to Congress within one year on actions and resources necessary to oversee the Remedial Action Plans and the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement.(Sec. 103) Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, acting through the Great Lakes National Program Office, to carry out projects in areas of concern that: (1) monitor or evaluate contaminated sediment; (2) implement a plan to remediate contaminated sediment; or (3) prevent further or renewed contamination of sediment.Grants priority to projects which will use an innovative approach or can be commenced within one year.Prohibits the Administrator from carrying out a remediation project if an evaluation of remedial alternatives (including a review of health effects) has not been conducted or if the Administrator determines that the area is likely to suffer significant further or renewed contamination from existing sources following the project's completion.Requires commitments of continued financial support from non-Federal sponsors as a condition for implementing remediation projects. Requires the Administrator to coordinate efforts with the Secretary of the Army and the Governors of the affected States.Authorizes the Administrator to carry out a public information program.(Sec. 104) States that nothing in the Great Lakes management provisions shall be construed to affect any other Federal or State authority that is being used or may be used to facilitate Great Lakes cleanup and protection.(Sec. 105) Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 through 2008.(Sec. 106) Authorizes the Administrator to conduct research on innovative technologies and techniques.Title II: Lake Champlain - Daniel Patrick Moynihan Lake Champlain Basin Program Act of 2002 - (Sec. 202) Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to establish the Lake Champlain Basin Program, incorporating, in part, the Lake Champlain Management Conference.Authorizes the Administrator to provide support to Vermont, New York State, and the New England Interstate Water Pollution Control Commission for the implementation of the program and to coordinate actions with other appropriate Federal agencies.Requires that the plan be reviewed at least every five years.Authorizes the Administrator to make grants in consultation with participants in the program (rather than the Management Conference).Includes Hamilton and Bennington Counties in the Lake Champlain watershed.States that existing authorities remain unaffected by this program.Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 through 2008.Title III: Miscellaneous - (Sec. 301) Permits a State to use FY 2003 nonpoint source management program funds (section 319 funds) for phase II of the stormwater program established by the rule "National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System Regulations for Revision of the Water Pollution Control Program Addressing Storm Water Discharges."(Sec. 302) Excludes specified reporting requirements under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act from certain requirements of the Federal Reports Elimination and Sunset Act of 1995 and the Federal Reports Elimination Act of 1998.(Sec. 303) Repeals development of a National Health Museum.(Sec. 304) Amends the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century to eliminate the reconstruction of the 79th Street Traffic Circle, New York City, and to include the Cross Harbor Freight Movement Project EIS, New York City.(Sec. 305) Directs the Administrator to make at least one grant to a regional nonprofit community redevelopment organization for the establishment and operation of a center for Brownfields Excellence. Requires that such center include the transfer of technology and expertise in the redevelopment of abandoned or underutilized property that may have environmental contamination. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 306) Amends the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century to include Louisiana Highway 1026 rather than Louisiana Highway 16.</summary>
</bill>
