<bill session="108" type="h" number="1058" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for an exchange of certain private property in Colorado and certain Federal property in Utah.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400116"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2003--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of the Interior to convey specified Federal land in Utah to the owners of specified land in Colorado if the owners of the Colorado land convey their land to the United States. Directs that if the values of the lands to be exchanged are not equal, they shall be equalized either through a payment of money or, upon agreement, by a decrease in the amount of land conveyed. Prescribes that the values of the lands being exchanged shall be determined by a mutually agreed upon appraiser or appraisers following standards set forth in Federal appraisal standards publications, with the cost of such appraisals to be equally shared between the parties.Requires that as a condition of the conveyance, the recipients of the Utah land must obtain a conservation easement to protect the land's cultural and natural resources.</summary>
</bill>
