<bill session="105" type="h" number="3751" updated="2012-11-01T22:49:10-05:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family and Medical Leave Clarification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="1998-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="1998-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1998-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1998-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400603" joined="1998-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1998-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E710-711)</text>
      <reference ref="CR E710-711"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Government Reform and Oversight, and House Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO04" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Human Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Diseases"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family leave"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Sick leave"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>04/29/1998--Introduced.
Family and Medical Leave Clarification Act - Amends the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (FMLA) to provide that the term serious health condition does not cover short-term conditions for which treatment and recovery are very brief. Lists examples of conditions which are covered by such term. (Sec. 3) Voids specified regulations and opinion letters of the Secretary of Labor under FMLA on the effective date of new final regulations. Directs the Secretary to revise such regulations and issue new proposed and final regulations by certain deadlines. (Sec. 4) Revises requirements for FMLA leave taken intermittently or on a reduced leave scheduleor. Requires certification by the health care provider of the medical necessity of such leave. Authorizes employers to require: (1) an employee to take intermittent leave in increments of up to one-half of a work day; and (2) employees who travel as part of their normal day-to-day work or duty assignments to take leave for the duration of that work or assignment if the employer cannot reasonably accommodate the employee's request to take leave intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule. (Sec. 5) Authorizes an employer who does not exercise the right to substitute other employer-provided leave for FMLA leave to require an employee to request such leave in a timely manner. (Sec. 6) Authorizes an employer to require the employee to choose between FMLA unpaid leave and employer-provided paid absence. (Sec. 7) Requires documentation by objective medical findings of the appropriate medical facts for purposes of certification of a request for leave under FMLA.</summary>
</bill>
