<bill session="105" type="h" number="3669" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Upper Colorado River and San Juan River Endangered Fish Recovery Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide funding for the implementation of the endangered fish recovery implementation programs for the Upper Colorado and San Juan River Basins.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400265"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Endangered animals"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/1998--Introduced.
Upper Colorado River and San Juan River Endangered Fish Recovery Act of 1998 - Limits to $100 million the costs of capital projects undertaken for the Upper Colorado and San Juan River recovery implementation programs (as agreed to in 1988). Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to undertake capital projects under this Act. Terminates in 2005 and 2007, respectively, the authority of the Secretary to request appropriations to implement such projects for the recovery programs in the Upper Colorado and San Juan River basins. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into agreements for non-federal contributions to project costs; and (2) utilize for such projects power revenues collected pursuant to the Colorado River Storage Project Act. Limits such contributions with respect to each recovery program. Requires the Secretary to report to specified committees and subcommittees on the utilization of such power revenues. Authorizes the retention of appropriated but unexpended project funds for use in future fiscal years. States that nothing in this Act shall restrict the Secretary from funding activities or capital items in accordance with the Federal Government's Indian trust responsibility.</summary>
</bill>
