<bill session="108" type="h" number="3391" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Provo River Project Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Provo River Project Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain lands and facilities of the Provo River Project.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2003-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2003-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-719.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-10-04T12:21:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="442">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 442.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gibbons moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7965-7967" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3391.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-10-04T14:50:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7966-7967" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2004-10-10" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11183" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2004-10-10">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2004-10-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-10-19">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-10-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2004-10-30" type="public" number="108-382">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-382.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1876"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="1876"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2004--Public Law.
Provo River Project Transfer Act - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Provo River Water Users Association (Association) all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Provo Reservoir Canal in the State of Utah. Conditions such conveyance upon the execution by the Secretary of the Agreement entitled "Agreement Among the United States, the Provo River Waters Users Association, and the Metropolitan Water District of Salt Lake &amp; Sandy to Transfer Title to Certain Lands and Facilities of the Provo River Project (Agreement)," and upon the Secretary's acceptance of future arrangements governing the operation, ownership, financing, and improvement of the Provo Reservoir Canal. Directs the Secretary to convey to the Association all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Pleasant Grove Property in the State of Utah. Directs the Secretary to: (1) convey to the Metropolitan Water District of Salt Lake &amp; Sandy (District) in the State of Utah, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to Salt Lake Aqueduct; (2) grant permanent easements to the District for the use, operation, maintenance, repair, improvement, or replacement of the Salt Lake Aqueduct by the District; (3) determine the boundaries of such easements; and (4) transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain land of the Aqueduct Division of the Provo River Project to the Secretary of Agriculture. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to administer such land as an administrative site subject to provisions of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976. Prohibits the United States from carrying out any activities on the lands covered by the Salt Lake Aqueduct easements that would materially interfere with the operation, maintenance, repair, improvement, or replacement of the Salt Lake Aqueduct by the District. Sets forth a formula for for payments by the Association and the District for the land conveyances under this Act. Requires the Association and the District to pay certain additional costs relating to the land conveyances. Requires the Secretary to comply with certain environmental and other laws prior to making land conveyances under this Act. (Sec. 4) Confirms that: (1) certain existing contracts covering lands of the Provo River Project not conveyed by this Act remain in effect; and (2) entities with existing contractual capacity rights to either the Provo Reservoir Canal or Salt Lake Aqueduct may transport Central Utah Project water. Authorizes the Agreement to provide for modifications to repayment contracts for the Deer Creek and Aqueduct Divisions of the Provo River Project. Provides that nothing in this Act impairs any existing contract (including subscription contracts) regarding the conveyance of water through the Provo Reservoir Canal. (Sec. 5) Provides that: (1) lands and facilities conveyed under this Act are no longer part of a Federal reclamation project; (2) the Association and the District are no longer entitled to reclamation benefits for conveyed lands, except for benefits available to other nonreclamation facilities; and (3) the United States shall not be liable for damages for acts, omissions, or occurrences relating to conveyances under this Act, except for negligent acts committed prior to the date of conveyance. (Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the status of any land conveyances not completed within 18 months after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
