<bill session="105" type="h" number="2469" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Food and Nutrition Information Reform Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Food and Nutrition Information Reform Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and other statutes to provide for improvements in the regulation of food ingredients, nutrient content claims, and health claims, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400431"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1997-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1997-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400169" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1997-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="1997-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1997-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-09-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 43 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T21:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Commerce. H. Rept. 105-306.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-10-06T21:10:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="177">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 177.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Cadmium"/>
    <term name="Ceramics"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diet"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Food additives"/>
    <term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food irradiation"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Glass and glass industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Margarine"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1997--Reported to House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Improving the Regulation and Labeling of Food Title II: Effective Date Food and Nutrition Information Reform Act of 1997 - Title I: Improving the Regulation and Labeling of Food - Amends Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act provisions relating to food nutrition levels and health-related claims to allow certain regulations to be effective on publication at the discretion of the Secretary of Health and Human Services. (Sec. 102) Modifies requirements regarding petitions to issue a regulation on health-related claims. (Sec. 103) Allows a health or nutrient content claim not authorized by the Secretary if: (1) a U.S. governmental scientific body with public health protection or research responsibility directly relating to human nutrition or the National Academy of Sciences has published an authoritative statement, currently in effect, about the relationship to which the health claim refers or that identifies the nutrient level to which the nutrient claim refers; (2) a person has notified the Secretary; (3) the claim and food are in compliance with certain requirements; and (4) the claim is stated in a way that it is an accurate representation of the authoritative statement and in a way that it enables the public to understand the information and its significance. (Sec. 105) Requires, if a nutrient claim is made and the food contains a nutrient at a level that increases to persons in the general population the risk of a disease or health-related condition that is diet-related, that the label contain, close to the claim, a statement referring to the nutrition information elsewhere on the label. (Sec. 107) Mandates a: (1) final determination on any pending petition that would permit red meat irradiation; and (2) report to specified congressional committees regarding the process followed in reviewing that petition. (Sec. 108) Prohibits: (1) implementation of any requirement banning, as an unapproved food additive, lead and cadmium based paints in the lip and rim area of glass and ceramic ware before one year after the requirement is published; and (2) banning such paints on glass and ceramic ware meeting specified criteria. (Sec. 109) Deems a food contact substance (a substance used as a component of materials used in manufacturing, packing, packaging, transporting, or holding food, but not intended to have any technical effect in the food) unsafe and the food adulterated unless: (1) there is (and the substance is in conformity with) a regulation prescribing the conditions under which the substance may be safely used; or (2) the manufacturer or supplier has notified the Secretary of the identity and intended use of the substance and the manufacturer's or supplier's determination that the substance is safe under a specified standard. (Sec. 110) Revises oleomargarine sale and labeling requirements. Repeals provisions relating to: (1) a congressional declaration of policy regarding oleomargarine sales; and (2) noncontravention of State oleomargarine laws. Title II: Effective Date - Makes this Act and its amendments effective on enactment.</summary>
</bill>
