<bill session="106" type="h" number="4491" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2001 and 2002 for the National Science Foundation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400382"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Black scientists"/>
    <term name="Brain research"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Learning"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in government"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Plant breeding"/>
    <term name="Plant genetics"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science and ethics"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Supercomputers"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women engineers"/>
    <term name="Women in government"/>
    <term name="Women scientists"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2000--Introduced.
National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2000 - Authorizes appropriations to the National Science Foundation (NSF) for FY 2001 and 2002, with specific allocations for Research and Related Activities, Education and Human Resources, Major Research Equipment, Salaries and Expenses, and the Office of Inspector General. Prohibits any such funds from being used: (1) for travel expenses, except as provided; and (2) to employ more than 75 full-time equivalent positions in the Office of the Director for either FY 2001 or 2002.(Sec. 3) Authorizes NSF to make grants for the establishment of regional plant genome and gene expression research and development centers to: (1) develop capabilities in basic plant genome research; (2) extend basic plant genomics research through plant breeding programs and accelerate its application to crop improvement; and (3) serve as centers for scientific and safety information on plant genomics. Prohibits NSF from providing funds for more than half of the cost of establishing any such research and development center.((Sec. 4) Directs NSF to make grant awards to support research on learning, focusing on: (1) brain research as a foundation for research on human learning; (2) behavioral, cognitive, affective, and social aspects of learning; (3) science, mathematics, engineering, and technological learning in formal and informal educational settings; and (4) learning in complex educational systems. Specifies the goals of such research to be to integrate scientific disciplines into research on learning, to gain a better understanding of how research and educational practice can be reconciled, and to test, evaluate, and refine hypotheses across disciplines.Requires NSF to make grants for the establishment of centers of research on learning to bring together multidisciplinary teams of researchers to support such research goals.Authorizes NSF to participate in the Interagency Education Research Initiative.Directs NSF to sponsor a conference on human learning and education research to bring together researchers from many disciplines, including the physical sciences, neurological sciences, social sciences, and education practitioners to review past research on learning, assess current research efforts, and develop recommendations to address outstanding research issues and to disseminate research results to such practitioners.(Sec. 5) Prohibits NSF from entering into an arrangement under the Intergovernmental Personnel Act of 1970 for the detail of any of its employees to locations other than NSF facilities.(Sec. 6) Requires the Director of NSF to establish a program providing for: (1) an external review and appropriate revision of NSF ethics rules and procedures; and (2) training of all NSF employees on revised rules and procedures. Requires the Director to report to specified congressional committees at least once every six months on: (1) the number of NSF employees trained; and (2) the number and type of ethics violations determined to have occurred, along with a description of their resolution.(Sec. 8) Prohibits the application of the Federal Reports Elimination and Sunset Act of 1995 with respect to specified NSF reports.</summary>
</bill>
