<bill session="105" type="h" number="2573" updated="2012-11-01T22:48:39-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Election Reform in Campaigns Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require that a majority of the funds raised by a candidate for election to the Senate or the House of Representatives come from individuals residing in the State the candidate seeks to represent, to require labor organizations to provide their members with information on the use of member dues for political purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400173"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor union finances"/>
    <term name="Labor union membership"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Union dues"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>09/29/1997--Introduced.
Election Reform in Campaigns Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to prohibit House candidates from accepting contributions in an election cycle from persons in excess of the total of contributions accepted from individuals who reside in the State involved. (Sec. 3) Modifies the term "contribution or expenditure" (as defined for the purposes of FECA and the Public Utility Holding Company Act) to include contributions and expenditures made to political committees by national banks, corporations, and labor organizations. Prohibits applying current FECA requirements regarding certain permissible political activities by national banks, corporations, and labor organizations to labor organizations unless specified conditions are met. Sets a limitation on communications made by labor organizations to their members and families. (Sec. 4) Eliminates thresholds for the reporting of identification information of certain persons. (Sec. 5) Equalizes the separate individual multicandidate political committees limits on contributions to candidates. (Sec. 6) Indexes the amount of the limitation on aggregate annual annual individual contributions. (Sec. 7) Revises requirements relating to the administrative duties of the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to require the FEC to post FECA reports on the Internet within 48 hours of receipt by the FEC.</summary>
</bill>
