<bill session="104" type="h" number="2067" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate improved management of National Park Service Lands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-07-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1469"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held. Hearings Printed: H. Hrg. 104-42.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.4236.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="4236"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Tourist trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Minor Boundary Revisions Title II: Authorization for Certain Park Facilities to be Located Outside of Units of the National Park System Title I: Minor Boundary Revisions - Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to allow the Secretary of the Interior to modify national park borders only if: (1) the total acreage of lands to be added and deleted will not exceed five percent of the total Federal acreage authorized in the area; (2) the acquisition will not significantly affect the quality of the human environment; (3) the value of the lands added and deleted will not exceed $500,000; (4) the proposed revision is not part of a more comprehensive modification proposal; and (5) the Director of the National Park Service obtains written support for the boundary modifications from all affected property owners. Provides that minor boundary revisions which only delete acreage from the national parks system may only be authorized by an Act of Congress. Title II: Authorization for Certain Park Facilities to be Located Outside of Units of the National Park System - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to establish essential facilities for park administration, visitor use, and park employee residential housing outside the boundaries, but within the vicinity, of national park system units. Allows the Secretary to lease or acquire land to develop essential facilities. Authorizes the Secretary to construct, operate, and maintain permanent and temporary buildings on land within the vicinity of the national park system after the Secretary has entered into a binding agreement with the owner of such land.</summary>
</bill>
