<bill session="104" type="h" number="3522" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Construction and Demolition Debris Disposal Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 23, United States Code, to ensure consideration of and planning for reuse or disposal of construction and demolition debris resulting from highway projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402763"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402762" joined="1996-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="1996-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1996-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="1996-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1996-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1996-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1996-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Highway planning"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/1996--Introduced.
Construction and Demolition Debris Disposal Act - Amends Federal highway provisions to direct the Secretary of Transportation to consider the method and location of disposal of construction and demolition debris resulting from a project, including its transportation, in promulgating guidelines concerning any proposed project on a Federal-aid system. Expresses congressional intent that any project for resurfacing, restoring, or rehabilitating a highway (other than a highway access to which is fully controlled) involving Federal funds shall include: (1) the reuse or recycling of debris to the extent possible; and (2) where not possible, a requirement that such debris be disposed of in existing municipal landfills or used for fill as permitted under State and local law. Requires any State highway department which submits plans for: (1) a Federal-aid highway project involving bypassing or going through any city, town, or village to certify to the Secretary that it has considered the economic, social, environmental, and other effects of the method and location of disposal of debris; (2) an Interstate System project to certify to the Secretary that it has had or afforded opportunities for public hearings for persons whose schools are in or contiguous to areas through which the highway will pass or into whose neighborhoods debris will be disposed (and requires such certification to be accompanied by a report which indicates the consideration given to the method and location of the disposal of debris). Directs that the hearings held regarding the effects of debris disposal include consideration of: (1) debris resulting from any previous construction that must be removed in order to carry out the project; (2) debris resulting from any renovation, rebuilding, or construction attributable to the project; and (3) other debris indirectly attributable to the project. Requires that: (1) contiguous property owners be personally notified of the public hearing if the location proposed for the disposal of debris is not in an existing municipal solid waste landfill; and (2) the statewide planning process consider the effects of debris disposal.</summary>
</bill>
