<bill session="106" type="h" number="1262" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that existing facilities located on the Pentwater River in Michigan, are not required to be licensed by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission under part 1 of the Federal Power Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400182"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/1999--Introduced.
Provides that it shall not be unlawful for the city of Hart, Michigan, to operate, repair, reconstruct, or modify any dam which, as of this Act's enactment date, is owned and operated by the city and located on the Pentwater River in Oceana County or any water conduit, reservoir, power house, and other works incidental to such dam. Provides that no Federal license for the regulation of development of water power and resources under part 1 of the Federal Power Act shall be required for such dam and project works. Grants permission for such facilities, subject to compliance with State laws, to the same extent as facilities are granted permission to construct dams or project works under provisions regarding projects not affecting navigable waters.</summary>
</bill>
