<bill session="104" type="h" number="3776" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prison Work and Victim Restitution Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Crime Control Act of 1990 with respect to the work requirement for Federal prisoners and to amend title 18, United States Code, with respect to the use of Federal prison labor by nonprofit entities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400549" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1996-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="404503" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="405258" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1996-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="406625" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="1996-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1996-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1246-1247"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric appliances"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Location of industries"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Plant shutdowns"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sex"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination against women"/>
    <term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/1996--Introduced.
Prison Work and Victim Restitution Act of 1996 - Amends the Crime Control Act of 1990 to require convicted inmates confined in Federal prisons, jails, and other detention facilities to engage in: (1) work for no fewer than 50 hours weekly; and (2) job-training and educational and life skills preparation study. Allows nonprofit entities to utilize the services of prisoners if opportunities otherwise provided by law for inmates to work are insufficient to meet such requirements. Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) make prisoners available to for-profit American entities either located in a foreign country or considering moving to a foreign country because of high domestic labor costs, subject to specified requirements; and (2) provide incentives to such entities, such as the use of space and facilities in Federal prisons at a free or reduced rate. Directs the Attorney General to make rules governing the provision of services by inmates to such nonprofit and for-profit entities. Establishes in the Treasury a Fund into which shall be placed all proceeds and wages from prison labor. Directs that such Fund be used: (1) to offset the costs of prisoner incarceration (one third); (2) for victim restitution (one third); (3) for payment into the individual prisoner's account to be paid upon his or her release (one tenth); and (4) for payments to States with prison work requirements that are substantially the same as Federal requirements for programs to benefit the dependents of prisoners. Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 and the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to exclude prisoners from the term "employee" for purposes of such Acts. Directs the Bureau of Prisons to ensure that Federal prisoners: (1) are subject to regular and random testing for drugs and illegal substances; (2) do not engage in specified activities, such as smoking, viewing pornographic materials, or sexual activity; and (3) do not possess microwave ovens, hot plates, toaster overs, televisions, or VCRs. Repeals the limitation on the number of non-Federal prison work pilot projects with respect to which penalties for transporting in interstate commerce or importing from any foreign country into the United States goods, wares, or merchandise manufactured, produced, or mined wholly or in part by convicts or prisoners are inapplicable.</summary>
</bill>
