<bill session="105" type="h" number="1533" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Initiative on Surface Transportation and the Environment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 23, United States Code, relating to environmental improvements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative fuels"/>
    <term name="Automobile fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Brownfields"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to cities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan politics and government"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Nonpoint source pollution"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Terminals (Transportation)"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban transportation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/1997--Introduced.
National Initiative on Surface Transportation and the Environment Act - Amends Federal highway provisions to expand eligibility for projects under the congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a system for ranking projects and programs that are likely to have long-term sustainable air quality benefits and for providing funding for projects and programs that are ranked the highest under such system. Authorizes appropriations. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the authorization of appropriations from the Highway Trust Fund for the National Highway System and the surface transportation program (STP) shall be reduced in the aggregate by $400 million for each of FY 1998 through 2003. (Sec. 3) Requires that participation in assessment and cleanup of brownfield sites relating to specified projects provide a substantive and demonstrable benefit to transportation on such system, including reduction of congestion, increased use of mass transit, and improved access to a transportation facility. Permits contributions toward such efforts to occur in advance of project construction only if such efforts are consistent with Federal requirements and State transportation planning processes. Increases the percentage of funds apportioned to a State for the STP that must be obligated to urbanized areas with population of over 200,000 and other areas of the State in proportion to their relative share of the State's population. Makes Federal transit block grants, discretionary grants and loans, and financial assistance for other than urban areas available for assessment and cleanup of brownfield sites relating to specified projects if such development will provide a substantive and demonstrable benefit to mass transportation. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to establish a wetlands restoration program under which the Secretary may make grants to States for projects to mitigate losses of wetlands that have occurred as a result of Federal-aid highway construction projects. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 5) Makes one percent of STP funds apportioned to a State for a fiscal year available for monitoring, mitigating, and cleaning up water pollution due to highway runoff. Directs the Secretary to carry out a program to assess the benefits of using porous paving materials for highways and parking lots as a method of mitigating such pollution. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to up to ten metropolitan planning organizations designated for implementing alternative transportation strategies to achieve reductions in motor vehicle emissions. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary, on or before December 31, 2003, to award a grant to each of the ten States that the Secretary determines have achieved the greatest per capita reduction in fuel consumption between October 1, 1997, and September 30, 2003. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
