<bill session="106" type="h" number="1859" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Postal Rate Transition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the United States Postal Service to submit certain reports to Congress before implementing the next rate increase for first-class postage, and to provide certain procedures regarding the use and sale of postage stamps during the initial period of such rate increase.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400058"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" subcommittee="Postal Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Postage stamps"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="United States Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/1999--Introduced.
Postal Rate Transition Act - Prohibits the U.S. Postal Service from requesting the first rate increase for first-class postage after enactment of this Act until reporting to Congress on: (1) the number of one-cent stamps printed to facilitate the first-class rate increase implemented as of January 10, 1999; (2) how the U.S. Postal Service determined how many of such one-cent stamps should be printed to facilitate such implementation; (3) the number of one-cent stamps that would have been printed during calendar year 1999 if such rate increase had not been implemented; and (4) the cost of printing them.Prohibits the U.S. Postal Service from implementing the first rate increase for first-class postage recommended by the Postal Rate Commission after enactment of this Act until reporting to Congress an estimate of the number of stamps at a compensatory price that need to be printed to facilitate the rate increase.Prohibits the U.S. Postal Service, with respect to the first increase in the first-class rate after enactment of this Act, during the 30 days following the first day of such increase, from: (1) failing to accept first-class mail weighing one ounce or less because a 33-cent stamp is used for such mail; or (2) selling any 33-cent stamps.Applies the same prohibition and requirements with respect to a postcard for which a 20-cent postage stamp is used.Requires a report to Congress on the number of stamps printed to facilitate such rate increase, with related price information.</summary>
</bill>
