<bill session="107" type="h" number="5400" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-10T23:40:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-10T23:40:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the President of the United States to agree to certain amendments to the Agreement between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the United Mexican States concerning the establishment of a Border Environment Cooperation Commission and a North American Development Bank, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2002-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2002-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400304" joined="2002-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-09-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-10-03T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 107-720.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-10-03T17:00:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="449">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 449.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T19:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Financial Services, H. Rept. 107-720, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-10T23:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Armey asked unanimous consent discharge the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-10T23:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7859-7887" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-10-10T23:40:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7886-7887" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-10T23:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Saline water conversion"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h616"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/10/2002--Passed House amended.
Amends the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act to authorize the President to agree to amendments to the Border Environment Cooperation Agreement (the November 1993 Agreement Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the United Mexican States Concerning the Establishment of a Border Environment Cooperation Commission and a North American Development Bank) that: (1) enable the North American Development Bank to make grants and non-market rate loans out of its paid-in capital resources with the approval of its Board of Directors for qualified water conservation projects; and (2) amend the definition of "border region" as it relates to such projects to include the area in the United States within 100 kilometers of the international boundary and the area in Mexico within 300 kilometers of the international boundary between the two countries.(Sec. 2) Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to report annually to specified congressional committees on the North American Development Bank.(Sec. 3) Expresses the sense of Congress that water conservation projects are eligible for funding from the Bank under the Cooperation Agreement.Expresses the sense of Congress that the Board of Directors of the Bank should support with financing: (1) qualified water conservation projects which can assist Texas irrigators and agricultural producers in the lower Rio Grande River Valley; (2) conservation as well as new water supply research and desalination projects in the border States of California, Arizona, New Mexico, and Texas; and (3) projects which address coastal and water and air pollution issues on both sides of the international boundary between the United States and Mexico, including along the Pacific Ocean and Gulf of Mexico shores of both countries.</summary>
</bill>
