<bill session="108" type="h" number="2135" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Law Enforcement Officers Due Process Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to law enforcement agencies that ensure that law enforcement officers employed by such agency are afforded due process when involved in a case that may lead to dismissal, demotion, suspension, or transfer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400212"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="2004-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2003-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400139" joined="2004-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2003-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400280" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400294" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2003-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2003-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2003-11-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2003-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1818"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police brutality"/>
    <term name="Police corruption"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2003--Introduced.
Law Enforcement Officers Due Process Act of 2003 - Authorizes the Attorney General to provide grants to law enforcement agencies (agencies) that: (1) have in effect an administrative process or an existing procedure that complies with officer rights requirements; or (2) certify that they will establish, within two years, an administrative process that complies with such requirements.Requires the administrative process to require that an agency that investigates an officer for matters which could reasonably lead to disciplinary action provide recourse for the officer that includes: (1) access to any existing administrative process established by the employing agency prior to disciplinary action; and (2) the right to a hearing before a fair and impartial board or hearing officer, to be represented by an attorney or other officer at such officer's expense, to confront any witness testifying against such officer, and to record all meetings.Permits the immediate suspension with pay of an officer: (1) whose continued presence on the job is considered to be a substantial and immediate threat; (2) who refuses to obey a direct order issued in conformance with the agency's written and disseminated rules and regulations; or (3) who is accused of committing an illegal act.Makes this Act inapplicable to an agency if the Attorney General determines that such agency has in effect an established civil service system, agency review board, grievance procedure, or personnel board which meets or exceeds the minimum standards set forth in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
