<bill session="105" type="h" number="3700" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prompt Payment Improvement Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 31, United States Code, to require the provision of a written prompt payment policy to each subcontractor under a Federal contract and to require a clause in each subcontract under a Federal contract that outlines the provisions of the prompt payment statute and other related information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400438"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1998-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="1998-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1998-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/1998--Introduced.
Prompt Payment Improvement Act of 1998 - Amends Federal law to direct the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to set forth in writing the prompt payment policy applicable to subcontractors under Federal contracts. Requires the head of each Federal agency to: (1) provide a copy of such policy to each contractor awarded a contract by the agency; and (2) require the contractor to provide a copy of the policy to each of its subcontractors under the contract. Directs the head of each agency to require each such contractor to include in each subcontract awarded under the contract a clause containing, among other things, the requirements and penalties of the prompt payment statute relating to the obligations of the Federal Government and prime contractors in making timely progress payments.</summary>
</bill>
