<bill session="104" type="h" number="1912" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care Fraud Prevention and Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To deter and penalize health care fraud and abuse and to simplify the administration of health benefit plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1995-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1995-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1995-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1995-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1995-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1995-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1995-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1995-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1309-1310"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Community service (Punishment)"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Embezzlement"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care fraud"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicaid fraud"/>
    <term name="Medical corporations"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-incrimination"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Fraud and Abuse Subtitle A: Amendments to Anti-Fraud and Abuse Provisions Applicable to Medicare, Medicaid, and State Health Care Programs Subtitle B: Establishment of All-Payer Health Care Fraud and Abuse Control Program Subtitle C: Application of Fraud and Abuse Authorities Under the Social Security Act to Other Payers Subtitle D: Advisory Opinions on Kickbacks and Self-Referral Subtitle E: Preemption of State Corporate Practice Laws Title II: Information Systems and Administrative Simplification Health Care Fraud Prevention and Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995 - Title I: Fraud and Abuse - Subtitle A: Amendments to Anti-Fraud and Abuse Provisions Applicable to Medicare, Medicaid, and State Health Care Programs - Amends the Social Security Act (SSA) title XI anti-fraud and abuse provisions applicable to Medicare, Medicaid, and State health care programs and concerning penalties and exclusionary matters, among other changes providing for: (1) civil monetary penalties for additional specified violations, including anti-kickback violations; (2) modifications to anti-kickback exceptions; (3) revisions in civil and criminal penalties; (4) deposit of penalties collected into the account established below; (5) private right of action in certain cases; and (6) mandatory exclusion from Medicare and State health care program participation for certain individuals convicted of a criminal felony relating to health care fraud. Subtitle B: Establishment of All-Payer Health Care Fraud and Abuse Control Program - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Attorney General to establish a program to coordinate their functions, as well as those of other organizations, with respect to the prevention, detection, and control of health care fraud and abuse. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 112) Establishes in the Treasury the All-Payer Health Care Fraud and Abuse Control Account for use in the program established above. Subtitle C: Application of Fraud and Abuse Authorities Under the Social Security Act to Other Payers - Applies civil monetary penalty provisions under SSA title XI (as amended by this Act), as well as certain criminal penalty provisions, to similar specified violations with respect to all payers. Subtitle D: Advisory Opinions on Kickbacks and Self-Referral - Directs the Secretary to establish a process for issuing certain advisory opinions, for a fee, to requesting individuals or entities concerning whether their conduct constitutes grounds for imposition of a sanction or denial of payment for a service rendered. Subtitle E: Preemption of State Corporate Practice Laws - Preempts State and local laws prohibiting corporate practice of medicine. Title II: Information Systems and Administrative Simplification - Requires issuance to health benefit plan beneficiaries, including Medicare and Medicaid beneficiaries, of a uniform card similar to a credit card with encoded electronic information for use in obtaining entitled items or services verified along with beneficiary enrollment under a new system the Secretary shall establish for facilitating electronic claims payment, in addition to enrollment verification. Requires submission of claims in a uniform format pursuant to standards the Secretary shall also establish, including standards for electronic reporting of specific claim elements, that incorporate specified requirements, taking into account certain task force and other specified recommendations. Provides for uniform electronic hospital cost reporting under Medicare, with civil money penalties to ensure appropriate enrollment reporting and claims submission.</summary>
</bill>
