<bill session="108" type="h" number="5252" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Access to Clinical Trials Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act and the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to the availability to the public of information on clinical trials to determine the safety and effectiveness of drugs, biological products, and devices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2004-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2004-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2004-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2004-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1882-1883"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Demography"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug advertising"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2004--Introduced.
Fair Access to Clinical Trials Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit an entity from receiving an award of a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement to conduct a clinical trial to determine the safety or effectiveness of a use of a drug or device unless the entity agrees to: (1) register the trial; (2) provide the results of such trial to the Secretary of Health and Human Services; (3) disclose specified information regarding the trial to the public; and (4) be subject to audits. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), to establish and operate a databank of such clinical trial information provided to the Secretary. Requires the Director to assign to the National Library of Medicine the primary responsibility for operating such databank. Requires the Secretary to: (1) identify false or misleading information in the databank, correct such information, and make appropriate public notifications; and (2) amend regulations to require institutional review boards to determine the safety or effectiveness of products registered under this Act and deny approval for trials that are not registered. Specifies information required for registration of clinical trials, including information important to clinicians or researchers. Sets forth provisions regarding periodic updates of databank information, submission of results of clinical trials, public disclosure of databank information, and violations of this Act. Amends the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act to allow exemptions for clinical investigational use of drugs or devices only if such drugs are registered in accordance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
