<bill session="105" type="h" number="1776" updated="2012-11-01T22:48:11-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campaign Independence Restoration Act, Part I</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to restrict the use of soft money in political campaigns, to improve the enforcement of campaign laws, to promote the disclosure of information on campaign spending, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="402284" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1997-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400584" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="1997-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1997-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1997-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400607" joined="1997-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="1997-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1997-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1997-09-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political consultants"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Primaries"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>06/04/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Soft Money Subtitle A: Provisions Relating to Soft Money of Political Parties Subtitle B: Soft Money of Persons Other Than Political Parties Title II: Enforcement and Disclosure Subtitle A: Improving Enforcement Subtitle B: Increasing Disclosure Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions Campaign Independence Restoration Act, Part I - Title I: Soft Money - Subtitle A: Provisions Relating to Soft Money of Political Parties - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) with respect to "soft money" to: (1) prohibit a national committee of a political party (including specified related entities) from soliciting or receiving contributions or making expenditures not subject to such Act; (2) require a State, district, or local committee of a political party to make Federal election year expenditures (with exceptions) from funds subject to such Act; (3) prohibit a national, State, district, or local committee from soliciting or donating funds to a nonprofit organization; and (4) prohibit an incumbent or candidate for Federal office from soliciting or receiving funds not subject to such Act, or solicit or receive funds for a non-Federal election in excess of certain limits or from prohibited sources (with exceptions for State or local candidates in compliance with State law). (Sec. 102) Increases limits on individual contributions to national political parties. (Sec. 103) Imposes or modifies political committee reporting requirements. (Sec. 104) Removes the exclusion of office facility construction or purchase contributions from the definition of "contribution." Subtitle B: Soft Money of Persons Other Than Political Parties - Imposes reporting requirements regarding disbursements over $2,000 by a person other than a political party committee or a candidate. Title II: Enforcement and Disclosure - Subtitle A: Improving Enforcement - Amends FECA to provide for: (1) random compliance audits; (2) injunction and litigation authority for the Commission; (3) Commission member term limits; and (4) expedited Commission procedures and increased penalties for violations of such Act. Subtitle B - Increasing Disclosure - Amends FECA to provide for: (1) certain reporting on an election cycle rather than a calendar year basis; (2) consulting service disclosure; and (3) mandatory (with exceptions) electronic filing of Commission reports. (Sec. 214) Sets forth political advertising provisions for print and broadcast or cablecast communications. Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions - Directs the Commission to promulgate regulations concerning the use of non-Federal money. (Sec. 303) Provides for expedited and mandatory Supreme Court review of any appeal of any interlocutory order or final court action on the constitutionality of any provision of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
