<bill session="108" type="h" number="4058" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Assistance for Civilians Affected by Conflict Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize assistance for civilians in foreign countries who have been affected by conflict, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Ethics"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Famines"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Prosthesis"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Psychotherapy"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations officials"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2004--Introduced.
United States Assistance for Civilians Affected by Conflict Act of 2004 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the President to: (1) appoint a Special Coordinator to ensure that Federal departments and agencies responsible for the conduct of foreign affairs and national security undertake advance planning, coordinated action, and harmonized execution to respond to complex humanitarian emergencies in foreign countries and to ensure that such planning and action is consistent with the national interests of the United States; and (2) take specified actions to respond to such emergencies. Authorizes fiscal year appropriations to the President for international disaster assistance. Authorizes the President to develop and undertake protection initiatives, including protection initiatives for women and children who are refugees or displaced persons, or living in areas affected by a complex humanitarian emergency. Expresses the sense of Congress that the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees should review its personnel practices to: (1) ensure that senior protection officers are assigned to the posts where women and children are in the most danger of gender-based violence or exploitation, and to ensure that more female staff are present in refugee or displaced persons camps; and (2) facilitate the permanent hiring of successful junior professional officers following their initial tours of duty. Declares that it shall be U.S. policy to ensure that U.S.-funded organizations that respond to complex humanitarian emergencies in foreign countries have the resources to address the specific health needs of women affected by such emergencies. Amends the Act to authorize the President to provide assistance: (1) to prevent, prepare for, and respond to foreign crises, including acts of ethnic cleansing, mass killings and genocide, peace and humanitarian intervention operations, and armed ethnic or civil conflicts; (2) to support the transition to democracy and long-term development in countries emerging from political instability or conflict; (3) to victims of foreign civil strife and warfare; and (4) for famine relief. Directs the Secretary of State to develop a strategy for the protection of women and children who are internally displaced, made refugees, or otherwise affected by a complex humanitarian emergency. Directs the Special Coordinator to maintain an information database and develop an early warning list related to occurrences of gender-based violence or exploitation of children during a complex humanitarian emergency. Directs the The Secretary to urge the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees to work with nongovernmental organizations to implement a model `whistleblower' system under which humanitarian workers, refugees, and internally displaced persons can report gender-based violence or exploitation of children. Prohibits assistance to a nongovernmental organization that assists refugees or displaced persons if such organization does not adopt a code of conduct that incorporates specified provisions respecting sexual exploitation of children and others by humanitarian workers. Expresses the sense of Congress that all U.S. agencies, nongovernmental organizations, and multilateral organizations that are implementing U.S. humanitarian assistance programs should review their administrative, management, and employment practices at refugee and displaced persons camps for the purposes of: (1) increasing the number of women involved in the distribution of food and humanitarian supplies; and (2) educating providers and beneficiaries of humanitarian assistance about the seriousness of gender-based violence and exploitation of children. Amends the Act to include in foreign military training and education the protection of displaced civilians, especially women and children.</summary>
</bill>
