<bill session="106" type="h" number="5426" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Conservation of Farmable Wetland Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Continued Dumping and Subsidy Offset Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Hass Avocado Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Medicine Equity and Drug Safety Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Prescription Drug Import Fairness Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400534"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="4461"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural appropriations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agricultural industries"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Antidumping"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Citrus fruits"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commodity Credit Corporation"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Drug adulteration"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Export subsidies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Farm Credit Administration"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to rural areas"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Fruit trade"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grain inspection"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insect control"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Livestock industry"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Marketing orders"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military parks"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Plant diseases"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Private forests"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Rural Telephone Bank"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural electrification"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Agricultural Programs Title II: Conservation Programs Title III: Rural Development Programs Title IV: Domestic Food Programs Title V: Foreign Assistance and Related Programs Title VI: Related Agencies and Food and Drug Administration Title VII: General Provisions Title VIII: Natural Disaster Assistance and Other Emergency Appropriations Title IX: Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Title X: Continued Dumping and Subsidy Offset Title XI: Conservation of Farmable Wetland Title XII: Hass Avocado Promotion, Research, and Information Title XIII: Debt Reduction Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001 - Title I: Agricultural Programs - Appropriates funds for FY 2001 for the following Department of Agriculture programs and services: (1) Office of the Secretary of Agriculture; (2) executive operations ; (3) Office of the Chief Information Officer; (4) Office of the Chief Financial Officer; (5) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Administration; (6) agriculture buildings and facilities and rental payments; (7) hazardous materials management; (8) departmental administration; (9) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations; (10) Office of Communications; (11) Office of the Inspector General; (12) Office of the General Counsel; (13) Office of the Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics; (14) Economic Research Service; (15) National Agricultural Statistics Service; (16) Agricultural Research Service; (17) Cooperative State Research, Education, and Extension Service; (18) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Marketing and Regulatory Programs; (19) Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service; (20) Agricultural Marketing Service; (21) Grain Inspection, Packers and Stockyards Administration; (22) Office of the Under Secretary for Food Safety; (23) Food Safety and Inspection Service; (24) Office of the Under Secretary for Farm and Foreign Agricultural Services; (25) Farm Service Agency; (26) Risk Management Agency; (27) Federal Crop Insurance Corporation Fund; and (28) Commodity Credit Corporation Fund.Title II: Conservation Programs - Appropriates funds for the: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Natural Resources and Environment; and (2) Natural Resources Conservation Service.Title III: Rural Development Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Rural Development; (2) Rural Housing Service; (3) Rural Business-Cooperative Service; and (4) Rural Utilities Service.Title IV: Domestic Food Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Food, Nutrition and Consumer Services; and (2) Food and Nutrition Service.Title V: Foreign Assistance and Related Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1)Foreign Agricultural Service; (2) Public Law 480 program account, title I ocean freight differential grants, and titles II and III grants; and (3) Commodity Credit Corporation export loans program account.Title VI: Related Agencies and Food and Drug Administration- Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Food and Drug Administration; (2) Commodity Futures Trading Commission; and (3) Farm Credit Administration.Title VII: General Provisions - Specifies certain uses and limits on or prohibitions against the use of funds appropriated by this Act.(Sec. 727) Prohibits Food and Drug Administration (FDA) fund use to close or relocate the FDA Division of Drug Analysis, St. Louis, Missouri, except that funds may be used to plan a relocation within St. Louis city limits.(Sec. 728) Prohibits FDA fund use to reduce the FDA District Office in Detroit, Michigan, below specified staffing levels.(Sec. 734) Prohibits fund use to declare excess any Federal (Department of Agriculture) lands or facilities at Fort Reno, Oklahoma, or to transfer such lands or facilities prior to a specified date without congressional authorization.(Sec. 736) Revises specified housing, community development, and business assistance provisions respecting isolated, high-cost rural Alaskan areas.(Sec. 737) Makes the Town of Lloyd, New York, and the Town of Thompson, New York, eligible for loans and grants through the rural community advancement program.(Sec. 742) Amends the Agricultural Market Transition Act to extend milk price support provisions.(Sec. 743) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to obligate specified dollar-equivalent amounts of agricultural commodities for foreign countries to assist in mitigating the effects of HIV and AIDS.(Sec. 745) Medicine Equity and Drug Safety Act of 2000 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require regulations permitting the importation into the United States of covered products (prescription drugs).(Sec. 746) Prescription Drug Import Fairness Act of 2000 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prohibit FDA from sending a warning notice to an individual who imports a prescription drug into the United States for personal use unless specified notice requirements are met.(Sec. 749) States that the Friends of the National Arboretum organization shall not be considered a prohibited fund source for the United States National Arboretum as long as such organization maintains its tax-exempt status and operates exclusively for the Arboretum.(Sec. 752) Subjects U.S. establishments that slaughter or process birds of the order Ratitae (ostriches, squab, emus, and rheas) for human consumption to inspection and sanitation requirements under the Poultry Products Inspection Act.(Sec. 754) Amends the Omnibus Consolidated and Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1999, with respect to the indemnity fund for cotton stored in bankrupt Georgia warehouses, to: (1) extend the use of remaining funds for producers; and (2) authorize fund use for cotton ginners and other cotton-related businesses, and for producers from other States with Georgia-stored cotton.(Sec. 756) Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to increase available funds for the National Sheep Industry Improvement Center.(Sec. 759) Maintains the eligibility, until the availability of 2000 Census population data, of: (1) the Sea Island Health Clinic, John's Island, South Carolina, for community facilities assistance; and (2) a specified area in Dade County, Florida, for business and industry guaranteed loans.(Sec. 761) Considers: (1) the cities of Kewanee and Jacksonville, Illinois, and Vicksburg, Mississippi, as having met certain rural housing area requirements; and; and (2) Jefferson County, Kentucky, as a rural area for purposes of certain business and industry loans.(Sec. 762) Provides settlement funds for claims associated with the Chuquatonchee Watershed Project, Mississippi.(Sec. 763) Makes the Konocti Water District, California, eligible for certain rural utilities grants and loans.(Sec. 765) Authorizes the conveyance of specified land in Prince George's County, Maryland, to resolve certain land claims at the Beltsville Agricultural Research Center, Maryland.(Sec. 766) Obligates specified funds under the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 for California.(Sec. 769) Makes Coachella, California, eligible for rural development mission area assistance.(Sec. 773) Amends the Consolidated Farmers Home Administration Act of 1961 to make Indian tribes (currently federally recognized Indian tribes) eligible for water and waste facility loans and grants.(Sec. 776) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) Alexander Hamilton made an immense contribution to the United States as a principal drafter of the Constitution; and (2) the National Park Service should restore and relocate his home, "the Grange", to St. Nicholas Park, New York City.(Sec. 777) Amends the Fallen Timbers Battlefield and Fort Miamis National Historic Site Act of 1999 to authorize land acquisition assistance and related appropriations.Title VIII: Natural Disaster Assistance and Other Emergency Appropriations - Authorizes additional Department of Agriculture appropriations for: (1) Office of the Chief Information Officer (common computing environment); (2) departmental administration; (3) Farm Service Agency; (4) Federal Crop Insurance Corporation Fund; (5) Natural Resources Conservation Service; and (6) Rural Community Advancement Program.Sets forth specified programs for which the Secretary shall make additional compensation and assistance available.Title IX: Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement - Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 - Sets forth provisions respecting: (1) presidential and congressional authorities and procedures for the imposition of new, and termination of existing, unilateral agricultural or medical sanctions; and (2) trade and travel restrictions with Cuba and other specified countries.Title X: Continued Dumping and Subsidy Offset Act of 2000 - Continued Dumping or Subsidy Offset Act of 2000 - Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to declare that, whenever continued dumping or subsidization is found to exist by the administering authority or by operation of law, any duties assessed shall be distributed as continued dumping or subsidy offsets to the affected domestic producers for qualifying expenditures on an annual basis.Limits qualifying expenditures to expenditures incurred since the issuance of the antidumping duty finding or order or countervailing duty order in any or all of the categories of plant, equipment, research and development, personnel training, acquisition of technology, employer-paid employee health care and pension benefits, environmental equipment, training or technology, acquisition of raw materials and other inputs, and borrowed working capital or other funds needed to maintain production.Directs the Commissioner of the U.S. Customs Service to prescribe offset disbursement procedures.Requires the Commissioner to establish a special account in the Treasury to receive all antidumping or countervailing duties.Title XI: Conservation of Farmable Wetland - Conservation of Farmable Wetland Act of 2000 - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out a pilot program for conservation reserve enrollment of wetland and buffer acreage in Iowa, Minnesota, Montana, Nebraska, North Dakota, and South Dakota.Title XII: Hass Avocado Promotion, Research, and Information - Hass Avocado Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 2000 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to issue a marketing order, subject to producer and importer referendum approval, providing for research and promotion of Hass avocados. Sets forth marketing order terms and related provisions, including establishment of a Hass Avocado Board. Authorizes appropriations.Title XIII: Debt Reduction - Deposits a specified sum for FY 2001 in the Department of the Treasury for public debt reduction.</summary>
</bill>
