<bill session="107" type="hr" number="71" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-03-01T11:22:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-03-01T11:22:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 333) to amend title 11, United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-02-28T16:33:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 107-4, by Mr. Sessions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-02-28T16:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 333 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendments recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as the original bill for amendment under the five-minute rule and shall be considered as read. Specified amendments are in order. Upon receipt of a message from the Senate transmitting H.R. 333 with Senate amendments thereto, it shall be in order to consider in the House a motion offered by the chairman of the Committee on the Judiciary or his designee that the House disagree to the Senate amendments and request or agree to a conference with ...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-02-28T16:33:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="2">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 2.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-03-01T10:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H512-517" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-01T10:27:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 71.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-01T11:00:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2001-03-01T11:22:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="22" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 281 - 132 (Roll no. 22).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H512" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-03-01T11:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="107" type="h" number="333"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2001--Reported to House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule (modified closed) for the consideration of H.R. 333 (bankruptcy law and consumer credit).</summary>
</bill>
