<bill session="104" type="h" number="1534" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to extend certain expiring authorities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to authorize medical construction projects for that Department for fiscal year 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300151"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment subsidies"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Gulf War syndrome"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Occupational therapy"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf War"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/1995--Introduced.
Extends through December 31, 1997, the following authorities of the Department of Veterans Affairs: (1) the authority to provide outpatient services to Persian Gulf veterans exposed to toxic substances or environmental hazards during such service; (2) the authority to contract with community-based treatment facilities for the care of eligible veterans suffering from alcohol or drug dependence or abuse disabilities (also extends a certain evaluation in connection with such treatment); (3) the authority to enter into agreements with States and nonprofit organizations for the provision of housing assistance for homeless veterans ( requires a report); (5) the Department's health professionals scholarship program (requires a report); (6) the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into enhanced-use leases of Department real property; (7) the authority under the Veterans' Benefits and Services Act of 1988 for a pilot program providing community-based residential care for homeless chronically mentally ill veterans; and (8) the Department's compensated work therapy and therapeutic transitional housing program. Extends through December 31, 1996, a pilot program for determining noninstitutional alternatives to veterans' nursing home care (requires a report). Repeals the authority of the Secretary to make contracts and grants for providing care and treatment for veterans at the Department's Veterans Memorial Medical Center in the Philippines. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out the Department's major medical facility projects and leases for which funds are requested in the President's FY 1996 budget and for which authorization is required. Authorizes FY 1996 appropriations to the Secretary for such projects and leases, with limitations.</summary>
</bill>
