<bill session="105" type="h" number="4720" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare HMO Beneficiary Emergency Relief Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to extend for 6 months the contracts of certain managed care organizations under the Medicare Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1998-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/1998--Introduced.
Medicare HMO Beneficiary Emergency Relief Act of 1998 - Provides that, if an eligible organization under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act has a risk-sharing contract in effect on December 31, 1998, and does not convert it to a contract to offer a Medicare+Choice plan under Medicare part C effective January 1, 1999, then such risk-sharing contract shall be deemed to be extended through June 30, 1999, under its existing terms and conditions. Excludes from the application of this Act any eligible organization that, for reasons of financial hardship, cannot convert a risk-sharing contract to a contract to offer a Medicare+Choice plan. Requires a Medicare+Choice organization offering a Medicare+Choice plan in an area affected by such a contract extension to accept, between November 1, 1998, and June 30, 1999, elections to enroll in such plan by individuals currently enrolled under the contract being extended. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the eligible organization whose contract is being extended to negotiate for a new contract which may enable the organization to convert its contract to a contract to offer a Medicare+Choice plan.</summary>
</bill>
