<bill session="105" type="h" number="879" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Teaching Responsibility and Accountability to Children Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require initial intake screenings and the use of youth development specialists in Federal juvenile proceedings, and to encourage States and local governments to use similar procedures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="1997-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1997-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1997-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1997-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Administration of juvenile justice"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Delinquency prevention"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Juveniles tried as adults"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Pretrial intervention"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Federal Juvenile Proceedings Title II: Grant Program for at Risk Juveniles Teaching Responsibility and Accountability to Children Act of 1997 - Title I: Federal Juvenile Proceedings - Amends the Federal criminal code to require an appropriate Federal authority (designated by the Attorney General), before any decision is made to proceed against a juvenile as a juvenile or as an adult, or to refer the juvenile to State authorities, to perform an initial intake screening to determine whether that juvenile is an at risk juvenile. Requires a juvenile who is determined to be at risk and who is proceeded against as a juvenile to be referred to a youth development specialist. Provides that if a juvenile is referred to State authorities for further proceedings or transferred for prosecution as an adult, the results of the screening shall be made available to those authorities or to the entity to which the juvenile is so transferred. Requires the screening body to determine that a juvenile is at risk if it determines that the juvenile is likely to exhibit recidivist or increasingly violent crimes, based on specified factors. Limits the use of such determination. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) the qualifications and duties of the youth development specialist, including determining a course of action for the juvenile that will avoid continued criminal activity and monitoring the juvenile's progress through the court system; and (2) data collection and dissemination by the Attorney General. Title II: Grant Program for At Risk Juveniles - Directs the Attorney General to award: (1) grants to an entity that has implemented specified at risk juvenile screening programs and youth development specialist referral services; and (2) not more than $10,000 each year for each juvenile who receives services to an entity that meets the requirements of this title. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) eligibility; and (2) permissible uses of grant funds. Authorizes appropriations. Specifies that funds authorized may be appropriated from the Violent Crime Reduction Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
