<bill session="104" type="h" number="67" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Conservation Reserve Program Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend the conservation reserve program for 10 years and the wetlands reserve program for 5 years to protect vulnerable soil and water resources by facilitating the transition of our Nation's most environmentally sensitive land to conservation uses by enabling farmers to meet conservation compliance requirements through the early withdrawal, modification, re-enrollment, or enrollment of lands in the conservation reserve; to best achieve such conservation purposes with sharply limited resources by permitting the Secretary of Agriculture to negotiate reduced annual rental payments in exchange for granting farmers increased flexibility to withdraw, enroll, or re-enroll parts of land parcels in the conservation reserve program and for permitting limited uses on lands enrolled in the conservation reserve, to permit the transfer of crop bases among owners upon the expiration of enrollment; and to authorize the establishment of demonstration projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1995-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1995-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1995-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1995-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Resource Conservation, Research and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG27" subcommittee="Resource Conservation, Research and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Legumes"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Conservation Reserve Program Reform Act of 1995 - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to extend: (1) the Environmental Conservation Acreage Reserve Program; and (2) the wetlands reserve program. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to extend or modify conservation reserve contracts under specified circumstances. Authorizes a demonstration grant program to permit grass or legumes to be grown on reserve land. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
