<bill session="105" type="h" number="1081" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:53-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PAC Limitation Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to reduce the influence of multicandidate political committees in elections for Federal office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400382"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>03/13/1997--Introduced.
PAC Limitation Act of 1997 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to: (1) prohibit multicandidate political committees from making contributions to candidates for Federal office; (2) limit contributions that a House of Representatives candidate may accept from outside his or her district; and (3) prohibit a national committee of a political party and the congressional campaign committees of a political party from accepting, in any calendar year, more than $25,000 from any single person in contributions or transfers that are not subject to certain limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements. Requires each operator of a radio or television broadcasting station or cable system, at such times and in such manner as the Federal Election Commission shall prescribe by regulation, to report to the Commission the identity of each advertiser, the cost, the duration, and other appropriate information with respect to each Federal political advertisement carried by the station or system.</summary>
</bill>
