<bill session="108" type="h" number="3087" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-09-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Extension of Highway Trust Fund bill</title>
    <title type="popular">TEA-21 bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide an extension of highway, highway safety, motor carrier safety, transit, and other programs funded out of the Highway Trust Fund pending enactment of a law reauthorizing the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Resources, the Budget, Ways and Means, and Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8819-8830" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3087.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-09-24T15:48:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8819-8824" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2003-09-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12095" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-09-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2003-09-26">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2003-09-29">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2003-09-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2003-09-30" type="public" number="108-88">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-88.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="3088"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="1640"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="1640"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="1646"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appalachia"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highspeed ground transportation"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Highway use tax"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Light rail transit"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Scenic byways"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seat belts"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Subways"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terminals (Transportation)"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Truck drivers"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban planning"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2003--Public Law.
Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2003 - Extends Federal highway, highway safety, motor carrier safety, and transit programs for five months, and authorizes appropriations, through February 29, 2004. (Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) apportion funds made available for Federal-aid highway programs under the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century (TEA21) to each State according to the ratio of the State's total FY 2003 obligation authority to the FY 2003 obligation authority for all States; and (2) ensure that each State is apportioned an amount determined according to a specified formula for the Interstate maintenance program, the National Highway System program, the bridge program, the surface transportation program, the congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program, the recreational trails program, the Appalachian development highway system program, and the minimum guarantee. Extends the off-system bridge set-aside through February 29, 2004. Directs the Secretary to reduce the amount that would be apportioned, but for this Act, to a State for programs for FY 2004 under a law reauthorizing the Federal-aid highway program enacted after this Act's enactment by the amount that is apportioned to each State under this Act for each such program. Authorizes the Secretary to establish procedures under which certain funds apportioned for a program category for which funds are not authorized under such a law may be restored to the Federal-aid highway program. Makes specified funds available from the Highway Trust Fund to carry out this Act for the period of October 1, 2003, through February 29, 2004, subject to a limitation on obligations for Federal-aid highways and highway safety construction programs. Sets forth specified obligation limitations. Prohibits a State from obligating any funds for a Federal-aid highway program project after February 29, 2004, until the date of enactment of a multi-year law reauthorizing the Federal-aid highway program. Directs that any obligation of an allocation of obligation authority under this section be considered to be an obligation for Federal-aid highways and highway safety construction programs for FY 2004 for purposes of appropriations for the Department of Transportation for FY 2004. (Sec. 3) Authorizes a State to transfer unobligated apportionments, with transferred funds subject to the provisions of the program to which the funds are transferred. Directs the Secretary, as soon as practicable after the enactment of a law reauthorizing the Federal-aid highway program enacted after this Act's enactment, to restore any funds that a State transferred for any project not eligible for the funds but for this section to the program category from which the funds were transferred. Authorizes the Secretary to establish procedures under which funds transferred from a program category for which funds are not authorized may be restored to the Federal-aid highway program. (Sec. 4) Makes specified funds available from the Highway Trust Fund for administrative expenses of the Federal-aid highway program for FY 2004, subject to a limitation on obligations for Federal-aid highways and highway safety construction programs. (Sec. 5) Extends the authorization of appropriations under TEA21 for: (1) Federal lands highways (Indian reservation roads, public lands highways, park roads and parkways, and refuge roads); (2) national corridor planning and development and coordinated border infrastructure programs; (3) construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities; (4) the national scenic byways program; (5) the value pricing pilot program; (6) highway use tax evasion projects; (7) the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico program; (8) safety grants; (9) the transportation and community and system preservation pilot program; (10) transportation infrastructure finance and innovation; (11) surface transportation research; (12) the technology deployment program; (13) training and education; (14) the Bureau of Transportation Statistics; (15) Intermodal Transportation System standards, research, operational tests, development, and deployment; (16) university transportation research; (17) metropolitan planning; (18) the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands; (19) the Alaska highway program; (20) Operation Lifesaver; (21) the bridge discretionary program; (22) interstate maintenance; (23) recreational trails administrative costs; and (24) railway-highway crossing hazard elimination in high speed rail corridors. (Sec. 6) Extends the authorization of appropriations for highway safety programs, including: (1) seat belt safety incentive grants; (2) prevention of intoxicated driver incentive grants; (3) highway safety research and development; (4) occupant protection incentive grants; (5) alcohol-impaired driving countermeasures incentive grants; and (6) the national driver register. (Sec. 7) Makes funds available from the Highway Trust Fund for the Secretary to pay administrative expenses of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration. Extends appropriations for: (1) the motor carrier safety assistance program; (2) information systems and commercial driver's license grants; and (3) continuation of a crash causation study. (Sec. 8) Extends appropriations for Federal transit programs, including: (1) fixed guideway modernization; (2) formula grants; (3) capital programs; (4) planning; (5) research, including university transportation research; (6) the job access and reverse commute program; (7) the rural transportation accessibility incentive program; (8) urbanized area formula grants; (9) the fuel cell bus and bus facilities program; (10) the advanced technology pilot project; (11) projects for new fixed guideway systems and extensions to existing systems; and (12) the New Jersey urban core project. (Sec. 9) Amends the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act to extend funding through February 29, 2004, for the National Outreach and Communications Program. Makes available funding to carry out the national recreational boating safety program. (Sec. 10) Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985, and TEA21, to set discretionary spending limits for FY 2004 under the highway and mass transit categories. (Sec. 12) Extends authorization for the use of the Highway Trust Fund and the Aquatic Resources Trust Fund, including with respect to the sport fish restoration account and the boat safety account.</summary>
</bill>
