<bill session="108" type="h" number="4959" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hunting Heritage and Fishing Preservation Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Freedom to Fish Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Hunting Heritage Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To recognize the heritage of hunting and provide opportunities for continued hunting on Federal public land, to protect the public's ability to fish for sport, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400203"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-08-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Trapping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2004--Introduced.
Hunting Heritage and Fishing Preservation Act of 2004 - Hunting Heritage Protection Act - Requires that Federal public lands be open to access and use for recreational hunting with certain exceptions. Directs the head of each relevant Federal agency to support, promote, and enhance recreational hunting opportunities. Declares that Federal land management decisions and actions should, to the extent practicable, result in no net loss of land area available for hunting opportunities on Federal public lands. Prohibits a withdrawal, change of classification, or change of management status that effectively closes 5,000 or more acres of Federal public land for use for recreational hunting from occurring unless the head of the Federal agency with authority to manage the land has submitted written notice of the action to specified congressional committees. Freedom to Fish Act - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to require that any fishery management plan, which is prepared by any Council or by the Secretary of Commerce, not establish geographic areas where recreational fishing is prohibited unless: (1) clear indication exists that recreational fishing in such area is the cause of a specific conservation problem; (2) no alternative conservation measures will adequately provide for conservation and management of the fishery; (3) the management plan provides for specific measurable criteria to assess whether the prohibition provides conservation benefits to the fishery, and requires periodic review to assess the continued need for the prohibition; (4) the best available scientific information supports the need to close the area to recreational fishing; and (5) the prohibition is terminated as soon as the condition that was the basis of the prohibition no longer exists.</summary>
</bill>
