<bill session="106" type="hj" number="6" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution to provide for a balanced budget for the United States Government and for greater accountability in the enactment of tax legislation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400121"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Debt limit"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Requires the Congress and the President, before each fiscal year, to agree on an estimate of total receipts (except those derived from borrowing) for that fiscal year by enactment of a single subject joint resolution. Prohibits outlays for that year (except those for repayment of debt principal) from exceeding this amount unless the Congress, by a three-fifths roll call vote of each House, authorizes a specific excess of outlays over receipts. Requires the Congress, whenever actual outlays exceed actual receipts for any fiscal year, to provide by law for the repayment of the excess in the ensuing fiscal year. Requires a three-fifths roll call vote of each House to increase the public debt. Directs the President to submit a balanced budget to the Congress. Requires the approval of a majority of the total membership of each House by roll call vote before any bill to increase revenue may become law. Waives these provisions when a declaration of war is in effect.</summary>
</bill>
