<bill session="105" type="h" number="497" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-08">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal the Federal charter of Group Hospitalization and Medical Services, Inc., and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An Act to amend the Federal charter for Group Hospitalization and Medical Services, Inc., and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1997-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-26T11:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis (VA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-26T11:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-26T11:39:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-26T11:49:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-26T12:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-02-26T12:40:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="26" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 417 - 0 (Roll no. 26).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-02-26T12:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-11-05">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Thompson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-11-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="261">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 261.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12204-12205" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Amendment SP 1616 proposed by Senator Craig for Senator Thompson.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Amendment SP 1616 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1997-11-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3025"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal incorporation"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1616"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/8/1997--Passed Senate amended.
Amends the Federal charter of Group Hospitalization and Medical Services, Inc., to: (1) permit the corporation to have one class of members consisting of at least one member and not more than 30; and (2) prohibit dissolution of the corporation without congressional approval. Deems enrollment in a health benefits plan administered by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) before termination of such plan on January 3, 1998, or enrollment in a plan with respect to which the eligibility of any employees or retired employees of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (FRS) terminates on January 3, 1998, to be periods of enrollment in a health benefits plan under Federal Employees Health Benefits Program (FEHBP) provisions. Authorizes an individual enrolled in such a plan on January 3, 1998, to enroll in an approved FEHBP if such individual: (1) meets FEHBP eligibility requirements; or (2) would meet such requirements if, to the extent such requirements involve the Civil Service Retirement System or the Federal Employees Retirement System, such individual satisfies similar requirements of the Retirement Plan for Employees of the Federal Reserve System. Provides for continued coverage under FEHBP for: (1) individuals entitled to such coverage under FDIC or FRS plans; and (2) certain unmarried dependent children covered under such plans. Makes eligibility for participation in FEHBP inapplicable to individuals whose eligibility for coverage does not involuntarily terminate on January 3, 1998. Requires FDIC and FRS to transfer amounts to the Employees Health Benefits Fund to reimburse the Fund for the cost of such benefits not otherwise paid for by the covered individuals.</summary>
</bill>
