<bill session="107" type="hr" number="569" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-07T14:12:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-07T14:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing support for the President's 2002 National Drug Control Strategy to reduce illegal drug use in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400385"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2002-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T13:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Souder moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T13:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7038-7041" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T13:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 569.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2002-10-07T14:12:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7038" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Community leadership"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2002--Introduced.
Expresses the support of the House of Representatives for the President and the Office of National Drug Control Policy in the goal to reduce drug use in America by 10 percent during the next two years and 25 percent during the next five years.Calls on Americans to reduce illegal drug use by talking to children about the dangers and consequences of using illegal drugs.Calls on the President and other specified officials to effectively implement the 2002 National Drug Control Strategy and to work to improve coordination among various actors, including the different levels of government, to reduce the demand in the United States for the international supply of drugs.Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that narcotics control is an integral part of homeland security and should be a priority mission for any new Department of Homeland Security.Reaffirms the sense of the House of Representatives against any use of narcotic and other drugs in a manner inconsistent with the Controlled Substances Act.</summary>
</bill>
