<bill session="104" type="h" number="1941" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make clarifying and technical amendments to further clarify the employment and reemployment rights and responsibilities of members of the uniformed services, as well as those of the employer community, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407838"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="1995-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1995-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1995-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1995-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education, Training, Employment and Housing.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-20">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.2289.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR07" subcommittee="Education, Training, Employment and Housing" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1633"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2289"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/1995--Introduced.
Removes the requirement that individuals performing temporary military service be discharged from such service under honorable conditions in order to be eligible for certain reemployment rights in the positions interrupted by such service. States that an employer shall be considered to have engaged in prohibited discrimination against an employee if the person's action in enforcing a protection, testimony or statement, assistance or other participation in an investigation, or other exercise of a right is a motivating factor in the employer's action, unless the employer can prove that the employer's action would have been taken in the absence of such person's action. Allows individuals to bring complaints concerning reemployment rights and prohibited actions against the Office of Personnel Management (currently, against Federal executive agencies). Repeals a provision that such reemployment rights shall not be construed to prohibit a person from seeking alternative employment in the Federal Government. Empowers the Secretary of Labor's authorized representative with reasonable access to, and the right to interview, persons with information relevant to the investigation. Amends the Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act of 1994 to remove the requirement that a person must have served on active duty in order to be eligible for the continuation of employer-provided insurance.</summary>
</bill>
