<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="464" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:56-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="3619" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2009-10-22T19:36:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-10-22"/>
  <description>Manager's amendment makes a number of technical corrections to the bill.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 111-311 to (1) make a number of technical corrections to the bill; (2) add language regarding the delegation of authority by the Coast Guard to classification societies; (3) clarify language regarding the enforcement of Coast Guard-imposed security zones around hazardous materials terminals and tankers; and (4) address discharges incidental to the normal operation of vessels; (5) would provide for an alternative licensing program for operators of uninspected passenger vessels on Lake Texoma in Texas and Oklahoma upon request of the Texas or Oklahoma Governors; (6) would require the Coast Guard's study of biometric identification to include facial and iris scan technology, would require the Homeland Security Secretary to study the Coast Guard's use of the combination of facial and iris recognition to rapidly identify individuals for security purposes, and would state the purpose of the study is to facilitate the use of a combination of facial and iris recognition; (7) would require the secretary of the Department of the Coast Guard is operating to report to Congress on the most common types of human errors that have led to oil spills from vessels, the most common types of `near miss' oil spill incidents, and includes recommendations to address these errors, and also re.uire the secretary to use the findings of the report to take appropriate action domestically and at the International Maritime Organization to reduce the risk of oil spills caused by human error; (8) would provide that, in conducting mission analysis along the Rio Grande under section 1324, the Secretary shall work with all appropriate entities, as needed, to facilitate the collection of information; (9) would require the Great Lakes Maritime Institute to evaluate the employment base supported by the Great Lakes marine transportation system, including the number and types of jobs, and general demographics about the employees holding those jobs, such as their gender and age; (10) would require the secretary of the Department of the Coast Guard is operating to assess whether the use of transponders or RFIDs can be used to mitigate the threat of small boat attacks in major ports; would encourage the Secretary of State to enter into negotiations with Canada to ensure that tugboat escorts are required for certain tank ships in the Strait of Juan de Fuca, Strait of Georgia, and in Haro Strait. The Secretary would consult with the Coast Guard, which shall consult with the State of Washington and affected tribal governments; (11) would require that the GAO report to Congress on the Coast Guard's efforts to recruit minority candidates to the Coast Guard Academy, which would include recommendations for enhancing such efforts; (12) would extend for two years, through December 31, 2011, an authorization to complete an in-kind exchange of certain Coast Guard property in Portland, Maine, to the Gulf of Maine Aquarium Development Corporation. It also would provide that a new building adjacent to the pier and bulkhead must comply with the waterfront provisions of the City of Portland Code of Ordinances; (13) would require the Secretary to allow any individual with a pending application for a transportation security card, who needs to work in secure area, to have access to such area for that purpose through an escort by another individual with a security card. It also contains timelines for reviews of transportation security card applications. The Secretary shall develop a process for individuals to receive the cards at their residence.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22T19:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Oberstar.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11673-11680" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11673-11678" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2009-10-22T19:36:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Oberstar amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
