<bill session="105" type="h" number="4567" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-10T14:19:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-10T14:19:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Home Health Care Interim Payment System Refinement Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Medicare Home Health and Veterans Health Care Improvement Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to make revisions in the per beneficiary and per visit payment limits on payment for health services under the Medicare Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1998-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1998-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1998-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1998-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1998-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1998-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1998-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="1998-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400190" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="1998-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1998-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400508" joined="1998-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1998-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1998-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400294" joined="1998-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1998-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409087" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="1998-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1998-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="1998-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="1998-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1998-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400613" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400434" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1998-09-23" withdrawn="1998-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="1998-09-23" withdrawn="1998-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1998-09-23" withdrawn="1998-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1998-09-23" withdrawn="1998-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1998-09-23" withdrawn="1998-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-09-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-05T19:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 105-773, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-05T19:11:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 9, 1998.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09T12:10:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 16, 1998.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09T12:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09T12:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10243-10259" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09T12:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09T12:59:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10407-10408" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-10-10T14:19:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="516" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 412 - 2 (Roll No. 516).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3828"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid fraud"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare Payment Advisory Commission"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/1998--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Medicare Home Health Care Interim Payment System Refinement Title II: Veterans Medicare Access Improvement Title III: Authorization of Additional Exceptions to Imposition of Penalties for Certain Inducements Title IV: Expansion of Membership of the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission Title V: Revenue Offset Medicare Home Health and Veterans Health Care Improvement Act of 1998 - Title I: Medicare Home Health Care Interim Payment System Refinement - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) increase per beneficiary and per visit payment limits under the interim system of limited payments for services provided by home health agencies; and (2) provide for the exclusion of certain additional Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) costs from determination of the Medicare part B monthly premium. (Sec. 101) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) to report to the Congress on: (1) research paid for by the Secretary on the development of a prospective payment system (PPS) for Medicare home health services; (2) the schedule for PPS implementation; and (3) one or more alternative means to provide for savings equivalent to the savings estimated to be made by the mandatory 15 percent reduction in payment limits for such home health services for FY 2000. Directs the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC) to: (1) report to the Congress its analysis of the Secretary's report, including any recommendations; and (2) include in its annual report to the Congress for June 1999 an analysis of whether changes in law made by the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 (BBA '97) and this Act with respect to payments for Medicare home health services impede access to them by Medicare beneficiaries. Directs the Comptroller General of the United States to audit the sums obligated or expended by the Health Care Financing Administration for PPS research and the information it has provided. Title II: Veterans Medicare Access Improvement - Amends SSA title XVIII, as amended by BBA '97, for the express purpose of improving certain veterans' access to Medicare health care services through a jointly administered program and related demonstration project under the jurisdiction of the Secretary and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs. Describes such program and demonstration project, the sites where they will be conducted, and their duration. Provides certain funding restrictions. Repeals BBA '97 requirements relating to an implementation plan for veterans subvention. (Sec. 201) Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress on a method to phase-in the costs of military facility services furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs or the Department of Defense to Medicare-eligible beneficiaries in the calculation of an area's Medicare+Choice capitation payment. Title III: Authorization of Additional Exceptions to Imposition of Penalties for Certain Inducements - Amends SSA title XI to authorize additional exceptions to the imposition of penalties for providing inducements to beneficiaries. Provides for extension of advisory opinion authority. Title IV: Expansion of Membership of the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission - Amends SSA title XVIII to provide for the expansion of the membership of MedPAC, and stagger the initial terms of members. Title V: Revenue Offset - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise the adjusted gross income ceiling for qualified rollover contributions to a Roth Individual Retirement Account (IRA) from a non-Roth IRA. Limits application of the ceiling to the taxable year of the distribution for which the contribution applies. Increases the ceiling from $100,000 to $145,000 ($290,000 in the case of a joint return). Repeals the disallowance of a contribution for any married taxpayer filing a separate return.</summary>
</bill>
