<bill session="104" type="h" number="3814" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-24T15:35:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-07-24T15:35:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY97, Commerce, Justice, State</title>
    <title type="popular">Commerce Department FY97 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Justice Department FY97 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">State Department FY97 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of State and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Department of State and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of State and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1997, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400340"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, State, and Judiciary.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-15">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-09">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-09">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-09">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16T12:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-676, by Mr. Rogers.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-07-16T12:25:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="348">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 348.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16T20:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 479 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3814 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-17T17:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Pryce asked unanimous consent that, during consideration of the bill H.R. 3814 in the Committee of the Whole pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 479: 1. It may be in order immediately after disposition of the first amendment made in order by H. Res. 479, and without intervention of any point of order, to consider an amendment placed at the desk relating to the Advanced Technology Program, if offered by Mr. Rogers (KY); and 2. if that amendment is adopted, then points of order under clauses 2 and 6 of rule XXI shall be waived for all provisions of the bill, as amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-17T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 479 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T13:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 479.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8149-8234" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T13:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3814 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T13:34:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 479 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T13:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steve Gunderson to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T13:34:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T14:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 479, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rogers amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>LIMITATION ON DEBATE - Mr. Rogers asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Mollohan amendment be limited to one hour. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T15:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Mollohan amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mollohan asked unanimous that the time for debate on the Mollohan amendment be extended for two additional minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole resumed debate on the Mollohan amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, debate on the Radanovich amendment and all amendments thereto will continue for not to exceed 10 minutes, equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, debate on the Schroeder amendment and all amendments thereto will proceed for not to exceed 20 minutes, equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Schroeder amendment, the Chair put the question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Rogers demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later tonight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T18:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, debate on the Scott amendment and all amendments thereto, will proceed for not to exceed 20 minutes equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Scott amendment, the Chair put the question and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Scott demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later tonight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T20:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers asked unanimous consent that it be in order for the Committee to return to Title one of the bill and that the time for debate on a proposed Norton amendment to that Title be limited to 10 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T20:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unananimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norton amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T20:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Hostettler amendment, and all amendments thereto, be limited to 20 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Hostettler amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Hostettler requested a recorded vote and further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3814 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers asked unanimous consent that, during the further consider of the bill for amendment in the Committee of the Whole: 1. The remainder of the bill be considered as read, and 2. No amendment shall be in order except the following amendments, which shall be considered read, not subject to amendment or to a demand for a division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole, and debatable for the time specified:</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T20:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T20:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T20:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair announced the unfinished business to be the further consideration of those amendments on which recorded votes had been requested and postponed in the following order: The amendment by Ms. Schroeder; the amendment by Mr. Scott (VA); the amendment by Mr. Hostettler.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T21:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Goss amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T21:46:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Goss amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Goss requested a recorded vote, and further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T21:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Porter amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T21:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 5 minutes of debate on the Traficant amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T21:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mink amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T22:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Engel amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T22:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Miller (FL) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23T22:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3814 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T10:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8254-8293" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T10:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T10:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rogers amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Allard amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T10:43:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Allard amendment, the Chair put the question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Mollohan demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T10:43:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business of the Committee of the Whole was proceedings that had been postponed on amendments which had been considered earlier and on which demands for recorded votes had been tendered. Votes on amendments will be taken in the following order: Goss of Florida, and Allard of Colorado.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T11:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ensign amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T11:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Brown (CA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T11:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Deutsch of Florida amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T11:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Frank amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of July 23, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Frank (MA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T12:22:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Frank (MA) amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Fields (TX) requested a recorded vote and further consideration was postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of July 23, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T12:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of July 23, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Ganske amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T13:14:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the Ganske amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Ganske requested a recorded vote and, pending that request, made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 479 and the order of the House of July 16, 1996, further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of July 23, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Gutknecht amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the Gutknecht amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Gutknecht requested a recorded vote and further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of July 23, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hutchinson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T13:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of July 23, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norton amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of July 23, 1996, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Collins (GA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the Collins (GA) amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Collins (GA) requested a recorded vote and further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair announced the unfinished business to be further consideration of those amendments on which recorded votes had been requested and postponed in the following order: Frank (MA), Ganske, Gutknecht, and Collins (GA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3814.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Obey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8293" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-07-24T15:35:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="352" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 246 - 179 (Roll no. 352).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, State. Approved for full committee consideration with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-08-01">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-08-27">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported to Senate by Senator Gregg under the authority of the order of Aug 2, 96 with amendments. With written report No. 104-353.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-08-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="568">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 568.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAP11" subcommittee="Commerce, Justice, State, and Judiciary" name="House Appropriations"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP11" subcommittee="Commerce, Justice, State, and the Judiciary" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="479"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3610"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Antimissile missiles"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms Control and Disarmament Agency"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms control negotiations"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric research"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Automation"/>
    <term name="Automobile theft"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commission on Civil Rights"/>
    <term name="Community policing"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against the elderly"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="DNA"/>
    <term name="Death and dying"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Delinquency prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal wage"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Electric appliances"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Maritime Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Prison Industries, Inc."/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Foreign fishing"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Geodesy"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Information superhighway"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International fishery management"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International propaganda"/>
    <term name="Inventions"/>
    <term name="Japan-U.S. Friendship Commission"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Judicial reform"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laos"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legal Services Corporation"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to the poor"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine Mammal Commission"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine mammal protection"/>
    <term name="Marine mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Mass media in religion"/>
    <term name="Medical innovations"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military base conversion"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Missing in action"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Musical instruments"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research ships"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Pardons"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Physical education and training"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Population statistics"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Protection of foreign officials"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Public defenders"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Reconnaissance aircraft"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Relocation of employees"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rights of institutionalized persons"/>
    <term name="School violence"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Shellfish fisheries"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stalking"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Stock exchanges"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Surgery"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Trials"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
    <term name="United States Information Agency"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
    <term name="Whales"/>
    <term name="Wife abuse"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women prisoners"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1313"/>
    <amendment number="h1314"/>
    <amendment number="h1315"/>
    <amendment number="h1316"/>
    <amendment number="h1317"/>
    <amendment number="h1318"/>
    <amendment number="h1319"/>
    <amendment number="h1320"/>
    <amendment number="h1321"/>
    <amendment number="h1322"/>
    <amendment number="h1323"/>
    <amendment number="h1324"/>
    <amendment number="h1325"/>
    <amendment number="h1326"/>
    <amendment number="h1327"/>
    <amendment number="h1328"/>
    <amendment number="h1329"/>
    <amendment number="h1330"/>
    <amendment number="h1331"/>
    <amendment number="h1332"/>
    <amendment number="h1333"/>
    <amendment number="h1334"/>
    <amendment number="h1335"/>
    <amendment number="h1336"/>
    <amendment number="h1337"/>
    <amendment number="h1338"/>
    <amendment number="h1339"/>
    <amendment number="h1340"/>
    <amendment number="h1341"/>
    <amendment number="h1342"/>
    <amendment number="h1343"/>
    <amendment number="h1344"/>
    <amendment number="h1345"/>
    <amendment number="h1346"/>
    <amendment number="s5204"/>
    <amendment number="s5347"/>
    <amendment number="s5380"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/27/1996--Reported to Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of Justice Title II: Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Title III: The Judiciary Title IV: Department of State and Related Agencies Title V: Related Agencies Title VI: General Provisions Title VII: Rescissions (Department of Justice) Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997 - Title I: Department of Justice - Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 1997 - Makes FY 1997 appropriations to the Department of Justice. Sets forth requirements and limitations relating to use of such funds. (Sec. 103) Prohibits the use of funds to pay for an abortion, except where the life of the mother would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term, or in the case of rape. (Sec. 104) Prohibits the use of funds to require any person to perform, or facilitate the performance of, any abortion. (Sec. 109) Amends the Federal judicial code to revise: (1) quarterly bankruptcy fees; and (2) the formulae for the deposit of portions of such fees in the United States Trustee System Fund. (Sec. 110) Amends specified Federal law to establish in the Treasury the Department of Justice Telecommunications Carrier Compliance Fund, which shall be available to the Attorney General to make specified payments to telecommunications carriers, equipment manufacturers, and providers of telecommunications support services. (Sec. 111) Amends the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 to authorize use of specified funds to make supplemental grants to U.S. Attorneys Offices to provide assistance to victims of the bombing of the Alfred P. Murrah Federal Building in Oklahoma City, to facilitate their observation or participation at related trial proceedings, and to pay other related expenses. (Sec. 112) Amends the Antiterrorism and Effective Death Penalty Act of 1996 with respect to the Secretary of the Treasury's mandated study of taggants marking, rendering inert, and licensing of explosive materials. Repeals: (1) the exclusion of black or smokeless powder from such study; and (2) the requirement for congressional review of such study and congressional hearings on the Secretary's recommendations. Shortens, from 270 to 90 days, the period before proposed regulations for the addition of tracer elements to explosive materials become effective (unless modified or disapproved by an Act of Congress). (Sec. 113) Revises standards for Federal criminal law enforcement applications to judges for multipoint wiretaps and procedures for interception of wire, oral, or electronic communications. Authorizes approval of such wiretaps where there is an adequate showing of intent to thwart interception or actions and conduct that would have that effect. (Sec. 114) Amends Federal criminal law to authorize interceptions of communications in cases of certain terrorism related offenses. Title II: Department of Commerce and Related Agencies - Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997 - Makes FY 1997 appropriations to the Department of Commerce and related agencies, including the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative and the International Trade Commission. Sets forth requirements and limitations relating to use of such funds. Rescinds a specified amount of unobligated balances for operations, research, and facilities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). (Sec. 206) Provides for transfer of appropriations to successor organizations in the event the Department of Commerce is dismantled or reorganized. (Sec. 208) Prohibits the use of any funds appropriated under this or any other Act henceforth to develop new fishery management plans, amendments, or regulations which create new individual fishing quota, individual transferable quota, or new individual transferable effort allocation programs, or to implement any such plans, amendments, or regulations approved by a Regional Fishery Management Council or the Secretary of Commerce after January 4, 1995, until offsetting fees to pay for administrative costs are expressly authorized under the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act. Makes such restriction inapplicable to the North Pacific halibut and sablefish, South Atlantic wreckfish, or the Mid-Atlantic surfclam and ocean (including mahogany) quahog individual quota programs. (Sec. 210) Establishes the Bureau of the Census Working Capital Fund to cover costs of maintenance and operation of services and projects that the Director of the Census Bureau determines may be performed more advantageously when centralized. (Sec. 211) Prohibits the use of funds under this or any previous Act, or hereinafter made available to the Department of Commerce, to develop, implement or collect any user fee for any activity within the Hawaiian Islands National Humpback Whale Sanctuary or for any use of the Sanctuary or its resources. Title III: The Judiciary - Judiciary Appropriations Act, 1997 - Appropriates FY 1997 funds for activities of the Judiciary, including: (1) the Supreme Court; (2) the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit; (3) the U.S. Court of International Trade; (4) Courts of Appeals, district courts, and other judicial services; (5) the Administrative Office of the United States Courts; (6) the Federal Judicial Center; (7) Judicial Retirement Funds; and (8) the U.S. Sentencing Commission. Sets forth requirements and limitations relating to use of such funds. (Sec. 305) Extends the Judiciary Automation Fund and related authorities through FY 1998. (Sec. 306) Prohibits the use of funds available to the Judiciary for certain costs related to the appointment of Special Masters before April 26, 1996. (Sec. 307) Establishes a Commission on Structural Alternatives for the Federal Courts of Appeals, which shall report its recommendations to the President and the Congress. Authorizes appropriations. Title IV: Department of State and Related Agencies - Department of State and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997 - Appropriates FY 1997 funds for the Department of State and related agencies, programs, and trust funds (including the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency and the U.S. Information Agency). Sets forth requirements and limitations relating to use of such funds. Provides specified funds for: (1) broadcasting to Cuba; (2) the Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange Between East and West, in Hawaii; and (3) the North-South Center, in Florida. Title V: Related Agencies - Appropriates FY 1997 funds for: (1) the Maritime Administration of the Department of Transportation; (2) the Commission for the Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad; (3) the Commission on Civil Rights; (4) the Commission on Immigration Reform; (5) the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe; (6) the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission; (7) the Federal Communications Commission; (8) the Federal Maritime Commission; (9) the Federal Trade Commission; (10) the Legal Services Corporation; (11) the Marine Mammal Commission; (12) National Bankruptcy Review Commission; (13) the Securities and Exchange Commission; (14) the Small Business Administration; (15) the Gambling Impact Study Commission; (16) the Japan-United States Friendship Commission; and (17) the State Justice Institute. Continues certain requirements and restrictions with respect to use of funds by the Legal Services Corporation. Title VI: General Provisions - Sets forth limitations and prohibitions on the use of funds appropriated by this Act. (Sec. 606) Prohibits the use of funds for the construction, repair, overhaul, conversion, or modernization of vessels for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) in shipyards located outside of the United States. (Sec. 607) Expresses the sense of the Congress that equipment and products purchased under this Act should be American-made. Declares ineligible to receive any Federal contract or subcontract made with funds under this Act any person finally determined by a court or Federal agency to have intentionally affixed a false "Made in America" label to any product sold in or shipped to the United States that is not made in the United States. (Sec. 608) Prohibits the use of funds to implement, administer, or enforce any guidelines of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission covering harassment based on religion, when it is made known that such guidelines do not differ from certain proposed guidelines. (Sec. 610) Prohibits the use of funds in this Act for any United Nations peacekeeping mission involving U.S. forces under the command or control of a foreign national, if the President's military advisors have not recommended that such involvement is in the U.S. national security interest, and the President has not submitted such a recommendation to the Congress. (Sec. 611) Prohibits the use of funds in this Act to provide specified amenities or personal comforts in the Federal prison system. (Sec. 615) Prohibits funds in this Act for the Federal Bureau of Prisons from being used to distribute or make available to a prisoner any commercially published information or material that is sexually explicit or features nudity. (Sec. 620) Amends the Department of Justice Appropriation Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1980 to repeal the mandate that Department of Justice organizations notify congressional committees before reprogramming funds or taking certain other administrative actions. (Sec. 621) Prohibits any Federal agency from using funds to pay administrative expenses or compensation of any Federal officer or employee to deny certain qualified applications for permits to import U.S. origin "curios or relics" firearms, parts, or ammunition. (Sec. 622) Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to provide a guarantee or commitment to guarantee, under the Merchant Marine Act, 1936, for shipyard infrastructure development and modernization and for vessels integral to the reactivation and modernization of an eligible shipyard that receives such a guarantee. Title VII: Rescissions (Department of Justice) - Rescinds specified amounts from unobligated balances under the following headings for the Department of Justice: (1) general administration, working capital fund; and (2) Immigration and Naturalization Service, Immigration Emergency Fund.</summary>
</bill>
