<bill session="106" type="h" number="4343" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Officials Protection Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles 18 and 28, United States Code, to inhibit further intimidation of public officials within the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400426"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="3094"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Extortion"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2000--Introduced.
Public Officials Protection Act of 2000 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit: (1) intimidating, corruptly or by force, a Federal official or otherwise obstructing or impeding the performance of such official's duties; and (2) filing in any public record, or in any private record which is generally available to the public, any frivolous lien, encumbrance, or other document that attempts to create a cloud on the title of any property belonging to such an official with intent to intimidate, obstruct, or impede, or to retaliate against such official in or on account of the performance of such official's duties. Sets penalties for violations.(Sec. 3) Amends the Federal judicial code to direct the court to assess an additional penalty for filing a frivolous civil action against an officer of the United States or of any agency of a State or political subdivision thereof with intent to intimidate or obstruct, or to retaliate against, such officer.(Sec. 4) Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit specified attempts to interfere with the performance of a State officer's duties (similar to those involving Federal officers under this Act) where: (1) the mail or any facility of interstate or foreign commerce is used in furtherance of the offense; (2) any offender travels in or causes another to travel in interstate or foreign commerce in furtherance of the offense; or (3) the offense obstructs, delays, or otherwise affects interstate or foreign commerce or would have done so. Sets penalties for violations.</summary>
</bill>
