<bill session="106" type="hr" number="657" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-27">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Directing the Speaker to certify the report of the Committee on Resources to the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-10-27T10:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H11385-11398" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H11385" label="text  of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-27T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Mr. Young (AK) asked that, in the event that the amendment is agreed to, the question on adoption of the resolution be divided within section 2 so that refusal of each of the 3 named individuals will be voted on separately. The Chair responded to the effect that a division of the question, as requested, will be in order at the appropriate time. Subsequently, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 657 and on the amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-27T11:36:00-04:00">
      <text>WITHDRAWAL OF RESOLUTION - Pursuant to clause 2, rule XVI, Mr. Young (AK) withdrew H. Res. 657.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional witnesses"/>
    <term name="Contempt of legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="House Resources"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1060"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/27/2000--Introduced.
Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives to certify to the U.S. Attorney for the District of Columbia a report of the Committee on Resources regarding the refusal of specified persons to produce papers and to answer questions under subpoena before the Subcommittee on Energy and Natural Resources and the refusal of the Project on Government Oversight to produce papers subpoenaed by the Committee.</summary>
</bill>
