<bill session="104" type="h" number="3820" updated="2012-11-01T22:45:23-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-25T16:56:00-05:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-07-25T16:56:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Campaign Finance Reform bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campaign Finance Reform Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to reform the financing of Federal election campaigns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404009" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404587" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="406863" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408553" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409228" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="411214" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="411247" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1996-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-17T23:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 481 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3820 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T13:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 481 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T13:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 481. (CR H8470-8516)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8470-8516" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T13:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3820 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T13:12:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 481 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T13:12:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Bob Inglis to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T13:13:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T14:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 481, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Fazio amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T16:06:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3820.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T16:06:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T16:07:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 481.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T16:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Fazio moved to recommit with instructions to House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T16:12:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fazio motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T16:22:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T16:39:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 209 - 212 (Roll no. 364). (CR H8514-8516)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8514-8516" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE" datetime="1996-07-25T16:56:00-05:00">
      <text>On passage Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 162 - 259 (Roll no. 365).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T16:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Business and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election statistics"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Facsimile transmission"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor union finances"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Labor unions and social problems"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political paraphernalia"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Population statistics"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Term limits"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Union dues"/>
    <term name="Union security"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in politics"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>07/25/1996--Failed of passage in House.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;(There is 1 &lt;a href="/cgi-bin/bdquery/z?d104:HR03820:@@@D&amp;summ1&amp;"&gt;other summary&lt;/a&gt;).
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Restoring Control of Elections to Individuals Title II: Strengthening Political Parties Title III: Disclosure and Enforcement Title IV: Worker Right to Know Title V: General Provisions Campaign Finance Reform Act of 1996 - Title I: Restoring Control of Elections to Individuals - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit a candidate for the office of Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress from accepting contributions from individuals other than local individual residents which exceed the total amount of contributions accepted from local individual residents. Sets forth penalties for exceeding contribution limitations. (Sec. 102) Decreases allowable contribution amounts for multicandidate political action committees in Federal elections. Limits political party committee contributions. (Sec. 103) Modifies the limitations on contributions for an opposition candidate when a candidate spends or contributes amounts exceeding personal fund spending limitations. Requires the principal campaign committee of a House candidate to submit certain notifications of expenditures or contributions of such personal funds. (Sec. 105) Prohibits a candidate for Federal office or an individual holding Federal office from establishing or controlling a political committee, other than a principal campaign committee. (Sec. 106) Prohibits bundling of contributions to candidates for Federal office by political action committees and lobbyists. (Sec. 107) Redefines the term "independent expenditure." (Sec. 108) Sets forth requirements for the use of payroll deductions for campaign contributions. Title II: Strengthening Political Parties - Modifies contribution limits with respect to contributions made by an individual to a political party or a political party committee. Limits contributions made by individuals to State political parties. (Sec. 202) Allows political parties to offset funds carried over from previous elections. (Sec. 203) Set forth limitations on the use of funds not subject to the limitations of the Act. (Sec. 204) Permits national and State political party committees (including any subordinate committee of a State committee) to exclude from expenditure limits any amounts expended by the committee for communications with party members. Prohibits such exclusion when the communication expressly advocates the election or defeat of a specific candidate for election to Federal office and other conditions are met. (Sec. 205) Excludes from the definition of "contribution" State or local political party committee payments for specified volunteer and grassroots activities. Requires that all State and local party committees allocate their expenses for mixed activities based on a specified ballot composition method. Title III: Disclosure and Enforcement - Modifies political committee reporting requirements, including requiring: (1) certain reports to be made available within 24 hours; (2) making reports available on the Internet; (3) certain reporting by secondary campaign committees; (4) additional post election reporting; and (5) certain information on aggregate contributions. (Sec. 302) Revises Federal Election Commission (the Commission) rules and procedures, including provisions concerning: (1) judicial interpretation standards; (2) requiring written responses to certain questions; (3) oral arguments before the Commission; (4) publication of an index to advisory opinions; (5) treating commercial loans not as contributions; (6) abolishing the Ex-Officio membership of the Clerk of the House on the Commission; (7) granting the Commission the authority to waive reporting requirements, if consistent with the purposes of the Act; (8) solicitations by corporations or labor organizations; (9) protections against force and reprisals; (10) payments on behalf of a candidate; and (11) partnership contributions. Title IV: Worker Right to Know - Amends the National Labor Relations Act (NLRA) to limit the scope of allowable union security agreements to requiring employee payment of union dues or fees related only to collective bargaining, contract administration, or grievance adjustment necessary to performing the duties of exclusive representation. (Sec. 404) Requires, under NLRA, employee consent in an annual signed written agreement before a union may accept that employee's payment of dues or fees for purposes beyond the scope of the union security agreement as limited by this Act. Requires such an agreement to include a ratio of the dues or fees related to the limited purposes and those related to other purposes. Amends the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947 to prohibit payroll deduction for union dues unrelated to the limited scope purposes, unless a written agreement authorizes such deduction. (Sec. 405) Requires, under NLRA, employers to post notice of worker rights to organize and collectively bargain, as well as of the limited scope of any union security agreement. (Sec. 406) Amends the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 to require every labor union to attribute and report expenses by function classification in detail necessary to allow its members to determine whether such expenses were related to collective bargaining, contract administration, or grievance adjustment necessary to performing the duties of exclusive representation or were related to other purposes. Requires disclosure under such Act to employees required to pay any union dues or fees (under a union security agreement) as well as to union members. Directs the Secretary of Labor to prescribe related regulations. Title V: General Provisions - Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) effective date; (2) severability; and (3) Supreme Court review of Constitutional issues.</summary>
</bill>
