<bill session="108" type="h" number="3962" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Support for Military Reserve Families Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to establish a program of interest-free loans to members of the Selected Reserve who experience financial hardship due to service on active duty in the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400369"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Garnishment"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2004--Introduced.
Support for Military Reserve Families Act of 2004 - Directs the Secretary of Defense to establish, for members of the Ready Reserve (including the Coast Guard Reserve), a loan program to be known as the Ready Reserve Mobilization Loan Program. Directs the Secretary, upon application, to make a Program loan to a Ready Reserve member who has one or more dependents enrolled in the Department of Defense Enrollment Eligibility Reporting System for any period during which the member performs active duty under an involuntary call or order to active duty in support of a contingency operation if: (1) the income of the member during such service is less than the member's income before being called or ordered to such service; and (2) the member incurs a financial hardship by reason of such service. Prohibits such loans from being used for investment purposes. Allows loan amounts of up to $500 for each full month of covered service. Makes such loans interest-free for: (1) five years after the end of such service, if the service is for less than 12 consecutive months; or (2) ten years after the end of such service, if the service is for 12 consecutive months or more. Mandates a five percent interest rate thereafter. Requires such loans to be repaid within the same period as the interest-free period, above.</summary>
</bill>
