<bill session="106" type="h" number="4203" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Over-the-Counter Derivatives Systemic Risk Reduction Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a comprehensive regulatory framework over the clearing of over-the-counter derivative instruments that will operate under the supervision of the Federal banking agencies, to clarify the lawfulness of the use of multilateral clearing systems for over-the-counter derivative instrument transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="2000-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, Agriculture, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Risk Management, Research and Specialty Crops.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG28" subcommittee="Risk Management, Research and Specialty Crops" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Corporate liquidations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Derivative securities"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange futures"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="International banking"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Options (Contract)"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Swaps (Finance)"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2000--Introduced.
Over-the-Counter Derivatives Systemic Risk Reduction Act of 2000 - States that the operation of a multilateral clearing organization for over-the-counter derivative instruments is limited to: (1) banks; and (2) certain corporations chartered under the Federal Reserve Act.Sets forth rules of construction to emphasize that the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and the Securities and Exchange Commission retain their inherent jurisdiction over the trading and clearing activities within their respective purviews.States that a multilateral clearing organization under the jurisdiction of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (the Board) or the Comptroller of the Currency does not fall within the jurisdiction of any other Federal entity as a result of clearing any over-the-counter derivative instrument.States that no over-the-counter instrument to which a financial institution is a party shall be subject to rescission or held unenforceable based solely on the regulatory status or jurisdiction over such instrument under Federal or State law.Provides that an over-the-counter instrument does not fall within the purview of the Commodity Exchange Act as a consequence of being the subject of an electronic trade or communication.Authorizes the Board to appoint a conservator or receiver to take possession and control of a State bank which operates, or operates as, a multilateral clearing organization in the same manner as the Comptroller of the Currency may do so.</summary>
</bill>
