<bill session="107" type="h" number="5503" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National All Schedules Prescription Electronic Reporting Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish an electronic system for practitioner monitoring of the dispensing of any schedule II, III, or IV controlled substance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400431"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2002-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400135" joined="2002-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="2002-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2002-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2002-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2002-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2002-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2002-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="3033"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medication abuse"/>
    <term name="Narcotics"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Physician-patient privilege"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2002--Introduced.
National All Schedules Prescription Electronic Reporting Act of 2002 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to establish an electronic system for practitioner monitoring of the dispensing of any schedule II, III, or IV controlled substance to patients. Directs dispensers to report the information required under this Act to the Secretary as prescribed by the Secretary, with specified exceptions.Requires the Secretary to specify the electronic format for the reporting of the information required under this Act, but allows the Secretary to waive the required format for an individual dispenser. Allows the Secretary to provide information from the monitoring system to practitioners and specified government personnel under certain circumstances. States that this Act shall not preclude any authority from securing information as otherwise authorized by law.Directs the Secretary to make reasonable efforts to implement a real-time electronic system.Specifies the circumstances in which information provided by the Secretary from the monitoring system can lawfully be subsequently transmitted.Assesses civil monetary penalties for the failure to communicate information requested by the Secretary and for the unauthorized disclosure of information transmitted by the Secretary. Allows a State to have its own prescription monitoring system to the exclusion of the Federal program so long as the State system provides the information required by this Act to the Federal program in a fashion set forth by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
