<bill session="108" type="hc" number="143" updated="2013-07-14T19:03:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Relating to the prosecution of Saddam Hussein and other Iraqi officials, military leaders, and citizens who may be responsible for crimes against humanity, attempted genocide, and war crimes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400045"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2003-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aggression"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2003--Introduced.
Recognizes the necessity to pursue justice and national reconciliation in Iraq through the establishment of a special court or other appropriate tribunal or commission which should adjudicate the cases of those accused of bearing greatest responsibility for war crimes and crimes against humanity, including prosecuting Saddam Hussein and other Iraqi officials, military leaders, and other citizens who may have committed crimes in contravention of the Hague and Geneva Conventions on the laws of war. Considers the International Criminal Court not to be the appropriate forum for the prosecution of such crimes since that court only has jurisdiction to hear cases relating to crimes committed after July 1, 2002. Calls upon the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State to notify Congress of the steps the United States and allied coalition nations are taking to seek justice for the violations of international law against the Iraqi people and others.</summary>
</bill>
