<bill session="106" type="h" number="5049" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fderal Water Pollution Control Act to increase efforts to prevent and reduce contamination of navigable waters by methyl tertiary butyl ether, tetrachloroethylene, and trichloroethylene, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400213"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Cleaning industry"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Groundwater pollution"/>
    <term name="Nonpoint source pollution"/>
    <term name="Oxygenates"/>
    <term name="Reformulated gasoline"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Solvents"/>
    <term name="Underground petroleum tanks"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2000--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to engage in research and studies on the removal of methyl tertiary butyl ether from waters.Extends the authorization of appropriations to carry out water pollution prevention and control investigations, training, and information activities through FY 2004.Adds to the list of State programs that may receive priority for water quality management grants those that control problems resulting from storage tank petroleum releases and problems involving the presence of dry cleaning solvents in groundwater or surface water.Extends through FY 2004 the authorization of appropriations for grants for water quality protection programs and groundwater quality protection. Increases the maximum amount available for groundwater quality protection grants.</summary>
</bill>
