<bill session="105" type="h" number="823" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airport and Airway Trust Fund Tax Reinstatement Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reinstate the Airport and Airway Trust Fund excise taxes and to suspend the 4.3-cent general revenue portion of such taxes during the reinstatement period.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400547"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1997-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1997-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/1997--Introduced.
Airport and Airway Trust Fund Tax Reinstatement Act of 1997 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to restore the Airport and Airway Trust Fund excise taxes. Extends authority to transfer revenue to such Fund. (Sec. 3) Reduces by 4.3 cents the excise tax rate on various transportation motor fuels. Prohibits the taxation on any sale or use of compressed natural gas beginning six days after enactment of this Act until October 1, 1997. (Sec. 4) Sets forth the procedure for filing a claim for a credit or refund for any such tax imposed on any liquid prior to the seventh day after enactment of this Act. (Sec. 5) Imposes a floor stocks tax of 4.3 cents per gallon on any liquid on which such fuel tax was imposed before October 1, 1997, and which is held on such date by any person. Sets forth provisions on method of payment and exceptions to such tax. (Sec. 6) Expresses the sense of the Congress that consumers receive the benefit of such excise tax reduction and that transportation motor fuels producers and dealers take necessary action to reduce fuel prices to reflect such tax reduction. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to the Congress on whether there has been a pass through to consumers because of such fuel tax reduction.</summary>
</bill>
