<bill session="108" type="h" number="4683" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-28T15:22:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-28T15:22:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gullah/Geechee Cultural Heritage Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Gullah/Geechee Cultural Heritage Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance the preservation and interpretation of the Gullah/Geechee cultural heritage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2004-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Radanovich moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7666-7669" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4683.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-09-28T15:22:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7666-7668" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Black history"/>
    <term name="Blacks"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Social life and customs"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2004--Passed House amended.
Gullah/Geechee Cultural Heritage Act - Establishes the Gullah/Geechee Cultural Heritage Corridor (Heritage Corridor) to: (1) recognize the important contributions made to American culture and history by African-Americans known as the Gullah/Geechee who settled in the coastal counties of South Carolina and Georgia; (2) assist State and local governments and public and private entities in South Carolina and Georgia in interpreting the story of the Gullah/Geechee and preserving Gullah/Geechee folklore, arts, crafts, and music; and (3) assist in identifying and preserving sites, historical data, artifacts, and objects associated with the Gullah/Geechee for the benefit and education of the public. Provides that the Heritage Corridor shall be comprised of lands and waters depicted on a map entitled "Gullah/Geechee Cultural Heritage Corridor" dated September 2004 and on file at the National Park Service. Establishes the Gullah/Geechee Cultural Heritage Corridor Commission (Commission) to assist Federal, State, and local authorities to develop and implement a management plan for Gullah/Geechee lands and waters. Sets forth the duties of the Commission, including the preparation and submission of a management plan to the Secretary of the Interior and annual reporting to the Secretary. Authorizes the Commission to make grants and enter into cooperative agreements with the States of South Carolina and Georgia to prepare and implement the management plan. Sets forth criteria for developing a management plan for the Heritage Corridor. Requires the Commission to submit the management plan to the Secretary for approval not later than three years after the funding of this Act. Requires the Secretary to approve or disapprove (citing reasons) the management plan within 90 days after receiving the plan. Provides for technical and financial assistance to the Commission. Requires the Commission to establish one or more Coastal Heritage Centers in the Heritage Corridor in accordance with the Low Country Gullah Culture Special Resource Study and Environmental Impact Study, December 2003. Sets forth protections for private landowners in the Heritage Corridor. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the authorities under this Act 15 years after enactment.</summary>
</bill>
