<bill session="106" type="hc" number="312" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-27T14:24:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-06-27T14:24:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress that the States should more closely regulate title pawn transactions and outlaw the imposition of usurious interest rates on title loans to consumers.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress that the Federal Government and the States should engage in greater oversight of title loan and title pawn transactions, work cooperatively to address the problem of abuses in title loan and title pawn transactions through effective legislation at both the Federal and State level, as necessary, and ensure that any Federal legislative effort preserves the ability of the States to enact stronger protections for consumers with respect to such transactions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="2000-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T10:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Roukema moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T10:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5179-5181" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T10:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 312.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T11:10:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T14:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5205-5206" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-06-27T14:24:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="331" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 420 - 6 (Roll no. 331).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5180" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Pawnbroking"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Usury"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2000--Passed House amended.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the Federal Government and the States should: (1) engage in greater oversight of title loan and title pawn transactions; (2) work cooperatively to address the problem of abuses in title loan and title pawn transactions through effective legislation at both the Federal and State level, as necessary, including by prohibiting title pawn transactions and prohibiting usurious interest rates in title loan transactions; and (3) ensure that any Federal legislative effort preserves the ability of the States to enact stronger protections for consumers with respect to such transactions.</summary>
</bill>
