<bill session="106" type="h" number="5196" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Human Rights Investment Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote, protect, and enhance democracy and human rights in United States foreign policy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="2000-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-09-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1514"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1514-1515" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Assassination"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights workers"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Police brutality"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Police-community relations"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Victims"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2000--Introduced.
Human Rights Investment Act of 2000 - Earmarks for FY 2001 and each subsequent fiscal year a specified percentage of amounts made available to the Department of State for diplomatic and consular programs for salaries and expenses of the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor, including funding of positions at U.S. missions abroad that are primarily dedicated to following human rights developments in foreign countries.Establishes a Human Rights and Democracy Fund to be administered by the Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights and Labor. Sets forth the purposes of the Fund, including to: (1) support defenders of human rights and assist the victims of human rights violations; and (2) promote and encourage the growth of democracy, including the support for nongovernmental organizations in other countries. Authorizes appropriations.Directs the Secretary of State to establish and implement a program to monitor U.S. military assistance and arms transfers to ensure to maximum extent feasible that U.S. military assistance and weapons manufactured in or sold from the United States are not used: (1) to commit gross violations of human rights; or (2) to violate other U.S. laws applicable to U.S. military assistance and arms transfers that are also related to human rights and preventing human rights violations. Earmarks for each fiscal year after FY2000 a specified percentage of amounts appropriated for each fiscal year for U.S. military assistance to carry out such program.Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to direct the Secretary to report annually to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and a specified congressional committee about: (1) each country in which extrajudicial killings, torture, or other serious violations of human rights have occurred; and (2) the extent to which the United States has taken or will take action to encourage an end to such practices in the country.Authorizes appropriations for the Department of State to carry out the National Endowment for Democracy Act.</summary>
</bill>
