<bill session="105" type="h" number="1209" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Defense of the Environment Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the defense of the environment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400425"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1997-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E558"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental degradation"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Groundwater pollution"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/1997--Introduced.
Defense of the Environment Act of 1997 - Requires any report of a congressional committee or committee of conference accompanying a public bill or joint resolution that includes any provision that reduces environmental protection to contain: (1) an identification and description of the provision; (2) an assessment of the extent of such reduction; (3) a description of any actions to avoid such reduction; and (4) any statement received from the Comptroller General, upon request of the committee or a majority of either the minority or majority members of the committee, assessing the reduction. Deems a provision to reduce environmental protection if it may: (1) allow increased pollution; (2) adversely affect the environmental quality of public lands or diminish protection of species that may be endangered; (3) increase children's exposure to environmental contaminants and other environmental risks; or (4) have the effect of shielding environmental law violators or limiting judicial review of agency action under authority of any environmental law. Provides for consultation and assistance of the Comptroller General at the request of any committee. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to ensure that, before proposing or promulgating any major rule, the responsible agency has conducted an analysis of any provision that reduces environmental protection. Makes out of order in the House of Representatives and the Senate the consideration of any reported bill or joint resolution, or conference report, unless the committee has complied with the identification and assessment provisions of this Act. Makes any rule waiving these provisions out of order in the House. Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives with respect to the consideration and striking of provisions reducing environmental protection within the meaning of this Act. Provides Senate procedures for the striking of such provisions.</summary>
</bill>
