<bill session="108" type="h" number="1204" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-18T19:09:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-11-18T19:09:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 to establish requirements for the award of concessions in the National Wildlife Refuge System, to provide for maintenance and repair of properties located in the System by concessionaires authorized to use such properties, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400385"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04T12:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-347.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-04T12:09:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="204">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 204.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18T19:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Souder moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18T19:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/19/2003 H11446-11448" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18T19:05:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1204.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-11-18T19:09:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/19/2003 H11446-11447" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18T19:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2003--Passed House amended.
Amends the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 to prohibit the Secretary of the Interior from authorizing a person to use any land or water in the National Wildlife Refuge System for any commercial activity conducted to provide accommodations, facilities, or services for visitors' recreational, educational, or interpretive enjoyment of System lands or waters, except under a standardized concession contract established pursuant to this Act. Excludes certain activities from coverage of such requirement, including volunteer and government activities and the operation of a bookstore in a refuge facility by a national wildlife refuge Friends organization, as well as performance of any authorized guide or outfitter services. Exempts from such standardized contract requirement administrative sites, visitor facilities, and revenue producing visitor services mandated or authorized pursuant to the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, to issue regulations that authorize a contract to use a provision other than those specified by the Secretary as part of a standardized contract, subject to certain conditions. Directs the Secretary to require in each contract provisions requiring any activity conducted in the System under the contract to be: (1) a compatible use; and (2) designed to conserve the System's natural and cultural resources, facilitate the enjoyment of System lands and waters, and enhance visitors' knowledge of the natural resources. Requires the Secretary to include in any such contract provisions that: (1) authorize the person to maintain or repair any improvement on or in such land or water that the person is authorized to use; and (2) treat costs incurred by the person for such maintenance or repair as consideration otherwise required to be paid to the United States for such use. Makes available to the Secretary for specified expenditures any amounts received by the United States as fees or other payments required under any contract for use of real property located in an area of the System, other than lands withdrawn for Native selection pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act. Directs the Secretary to: (1) include in the comprehensive conservation plan for each refuge a description of the activities that may be conducted in the refuge and the lands, water, and facilities of the refuge that may be used under concession contracts; and (2) report by December 31 each year to specified congressional committees on concessions activities in the System.</summary>
</bill>
