<bill session="104" type="h" number="4289" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Trade Opportunities Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a more effective remedy for inadequate trade benefits extended to the United States by other countries and for restrictions on free emigration imposed by other countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Emigration"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1996--Introduced.
Fair Trade Opportunities Act - Amends the Trade Act of 1975 to repeal Title IV (Trade Relations with Countries not Currently Receiving Nondiscriminatory Treatment) (Jackson Vanick Act). Directs the President to consult with the appropriate congressional committees and determine whether each foreign country that is not a member of the World Trade Organization (WTO) is not according adequate trade benefits or substantially equal competitive opportunities to U.S. commerce. Mandates an increase in the rate of duty with respect to the products of such a country. Authorizes the President to increase such rate on any product of a non-market economy country that is not a WTO member if it: (1) denies its citizens the right or opportunity to emigrate; (2) imposes more than a nominal tax on emigration documents, for any purpose; or (3) imposes more than a nominal tax, fine, fee or other charge on any citizen as a consequence of such citizen's desire to emigrate to a country of his or her choice.</summary>
</bill>
