<bill session="113" type="h" number="687" updated="2013-07-17T15:53:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate the efficient extraction of mineral resources in southeast Arizona by authorizing and directing an exchange of Federal and non-Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2013-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 19.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="339"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2013--Introduced.
Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013 - Authorizes and directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) (the Secretary), if Resolution Copper Mining, LLC offers to convey specified parcels of non-federal land in Gila, Yavapi, Maricopa, Coconino, Pinal, and/or Santa Cruz Counties, Arizona, that are acceptable to the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior, to convey certain federal land in Pinal County, Arizona, to Resolution Copper. Makes the federal lands available to Resolution Copper for use for mining and related activities. Requires the Secretary, if so requested by Resolution Copper, to issue separate special use permits to it to carry out mineral exploration activities: (1) under the Oak Flat Withdrawal Area from existing drill pads outside the Area, if they would not disturb the surface of the area; and (2) within the Withdrawal Area (with the exception of within the Oak Flat Campground), if they are conducted from a single exploratory drill pad which is located to minimize visual and noise impacts on the Campground. Makes lands acquired by the Secretary under this Act part of the National Forest within which the land is located. Adds certain of the non-federal land acquired by the Secretary of the Interior in Pinal and Santa Cruz Counties to the San Pedro Riparian and Las Cienegas National Conservation Areas, respectively. Instructs Resolution Copper to surrender, without compensation, the rights held by it under mining and other U.S. laws to commercially extract minerals under Apache Leap. Requires Resolution Copper to make value adjustment payments to the United States based upon locatable minerals produced from the federal land in Pinal County, Arizona. Authorizes the Secretary to issue to Resolution Copper special use permits that allow it to carry out underground activities (other than the commercial extraction of minerals) under the surface of Apache Leap that would not disturb the surface. Requires preparation of a management plan for Apache Leap. Directs the Secretary to convey specified lands in Pinal County to the town of Superior, Arizona.</summary>
</bill>
