<bill session="105" type="h" number="534" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transition to Work Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide as a demonstration project a Transition to Work Program for individuals entitled to disability benefits under title II of the Social Security Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1997-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1997-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1997-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1997-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1997-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1997-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E142"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/1997--Introduced.
Transition to Work Act of 1997 - Directs the Commissioner of Social Security to establish a demonstration Transition to Work Program (TWP) as a demonstration project in appropriate localities to determine the best practicable means of providing certain eligible individuals entitled to disability benefits under title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act (SSA) (social security disability benefits) prompt access to vocational rehabilitation services in order to move them to work. Requires each certified participating vocational rehabilitation service provider (which may be public or private) to develop a transition to work plan jointly with an individual (and subject to his or her approval), taking into account an employment evaluation. Includes in TWP the Ticket for Work Opportunity (TWO) Program under which the Commissioner issues a TWO to an eligible disabled individual to present to a provider for payment for the services rendered which result in a successful return to work. Outlines provider certification requirements. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a refundable tax credit (adjusted for inflation and subject to eventual phaseout) for a specified percentage of earned income to an eligible disabled individual whose social security disability entitlement has ceased because of ability to engage in substantial gainful employment; and (2) provide for advance payment of such disabled worker credit by the individual's employer. Amends SSA titles II and XVIII (Medicare) to: (1) provide for an additional two years of Medicare continuation coverage after an individual first leaves the social security disability roll to return to work; and (2) provide that afterwards (Medicare would now continue for a total of six years after the individual first began to work) such individuals who retained employment and made over $15,000 per year would be allowed to buy-in to Medicare part A (Hospital Insurance) based on a capped, income-related premium, with those earning less than $15,000 per year continuing to get Medicare part A coverage free.</summary>
</bill>
