<bill session="104" type="hr" number="291" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-07T12:52:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-12-07T12:52:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the further conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 2099) making appropriations for the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and for sundry independent agencies, boards, commissions, corporations, and offices for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408976"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-12-06T19:00:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-385, by Mr. Quillen.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-06T19:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2099. Providing for the consideration of the further conference report to accompany the bill H.R. 2099. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration, and against the motion printed in the joint explanatory statement of the committee of conference to dispose of Senate amendment No. 63, shall be waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motion except debate pursuant to clause 2(b)(1) of rule XXVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-12-06T19:00:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="144">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 144.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-12-07T11:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14182-14187" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-07T11:56:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-07T12:33:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-12-07T12:52:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="842" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 242 - 175 (Roll no. 842).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-07T12:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="2099"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/6/1995--Introduced.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the further conference report on H.R. 2099 (Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development and certain independent agencies and entities appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
