<bill session="106" type="h" number="1302" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sales Incentive Compensation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exempt from the minimum wage recordkeeping and overtime compensation requirements certain specialized employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400036"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1999-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Sales personnel"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1999--Introduced.
Sales Incentive Compensation Act - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exempt from minimum wage recordkeeping and overtime compensation requirements any employee in a sales position, if: (1) the employee has specialized or technical knowledge related to products or services being sold; (2) the employee's sales are predominantly to persons who are entities to whom the employee has made previous sales or the employee's position does not involve initiating sales contacts; (3) the employee has a detailed understanding of customers' needs and exercises discretion in offering a variety of products and services; (4) the employee receives a base compensation at a specified minimum rate and additional compensation based on sales attributable to the employee; (5) the employee's aggregate compensation based upon sales reaches a specified minimum level; and (6) the rate of annual compensation or base compensation for an employee who did not work for an employer for an entire calendar year is prorated to reflect annual compensation which would have been earned if the employee had been compensated at the same rate for the entire calendar year. Makes this Act inapplicable to individuals employed as route sales drivers.</summary>
</bill>
