<bill session="108" type="hr" number="428" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-05T13:03:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-11-05T13:03:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1829) to amend title 18, United States Code, to require Federal Prison Industries to compete for its contracts minimizing its unfair competition with private sector firms and their non-inmate workers and empowering Federal agencies to get the best value for taxpayers' dollars, to provide a five-year period during which Federal Prison Industries adjusts to obtaining inmate work opportunities through other than its mandatory source status, to enhance inmate access to remedial and vocational opportunities and other rehabilitative opportunities to better prepare inmates for a successful return to society, to authorize alternative inmate work opportunities in support of non-profit organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04T18:50:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 108-348, by Mrs. Myrick.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04T18:50:00-05:00">
      <text>It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-11-04T18:50:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="122">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 122.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-11-05T12:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10374-10376" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-05T12:36:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 428.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-05T13:03:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2003-11-05T13:03:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10374" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-11-05T13:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="h" number="1829"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/2003--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 1829 (Federal Prison Industries Competition in Contracting Act of 2003).</summary>
</bill>
