<bill session="108" type="h" number="1427" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Heritage Areas Policy Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the criteria and mechanisms for the designation of certain areas in the United States containing nationally important natural, historic, and cultural resources and recreational and educational opportunities that are geographically assembled and thematically related as areas that provide unique frameworks for understanding the great and diverse character of the United States and the development of communities and their surroundings as national heritage areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Social life and customs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2003--Introduced.
National Heritage Areas Policy Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to recommend to Congress that an area or corridor be designated as a national heritage area (area) only if, within five years of the authorization to conduct a feasibility study, the Secretary has: (1) determined that the area contains resources of national importance and is suitable for such designation; (2) approved a management plan that includes a business plan; and (3) provided for the consideration of local property owners within the boundaries of the proposed area.Outlines process and content requirements applicable to feasibility studies concerning the designation of an area.Requires the local coordinating entity for the proposed area to prepare a management plan containing specified requirements. Provides for approval or disapproval of such plan by the Secretary.Authorizes the Secretary to make: (1) five-year grants for proposed areas; and (2) ten-year grants to support designated areas.Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance on a non-reimbursable basis to any interested party or local coordinating entity for any activity for which the Secretary is authorized to provide a grant.Directs the Secretary to provide written notice to a local coordinating entity of the termination of designation of an area.Provides: (1) private property protections; (2) savings provisions; and (3) funding for grants, technical assistance, and feasibility studies authorized under this Act. Requires grant recipients to provide matching funds.</summary>
</bill>
