<bill session="104" type="h" number="2580" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-11-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Republican Form of Government Guarantee Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To guarantee a republican form of government to the States by preventing paramilitary violence.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1996-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1995-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1995-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="406082" joined="1995-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1995-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1995-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Extortion"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Local officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Political rights"/>
    <term name="Postal crimes"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/2/1995--Introduced.
Republican Form of Government Guarantee Act - Revises Federal criminal code provisions setting penalties for assaulting, resisting, intimidating, or impeding any of specified U.S. officers and employees (including Federal judges), to: (1) cover persons who commit such acts against State or local government officers or employees or persons assisting such officers or employees in the performance of official duty; and (2) increase penalties for such acts. Sets a minimum term of two years' imprisonment for: (1) transmitting in interstate or foreign commerce any communication containing a threat to kidnap or injure any person; and (2) depositing, or causing to be delivered, any communication threatening to kidnap or injure any person. Declares that each person not otherwise disqualified, barred, or disabled by State or Federal law shall have the right to participate in a republican form of State government free from interference from unlawful violence and the reasonably perceived threat of such violence. Creates a private cause of action, as well as a government remedy (enforceable by the chief executive officer of any State) against any individual or organization for a violation of that right. Authorizes the court to award a reasonable attorney's fee to a prevailing plaintiff. Sets a five-year statute of limitations that begins with the date of discovery of the violation. Directs the Attorney General to develop and implement a training program for Federal law enforcement personnel to enable them to deal more effectively with politically motivated violence. Authorizes an agency that determines that an agency employee or agent is being unlawfully and physically prevented from carrying out lawful duties by employees or agents of a State, county, or local government, to file a complaint with the Attorney General. Directs the Attorney General to investigate the complaint and, if the Attorney General finds the complaint is meritorious, to place in escrow any payments that otherwise would be made to that county under the Payments in Lieu of Taxes Act of 1976 until such time as such interference has ceased.</summary>
</bill>
