<bill session="104" type="h" number="4311" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow penalty-free withdrawals from IRA's for certain purposes, to increase the amount of tax deductible IRA contributions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grandparents"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Unemployed"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1996--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow penalty-free (and exclude from income if repaid) distributions from an individual retirement account (IRA) for first home purchases, higher education expenses, qualified long-term care expenses, and qualified unemployment distributions. Increases deductible IRA contribution amounts, and provides for inflation indexing. Eliminates the phase-out for individuals who are not active participants in defined contribution plans, and increases applicable dollar amounts for taxpayers other than those married filing separately. Increases 401(k) plan contribution limits. Establishes an alternative method for satisfying nondiscrimination requirements. Excludes inherited IRAs and certain 401(k) plans from a decedent's gross estate. Allows a designated beneficiary of an inherited IRA to hold such IRA free of immediate distribution provisions. Allows inherited 401(k) amounts as nondeductible contributions to a beneficiary's IRA, and excludes such amounts from income if so contributed.</summary>
</bill>
