<bill session="107" type="h" number="5210" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Beverage Producer Responsibility Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require implementation by brand owners of management plans that provide refund values for certain beverage containers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400528"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="2220"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Beverage containers"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Glass recycling"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Paper recycling"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Plastics recycling"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Soft drink industry"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2002--Introduced.
National Beverage Producer Responsibility Act of 2002 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require beverage brand owners (trademark owners, manufacturers, distributors, or importers of beverages sold in containers) to implement effective redemption, transportation, processing, marketing, and reporting systems for the reuse and recycling of their used beverage containers.Prohibits the sale of a beverage in a beverage container unless a clear refund value statement prominently appears on the container.Requires each beverage container agency (the brand owner or an entity acting as its agent) to submit to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency a recycling management plan subject to the Administrator's approval and a fee to cover administrative costs.Requires sellers of beverages to collect from each purchaser at the time of sale a deposit no greater than a specified minimum refund value and pay the refund value upon container returns either in cash or in the form of a voucher.Establishes a recovery rate performance standard and penalties for failure to achieve such rate. Requires arbitration to settle disputes between a beverage container agency and a return site.Imposes penalties for violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
