<bill session="107" type="h" number="5163" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Zuni Indian Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To approve the settlement of the water rights claims of the Zuni Indian Tribe in Apache County, Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400173"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="2002-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2002-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="2743"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2002--Introduced.
Zuni Indian Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act of 2002 - Ratifies the Settlement Agreement concerning Zuni Indian Tribe water rights claims in the Little Colorado River basin, Arizona.Includes the provision of assistance for acquiring surface water rights, the use of groundwater, and wetland restoration. Names the Tribe, the State of Arizona and specified state agencies, specified neighboring non-Indian communities, and specified water and power companies as parties to the agreement.Directs the Secretary of the Interior to execute the Settlement Agreement and subsequent, mutually agreed upon amendments.Establishes and authorizes appropriations to the Zuni Indian Tribe Water Rights Development Fund to be allocated among specified activities, including the acquisition of water rights and restoration at the Zuni Heaven Reservation. Includes funds paid to the Tribe as required by the Settlement Agreement. Conditions Zuni expenditures from such Fund upon the approval of a tribal management plan and an expenditure plan.Directs the Secretary to take title to specified lands in trust for the benefit of the Tribe, including lands to become part of the Reservation. Sets forth the status of such lands with regard to Federal and State water rights and ad valorem taxes.Extinguishes all claims for water rights in Zuni lands.</summary>
</bill>
