<bill session="104" type="h" number="4316" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Power Act to provide a moratorium on the retail wheeling of electric energy until the Clean Air Act is amended to reduce significantly certain transboundary air pollution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1996--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Power Act to declare that, from September 26, 1996, until an amendment to the Clean Air Act has been enacted to reduce transboundary air pollution associated with ozone and ozone precursors, PM-10, mercury, and carbon dioxide, neither the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission nor any State may permit any arrangement for the interstate sale of electric energy to any retail electric customer located within the exclusive service territory of any State electric utility serving retail electric customers in that State (retail wheeling). Exempts from such moratorium any electric energy sale: (1) by a State regulated or nonregulated electric utility to retail customers located within the utility's exclusive service territory; or (2) pursuant to an arrangement entered into before September 26, 1996.</summary>
</bill>
