<bill session="107" type="hc" number="167" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the International Olympic Committee for its work to bring about understanding of individuals and different cultures, for its focus on protecting the civil rights of its participants, for its rules of intolerance against discriminatory acts, and for its goal of promoting world peace through sports.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400226"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="2001-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2001-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Ethics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2001--Introduced.
Olympic Movement and Athlete Recognition Resolution - Recognizes the International Olympic Committee (IOC) for its: (1) work to bring about understanding of individuals and different cultures; (2) focus on protecting the civil rights of its participants; (3) rules of intolerance against discriminatory acts; and (4) goal of promoting world peace through sports.Encourages IOC members from the United States to abide by all IOC rules when considering and voting for host cities for future Olympic Games.Recognizes that any government action designating a preference or displeasure with any Olympic Games candidate host city is inconsistent with the IOC's Olympic Charter, Code of Ethics, and rules.Endorses the concept of the Olympic Games being a competition between athletes in individual or team events and not between countries.</summary>
</bill>
