<bill session="107" type="hc" number="237" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress urging the Republic of Italy to safely and immediately return Ludwig Maximilian Koons to the custody of his father in New York.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400229"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5966-5967"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3613"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fathers"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Italy"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parental kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2001--Introduced.
Urges the Republic of Italy to immediately return Ludwig Maximilian Koons to the United States and to the custody of his father, Jeffrey Koons, in accordance with the divorce judgment of the New York Supreme Court on December 9, 1994.Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) pursuant to Article 36 of the Convention for the Protection of Human Rights and Fundamental Freedoms, the United States should intervene in the proceeding pending before the European Court of Human Rights, Jeffrey Lynn Koons v. Italy, case no. 68183/01, to request the Republic of Italy to remedy the violations of international law committed against Mr. Koons and his son; and (2) pending a final decision by the Republic of Italy regarding the permanent return of Ludwig to the United States, the United States should request that the Republic of Italy authorize Ludwig to visit his father in his New York residence on a temporary basis.</summary>
</bill>
