<bill session="104" type="h" number="2079" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide amnesty from criminal and civil tax penalties for individuals who, within the 6-month amnesty period, notify the Internal Revenue Service of previous nonpayments or underpayments of Federal income tax and pay such underpayments in full.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404332"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Tax amnesty"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/1995--Introduced.
Provides that an individual shall not be liable for any criminal or civil penalty or additional amount of tax respecting any underpayment of Federal income tax for any taxable year, subject to stated exceptions, if, during the amnesty period, such individual: (1) files a written statement with the Secretary of the Treasury; and (2) agrees to a waiver of any restriction on the assessment or collection of such underpayment. Requires that an individual pay: (1) the amount of underpayment shown on such statement; and (2) the full amount of the interest payable respecting such underpayment not later than 90 days after notification by the Secretary of the amount of such interest or any other date agreed to by the Secretary and the individual before the end of the 90-day period. Limits provisions for which amnesty is available to underpayments of Federal income tax for taxable years ending before January 1994.</summary>
</bill>
