<bill session="104" type="hr" number="182" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require the reduction of section 602(b)(1) suballocations to reflect floor amendments to general appropriation bills, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400348"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1995-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Legislative and Budget Process.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU02" subcommittee="Legislative Process" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/1995--Introduced.
Amends rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require the chairman of the Committee on Appropriations, upon the engrossment in the House of any general appropriations bill (or resolution making continuing appropriations, if applicable), to: (1) reduce the suballocation of new budget authority or outlays to the appropriate subcommittee by the net amount of reductions resulting from amendments agreed to by the House to that bill; and (2) report those revisions to the House. Prohibits the reductions in suballocations from being reallocated by the Committee on Appropriations to any other subcommittee. Requires, upon the reporting of revised suballocations to the House by the Committee on Appropriations, the chairman of the Committee on the Budget to: (1) make appropriate revisions in the allocations to the Committee on Appropriations to reflect the revised suballocations; and (2) report those revisions to the House. Deems, in the House, such revised suballocations and revised allocations as suballocations and allocations made under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974.</summary>
</bill>
