<bill session="106" type="hr" number="348" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-02T19:11:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-02T19:11:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Agreeing to the conference requested by the Senate on the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 2990) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals greater access to health insurance through a health care tax deduction, a long-term care deduction, and other health-related tax incentives, to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to provide access to and choice in health care through association health plans, to amend the Public Health Service Act to create new pooling opportunities for small employers to obtain greater access to health coverage through HealthMarts; to amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to protect consumers in managed care plans and other health coverage; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-11-01T19:11:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-430, by Mr. Goss.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-01T19:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of Senate amendment to H.R. 2990. Providing that the House disagrees to the Senate amendment and agrees to the conference requested by the Senate thereon.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-11-01T19:12:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="143">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 143.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T18:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11341-11344" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T18:51:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 348.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T19:11:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1999-11-02T19:11:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T19:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="2990"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/1999--Introduced.
Provides that the House of Representatives disagrees to the Senate amendment to H.R. 2990 (quality care for the uninsured) and agrees to the conference requested by the Senate.</summary>
</bill>
