<bill session="106" type="h" number="3220" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Millennium Digital Commerce Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To regulate interstate commerce by electronic means by permitting and encouraging the continued expansion of electronic commerce through the operation of free market forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400146"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1999-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1999-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1999-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1999-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="1999-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1999-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1999-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-04">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-04">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/4/1999--Introduced.
Millennium Digital Commerce Act - Declares that an interstate contract transaction shall not be denied legal effect solely because an electronic signature or electronic record was used in its formation.Authorizes parties to an interstate transaction to determine the appropriate electronic signature technologies for their transaction, and the means of implementing such technologies. Denies the legal effect of an electronic record of a contract required by law to be in writing, unless it is delivered to all parties in a form that can be: (1) retained for later reference; and (2) used to prove agreement terms. Provides exclusions. Prohibits a contract relating to a commercial transaction from being denied legal effect solely because its formation involved electronic agents (computers or other automated means). States as the specific intent of Congress that this section apply to the business of insurance.Directs the Federal Government, to the extent practicable, to observe certain principles governing the use of electronic signatures in international commercial transactions, including to: (1) remove paper-based obstacles to electronic transactions by adopting relevant principles from the Model Law on Electronic Commerce adopted in 1996 by the UN Commission on International Trade Law (UNCITRAL); (2) permit parties to a transaction to determine the appropriate authentication technologies for such transactions, with assurance that they will be recognized and enforced; (3) permit such parties to have the opportunity to prove in court that such authentication approaches and transactions are valid; and (4) take a nondiscriminatory approach to electronic signatures and authentication methods from other jurisdictions.Directs each Federal agency to report to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and the Secretary of Commerce on any provision of law administered, or regulation issued, by it that imposes a barrier to electronic transactions. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress concerning any legislation needed or Executive or Federal agency action being taken to remove such barriers.</summary>
</bill>
