<bill session="104" type="h" number="175" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Collision Damage Waiver Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit rental car companies from imposing liability on renters with certain exceptions, to prohibit such companies from selling collision damage waivers in connection with private passenger automobile rental agreements of not more than 30 days, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402763"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Automobile repair"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Collision Damage Waiver Act - Prohibits rental car companies, in rental agreements of 30 continuous days or less, from holding any authorized driver liable for any damage, except in any case in which: (1) the damage is caused intentionally by an authorized driver or as a result of such driver's willful and wanton misconduct, operation of the vehicle while legally intoxicated or under the influence of an illegal drug, while engaged in a criminal act, or in the course of any speed contest; (2) the rental transaction is based on information the renter supplied with intent to defraud the rental car company; (3) damage arises out of the use of the vehicle to carry individuals or property for hire; or (4) the damage arises out of the use of the vehicle outside the United States or Canada (unless specifically authorized by the rental agreement). Prohibits waiver of these exceptions. Prohibits a rental car company, during the rental period or pending resolution of any dispute, from requiring or requesting a damage security deposit in any form. Sets forth civil penalties for violation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
