<bill session="105" type="h" number="3115" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Teacher Excellence in America Challenge Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish professional development partnerships to improve the quality of America's teachers and the academic achievement of students in the classroom, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400275"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="1169"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Class size"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Middle schools"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/27/1998--Introduced.
Teacher Excellence in America Challenge Act of 1997 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to replace current State and local Programs for Teacher Excellence with a Teacher Excellence in America Challenge program under which the Secretary of Education may award competitive grants to professional development partnerships for 80 percent of the cost of providing teacher preparation, induction, classroom experience, and professional development opportunities to prospective, beginning, and veteran teachers while improving the education of students in the classroom. Provides for such professional development partnerships among institutions of higher education, elementary schools or secondary schools, local educational agencies (LEAs), State educational agencies, teacher organizations, and nonprofit organizations. Requires that priority be given to partnerships serving elementary schools, secondary schools, or LEAs that serve high percentages of children from families below the poverty line. Lists activities for which partnerships shall use such grants, excluding construction, renovation, or repair of any school or facility. Sets forth requirements for grant applications and partnership assurances. Directs the Secretary to reserve a certain amount of funds under this Act for national evaluation and information dissemination activities. Authorizes appropriations. Repeals the following HEA programs: (1) National Teacher Academies; (2) Paul Douglas Teacher Scholarships; (3) the Teacher Corps; (4) the Class Size Demonstration Grant program; (5) Middle School Teaching Demonstration Programs; (6) New Teaching Careers programs (for minority teacher recruitment); and (7) Programs for Special Populations, including the National Mini Corps Program, Foreign Language Instruction, Small State Teaching Initiative, Faculty Development Grants, and Early Childhood Education Training.</summary>
</bill>
