<bill session="104" type="h" number="3003" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rent-To-Own Reform Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Rent-To-Own Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish requirements applicable to rent-to-own transactions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404634"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1996-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="402454" joined="1996-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400532" joined="1996-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1996-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1996-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1996-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1996-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1996-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1996-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1996-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1996-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1996-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1996-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="1996-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services. period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Credit insurance"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Finance charges"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Trade regulation"/>
    <term name="Warranties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/1996--Introduced.
Rent-To-Own Reform Act of 1996 - Amends the Consumer Credit Protection Act to designate a new title X as the Rent-To-Own Protection Act to prohibit a seller in a rent-to-own transaction from taking, receiving, or assessing any interest, finance charge, or other fee for the transaction in excess of that which may be charged under State law which establishes in connection with a credit or retail installment sale for the same or a similar item: (1) a maximum rate or amount of interest, finance charge, or time-price differential that may be charged; (2) the types and maximum amount of fees that a seller may charge; or (3) the types of credit insurance and the maximum amount of premiums that can be charged for credit insurance. Sets forth requirements regarding: (1) termination, recovery, and other fees; (2) the effect of termination; and (3) guarantees and warranties. Makes the following Federal laws applicable to rent-to-own transactions: (1) the Truth in Lending Act; (2) the Equal Credit Opportunity Act; (3) the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act; and (4) the Fair Credit Reporting Act. Requires a seller to include the following information on each item in the seller's place of business that is available for purchase pursuant to a rent-to-own transaction: (1) the cash price; (2) an itemization of services offered and the price of each service; (3) the annual percentage rate; (4) any applicable periodic payment and the number of payments; (5) the total number of payments required to acquire ownership; and (6) whether the item is new or used. Requires a seller to provide such information to a consumer in writing at the time the parties enter into the contract. Prohibits a seller under a rent-to-own contract with a consumer from taking specified actions, such as using threats or coercion to collect amounts alleged due, or unreasonably disclosing information to third parties regarding amounts owed by the consumer. Makes compliance with the requirements of this Act enforceable by the Federal Trade Commission. Deems a violation of this Act to be an unfair or deceptive act or practice in violation of the Federal Trade Commission Act. Subjects sellers who violate the requirements of this Act to civil liability.</summary>
</bill>
