<bill session="108" type="h" number="142" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-07-19T15:13:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-19T15:13:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Inland Empire regional water recycling project, to authorize the Secretary to carry out a program to assist agencies in projects to construct regional brine lines in California, and to authorize the Secretary to participate in the Lower Chino Dairy Area desalination demonstration and reclamation project.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Prado Basin Natural Treatment System Project, to authorize the Secretary to carry out a program to assist agencies in projects to construct regional brine lines in California, and to authorize the Secretary to participate in the Lower Chino Dairy Area desalination demonstration and reclamation project.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="2003-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2003-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-564.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-06-23T18:34:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="329">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 329.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hayworth moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5939-5940" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 142.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-07-19T15:13:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5939" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2004--Passed House amended.
Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior: (1) in cooperation with the Orange County Water District, to participate in the design, planning, and construction of natural treatment systems and wetlands for the flows of the Santa Ana River, California, and its tributaries into the Prado Basin; (2) in cooperation with local governments, to carry out a program to assist agencies in projects to construct regional brine lines to export the salinity imported from the Colorado River to the Pacific Ocean; and (3) in cooperation with the Chino Basin Watermaster, the Inland Empire Utilities Agency, and the Santa Ana Watershed Project Authority, to participate in the design, planning, and construction of the Lower Chino Dairy Area desalination demonstration and reclamation project. Limits the Federal share to 25 percent of total project costs. Prohibits using funds provided by the Secretary for operation and maintenance of the projects. Authorizes appropriations for the Prado Basin and Lower Chino Dairy Area projects.</summary>
</bill>
