<bill session="104" type="hj" number="73" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-29T21:35:00-05:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-03-29T21:35:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Contract with America bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Term Limits bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States with respect to the number of terms of office of Members of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400079" joined="1995-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-15T23:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 116 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 73 with 3 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment to the joint resolution shall be in order except those specified in the report accompanying this resolution, to be offered in the order and manner specified. Each amendment shall be considered notwithstanding the adoption of a previous amendment in the nature of a substitute and not subject to further amendment. If more than one amendment is adopted, the amendment receiving the greatest number of affirmative votes shall be considered as finally adopted. In the case of a tie, only the last amendment to receive that number of affirmative votes shall be considered as finally adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3553"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T16:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 116 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 116.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3888-3909" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 73 with 3 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment to the joint resolution shall be in order except those specified in the report accompanying this resolution, to be offered in the order and manner specified. Each amendment shall be considered notwithstanding the adoption of a previous amendment in the nature of a substitute and not subject to further amendment. If more than one amendment is adopted, the amendment receiving the greatest number of affirmative votes shall be considered as finally adopted. In the case of a tie, only the last amendment to receive that number of affirmative votes shall be considered as finally adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 116 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Scott L. Klug to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T11:43:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with three hours of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T12:46:00-05:00">
      <text>During the course of debate, Mr. Dingell demanded that certain words of Mr. Hoke be taken down. Mr. Hoke asked unanimous consent that the words in question be stricken from the record, and objection was heard to the request. The Committee of the Whole then rose to report the words.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T12:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.J. Res. 73 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T12:51:00-05:00">
      <text>The Committee of the Whole reported the words of Mr. Hoke back to the House. The Chair declared the words to be unparliamentary and, by unanimous consent, the words were stricken from the record. Objection was heard to a unanimous consent request to allow Mr. Hoke to proceed in order. The Chair then put the question on allowing Mr. Hoke to proceed in order and announced that, by voice vote, the motion had passed. Mr. Conyers objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present and a roll call vote was ordered.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T13:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3915-3965" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T13:17:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T13:17:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole continued with approximately 2 hours remaining for general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T14:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.J. Res. 73 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T14:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T14:54:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T14:54:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole continued with approximately 1 hour remaining for general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T15:49:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 116, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Peterson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T17:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 116, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 1 hour of debate on the Inglis amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T19:00:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 116, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Hilleary amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T20:29:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 116, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the McCollum amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T20:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McCollum asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the McCollum amendment be reduced to 30 minutes, equally divided. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T21:10:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.J. Res. 73.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T21:10:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE" datetime="1995-03-29T21:35:00-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="277" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Failed by recorded vote (2/3 required): 227 - 204, 1 Present (Roll No. 277).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="116"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hj" number="2"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hj" number="2"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hj" number="82"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional terms of office"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Term limits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h329"/>
    <amendment number="h330"/>
    <amendment number="h331"/>
    <amendment number="h332"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/2/1995--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Prohibits the election of any person to a full term as a Senator more than twice or to a full term as a Representative more than six times. Bars any person who has been a: (1) Senator for more than three years of a term to which another person was elected from being subsequently elected more than once; and (2) Representative for more than a year from being subsequently elected more than five times. Excludes election or service occurring before this amendment becomes operative when determining eligibility for election.</summary>
</bill>
