<bill session="105" type="h" number="3905" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fairness in Asbestos Compensation Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish legal standards and procedures for the fair, prompt, inexpensive and efficient resolution of personal injury claims arising out of asbestos exposure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1998-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400549" joined="1998-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1998-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1998-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1998-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="1998-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1998-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1998-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1998-06-25" withdrawn="1998-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Asbestos"/>
    <term name="Asbestosis"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Colon cancer"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lung cancer"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Stomach diseases"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="X-rays"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Asbestos Resolution Corporation Title II: Medical Eligibility Determinations Title III: Alternative Dispute Resolution Title IV: Civil Actions Title V: Rules Applicable to Arbitrations and Civil Actions Title VI: Funding Title VII: Applicability; Pending Civil Action Title VIII: Miscellaneous Provisions Fairness in Asbestos Compensation Act of 1998 - Title I: Asbestos Resolution Corporation - Establishes the Asbestos Resolution Corporation which shall: (1) have exclusive authority to adopt rules for cost recovery, physician qualifications, alternative dispute resolution, exceptional medical cases, and disease eligibility; and (2) appoint a Medical Advisory Board. Title II: Medical Eligibility Determinations - Sets forth claimant medical eligibility determination criteria for: (1) nonmalignant conditions; (2) mesothelioma; (3) lung cancer; and (4) other cancer. (Sec. 205) Sets forth procedures for Corporation determination of a claimant's certificate of medical eligibility. (Sec. 206) Directs the Corporation to establish one or more exceptional medical claims panels. Sets forth application and acceptance provisions. (Sec. 207) Provides for: (1) confidentiality; and (2) U.S. district court review of Corporation determinations of eligibility. Title III: Alternative Dispute Resolution - Directs the Board to establish procedural rules for an alternative dispute resolution process. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) motions officers; (2) respondent notification; (3) additional respondents; (4) grace period; (5) mediation and arbitration; and (6) subpoena powers. Title IV: Civil Actions - Prohibits: (1) a civil asbestos action unless the plaintiff has obtained a certificate of medical eligibility and release from mediation; and (2) a class action or other collective action without the consent of each defendant. (Sec. 404) Requires a penalty for a final offer made by a respondent in mediation if such offer is below a certain amount assigned by the jury or fact-finder. Title V: Rules Applicable to Arbitrations and Civil Actions - Sets forth arbitration and civil action rules with respect to: (1) relief; (2) timeliness defenses; (3) attorney's fees; and (4) nonpreclusion of nonmalignant claims upon subsequent malignancy claims. Title VI: Funding - Directs the Corporation to estimate its annual medical review and administrative and overhead costs and allocate proportionate cost shares among the previous year's respondents. Provides monetary penalties for noncooperation with the Corporation. (Sec. 602) Provides for mediation and arbitration costs to be charged on a per capita basis to participating respondents. (Sec. 603) Directs the Corporation to establish procedures for informal resolution of cost assessment disputes. Provides for U.S. district court review of cost assessment disputes. Title VII: Applicability; Pending Civil Actions - Makes this Act applicable to any civil asbestos action that has not resulted in a final, nonappealable judgment, with specified conditions applicable to pending civil actions. Title VIII: Miscellaneous Provisions - Defines specified terms. (Sec. 804) Makes this Act inapplicable to existing asbestos trusts, with an elective trust exception.</summary>
</bill>
