<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="842" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:19-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="5386" sequence="9"/>
  <status datetime="2006-05-18">offered</status>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <offered datetime="2006-05-18"/>
  <description>Amendments sought to strike sections 104, 105, and 106 which prohibit the expenditure of funds for Outer Continental Shelf oil leasing activities in certain areas.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment comprised of 3 amendments offered en bloc to strike sections 104, 105 and 106 from the bill. Sections 104, 105, and 106 provide that no funds provided in this title may be expended by the Department of the Interior for the conduct of offshore oil preleasing, leasing and related activities placed under restriction in the President's moratorium statement of June 12, 1998, in the areas of northern, central, and southern California; the North Atlantic; Washington and Oregon; and the eastern Gulf of Mexico south of 26 degrees north latitude and east of 86 degrees west longitude; no funds provided in this title may be expended by the Department of the Interior to conduct offshore oil preleasing, leasing and related activities in the eastern Gulf of Mexico planning area for any lands located outside Sale 181, as identified in the final Outer Continental Shelf 5-Year Oil and Gas Leasing Program, 1997-2002; and, no funds provided in this title may be expended by the Department of the Interior to conduct oil preleasing, leasing and related activities in the Mid-Atlantic and South Atlantic planning areas.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendments (A009) offered by Mr. Poe.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2812-2813, CR 5/19/2006 H2843-2844" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2812" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T18:18:00-04:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the Poe amendments (A009) Failed by recorded vote: 141 - 279 (Roll no. 164).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
