<bill session="107" type="h" number="4960" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rebuild Infrastructure and Support Entrepreneurs Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To foster economic development through the involvement of small businesses located in the New York City metropolitan area in procurements related to the improvement and reconstruction of the area in New York damaged by the terrorist attacks perpetrated against the United States on September 11, 2001.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2002-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2002-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2002-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2002-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2002-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2002-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2002-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy, Technology and Economic Growth, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA18" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy, Technology, and Economic Growth" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2002--Introduced.
Rebuild Infrastructure and Support Entrepreneurs Act of 2002 - Prohibits a Federal agency from providing any New York recovery funds to an entity unless: (1) the entity has submitted a fund use plan to the Administrator of the Small Business Administration that has been approved; (2) the entity agrees to give a ten percent price evaluation adjustment in the competition for any New York recovery contract for small businesses located in the New York City metropolitan area; and (3) the entity agrees to meet specified small business procurement requirements in its contract awards. Includes within such small business procurement requirements the award of: (1) 23 percent of such contracts to New York City small businesses; (2) five percent to New York City small businesses owned and controlled by women; and (3) five percent to New York City small businesses owned by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals. Requires funds recapture if such minimum requirements are not met.Requires the Administrator to use New York recovery funds to provide grants, loans, and other assistance to small businesses in New York City and allows any other Federal agency to provide additional New York recovery funds to an entity that follows the minimum small business procurement requirements specified above (substituting 25 for 23 percent in the first requirement).</summary>
</bill>
