<bill session="106" type="hr" number="628" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-12T15:11:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-12T15:11:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 4386) to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide medical assistance for certain women screened and found to have breast or cervical cancer under a federally funded screening program, to amend the Public Health Service Act and the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to surveillance and information concerning the relationship between cervical cancer and the human papillomavirus (HPV), and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-10-11T21:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-975, by Mrs. Myrick.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-11T21:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of Sen. amendment with amemdment to H.R. 4386 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-10-11T21:12:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="309">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 309.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-10-12T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9843-9847" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9843" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-12T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 628.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-12T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on both the amendment and on the resolution was ordered.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2000-10-12T15:11:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-12T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="4386"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1054"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/11/2000--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of the Senate amendment to H.R. 4386 (medical assistance relating to breast and cervical cancer).</summary>
</bill>
