<bill session="108" type="hr" number="627" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-06T15:06:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-06T15:06:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Condemning Iraq Abuse of Prisoners resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Deploring the abuse of persons in United States custody in Iraq, regardless of the circumstances of their detention, urging the Secretary of the Army to bring to swift justice any member of the Armed Forces who has violated the Uniform Code of Military Justice, expressing the deep appreciation of the Nation to the courageous and honorable members of the Armed Forces who have selflessly served, or are currently serving, in Operation Iraqi Freedom, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06T07:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 628 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 627 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit allowed. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06T12:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 628 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 628.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2680-2698" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 627 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit allowed. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 627.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hoyer moved to recommit with instructions to Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2696" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2696" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hunter raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Hunter stated that the rule governing debate on this resolution does not allow for a motion to recommit with instruction. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2696" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2697" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2004-05-06T15:06:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="150" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 365 - 50 (Roll no. 150).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2680-2681" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06T15:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="628"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Courts-martial and courts of inquiry"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military and naval offenses"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2004--Passed House without amendment.
Deplores and condemns the abuse of persons in U.S. custody in Iraq, regardless of the circumstances of their detention. Declares that the alleged crimes of a handful of individuals should not detract from the commendable sacrifices of over 300,000 members of the U.S. armed forces who have served, or are serving, in Operation Iraqi Freedom. Reaffirms the American principle that any and all individuals under U.S. custody and care shall be afforded proper and humane treatment. Urges the Secretary of the Army: (1) to conduct a full and thorough investigation into any and all allegations of mistreatment or abuse of detainees in Iraq; (2) and appropriate military authorities to undertake corrective action to address command and systemic deficiencies identified in the incidents in question; and (3) to bring swift justice to any member of the Armed Forces who violated the Uniform Code of Military Justice. Reaffirms the need for Congress to be frequently updated on the status of efforts by the Department of Defense to address and resolve such issues. Expresses: (1) deep appreciation to the members of the Armed Forces who have selflessly served, or are so serving, in Operation Iraqi Freedom; (2) the support and thanks of the Nation to the families and friends of such members; and (3) the continuing solidarity and support of the House of Representatives and the American people for the partnership of the United States with the Iraqi people in building a viable Iraqi government and a secure nation.</summary>
</bill>
