<bill session="105" type="h" number="4353" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-09T16:07:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-09T16:07:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Anti-Bribery and Fair Competition Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">International Anti-Bribery and Fair Competition Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977 to improve the competitiveness of American business and promote foreign commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1998-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1998-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1998-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1998-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1998-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411550" joined="1998-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1524"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-09-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T22:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Commerce. H. Rept. 105-802.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-10-08T22:23:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="449">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 449.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bliley moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10302-10309" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-10-09T16:07:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09T16:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Laid on the table. See S. 2375 for further action.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10309" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="105" type="s" number="2375"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication satellites"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate corruption"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Election fraud"/>
    <term name="Extraterritoriality"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Immunities of foreign states"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="International officials"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maritime satellites"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/9/1998--Passed House amended.
International Anti-Bribery and Fair Competition Act of 1998 - Revises the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977 to prohibit conduct intended to secure improper advantages from foreign officials by: (1) issuers of securities; (2) officials of international organizations; and (3) domestic concerns. (Sec. 2) Redefines "foreign official" to include an official of a public international organization. Defines such an organization as either one designated by Executive order pursuant to the International Organizations Immunities Act, or any other international organization designated by Executive order of the President. (Sec. 3) Declares that it is unlawful for any issuer organized under the laws of the United States (or any U.S. person acting on the issuer's behalf) to corruptly do specified prohibited acts outside of the United States. (Sec. 4) Amends the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977 to proscribe specified foreign trade practices by a covered person (or any officer, director, employee, agent, or stockholder thereof) while in United States territory. Sets forth affirmative defenses to enforcement actions. Authorizes the Attorney General to bring a civil action in Federal district court to enjoin such proscribed actions. Prescribes civil and criminal penalties for violations of this Act. (Sec. 5) Declares that, for purposes of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977, an international organization providing commercial communications services shall be treated as a public international organization until the President certifies to certain congressional committees that it has achieved a privatization consistent with Federal policy of obtaining full and open competition, and nondiscriminatory market access in the provision of satellite services (pro-competitive privatization). Prohibits such certification from being construed to affect Federal Communications Commission (FCC) authorization of services to, from, or within the United States over space segment (sic) of international satellite organizations, or their privatized affiliates and successors. Denies an international organization immunity from suit or legal process for any act or omission it has taken as a provider of commercial telecommunications services to, from, or within the United States. (Retains the immunity from personal liability of an individual official or employee of an international organization providing commercial communications services.) Directs the President and the FCC expeditiously to take all actions necessary to eliminate or limit substantially any exceptions to such denial. Preserves an organization's immunity from suit or legal process for certain law enforcement and intelligence functions. Prohibits this Act from being construed as legislative authorization for the privatization of INTELSAT or Inmarsat, nor to increase the President's authority with respect to privatization negotiations. (Sec. 6) Directs Secretary of Commerce to report periodically to certain congressional committees on specified aspects of the implementation of the Convention on Combating Bribery of Foreign Public Officials in International Business Transactions.</summary>
</bill>
