<bill session="106" type="h" number="3987" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Gun Safety and Gun Access Prevention Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent children's access to firearms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2000-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Age (Law)"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Assault weapons"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Criminal negligence"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary school students"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Firearms injuries"/>
    <term name="High school students"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Trade fairs"/>
    <term name="Youth violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2000--Introduced.
Child Gun Safety and Gun Access Prevention Act of 2000 - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to: (1) raise the age of handgun eligibility to 21 (currently, 18); and (2) prohibit persons under age 21 from possessing semiautomatic assault weapons or large capacity ammunition feeding devices, with exceptions.(Sec. 3) Increases penalties imposed upon: (1) a juvenile who violates Brady Act provisions for a second or subsequent violation, or for a first violation committed after an adjudication of delinquency or after a State or Federal conviction for an act that, if committed by an adult, would be a serious violent felony; and (2) a person other than a juvenile who knowingly violates such provisions if the person sold, delivered, or otherwise transferred a handgun, ammunition, semiautomatic assault weapon, or large capacity ammunition feeding device to a person who is under age 21, knowing or having reasonable cause to know that such person intended to carry, otherwise possess, discharge, or otherwise use it in the commission of a crime of violence.(Sec. 4) Prohibits any licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer from selling, transferring, or delivering a firearm to any person (other than a licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer) unless the transferee is provided with a secure gun storage or safety device. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury, after notice and opportunity for hearing, to suspend or revoke any license issued under the Act, or to subject the licensee to a civil penalty of up to $10,000 if the holder of such license has knowingly violated this section.(Sec. 5) Imposes penalties (with exceptions) upon any person who: (1) keeps a loaded firearm, or an unloaded firearm and ammunition for it, any one of which has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce, within any premises that is under the custody or control of that person; (2) knows, or recklessly disregards the risk, that a child is capable of gaining access to the firearm; and (3) knows, or recklessly disregards the risk, that a child will use the firearm to cause death or serious bodily injury to the child or any other person, or that possession of the firearm by the child is unlawful under Federal or State law, if the child uses the firearm to cause death or serious bodily injury.(Sec. 6) Requires the parent or legal guardian of a child to ensure that, while the child is attending a gun show, the child is accompanied by an adult. Prohibits a person from conducting a gun show to which there is admitted a child who is not accompanied by an adult. Sets penalties for violations.(Sec. 7) Authorizes the Attorney General to provide grants to units of local government to enable law enforcement agencies to develop and sponsor gun safety classes for parents and their children.(Sec. 8) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) each school district should provide or participate in a firearms safety program for students in grades kindergarten through 12 and should consult with a certified firearms instructor before establishing the curriculum for the program; and (2) participation by students in a firearms safety program should not be mandatory if the district receives written notice from a parent of the student to exempt the student from the program.</summary>
</bill>
