<bill session="104" type="hj" number="95" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">War Powers Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the War Powers Resolution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="1995-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-16">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-16">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Legislative and Budget Process.</text>
      <committee name="House Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU02" subcommittee="Legislative Process" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Declaration of war"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/1995--Introduced.
War Powers Amendments of 1995 - Amends the War Powers Resolution to revise the circumstances permitting the introduction of U.S. armed forces into hostilities, or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated. Adds general authorization for participation of U.S. armed forces in certain United Nations (UN) military operations. Revises requirements for emergency uses of U.S. armed forces in hostilities to specify additional circumstances, including: (1) retaliating for an armed attack on the United States; (2) forestalling the direct and imminent threat of an attack on the United States or its armed forces; and (3) protecting U.S. nationals while evacuating them from a situation that threatens their lives or liberty. Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds for any such introduction of the armed forces except as described under this Act. Requires the President to consult with the Congress before the armed forces are: (1) introduced into hostilities; (2) introduced into the territory, airspace, or waters of a foreign country while equipped for combat, except for deployments which relate solely to supply, replacement, repair, or training of such forces, or in which there are already armed forces equipped for combat if such introduction would substantially enlarge the number of armed forces equipped for combat or increase the military capabilities of such forces; or (3) committed to an operation authorized by the UN. Declares that the President, in order to satisfy the consultation requirement, must: (1) ask Members of Congress for their advice and opinions before the decision is made to introduce the armed forces; and (2) make available to the Members consulted all information relevant to the situation. Declares that this consultation requirement is not met if the Congress is merely informed about the situation. Repeals congressional authority to direct the President by concurrent resolution to remove U.S. armed forces engaged in hostilities outside U.S. territory. Replaces such authority with a prohibition against funding for continued involvement of the armed forces 60 days after their introduction unless the Congress has provided specific statutory authorization and other conditions have been met. Sets forth expedited congressional procedures for the consideration of a privileged joint resolution authorizing the introduction of the armed forces into hostilities. Authorizes Members of Congress to bring actions for judicial review of such introduction, including declaratory judgment and injunctive relief for failures by the President to comply with this resolution. Provides for removal of the armed forces from hostilities by court order if the court finds that this resolution has been violated. Declares that the failure of the Congress to adopt a measure terminating, limiting, or prohibiting the involvement of the armed forces in hostilities, or finding that the President or the armed forces are acting in violation of this joint resolution, may not be construed as indicating congressional authorization or approval of, or acquiescence in, such involvement.</summary>
</bill>
