<bill session="104" type="hj" number="116" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400300"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/7/1995--Introduced.
Makes continuing appropriations for FY 1996 for projects or activities including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees provided for in the following Acts: (1) the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996; (2) the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 1996; (3) the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1996; (4) the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1996; (5) the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1996; (6) the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996; (7) the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996; (8) the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1996; (9) the Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 1996; (10) the Treasury, Postal Service, and General Government Appropriations Act, 1996; and (11) the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996. Sets forth limitations on the use of such funds. (Sec. 112) Requires that whenever the rate of operations for any continuing project or activity provided for which there is a budget request would result in a furlough of Government employees, that rate for operations may be increased to a level that would enable the furlough to be avoided. (Sec. 113) Requires that for those programs that had high initial rates of operation or complete distribution of funding at the beginning of FY 1995 because of distributions of funding to States, foreign countries, grantees, or others, similar distributions of funds for FY 1996 shall not be made and no grants shall be awarded for such programs, subject to stated exceptions. (Sec. 115) Requires that the rate of operations for any continuing project or activity that have not been increased shall be reduced by five percent but shall not be reduced below a defined minimum level or below the level that would result in a furlough. (Sec. 116) Provides that section 132 of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act of 1988 (which provides that amounts appropriated for the Federal Payment to the District of Columbia shall not be subject to apportionments) shall not apply for this joint resolution. Provides for including in the apportionment for the Federal Payment to the District of Columbia an additional $217 million. (Sec. 117) Requires that the authority and conditions for the application of appropriations of the Office of Technology Assessment as contained in House Report 104-212, shall be followed when applying the funding made available by this joint resolution. (Sec. 120) Requires the Securities and Exchange Commission's Salaries and Expenses account to include, in addition to direct appropriations, the amount it collects under the fee rate and offsetting collection authority. (Sec. 121) Requires that funding be made available for the necessary expenses of the Bureau of Mines for: (1) continuing limited health and safety and related research, materials partnerships, and minerals information activities; (2) for mineral assessments in Alaska; and (3) for terminating all other activities of the Bureau of Mines. (Sec. 122) Requires that funds for the Environmental Protection Agency shall be made available.</summary>
</bill>
