<bill session="106" type="h" number="5583" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Alternative Path to Teaching Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish an alternative path to teaching in needy school districts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2000-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Rating of teachers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/26/2000--Introduced.
Alternative Path to Teaching Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to establish a collaborative grants program to provide for an alternative path to teaching in needy school districts.Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make competitive grants to collaboratives established by local educational agencies (LEAs), and made up of LEAs and selected institutions of higher education and additional entities.Requires such grants to be used for: (1) intensive full-time pre-service training programs for collaborative participants; (2) recruiting and screening of applicants; (3) stipends to participants during training; (4) providing mentor teachers for participants; (5) buying release time for mentors and participants for induction activities; and (6) evaluating both individual participants and programs as a whole. Allows grant funds to also be used for bonuses for mentors and signing bonuses for participants.Sets forth requirements relating to: (1) qualifications of individual participants, including three-year commitments to teach in eligible schools; (2) eligibility of LEAs to establish collaboratives, benefit from grants, and employ participants; (3) State agency assurances of granting full and unrestricted first-year teacher certification to collaborative participants who complete the pre-service training and pass all applicable State and local licensing examinations for first-year teachers (in order for a collaborative to receiving a grant); and (4) collaborative accountability and program evaluation.</summary>
</bill>
