<bill session="106" type="h" number="2031" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-03T15:40:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-08-03T15:40:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Alcoholic Beverages Shipment bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Direct Shipment of Alcohol bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Twenty-First Amendment Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Twenty-First Amendment Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Twenty-First Amendment Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for injunctive relief in Federal district court to enforce State laws relating to the interstate transportation of intoxicating liquor.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1999-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1999-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1999-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="1999-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="1999-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400248" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="1999-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1999-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1999-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400603" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1999-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="1999-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400530" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400410" joined="1999-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-07-27T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 106-265.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-07-27T14:09:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="158">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 158.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-08-02T19:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 272 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2031 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Makes in order as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the Committee on the Judiciary amendment in the nature of a subsititute now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. The bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule for a period not to exceed two hours.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T11:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 272 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T11:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 272.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6857-6887" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T11:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2031 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Makes in order as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the Committee on the Judiciary amendment in the nature of a substitute now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. The bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule for a period not to exceed two hours.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T11:38:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 272 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T11:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable James V. Hansen to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T11:39:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2031.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T12:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Goodlatte.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the perfecting amendment offered by Mr. Conyers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Ms. Lofgren.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T13:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Ms. Lofgren.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Ms. Jackson-Lee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T14:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2031.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T14:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering engrossment and third reading. Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 325 - 99 (Roll no. 363).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Conyers moved to recommit the bill to the Committee on the Judiciary with instructions to report it back with an amendment directing the Attorney General to submit a study on the results of this legislation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6887" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-08-03T15:40:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="364" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 310 - 112 (Roll no. 364).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T15:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T15:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2031.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="272"/>
    <bill relation="includes" session="106" type="h" number="3244"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="577"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverage control"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverage industry"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h383"/>
    <amendment number="h384"/>
    <amendment number="h385"/>
    <amendment number="h386"/>
    <amendment number="h387"/>
    <amendment number="h388"/>
    <amendment number="h389"/>
    <amendment number="h390"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/3/1999--Passed House amended.
Twenty-First Amendment Enforcement Act - Amends the Webb-Kenyon Act to authorize a State attorney general (State AG) who has reasonable cause to believe that a person is engaging in any act that would constitute a violation of State law regulating the importation or transportation of any intoxicating liquor, to bring a civil action for injunctive relief to: (1) restrain the person from engaging in the violation; and (2) enforce compliance with State law. Grants U.S. district courts jurisdiction over any action brought by a State AG against any person, except one licensed or otherwise authorized to produce, sell, or store intoxicating liquor in such State. Permits such an action to be brought only in accordance with Federal judicial code provisions regarding venue, or in the district in which the recipient of such liquor resides or is found. Authorizes the court, in such action and upon a proper showing by the State AG, to issue a preliminary or permanent injunction or other order to restrain a violation. Specifies that a proper showing shall require clear and convincing evidence that a violation of State law regulating the importation or transportation of intoxicating liquor has taken place, and that no temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction may be granted except upon evidence: (1) demonstrating the probability of irreparable injury if injunctive relief is not granted; and (2) supporting the probability of success on the merits. Prohibits such issuance without notice to the adverse party and an opportunity for a hearing. Sets forth provisions regarding the form and scope of the order. Specifies that nothing in this Act may be construed to modify or supersede the operation of the Internet Tax Freedom Act. Prohibits any State from enforcing under this Act a law regulating the importation or transportation of intoxicating liquor that unconstitutionally discriminates against interstate commerce by out-of-State sellers by favoring local industries, erecting barriers to competition, and constituting mere economic protectionism. Provides that nothing in this Act may be construed to: (1) permit State regulation or taxation of Internet services or any other related interstate telecommunications services; or (2) authorize any injunction against an interactive computer service or against an electronic communication service used by another person to engage in any activity that is subject to this Act. (Sec. 3) Provides that the amendment made by this Act shall apply only with respect to the importation or transportation of intoxicating liquor occurring after: (1) October 31, 1999, or the expiration of the 90-day period beginning on the date of this Act's enactment, whichever is earlier, if this Act is enacted before November 1, 1999; or (2) the date of this Act's enactment if this Act is enacted after October 31, 1999. (Sec. 4) Directs the Attorney General to conduct and report to Congress on the impact of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
