<bill session="107" type="h" number="4876" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Brevard County Sea Turtle Habitat Restoration and Federal Mitigation Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the project for shoreline protection, Brevard County, Florida, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400427"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Beach erosion"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Sea turtles"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2002--Introduced.
Brevard County Sea Turtle Habitat Restoration and Federal Mitigation Act of 2002 - Modifies the Brevard County, Florida, shoreline protection project to authorize the Secretary of the Army to incorporate in such project any or all of the 7.1-mile reach of the project that was deleted from the project's south reach if the Secretary determines that such modification is technically sound, environmentally acceptable, and economically justified. Requires the Secretary, after the completion of a certain damage study, to provide the non-Federal interest credit toward non-Federal nourishment costs and renourishment costs associated with the shore protection project for any damages to Brevard County beaches that are the result of a Federal navigation project, as determined in the final report for the study by the independent coastal expert. Requires the amount of the credit to be determined based on the reported damages, and to be applied (without interest) against future non-Federal nourishment and renourishment costs until the entire mitigation credit is depleted. Calls for certain actions to ensure that the Federal navigation project does not cause further downstream erosion.</summary>
</bill>
