<bill session="107" type="h" number="5700" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Employees, Uniformed Service and Foreign Service Members Humanitarian Travel Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles 5 and 37, United States Code, and the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to authorize the payment of certain travel expenses for Federal employees, members of the uniformed services, and members of the Foreign Service involved in disasters or other catastrophic events, as well as the travel of their family representatives and agency representatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/24/2002--Introduced.
Federal Employees, Uniformed Service and Foreign Service Members Humanitarian Travel Act of 2002 - Authorizes the head of an agency to pay the travel expenses of family and agency representatives to support the needs of certain employees traveling on official business who abandon or interrupt their travel assignments prior to completion because of an incapacitating illness or injury.Authorizes an agency head, the Secretary of Defense or the military department concerned, or the Secretary of State with regard to members of the Foreign Service to pay the travel expenses of employees involved in a disaster or other catastrophic event, their family representatives, and agency representatives to, from, and at the site of such disaster or such catastrophic event, the site of a memorial service related to such disaster or event, and any other location as determined by the appropriate official.</summary>
</bill>
