<bill session="106" type="hr" number="588" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to violations in Western Europe of provisions of the Helsinki Final Act and other international agreements relating to the freedom of individuals to profess and practice religion or belief.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400606"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="2000-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2000-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2000--Introduced.
Disapproves of the growing intolerance, discrimination, and violence directed against individuals and groups because of their religion or belief in violation of international agreements. Expresses concern about the adoption of laws and regulations by Participating States of the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) that discriminate against minority or so-called "non-traditional" religions or beliefs and that limit the freedom of individuals to profess and practice religion or belief.Calls upon the President and the Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom to: (1) raise violations of the freedom of thought, conscience, religion, or belief, at every appropriate level with representatives of countries that have failed to implement their international commitments and obligations in this regard; (2) ensure that the United States makes full use of existing meetings and structures of international organizations to raise violations of Participating States' freely undertaken international commitments in this regard; and (3) support the inclusion of experts on religious liberty on U.S. delegations to appropriate meetings of international organizations, including the OSCE.</summary>
</bill>
