<bill session="105" type="hj" number="119" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-11T11:18:00-04:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-06-11T11:18:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to limit campaign spending.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400104"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-20T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 442 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 119 and H.R. 2183. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Upon the adoption of this resolution, the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 1(b) of rule XXIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union for consideration of H.J. Res. 119. General debate shall be limited to one hour. After general debate the joint resolution shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule and shall be considered as read. Bill is open to amendments. At any time after the adoption of this resolution the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 1(b) of rule XXIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the the bill H.R. 2183. General debate shall not exceed two hours. Befo...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10T19:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 442.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4443-4465" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10T19:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 119 and H.R. 2183. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Upon the adoption of this resolution, the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 1(b) of rule XXIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union for consideration of H.J. Res. 119. General debate shall be limited to one hour. After general debate the joint resolution shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule and shall be considered as read. Bill is open to amendments. At any time after the adoption of this resolution the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 1(b) of rule XXIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the the bill H.R. 2183. General debate shall not exceed two hours. Befo...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 442 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable James V. Hansen to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10T22:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.J. Res. 119.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10T22:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10T22:39:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the joint resolution, the Chair put the question, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hastings of Washington demanded a vote pending the absence o a quorum. Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 442, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the joint resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-11T10:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4487-4488" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE" datetime="1998-06-11T11:18:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="226" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Failed by the Yeas and Nays (2/3 required): 29 - 345, 51 Present (Roll No. 226).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-06-11T11:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hr" number="442"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="442"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hj" number="9"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hj" number="14"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hj" number="17"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hj" number="47"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional powers"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/1998--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Authorizes the Congress, with respect to Federal elections, and States, for all other elections, to adopt reasonable regulations of campaign funds expended, including contributions, to influence the outcome of elections, provided that such regulations do not impair the right of the public to a full and free discussion of all issues and do not prevent any candidate for elected office from amassing the resources necessary for effective advocacy.</summary>
</bill>
