<bill session="105" type="hr" number="446" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-22T11:54:00-04:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-05-22T11:54:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Disposing of the conference report to accompany the bill (S. 1150) to ensure that federally funded agricultural research, extension, and education address high-priority concerns with national or multistate significance, to reform, extend, and eliminate certain agricultural research programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-05-22T00:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-548, by Mr. Solomon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-22T00:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to S. 1150. Resolution waives all points of order against the conference report to accompany S. 1150 (except those arising under clause 3 of rule XXVIII(pertaining to the scope of the conference) and predicated on provisions in subtitle A of title V(relating to the Food Stamp Program)) and against its consideration (except those arising under section 425 of the Congressional Budget Act (relating to unfunded mandates)).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-05-22T00:14:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="196">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 196.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-05-22T09:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3761-3773" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-22T09:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-22T10:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE" datetime="1998-05-22T11:54:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="188" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 120 - 289, 1 Present (Roll No. 188).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-05-22T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="s" number="1150"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h654"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/22/1998--Failed of passage in House.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the conference report on S. 1150 (agricultural research programs), except for those arising under: (1) rule XXVIII (prohibiting consideration of matter which extends beyond the scope of the conference report) of the Rules of the House of Representatives and predicated on subtitle A of title V of the report (providing funds for food stamps for certain noncitizens); and (2) provisions of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (prohibition on unfunded mandates). Provides that if a point of order for failure to comply with rule XXVIII is sustained, the conference report shall be considered as rejected and the pending question shall be, without intervention of any point of order, whether the House shall recede from its amendment and agree to an amendment to S. 1150 consisting of the reported text, modified by striking subtitle A of title V.</summary>
</bill>
