<bill session="105" type="h" number="4864" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Education Bill of Rights Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to local educational agencies to allow such agencies to promote certain education initiatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Curriculum planning"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Parent-teacher relationships"/>
    <term name="Rating of teachers"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="School choice"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/1998--Introduced.
Education Bill of Rights Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to promote certain education initiatives. Requires an applicant LEA, to be eligible for such a grant, to demonstrate that it has developed the following initiatives: (1) a charter school program to allow parents greater choice in selecting the appropriate educational setting for their child; (2) a parental school choice program that allows parents the ability to select a public school located within the LEA; (3) a vocational and academic opportunities program that allows parents to choose a vocational or college preparatory program for their secondary school student child; (4) an early elementary reading program to ensure that all students can read by the third grade; (5) a program to provide a safe and drug-free environment at school; (6) a locally-developed standardized testing program; (7) curriculum development panels composed of teachers and parents; (8) a program to improve or increase the standards for teachers; (9) a merit pay system to reward teachers who meet or exceed performance criteria; and (10) a teaching excellence program to ensure that the most qualified teachers are hired, including teachers with expertise in the workplace. Sets forth a formula for allocation of funds to LEAS that meet such eligibility criteria. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
