<bill session="105" type="h" number="223" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:27-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Presidential Debate Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to establish the Presidential Debate Commission on an ongoing basis and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce the amount of funds provided under such Act for party nominating conventions for any party whose nominee for President or Vice-President does not participate in any debate scheduled by the Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E4)</text>
      <reference ref="CR E4"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Campaign debates"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Political conventions"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential debates"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Public opinion polls"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidential candidates"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>01/07/1997--Introduced.
Presidential Debate Reform Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to establish a Presidential Debate Commission one year before each general election for the offices of President and Vice President beginning with the general election in 2000. Directs the Commission to establish: (1) one preliminary debate; (2) not fewer than one nor more than two vice presidential debates; and (3) not fewer than two nor more than four presidential debates. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reduce the amount of Federal payments for a party's nominating convention for the following general election if the party's nominee for President or Vice President does not certify to the Presidential Debate Commission that the nominee will participate in all applicable Commission debates (other than a preliminary debate).</summary>
</bill>
