<bill session="104" type="hr" number="169" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-20T13:33:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-06-20T13:33:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 1854) making appropriations for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400107"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-06-19T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-146, by Mr. Diaz-Balart.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-19T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1854 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with sec. 302(f) or 308(a) of the Congressional Budget Act shall be waived. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI shall be waived. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this report, to be considered in order, manner and time specified in the report and not subject to further amendment or demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole. The Chairman of the Committee of the Whole may postpone requests for recorded votes on amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-06-19T17:59:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="59">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 59.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20T10:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6096-6104" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20T10:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20T11:23:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on moving the previous question and announced that, by voice vote, the motion was agreed to. Mr. Beilenson objected to the vote on grounds that a quorum was not present and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings were postponed and, by unanimous consent, the point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20T13:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6117-6118" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by recorded vote: 232 - 196 (Roll no. 391).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-06-20T13:33:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="392" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 236 - 191 (Roll no. 392).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20T13:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="1854"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the modified closed rule for the consideration of H.R. 1854 (legislative branch appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
