<bill session="113" type="h" number="1582" updated="2013-07-17T16:00:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Consumers Relief Act of 2013</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect consumers by prohibiting the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from promulgating as final certain energy-related rules that are estimated to cost more than $1 billion and will cause significant adverse effects to the economy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412269"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412541" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2013-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="General energy matters"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/16/2013--Introduced.
Energy Consumers Relief Act of 2013 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), before promulgating a final rule that regulates any aspect of the production, supply, distribution, or use of energy (or that provides for such regulation by state or local governments) and that is estimated by the Administrator or the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to impose aggregate costs of more than $1 billion, to submit a report that contains: (1) an estimate of the total costs of the rule, (2) an estimate of the increases in energy prices that may result from implementation or enforcement of the rule, and (3) a detailed description of the employment effects that may result from implementation or enforcement of the rule. Requires the Secretary of Energy (DOE): (1) to prepare an independent analysis to determine whether such rule will cause any increase in energy prices for consumers, any impact on fuel diversity of the nation's electricity generation portfolio or on electric reliability, or any other adverse effect on energy supply, distribution, or use; and (2) upon making such a determination, to determine whether such increase, impact, or effect will cause significant adverse effects to the economy and publish such determination in the Federal Register. Prohibits the Administrator from promulgating any such final rule if the Secretary determines that such rule will cause significant adverse effects to the economy.</summary>
</bill>
