<bill session="105" type="h" number="4758" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Access to Emergency Care Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve access of veterans to emergency medical care in non-Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400126"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="2619"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/9/1998--Introduced.
Veterans' Access to Emergency Care Act of 1998- Declares the annual patient enrollment system of the Department of Veterans Affairs to be a health care plan and the veterans enrolled in such system to be participants in a health care plan. Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to contract for the emergency health care of such veterans in non-Department facilities. Includes such contracted emergency care within the definition of authorized Department medical services. Authorizes the reimbursement of enrolled veterans for expenses incurred in the treatment of any medical emergency which poses a serious threat to life or health. Directs the Secretary to require in such a contract that payment by the Secretary for treatment of enrolled veterans at the non-Department facility be made only after any payment that may be made with respect to such treatment: (1) under part A or B of the Medicare program (title XVIII of the Social Security Act); and (2) by a third-party insurance provider.</summary>
</bill>
