<bill session="105" type="h" number="4823" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">21st Century Retirement Savings Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for retirement savings for the 21st century.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400226"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1998-10-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="2635"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Defined contribution plans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Pension portability"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: New Employer Pension Plans Must Be 401(k) Plans and Not 403(b) or 457 Plans Title II: Safe Annuities and Trusts Title III: Enhanced Portability of Retirement Plans Title IV: Credit for Pension Plan Startup Costs of Small Employers Title V: Miscellaneous Improvements to Pension Plans 21st Century Retirement Savings Act - Title I: New Employer Pension Plans Must Be 401(k) Plans and Not 403(b) or 457 Plans - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require new State and local government and tax-exempt organization pension plans to be 401(k) plans. Title II: Safe Annuities and Trusts - Requires employers to establish SAFE annuities (a defined individual retirement annuity). Title III: Enhanced Portability of Retirement Plans - Permits specified rollovers. Makes other revisions concerning portability. Title IV: Credit for Pension Plan Startup Costs of Small Employers - Establishes a small employer pension plan cost startup credit. Title V: Miscellaneous Improvements to Pension Plans - Permits IRA "catch-up" contributions. Repeals the 25 percent limitation on defined contribution plans. Provides for faster vesting of employer matching contributions. Revises provisions concerning: (1) pension benefit statements; and (2) assignment and alienation. Sets penalties for pension plans failing to meet requirements.</summary>
</bill>
