<bill session="105" type="h" number="3680" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">English Language Fluency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a program to help children and youth learn English, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409228"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400500" joined="1998-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="1998-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400225" joined="1998-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1998-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1998-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1998-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E585-586"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bilingual education"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigrant education"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court decisions"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/1998--Introduced.
English Language Fluency Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to establish a program to help children and youth learn English under title VII, changing its from Bilingual Education, Language Enhancement, and Language Acquisition Programs to English Language Fluency and Foreign Language Acquisition Programs. Requires that parents be given: (1) notification of a child's identification as needing English language instruction; (2) the right to consent, or not, to the child's participation in such program; and (3) program information and notice of opportunities for regular meetings to formulate and get responses to their recommendations. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary of Education to reserve a specified portion of such appropriations for specified entities serving Native American or Alaska Native children and youth at elementary, secondary, and postsecondary school levels. Directs the Secretary to make English language acquisition formula grants to States for: (1) subgrants to eligible entities to provide assistance to children and youth who are English language learners, as well as immigrant children and youth; and (2) professional development and personnel certification, technical assistance to local educational agencies, planning, administration, and interagency coordination. Provides that nothing in this Act shall be construed as requiring a State or a local educational agency to establish or continue a program of native language instruction. Authorizes the Secretary to conduct, through the Office of Educational Research and Improvement, research to improve English language instruction for children and youth who are English language learners and immigrant children and youth. Limits such research- related activities to: (1) identification of successful models for teaching children English; and (2) distribution of research results to States for dissemination to schools with populations of students who are English language learners. Prohibits such research from focussing on any one method of instruction. (Sec. 2) Repeals authority for the Emergency Immigrant Education Program. (Sec. 3) Revises ESEA title VII administrative coordination and reporting requirements. Provides for commingling of different ESEA funds. Repeals certain provisions relating to release time, education technology, notification of State agencies, and continued eligibility of entities receiving funds. (Sec. 4) Declares that nothing under ESEA title VII shall be construed to negate or supersede the legal authority under State law of State agencies, State entities, or State public officials over programs that are under their jurisdiction.</summary>
</bill>
