<bill session="107" type="h" number="5423" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the annual audit of the White County Bridge Commission, for the New Harmony Bridge over the Wabash River, Indiana and Illinois, for the filling of vacancies in the membership thereof, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="2002-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400207" joined="2002-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Interstate commissions"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Toll roads"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2002--Introduced.
Requires the White County Bridge Commission to provide for the annual audit of its financial transactions (with respect to the New Harmony Bridge over the Wabash River) as prescribed by the Governors of the States of Indiana and Illinois. Directs the General Accounting Office to give advice on such audits. Requires the Commission to submit a copy of the audit report to the Governors and the Secretary of Commerce. Allows each Governor or the Secretary of Commerce to provide for the conduct of further audits as they see fit. Declares that the Commission shall bear all expenses of the annual audit.Directs the Commission to submit an annual report to the Governors and the Secretary covering operations and fiscal transactions. Allows the Commission to transfer all functions, powers, duties, and other specified elements to the highway department or other agency of either of the two States, upon which action the Commission shall cease to exist.</summary>
</bill>
