<bill session="107" type="h" number="5760" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Internet Gambling Licensing and Regulation Commission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create a commission on Internet gambling licensing and regulation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-19">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-19">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian gambling operations"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Lotteries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minors"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court decisions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Video games"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2002--Introduced.
Internet Gambling Licensing and Regulation Commission Act - Establishes the Internet Gambling Licensing and Regulation Study Commission to conduct a comprehensive study of the existing legal framework governing Internet gambling and the issues involved with the licensing and regulation of Internet gambling.Includes within the matters to be studied by the Commission: (1) a review of existing laws governing various forms of wagering over the Internet; (2) assessments of the impact of Internet gambling with respect to problem gambling, the availability of gambling to minors, and its susceptibility to money laundering by terrorists or criminal enterprises; (3) the potential of regulatory measures to minimize adverse impacts of Internet gambling; (4) federalism issues; and (5) the problems of unregulated international Internet wagering and Federal options in seeking international cooperation.Requires the Commission to issue proposed changes to Federal laws and regulations providing for the licensing and regulation of Internet gambling in the United States which: (1) preserve the prerogatives of States and tribal sovereignty; (2) include measures to minimize adverse impacts of Internet gambling and to eliminate the disparate treatment of various forms of Internet gambling (with an exception); (3) provide for the appropriate taxation of Internet gambling enterprises (comparable to land-based gambling); (4) provide for the licensing of enterprises both within and outside of the United States; (5) remain consistent with U.S. goals, principles, and obligations in other international negotiations governing electronic commerce; and (6) include measures to discourage, prohibit, or prevent U.S. citizens from wagering with unlicensed Internet gambling operations outside the United States.</summary>
</bill>
