<bill session="104" type="h" number="978" updated="2012-11-01T22:43:58-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the formula for determining the Official Mail Allowance for Members of the House of Representatives; to amend the provisions of title 39, United States Code, relating to the franking privilege for Members of Congress and provide that the provisions of law preventing Members from sending mass mailings within the 60-day period immediately before an election be expanded so as to prevent Members from mailing any unsolicited franked mail within that period, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401547"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Postal Service"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional allowances"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>02/16/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991 to revise the formula for the official mail allowance (thus, reducing the amount allowed) for Members of the House of Representatives. Prohibits the transfer of funds appropriated for official mail costs of the House. Prohibits any: (1) Member of Congress from sending any unsolicited franked mail (currently, franked mass mailings) postmarked fewer than 60 days immediately before any primary or general election in which such Member is a candidate; and (2) Representative who is a candidate for any other public office from sending unsolicited franked mail outside his or her congressional district. Repeals Federal law that makes frankable mail matter which consists of voter registration, election information, or assistance prepared and mailed in a nonpartisan manner. Requires any amount remaining in an official allowance of a Member of the House of Representatives at the end of the session of the Congress or other period for which the allowance is made available to be returned to the Treasury for deficit reduction.</summary>
</bill>
