<bill session="107" type="h" number="2341" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-03-13T18:11:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-03-13T18:11:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Class Action Fairness Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Class Action Fairness Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Class Action Fairness Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the procedures that apply to consideration of interstate class actions to assure fairer outcomes for class members and defendants, to outlaw certain practices that provide inadequate settlements for class members, to assure that attorneys do not receive a disproportionate amount of settlements at the expense of class members, to provide for clearer and simpler information in class action settlement notices, to assure prompt consideration of interstate class actions, to amend title 28, United States Code, to allow the application of the principles of Federal diversity jurisdiction to interstate class actions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="2001-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2001-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2001-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2002-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400549" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2001-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400060" joined="2002-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2001-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="2001-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2002-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="2001-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="2001-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2001-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2002-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2002-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2001-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="2002-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2001-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="2001-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2002-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2002-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400168" joined="2001-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="2002-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2001-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2001-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2002-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400212" joined="2001-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400225" joined="2001-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="2001-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="2002-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2001-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400501" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2002-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400362" joined="2002-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2001-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400375" joined="2001-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2001-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400392" joined="2002-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2001-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2002-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2001-11-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1234"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-06">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-03-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 16 - 10.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-03-07T12:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Armey asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Judiciary have until 7:00 p.m. on March 11 to file a report on H.R. 2341. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-12T14:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 107-370.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/13/2002 H857-859" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-03-12T14:25:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="213">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 213.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-03-12T19:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 367 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2341 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T12:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 367 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T12:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 367.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H847-886" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T12:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2341 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T12:20:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John Linder to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T12:20:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 367 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T12:20:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2341.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T13:30:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 367, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Nadler amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T13:31:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Nadler demanded a recorded vote and made a point of no quorum. Pursuant to clause 8 of Rule XX, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment and the point of no quorum was considered withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T13:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Debate - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 367, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Waters amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T13:59:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Conyers demanded a recorded vote and made a point of no quorum. Pursuant to clause 8 of Rule XX, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment and the point of no quorum was considered withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 367, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Keller amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T14:21:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 367, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Lofgren amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T14:41:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Lofgren demanded a recorded vote and made a point of no quorum. Pursuant to clause 8 of Rule XX, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment and the point of no quorum was considered withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T14:42:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Conyers demanded a recorded vote and made a point of no quorum. Pursuant to clause 8 of Rule XX, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment and the point of no quorum was considered withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T14:42:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 367, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Conyers amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T15:44:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 367, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee, (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T16:09:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson-Lee of Texas demanded a recorded vote and made a point of no quorum. Pursuant to clause 8 of Rule XX, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment and the point of no quorum was considered withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T16:10:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 367, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Frank amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T16:10:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Frank demanded a recorded vote and made a point of no quorum. Pursuant to clause 8 of Rule XX, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment and the point of no quorum was considered withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T16:31:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 367, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Hart amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2341.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T17:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Sandlin moved to recommit with instructions to Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T17:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment providing that any defendant who is a knowing participant in any conspiracy to hijack any aircraft or commit an act of terrorism shall not be entitled to remove a class action to federal court pursuant to section 1332(d) of title 28, as added by section 4 of the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T17:41:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T18:01:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 191 - 235 (Roll no. 61).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-03-13T18:11:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="62" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 233 - 190 (Roll no. 62).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T18:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-31">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="107" type="hr" number="367"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate governance"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Legal advertising and soliciting"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Newspapers"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h435"/>
    <amendment number="h436"/>
    <amendment number="h437"/>
    <amendment number="h438"/>
    <amendment number="h439"/>
    <amendment number="h440"/>
    <amendment number="h441"/>
    <amendment number="h442"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/13/2002--Passed House amended.
Class Action Fairness Act of 2002 - Establishes a consumer class action bill of rights, including provision for: (1) judicial review and approval of noncash settlements; (2) protection against loss by class members because of payments to class counsel; (3) a prohibition against court approval of a proposed settlement providing for greater payments to class members because they are located in closer geographic proximity to the court; (4) a prohibition against court approval of a proposed settlement providing for payment of a greater share of the award to a class representative serving on behalf of a class; (5) standardized settlement notification information; (6) disclosure of attorney's fees; and (7) sunshine in court records (limiting the sealing, or subjection to a protective order, of such records).Grants the district courts original jurisdiction of any civil action in which the matter in controversy exceeds $2 million, exclusive of interest and costs, and is a class action in which any member of a class of plaintiffs is: (1) a citizen of a State different from any defendant; (2) a foreign state or a citizen or subject of a foreign state and any defendant is a citizen of a State; or (3) a citizen of a State and any defendant is a foreign state or a citizen or subject of a foreign state. Lists exceptions, such as where a class action brought by shareholders solely involves a claim concerning a covered security or relating to the internal governance of a corporation.Sets forth procedures for removal of interstate class actions to U.S. district court and for review of orders remanding class actions to State courts. Prohibits a plaintiff class member who is not a named or representative class member of the action from seeking removal of the action before an order certifying a class of which the plaintiff is a class member has been entered.Grants the courts of appeals jurisdiction of appeals from orders of the U.S. district courts granting or denying class certification under rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, if notice of appeal is filed within ten days after entry of the order.Requires the Judicial Conference of the United States, with the assistance of the Director of the Federal Judicial Center and the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, to prepare and transmit to the Senate and House Judiciary Committees a report on class action settlements in the Federal courts.</summary>
</bill>
