<bill session="106" type="h" number="2200" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Omnibus Airline Passenger Fair Treatment Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a national policy of basic consumer fair treatment for airline passengers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2000-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="2000-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="1999-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2000-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1999-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="2000-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1999-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1999-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1999-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="1999-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="2000-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1999-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400603" joined="1999-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1999-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2000-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="1999-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2000-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="383"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="383"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Airline employees"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airline rates"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Travel agents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/1999--Introduced.
Omnibus Airline Passenger Fair Treatment Act of 1999 - Amends Federal aviation law to revise provisions prohibiting an air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent from engaging in unfair or deceptive practices or unfair methods of competition in air transportation. Extends such prohibition to any action of an air carrier or foreign air carrier that: (1) fails to provide a consumer full access to all fares for air transportation provided by them, regardless of the technology or other method the consumer uses to access the fares; (2) fails to provide an air carrier passenger with an accurate explanation of the reasons for a flight delay, cancellation, or diversion from a ticketed itinerary; and (3) prohibits a person (including a governmental entity) that purchases air transportation from only using a portion of the air transportation purchased (including using air transportation purchased only for one-way travel instead of round-trip travel), or assesses an additional fee on or charge to such person or ticket agent that sold the air transportation to such person.(Sec. 2) Prohibits an air carrier or foreign air carrier, in the case of a termination, cancellation, nonrenewal, or substantial change in the competitive circumstances of a ticket agent's appointment, from failing to provide the ticket agent with: (1) written notice, and a full statement of reasons for the action, on or before the 90th day preceding the action; and (2) at least 60 days to correct any deficiency claimed in such notice. Exempts a carrier from this requirement only in cases of insolvency, an assignment for the benefit of creditors, bankruptcy, or nonpayment of sums due under the appointment.(Sec. 3) Revises the preemption of State, local, and regional law or regulation related to a price, route, or level of service for air transportation provided by an air carrier. Limits the preemption to any such law or regulation that would directly prescribe a price, route, or level of service.(Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations to establish minimum Federal standards for resuscitation, emergency medical, and first-aid equipment and supplies to be carried on board an aircraft operated by an air carrier that is capable of carrying at least 30 passengers.Bars an air carrier or foreign air carrier from preventing or hindering (including by failing to assist) a passenger from exiting an aircraft if: (1) the aircraft is parked at an airport terminal gate with access to ramp or other facilities through which passengers are customarily boarded and deplaned; (2) such aircraft has remained at the gate more than one hour past its scheduled departure time; and (3) the captain of the aircraft has not been informed by air traffic control authorities that such aircraft can be cleared for departure within 15 minutes.(Sec. 5) Establishes the National Commission to Ensure Consumer Information and Choice in the Airline Industry. Requires the Commission, among other things, to study and make policy recommendations to the President and Congress on consumer access to information about the products and services of the airline industry, especially airline fares and routes.</summary>
</bill>
