<bill session="104" type="h" number="508" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to ensure proper classification as employees and independent contractors of persons awarded Federal procurement contracts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1995-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/13/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to: (1) make persons who willfully misclassify an individual for purposes of any employment tax ineligible for any Government contract; (2) require a person who submits a bid or proposal for a Government contract to certify that the amount of the bid or proposal is adequate to pay all employment taxes with respect to all work to be performed under the contract by the contractor's employees; (3) require each Government contract to include a requirement that the contractor provide certain notifications to each person who performs work under the contract and who is treated as an independent contractor for purposes of employment taxes; and (4) allow a person who submits a bid or proposal for a Government contract and who suffers damages as a result of the award of the contract to a person who knowingly and willfully submits a false certification to bring an action for damages against the person awarded the contract in any U.S. district court in which the defendant is located.</summary>
</bill>
