<bill session="108" type="h" number="2654" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rigs to Reefs Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to issue regulations under which the Secretary may authorize use of a decommissioned offshore oil and gas platform for culture of marine organisms, an artificial reef, or scientific research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="2003-09-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Coral reefs"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Offshore structures"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Reefs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2003--Introduced.
Rigs to Reefs Act of 2003 - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to instruct the Secretary of the Interior to issue regulations authorizing the use for culture of marine organisms, an artificial reef, or scientific research of any offshore oil and gas platform decommissioned from service for oil and gas purposes. Denies liability under Federal law of any former owner of an offshore oil and gas platform for costs or damages arising from use of it for culture of marine organisms, an artificial reef, or scientific research, unless such costs or damages arise from: (1) use of the platform by the person for development or production of oil or gas; or (2) another act or omission. Amends the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to business-related credits) to establish an income tax credit for costs relating to converting offshore oil and gas platforms for culturing marine organisms.</summary>
</bill>
