<bill session="105" type="h" number="4733" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Trade Adjustment Assistance Reform Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Trade Act of 1974 to consolidate and enhance the trade adjustment assistance and NAFTA transitional adjustment assistance programs under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400256"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="1998-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1998-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Economic security"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Offshore manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/1998--Introduced.
Trade Adjustment Assistance Reform Act of 1998 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to authorize appropriations to the Department of Labor for FY 1999 through 2003 for trade adjustment assistance (TAA) for workers. (Sec. 2) Repeals the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) Transitional Adjustment Assistance Program (effectively eliminating TAA for workers under such program). (Sec. 3) Revises requirements for the filing of petitions for TAA for a group of workers adversely affected by imports. Authorizes employers of such workers, one-stop career centers, or State employment agencies to file on their behalf with the Governor of the State (currently, with the Secretary of Labor) a petition for certification of eligibility for such assistance. Requires the Governor to: (1) transmit the petition to the Secretary immediately; (2) ensure that rapid response assistance and basic readjustment services are made available to the workers; and (3) assist the Secretary in the review of the petition. Requires the Secretary to review such petitions for certification of eligibility within 40 days (currently, 60 days) of its filing. (Sec. 4) Adds as a factor in the Secretary's determination of the eligibility of a group of workers for TAA any shift in production by such workers' firm to a foreign country of articles like or directly competitive with articles produced by such firm. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to collect and maintain certain information with respect to certifications of TAA. (Sec. 6) Revises enrollment in training requirements with respect to the payment of TAA to adversely affected workers to set forth certain time periods during which such enrollment must occur. Authorizes the Secretary to issue a statement to a worker waiving the enrollment in training requirements if it is determined that such training requirement is not feasible or appropriate for the worker, based on specified factors. (Sec. 8) Increases from 14 to 30 the number of days an adversely affected worker may have a scheduled break in a training program and still be treated as participating in the program for purposes of TAA eligibility. (Sec. 9) Increases the total annual amount of payments for worker training from $80 million to $150 million for any fiscal year. (Sec. 11) Authorizes the Secretary to secure for adversely affected workers certain employment services, including services provided through one-stop career centers. Provides for the coordination of employment services for adversely affected workers under the Job Training Partnership Act and the Workforce Investment Act of 1998. (Sec. 12) Authorizes an adversely affected worker to file an application with the Secretary for the provision of supportive services, including transportation, child and dependent care, and other similar services. Sets forth specified conditions with respect to such services. (Sec. 14) Makes unappropriated Treasury funds available in any fiscal year that TAA funds become exhausted. (Sec. 15) Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Labor for FY 1999 through 2003 for TAA for firms. (Sec. 16) Establishes the Presidential Commission on Workers and Economic Change in the New Economy to study and report to the President and the Congress on matters relating to economic dislocation and worker adjustment to such dislocations. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
