<bill session="105" type="h" number="4310" updated="2012-11-01T22:49:20-05:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to permit a corporation or labor organization to expend or donate funds for staging public debates between presidential candidates only if the organization staging the debate invites each candidate who is eligible for matching payments from the Presidential Election Campaign Fund and qualified for the ballot in a number of States such that the candidate is eligible to receive the minimum number of electoral votes necessary for election.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400611"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1384)</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1384"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Business and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor union finances"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential debates"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>07/22/1998--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to permit a corporation or labor organization to expend or donate funds for staging a public debate between presidental candidates only if the person staging the debate invites each candidate who is eligible for matching payments from the Presidential Election Campaign Fund and qualified for the ballot in a number of States such that the candidate is eligible to receive not fewer than the minimum number of electoral votes necessary for election.</summary>
</bill>
