<bill session="105" type="h" number="4063" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Assistive and Universally Designed Technology Improvement Act for Individuals with Disabilities</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 to provide for research and development of assistive technology and universally designed technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1141"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-16">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-16">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2076"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY17" subcommittee="Technology" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to disability services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-help devices for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication systems"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/1998--Introduced.
Assistive and Universally Designed Technology Improvement Act for Individuals with Disabilities - Provides for research and development of assistive technology and universally designed technology. (Sec. 4) Amends the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (RA) to require the Director of the National Institute on Disability and Rehabilitation Research (Director) to establish a peer review process for the review of applications for grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements for research and development of assistive technology and universally designed technology. (Sec. 5) Directs the Interagency Committee on Disability Research (Committee) to carry out specified functions with respect to research and development of assistive technology and universally designed technology, including developing technology transfer activities. Requires the Director to: (1) establish special task forces and subcommittees of the Committee for research and development of assistive technology and universally designed technology, including ones related to medical rehabilitation, technology (including universal design), and the employment of individuals with disabilities; (2) issue a biannual report announcing the availability of the grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements through Federal departments and agencies represented on the Committee for research and development of assistive technology and universally designed technology; and (3) submit results and analyses of such research and development activities, Committee activities, and periodic surveys of manufacturers and suppliers of such technology, to the Commissioner of the Rehabilitation Services Administration for inclusion in an annual report to the Congress. Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to require the Federal Laboratory Consortium for Technology Transfer (Consortium) to develop and disseminate specified information to all Federal, State, and local agencies and instrumentalities involved in assistive technology and universally designed technology. Requires the Director to: (1) participate annually in the Consortium's national and interagency meetings; (2) coordinate the activities of the Federal laboratories with respect to research and development of assistive technology and universally designed technology; and (3) use Consortium resources to identify potential public and private sector partners for research and development collaboration regarding assistive technology and universally designed technology. (Sec. 6) Amends the Technology-Related Assistance for Individuals With Disabilities Act of 1988 to revise requirements for the microloan program under which the Secretary of Labor awards grants to States for alternative funding mechanism programs to allow individuals with disabilities to purchase assistive and universally designed technology devices, products, and services. Requires such programs to maximize consumer participation. Requires such grants to be awarded on the basis of State population. Extends through FY 2001 the authorization of appropriations for the microloan program. (Sec. 7) Amends the RA to extend through FY 2001 the authorization of appropriations for: (1) the National Institute on Disability and Rehabilitation Research, including specified expenses of the Interagency Committee on Disability Research, the Rehabilitation Research Advisory Council, and peer review panels; and (2) various research activities, including assistance for research and development on assistive technology and universally designed technology. (Sec. 8) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) establish an assistive technology business tax credit; (2) include communication barriers under the architectural and transportation barrier removal tax deduction; and (3) include expenses incurred in the acquisition of technology to facilitate the employment of any individual with a disability under the work opportunity tax credit.</summary>
</bill>
