<bill session="105" type="h" number="4105" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-23T17:36:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-06-23T17:36:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Internet Tax Freedom Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Internet Tax Freedom Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a national policy against State and local interference with interstate commerce on the Internet, to exercise congressional jurisdiction over interstate commerce by establishing a moratorium on the imposition of exactions that would interfere with the free flow of commerce via the Internet, to establish a national policy against federal and state regulation of Internet access and online services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400083"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, Ways and Means, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-23T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gekas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-23T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5028-5037" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-23T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-06-23T17:36:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-06-23T17:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-06-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="427">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 427.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="1054"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3529"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3849"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="442"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="442"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="442"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Internet service providers"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Price regulation"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Telephone rates"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/1998--Introduced.
Internet Tax Freedom Act - Prohibits, for three years after enactment of this Act, any State or political subdivision from imposing, assessing, collecting, or attempting to collect taxes on Internet access, bit taxes, or multiple or discriminatory taxes on electronic commerce. Provides an exception for such taxes imposed by certain States and in effect on the date of enactment of this Act (requiring such States, within one year, to expressly affirm that such a tax is imposed on Internet access). Establishes the Advisory Commission on Electronic Commerce to study State and local taxation of transactions using the Internet and Internet access, examine model State legislation with respect to such taxation and simplified administrative procedures concerning such taxation, and transmit to the President and the Congress proposed legislation reflecting the findings of such study and examination. Directs the President to review such proposals and submit to the Congress such policy recommendations as deemed necessary or expedient. Provides for the expedited consideration of the proposed legislation. (Sec. 3) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 (the Act) to prohibit the Federal Communications Commission or any State commission from having regulatory authority or jurisdiction with respect to charges paid by subscribers for Internet access or online services. (Sec. 4) Exempts providers of such services from Federal regulatory fees. Requires the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to determine whether any direct or indirect Federal regulatory fees, other than the fees identified under the Act, are imposed on such providers, and if so, make recommendations to the Congress regarding whether such fees should be modified or eliminated. (Sec. 5) Requires the Secretary of Commerce to examine: (1) barriers imposed in foreign markets on U.S. providers of property, goods, services, or information engaged in electronic commerce and on U.S. providers of telecommunications services; (2) how the imposition of such barriers will affect U.S. consumers, the competitiveness of U.S. citizens acting as such providers in foreign markets, and the growth and maturing of the Internet; and (3) measures the Government should pursue to foster, promote, and develop electronic commerce in the United States and in foreign markets. Directs: (1) the Secretary to report to the Congress on the results of the examination; and (2) the President to review such report and submit to the appropriate congressional committees such policy recommendations as deemed necessary or expedient. (Sec. 6) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the President should seek bilateral and multilateral agreements to remove barriers to global electronic commerce through various international organizations to require that the provision of Internet access or online services be free from undue and discriminatory regulation by foreign governments and that electronic commercial transactions between U.S. and foreign providers of property, goods, services, and information be free from undue and discriminatory regulation, international tariffs, and discriminatory taxation.</summary>
</bill>
