<bill session="107" type="h" number="3844" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen Federal Government information security, including through the requirement for the development of mandatory information security risk management standards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="2002-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-03-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E259"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Technology, and Standards.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Environment, Technology, and Standards" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Encryption"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Management audit"/>
    <term name="Military communications"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2002--Introduced.
Federal Information Security Management Act of 2002 - Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to oversee Federal agency information security policies and practices, including by requiring each Federal agency to identify and provide information security protections commensurate with the risk and magnitude of harm resulting from the unauthorized use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction of information or information systems. Requires each agency's senior officials to provide security for the information and systems that support their operations and assets and to develop plans and procedures to ensure the continuity of such information and systems.Requires the: (1) Director to establish and operate a central Federal information security incident center; and (2) head of each agency operating or controlling a national security system to take measures to protect such system.Authorizes appropriations for FY 2003 through 2007 for information security.Requires the Director (currently, the Secretary of Commerce) to promulgate standards and guidelines pertaining to Federal information (currently, computer) systems.Requires the National Institute of Standards and Technology to: (1) develop and submit to the Director standards and guidelines for information (currently, computer) systems used or operated by or for a Federal agency, other than national security systems; and (2) provide adequate security for such systems. Establishes in the Institute an Office for Information Security Programs.Renames the Computer System Security and Privacy Advisory Board as the Information Security Advisory Board.</summary>
</bill>
