<bill session="104" type="h" number="291" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Solid Waste Compact Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act to improve procedures for the implementation of State compacts providing for the establishment and operation of regional disposal facilities for municipal and industrial solid waste, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400210"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Solid Waste Compact Act of 1995 - Amends the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act to require States to submit solid waste disposal plans to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for approval. Authorizes States to enter into compacts to provide for the establishment and operation of regional solid waste disposal facilities. Prohibits a compact from restricting the use of such facilities to solid waste generated in the compact region before January 1, 1997, and before the Congress consents to such compact. Requires a compact to provide that every five years after such compact has taken effect the Congress may withdraw its consent. Directs EPA to: (1) identify alternative management programs for the control of solid waste and publish technical guidance regarding the implementation of such programs; and (2) publish information that a State or compact must provide to EPA, together with requirements for facilities, if such programs are pursued as alternatives to traditional solid waste management.</summary>
</bill>
