<bill session="106" type="h" number="951" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airline Service Improvement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide assistance and slots with respect to air carrier service between high density airports and airports not receiving sufficient air service, to improve jet aircraft service to underserved markets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400116"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.1000.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="1000"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Jet aircraft"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local service airlines"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
    <term name="Sparsely populated areas"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Service to Airports Not Receiving Sufficient Service Title II: Regional Air Service Incentive Program Title III: Contract Tower Program Airline Service Improvement Act of 1999 - Title I: Service to Airports Not Receiving Sufficient Service - Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to grant exemptions pertaining to the use of slots (arrival and departure spaces) at high density airports in order to enable air carriers to provide nonstop air transportation using noise-compliant aircraft between a high density airport and an airport that had less than two million enplanements and an airport that does not have such nonstop transportation on the date on which the application for an exemption is filed. Provides exemption limitations, including a limitation of no more than six exemptions per day for slots at Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport (with further conditions on the Washington exemptions). Requires exemption decisions to be made by the Secretary within 120 days of application. Makes funds not otherwise obligated or expended for the Federal essential air service program available for: (1) air carrier service to airports not receiving sufficient air service; and (2) rural air safety at airports with less than 100,000 annual boardings. Makes 50 percent of any available funds in excess of $50 million in a fiscal year after 1999 available for the rural air safety program. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2000 to provide jet aircraft service to underserved airports. Provides an assistance priority at airports for which a community will provide a portion of the costs incurred. Waives the local contribution requirement for any place for which a proposal was approved or designated as eligible for such assistance during the period beginning October 1, 1991, and ending on December 31, 1997. Title II: Regional Air Service Incentive Program - Authorizes the Secretary to guarantee any lender against loss on any loan made to a commuter air carrier (maximum seating capacity of 75 or less) or new entrant air carrier (less than five years of service) for the purchase of jet aircraft when such aircraft are to be used to provide at least two round-trips per day five days per week to underserved markets. Outlines loan conditions and limitations, including that: (1) such aircraft comply with certain Federal noise-level requirements; and (2) the air carrier agrees to provide service to the underserved airport(s) for at least two years after being placed in service. Directs the Secretary to repay the holder of a loan guaranteed by the Secretary after the holder has made reasonable collection efforts. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) collect a loan guarantee fee from such lenders; and (2) be given, and make use of, Federal facilities and assistance in carrying out the incentive program. Terminates the above authority five years after the enactment of this Act. Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Contract Tower Program - Directs the Secretary to establish a program to contract for air traffic control services at not more than 20 low activity air traffic control towers that do not qualify for the current contract tower program. Provides airport priority under the program. Requires the airport sponsor or appropriate State or local government to pay the portion of control tower costs exceeding benefits under the program. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
