<bill session="107" type="h" number="3707" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to improve protection for endangered species habitats.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400322"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2002-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2002-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2002-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2002-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="2002-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="2002-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2002-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-02-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E120-121"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2002--Introduced.
Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to direct the Secretary of the Interior, concurrently with: (1) making a determination that a species is an endangered or threatened species, to designate "survival habitat" of the species (i.e., the specific areas within the geographical area occupied by the species, at the time it is listed, on which are found those physical or biological features that are essential to the conservation of the species and that may require special management considerations or protection); and (2) adoption of the final recovery plan for a species, to designate critical habitat of the species.Requires that survival habitat designated for a species at the time of listing be revised and finalized as critical habitat concurrently with the adoption of the final recovery plan for the species.Directs the Secretary to designate survival habitat based only on the best scientific and commercial data available and after taking into consideration the economic and any other relevant impact. Allows the Secretary to exclude any area from survival habitat upon determining that the benefits of such exclusion outweigh the benefits of the specification unless the Secretary determines that the failure to designate such area will result in the extinction of the species concerned.</summary>
</bill>
