<bill session="104" type="hj" number="51" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to require three-fifths majorities for bills increasing taxes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404503"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1995-01-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-24">
      <text>See H.J.Res.1.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hj" number="1"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Gross national product"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/11/1995--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Requires a three-fifths majority of the whole number of each House of the Congress before a bill increasing any revenue may pass. Provides that total revenue of the United States Government for each fiscal year shall not exceed 20 percent of the gross domestic product and that any revenue in excess of this limit shall be used to reduce the public debt. Authorizes a specific amount of additional revenue above such limit for the current or next fiscal year when a bill for this sole purpose is passed by a three-fifths majority of the whole number of each House of the Congress and becomes law. Authorizes the Congress, upon the President's request, to waive the provisions of this joint resolution by a roll call vote for any fiscal year in which a declaration of war is in effect. Requires any law that has the effect of increasing any revenue, if adopted when a waiver is in effect, to expire within two years after the law is adopted.</summary>
</bill>
