<bill session="106" type="h" number="4329" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to make it illegal to operate a motor vehicle with a drug or alcohol in the body of the driver at a land border port of entry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400606"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2000-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400577" joined="2000-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2000-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400135" joined="2000-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2000-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2000-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="2000-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2000-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2000-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2000-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Automobile drivers"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Truck drivers"/>
    <term name="Urinalysis"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2000--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code (the code) to prohibit any person from operating a motor vehicle at land border ports of entry with a drug or alcohol in his or her body in violation of applicable State law. Deems any individual who operates a motor vehicle at a land border port of entry to have given consent to submit to a test of the driver's blood, breath, or urine for drugs or alcohol by an officer or employee (officer) of the Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS). Directs the Attorney General to notify the State or foreign state that issued an individual's motor vehicle license or that is the residence of such individual of any refusal by such individual to submit to such a test and of any conviction of an individual under this Act for violating this Act.(Sec. 2) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to authorize an INS officer who: (1) inspects a driver at a land border port of entry and who has reasonable grounds to believe that the driver may be operating a motor vehicle in violation of State laws to require the driver to submit to a breath test to determine the presence or concentration of the alcohol; and (2) arrests a driver for such prohibited operation of a motor vehicle to require the driver to submit to a drug or alcohol test.(Sec. 3) Amends the INA to require the Attorney General, at each point where motor vehicles regularly enter a land border port of entry, to post a notice that operation of a motor vehicle with a drug or alcohol in the driver's body at a land border port of entry is an offense under Federal law.(Sec. 4) Directs the Attorney General to issue regulations authorizing an INS officer to impound a vehicle if the individual who operates it refuses to submit to such a test.</summary>
</bill>
