<bill session="104" type="h" number="987" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Domestic Oil and Gas Production and Preservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Private Property Owners Bill of Rights</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage production of oil and gas within the United States by providing tax incentives and easing regulatory burdens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401774" joined="1995-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1995-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1996-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404503" joined="1995-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1995-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="1995-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1995-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1995-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1995-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="408476" joined="1995-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1995-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400534" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1995-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E381-382"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Resources, the Judiciary, Commerce, Science, Government Reform and Oversight, and International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, Commerce, Army.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO01" subcommittee="National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="451"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Depletion allowances"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy tax credits"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Offshore structures"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution control"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Regulatory reform"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary recovery of oil"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Tax Incentives for Oil and Gas Production Subtitle A: Production Credit Subtitle B: Modifications to Percentage Depletion Subtitle C: Other Provisions Title II: Regulatory Reform Subtitle A: Oil Pollution Act Amendments Subtitle B: Oil and Gas Royalties Subtitle C: Private Property Rights Subtitle D: Risk Assessments Title III: Repeal of Limitations on Exports Domestic Oil and Gas Production and Preservation Act - Title I: Tax Incentives for Oil and Gas Production - Subtitle A: Production Credit - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a business tax credit for producing crude oil and natural gas from new wells and marginal wells. Provides: (1) a formula for reducing such credit in years in which oil and gas prices increase; and (2) an inflation adjustment for such formula. Allows such credit against the regular and minimum tax. Subtitle B: Modifications to Percentage Depletion - Repeals the net income limitation on percentage depletion for oil and gas properties. (Sec. 112) Makes all marginal production of domestic crude oil or domestic natural gas eligible for percentage depletion. (Sec. 114) Revises the percentage depletion rate for such marginal production. Subtitle C: Other Provisions - Allows the election to treat geological and geophysical expenses incurred in connection with the exploration for, or development of, domestic oil or gas as expenses which are not chargeable to capital account. (Sec. 122) Makes the enhanced oil recovery credit applicable to secondary recovery methods. Allows such credit against the minimum tax. (Sec. 123) Allows the election of an optional five-year writeoff of intangible drilling costs for minimum tax purposes. Title II: Regulatory Reform - Subtitle A: Oil Pollution Act Amendments - Amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to revise general financial responsibility requirements for offshore facilities. Requires responsible parties (except as provided in provisions regarding deepwater ports) to maintain financial responsibility as described by this Act with respect to offshore facilities seaward of the U.S. coastline that are used for drilling for, producing, or processing oil or that have the capacity to transport, store, transfer, or handle more than 1,000 barrels of oil at any one time. Requires the financial responsibility of an offshore facility to be $35 million, unless the President determines that a greater amount (not to exceed $150 million) is necessary based on an assessment of the risk posed by such facility. Subtitle B: Oil and Gas Royalties - Establishes a six-year statute of limitations on actions commenced by the United States for recovery of royalties due under an oil and gas lease on Federal lands unless a lessee has made a false or fraudulent statement with the intent to evade the royalties due. Subtitle C: Private Property Rights - Private Property Owners Bill of Rights - Provides for the protection of private property rights. (Sec. 235) Prohibits an agency head from entering privately owned property to collect information regarding it without the owner's written consent and specified notices. (Sec. 236) Sets forth conditions under which an agency head may use the data collected from privately owned property to implement or enforce any applicable provisions of law. (Sec. 237) Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to grant a right to an administrative appeal of wetlands decisions. (Sec. 238) Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to grant owners or their authorized representatives a right to an administrative appeal with regard to certain actions under that Act. (Sec. 239) Provides compensation for the taking of private property. (Sec. 240) Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to provide for private property owner participation in cooperative agreements. Subtitle D: Risk Assessments - Requires each agency head to prepare a risk assessment, according to specified principles distinguishing scientific findings and best estimates of risk from other considerations, for each major rule relating to human health, safety, and natural resources. Requires the President, within one year after enactment of this Act, to issue a final regulation implementing such risk assessment and characterization principles. Provides for petitions for review of major rule risk assessments. Sets forth agency head decisional criteria and regulatory priorities. Directs the President to develop a systematic program for peer review of work products. Title III: Repeal of Limitations on Exports - Amends the Export Administration Act of 1979, the Mineral Lands Leasing Act, the Energy Policy and Conservation Act, and the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to repeal limitations on the export of domestically produced crude oil. Declares that the President may not prohibit or curtail the export of domestically produced crude oil other than crude oil produced from the naval petroleum reserves.</summary>
</bill>
