<bill session="108" type="h" number="2653" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rocky Flats Minerals Acquisition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate acquisition by the Secretary of the Interior of certain mineral rights, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1396"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Sand and gravel industry"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2003--Introduced.
Rocky Flats Minerals Acquisition Act - Amends Federal law to permit the Secretary of the Interior to acquire mineral interests, including interests in sand and gravel, within the Rocky Flats National Wildlife Refuge, Colorado, by purchase, exchange, issuance of credits, or any combination thereof. Defines credits as legal instruments or other written documentation, or an entry in an account managed by the Secretary, that can be used for: (1) bonus bids for lease sales on the Outer Continental Shelf; or (2) royalty due on any oil or gas production under any lease of an area located in a specified part of the Outer Continental Shelf. Declares that the requirement under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 that lands or interests exchanged under a section of such Act must be located in the same State shall not apply to land or an interest in land in the Rocky Flats National Wildlife Refuge that is acquired by the United States in an exchange under that section. States that any interests acquired by the United States under this Act shall be managed by the Secretary under the standards that apply to the Rocky Flats National Wildlife Refuge. Declares that no minerals acquired under this Act shall be subject to development or disposal by the United States or any other party under any law related to minerals owned by the United States.</summary>
</bill>
