<bill session="108" type="h" number="5081" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for a new program of educational assistance for certain reserve component members of the Armed Forces who perform active service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400020"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="2004-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400265" joined="2004-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400303" joined="2004-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2004-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400353" joined="2004-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400393" joined="2004-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2004-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Flight training"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2004--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of each military department, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, to establish a program as prescribed in this Act to provide educational assistance to members of the Ready Reserve of the Armed Forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned. Makes eligible for such benefits on or after September 11, 2001, members of Reserve components who: (1) served on active duty in support of contingency operations for at least 90 consecutive days; or (2) in the case of an Army or Air National Guard member, performed full time duty for at least 90 consecutive days for the purpose of responding to a national emergency declared by the President and supported by Federal funds. Creates an exception to the 90-day requirement for members released from duty because of injury, illness, or disease incurred or aggravated in the line of duty. States that members remain entitled to such educational assistance if ordered to active duty while serving in the Selected Reserve or the Ready Reserve. Terminates educational assistance for disabled members 10 years from the date of entitlement. Requires educational assistance under this Act to be provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs.</summary>
</bill>
