<bill session="105" type="h" number="181" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:27-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to reform the financing of elections for members of the House of Representatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1997-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSIF" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" name="House Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>01/07/1997--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to limit contributions to House of Representatives elections from persons other than local individual residents. Reduces maximum House contribution amounts from multicandidate political committees (PACs). Sets forth limitations and reporting requirements for amounts paid for mixed political activities ("soft money"). Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require a broadcast station to make broadcast time available to all House and Senate candidates in the last 30 (currently 45) days before a primary and the last 45 (currently 60) days before a general election, at the lowest unit charge of the station for the same amount of time (currently, the same class and amount of time) for the same period on the same date. Prohibits broadcasters from preempting advertisements sold to political candidates at the lowest unit rate, unless the preemption is beyond the broadcaster's control.</summary>
</bill>
