<bill session="106" type="h" number="2684" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2000, HUD</title>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2000, Veterans Affairs, HUD</title>
    <title type="popular">Housing and Urban Development FY2000 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Veterans Affairs FY2000 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Preserving Affordable Housing for Senior Citizens and Families into the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and for sundry independent agencies, boards, commissions, corporations, and offices for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2000, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400420"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-08-03T21:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-286, by Mr. Walsh.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-08-03T21:52:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="171">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 171.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05T00:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 275 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2684 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. Provides that before consideration of any other amendment it shall be in order to consider the amendment printed in the rules committee report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05T23:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 275 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T12:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 275.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7892-7958" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7910, H7913-7915, H7921, H7925" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7929, H7935, H7940-7944" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T12:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2684 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. Provides that before consideration of any other amendment it shall be in order to consider the amendment printed in the rules committee report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T12:47:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Obey raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Obey stated that the bill exceeded the budget authority allocation. Subsequently, Mr. Obey withdrew his point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T12:50:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 275 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T12:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steven C. LaTourette to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T12:50:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2684.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. Walsh asked unanimous consent that Mr. Filner be allowed to offer an amendment no. 1 at any time during consideration of the bill for amendment in the Committee of the Whole. Agreed to without objections.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment by voice vote and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cunningham demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 275, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Roemer.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T15:21:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment by voice vote and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Roemer demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to H. Res. 275 futher proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Nadler by voice vote and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Nadler demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to H. Res. 275 futher proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nadler amendment, the Chair put the question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Subsequently, a demand for a recorded vote was made and further proceedings were postponed until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T18:16:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rogan amendment, the Chair put the question and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Bateman subsequently demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bateman raised a point of order against the content of the measure. The proviso beginning on line 15, page 70 and extending to line 22 seeks to strike the Federal Water Pollution Control Act and is subject to a point of order resulting in legislation in an appropriation bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T18:48:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gutierrez amendment, the Chair put the question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Walsh subsequently demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Filner appealed the ruling of the Chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T19:23:00-04:00">
      <text>On sustaining the ruling of the Chair. Agreed to by recorded vote: 219 - 198 (Roll no. 390).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T19:23:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEEDINGS - The Chair annnounced that proceedings will resume on amendments postponed earlier in the following order: Cunningham, Roemer, Nadler, Nadler, Rogan, and Gutierrez.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08T20:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2684 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8020-8065" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8028-8029" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment by voice vote and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Smith of Michigan demanded a recored vote. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 275, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Hinchey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEEDINGS - Mr. Mollohan asked unanimous consent that debate on the Hinchey amendment and all amendments thereto be concluded by 4 p.m. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T15:40:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment by voice vote and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hinchey demanded a recored vote. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 275, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to H. Res. 275, the Chair announced that proceedings will resume on the amendments postponed earlier in the following order: The amendment offered by Mr. Smith of Michigan and the amendment offered by Mr. Hinchey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T17:40:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment by voice vote and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Tancredo demanded a recorded vote. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 275, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T18:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2684.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T18:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T18:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T18:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 207 - 215 (Roll no. 402).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8064-8065" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-09-09T18:55:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="403" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 235 - 187 (Roll no. 403).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Senate Committee on Appropriations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11201-11209, S11232-11237, S11244-11251" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Senate struck certain provisions of H.R. 2684 and inserted in lieu thereof the text of S.1596, which will be considered as original text for the purpose of further amendments, with the Senate amendments being proposed thereto by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1744 proposed by Senator Bond.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1744 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1747 proposed by Senator Wellstone.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1757 proposed by Senator Smith, of NH.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1760 proposed by Senator Bond.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1760 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Point of order with respect to the Budget Act raised in Senate with respect to SP 1747.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Motion to waive the Budget Act with respect to SP 1747 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 36-63. Record Vote No: 285.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>SP 1747 ruled out of order by the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Motion to table SP 1757 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 61-38. Record Vote No: 286.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1777 proposed by Senator Mikulski for Senator Inouye.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1777 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1778 proposed by Senator Reed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Proposed amendment SP 1778 withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1779 proposed by Senator Bond.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1779 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1780 proposed by Senator Bond for Senator Snowe.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1780 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1785 proposed by Senator Bond for Senator Fitzgerald.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1785 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1782 proposed by Senator Dewine.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1782 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1781 proposed by Senator Dewine.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1781 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1786 proposed by Senator Bond.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 1786 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11347-11354" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Amendment SP 1789 proposed by Senator Wellstone.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11379-11420" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1789 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 76-18. Record Vote No: 292.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1756 proposed by Senator Kerry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1756 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1761 proposed by Senator Kerry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>The adoption of amendment SP 1782, as previously previously agreed to, was vitiated by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Proposed amendment SP 1782 withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Proposed amendment SP 1761 withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1790 proposed by Senator Daschle.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1791 proposed by Senator Robb.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1791 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Proposed amendment SP 1790 withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1792 proposed by Senator Mikulski for Senator Feinstein.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1793 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Smith, of OR.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1794 proposed by Senator Mikulski for Senator Breaux.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1795 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Chafee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1796 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Gramm.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1797 proposed by Senator Mikulski for Senator Dodd.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1798 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Bond.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1799 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Bond.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1800 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Hutchison.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1801 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Coverdell.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1802 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Craig.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1792 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1793 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1794 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1795 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1796 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1797 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1798 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1799 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1800 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1801 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Amendment SP 1802 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1999-09-24" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote. (text: CR 9/27/1999 S11504-11518</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment asks for a conference, appoints conferees Bond; Burns; Shelby; Craig; Hutchison; Kyl; Stevens; Mikulski; Leahy; Lautenberg; Harkin; Byrd; Inouye.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11419" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04T16:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walsh asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9273" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04T16:50:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04T16:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mollohan moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House is proceeding with one hour of debate on the motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained in the motion require the managers on the part of the House to agree with the higher funding levels recommended in the Senate amendment for the Department of Housing and Urban Development; for the Science, Aeronautics and Technology and Mission Support accounts of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration; and for the National Science Foundation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate, the yeas and nays were demanded. Subsequently, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 306 - 113 (Roll no. 472).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9284" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04T18:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Walsh, DeLay, Hobson, Knollenberg, Frelinghuysen, Wicker, Northup, Sununu, Young (FL), Mollohan, Kaptur, Meek (FL), Price (NC), Cramer, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04T18:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-07">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-13T23:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 106-379 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9983-10030" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-13T23:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 328 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2684 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Waives points of order against the conference report and against its consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-14T10:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 328 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-14T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walsh brought up conference report H. Rept. 106-379 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 328.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-14T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-14T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="1999-10-14T12:22:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="500" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 406 - 18 (Roll no. 500).</text>
      <reference ref="CR  H10042-10060" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-10-14T12:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-14">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-14">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12620-12625" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-15">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12655-12659" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1999-10-15" how="roll" result="pass" roll="328" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 93-5. Record Vote No: 328.</text>
      <reference ref="CR  S12655-12659" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-10-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1999-10-15">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1999-10-18">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1999-10-20">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1999-10-20" type="public" number="106-74">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-74.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="275"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="328"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="2491"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1596"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="106" type="s" number="1596"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="American Battle Monuments Commission"/>
    <term name="Antarctic regions"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Astronautics"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Automobile fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Aviation insurance"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Brownfields"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular diseases"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Colonias"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community Development Financial Institutions Fund"/>
    <term name="Community development banking"/>
    <term name="Community development corporations"/>
    <term name="Compulsory military service"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congregate housing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Cooperative housing"/>
    <term name="Corporation for National and Community Service"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Earth science research"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Eviction"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal mandates"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government National Mortgage Association"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Groundwater pollution"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Homeless veterans"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing policy"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in astronautics"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in science"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Launch vehicles"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Lead abatement"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Long-term care facilities"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Management information systems"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Moderate income housing"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution control"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Prosthesis"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Selective Service System"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smog"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soldiers' homes"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space commercialization"/>
    <term name="Space flight"/>
    <term name="Space programs"/>
    <term name="Space stations"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley Authority"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley development"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Theater"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Underground petroleum tanks"/>
    <term name="Underground storage"/>
    <term name="Unfunded mandates"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs research"/>
    <term name="Urban housing"/>
    <term name="Urban problems"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Welfare-to-work"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h421"/>
    <amendment number="h422"/>
    <amendment number="h423"/>
    <amendment number="h424"/>
    <amendment number="h425"/>
    <amendment number="h426"/>
    <amendment number="h427"/>
    <amendment number="h428"/>
    <amendment number="h429"/>
    <amendment number="h430"/>
    <amendment number="h431"/>
    <amendment number="h432"/>
    <amendment number="h433"/>
    <amendment number="h434"/>
    <amendment number="h435"/>
    <amendment number="h436"/>
    <amendment number="h437"/>
    <amendment number="h438"/>
    <amendment number="h439"/>
    <amendment number="h440"/>
    <amendment number="h441"/>
    <amendment number="h442"/>
    <amendment number="h443"/>
    <amendment number="h444"/>
    <amendment number="h445"/>
    <amendment number="h446"/>
    <amendment number="h447"/>
    <amendment number="h448"/>
    <amendment number="h449"/>
    <amendment number="s1744"/>
    <amendment number="s1745"/>
    <amendment number="s1746"/>
    <amendment number="s1747"/>
    <amendment number="s1748"/>
    <amendment number="s1749"/>
    <amendment number="s1750"/>
    <amendment number="s1751"/>
    <amendment number="s1752"/>
    <amendment number="s1753"/>
    <amendment number="s1754"/>
    <amendment number="s1755"/>
    <amendment number="s1756"/>
    <amendment number="s1757"/>
    <amendment number="s1758"/>
    <amendment number="s1759"/>
    <amendment number="s1760"/>
    <amendment number="s1761"/>
    <amendment number="s1762"/>
    <amendment number="s1763"/>
    <amendment number="s1764"/>
    <amendment number="s1765"/>
    <amendment number="s1766"/>
    <amendment number="s1767"/>
    <amendment number="s1768"/>
    <amendment number="s1769"/>
    <amendment number="s1770"/>
    <amendment number="s1771"/>
    <amendment number="s1772"/>
    <amendment number="s1773"/>
    <amendment number="s1774"/>
    <amendment number="s1775"/>
    <amendment number="s1776"/>
    <amendment number="s1777"/>
    <amendment number="s1778"/>
    <amendment number="s1779"/>
    <amendment number="s1780"/>
    <amendment number="s1781"/>
    <amendment number="s1782"/>
    <amendment number="s1783"/>
    <amendment number="s1784"/>
    <amendment number="s1785"/>
    <amendment number="s1786"/>
    <amendment number="s1787"/>
    <amendment number="s1788"/>
    <amendment number="s1789"/>
    <amendment number="s1790"/>
    <amendment number="s1791"/>
    <amendment number="s1792"/>
    <amendment number="s1793"/>
    <amendment number="s1794"/>
    <amendment number="s1795"/>
    <amendment number="s1796"/>
    <amendment number="s1797"/>
    <amendment number="s1798"/>
    <amendment number="s1799"/>
    <amendment number="s1800"/>
    <amendment number="s1801"/>
    <amendment number="s1802"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/13/1999--Conference report filed in House.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of Veterans Affairs Title II: Department of Housing and Urban Development Title III: Independent Agencies Title IV: General Provisions Title V: Preservation of Affordable Housing Subtitle A: Authorization of Appropriations for Supportive Housing for the Elderly and Persons With Disabilities Subtitle B: Expanding Housing Opportunities for the Elderly and Persons With Disabilities Subtitle C: Renewal of Expiring Rental Assistance Contracts and Protection of Residents Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000 - Makes appropriations for FY 2000 for the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development and for sundry independent agencies.Title I: Department of Veterans Affairs - Makes appropriations for the Department of Veterans Affairs for: (1) veterans' compensation, pensions, and readjustment benefits; (2) veterans' insurance and indemnities; (3) veterans' housing, education, and vocational rehabilitation loan accounts; (4) veterans' medical care; (5) medical and prosthetic research; (6) medical administration; (7) the General post fund, national homes; (8) departmental administration; (9) the National Cemetery Administration; (10) the Office of Inspector General; (11) construction; (12) the parking revolving fund; and (13) grants to States for construction of extended care facilities and cemeteries.Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, funds made available under this title.(Sec. 108) Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to report to specified congressional committees on the impact of the allocation of funds under the Veterans Equitable Resource Allocation funding formula on the rural subregions of the health care system administered by the Veterans Health Administration.(Sec. 110) Prohibits the obligation of funds appropriated for medical care for the Department of Veterans Affairs for the realignment of the health care delivery system in VISN 12 until the Secretary of Veterans Affairs makes a specified certification regarding impacts on the accessibility of veterans health care services to affected veterans.Title II: Department of Housing and Urban Development - Makes appropriations for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) for: (1) public and Indian housing; (2) the Public Housing Capital and Operating Funds; (3) drug elimination grants for low-income housing; (4) revitalization of severely distressed public housing; (5) Native American housing block grants; (6) Indian housing loan guarantees; (7) housing opportunities for persons with AIDS; (8) the Office of Rural Housing and Economic Development; (9) the America's Private Investment Companies Program; (10) urban empowerment zones; (11) rural empowerment zone and enterprise communities programs; (12) community development block grants; (13) brownfields redevelopment; (14) the HOME investment partnerships program; (15) homeless assistance grants; (16) housing for special populations; (17) the Federal Housing Administration; (18) the Government National Mortgage Association; (19) housing policy development and research; (20) fair housing activities; (21) the Lead Hazard Reduction Program; (22) management and administration; (23) the Office of Inspector General; and (24) carrying out the Federal Housing Enterprise Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992.Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, funds made available under this title.(Sec. 203) Amends the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 to extend certain provisions regarding grants to otherwise ineligible States for housing for persons with AIDS.(Sec. 205) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to authorize the Secretary of HUD to establish income ceilings, with respect to eligibility for public housing or project-based Section 8 assistance, that are higher or lower than 30 percent of the area median income based on findings that such variations are necessary because of unusually high or low family incomes.(Sec. 206) Establishes the Millenial Housing Commission to study and report to specified congressional committees on: (1) the importance of housing, particularly affordable housing, to U.S. infrastructure; (2) possible methods for increasing the role of the private sector in providing affordable housing; and (3) whether existing HUD programs work in conjunction with one another to provide better housing opportunities for families, neighborhoods, and communities and how such programs can be improved with respect to such purpose.Terminates the Commission on June 30, 2002.(Sec. 208) Rescinds a specified amount of funds appropriated to HUD in the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998 and prior appropriations Acts.(Sec. 209) Makes appropriations for: (1) a grant to the National Cities in Schools Community Development program under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992; and (2) the Jobs-Plus Initiative of the Moving to Work Demonstration program.(Sec. 213) Amends provisions of the National Housing Act regarding payments of claims on defaulted mortgages with respect to multifamily housing units and health facilities to allow full (in addition to partial) payment of claims under one or more mortgage insurance contracts in connection with certain mortgage restructurings.(Sec. 214) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to direct owners responsible for determining a participant's eligibility or level of benefits to require families receiving certain HUD family income matching information to disclose such information. Includes families who receive such information and dwell in units receiving certain project-based assistance within the list of families subject to the disclosure requirement.(Sec. 215) Exempts public housing agencies in Alaska and Mississippi from certain membership requirements for their boards of directors under the United States Housing Act of 1937.(Sec. 216) Requires the Secretary of HUD to transfer the administration of the Small Cities component of the Community Development Block Grants program for all funds allocated for the State of New York under a specified provision of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to the State of New York, to be administered by the Governor.(Sec. 220) Extends the availability of certain grants made available under an economic development initiative pursuant to the Housing and Community and Development Act of 1974 through FY 2000.(Sec. 223) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to authorize the Secretary of HUD to reuse any budget authority recaptured on account of expiration of a housing assistance payments contract. Removes: (1) a condition that applies such authority only to contracts other than those for tenant-based assistance; and (2) a provision that makes such authority effective only for actions initiated by the the Secretary on or before September 30, 1995.(Sec. 225) Directs the Secretary of HUD, for purposes of allocating amounts under the AIDS Housing Opportunity Act, to allocate to the State of New Jersey the portion of funds based on the number of AIDS cases reported in the New Jersey portion of the Philadelphia, Pennsylvania-New Jersey primary metropolitan area.Title III: Independent Agencies - Makes appropriations for: (1) the American Battle Monuments Commission; (2) the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board; (3) the Department of the Treasury for community development financial institutions; (4) the Consumer Product Safety Commission; (5) the Corporation for National and Community Service; (6) the Office of Inspector General; (7) the Court of Veterans Appeals; and (8) the Department of Defense for Army cemeterial expenses.Appropriates funds for the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for: (1) science and technology activities; (2) environmental programs and management; (3) the Office of Inspector General; (4) buildings and facilities; (5) Superfund; (6) the leaking underground storage tank program; (7) oil spill response programs; and (8) assistance to States and Indian tribes for environmental programs and infrastructure.Appropriates funds for: (1) the Executive Office of the President for the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Council on Environmental Quality, and the Office of Environmental Quality; and (2) the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Office of Inspector General.Makes appropriations for the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) for: (1) disaster relief; (2) disaster assistance direct loans; (3) salaries and expenses; (4) the Office of Inspector General; (5) emergency management planning and assistance; (6) a specified emergency food and shelter program; (7) the Flood Map Modernization Fund; (8) the National Flood Insurance Fund; and (9) the National Flood Mitigation Fund.Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to extend through FY 2000: (1) a certain ceiling on obligations issued under the national flood insurance program; and (2) the authorization of appropriations for certain studies.Makes appropriations for: (1) the General Services Administration for the Consumer Information Center; (2) the National Aeronautics and Space Administration for human space flight, science, aeronautics, and technology research and development, mission support, and the Office of Inspector General; (3) the National Credit Union Administration's Central Liquidity Facility; (4) the National Science Foundation for research, major construction projects, science and engineering education and human resources programs, salaries and expenses, and the Office of Inspector General; (5) the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation; and (6) the Selective Service System.Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, funds appropriated under this title.Title IV: General Provisions - Sets forth provisions regarding availability, and prohibitions on the use, of funds appropriated by this Act. Expresses the sense of Congress that equipment and products purchased with funds made available in this Act should be American-made.(Sec. 422) Expresses the sense of Congress that the presence of an honor guard at a veteran's funeral is a benefit that a veteran has earned and the executive branch should provide honor details for the funerals of veterans when requested.(Sec. 424) Bars the use of funds made available in this Act to carry out a specified executive order regarding federalism.(Sec. 430) Extends the availability of appropriations to carry out the Coastal Wetlands Planning, Protection, and Restoration Act through FY 2000.(Sec. 431) Prohibits the EPA Administrator from promulgating the Phase II stormwater regulations until reporting to specified congressional committees: (1) an in-depth impact analysis on the effect the final regulations will have on urban, suburban, and rural local governments; (2) an explanation of the Administrator's rationale for lowering the construction site threshold from five acres to one acre; (3) documentation demonstrating that stormwater runoff is generally a problem in communities with populations of 50,000 to 100,000; and (4) information that supports the Administrator's position that the Phase II program should be administered as part of the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act.Directs EPA to report to such committees an explanation of the impact that the Phase I program has had in improving U.S. water quality.(Sec. 433) Amends the Commercial Space Launch Act to extend, though December 31, 2000, its commercial space launch industry damage indemnification provisions.(Sec. 434) Provides that the purpose of this section is to establish a demonstration regarding the commercial feasibility and economic viability of private sector business operations involving the International Space Station and its related infrastructure. Directs NASA to establish and publish a price policy to eliminate price uncertainty for those planning to utilize the Station and its related facilities for U.S. commercial use.Requires any receipts collected by NASA from the commercial use of the Station to be used first to offset any costs incurred by NASA in support of the U.S. commercial use of the Station. Authorizes the use of receipts collected in excess of such costs for promoting the commercial use of the Station.Requires NASA to report annually to Congress on all collected receipts, the use of such receipts, and the status of the demonstration.Applies the demonstration program to U.S. commercial use agreements entered into prior to the earlier of date of completion of the Station or the end of FY 2004.(Sec. 435) Amends the the National Aeronautics and Space Act of 1958 to permit the NASA Administrator to provide liability insurance for, or indemnification to, developers of experimental aerospace vehicles developed or used in execution of agreements between NASA and developers. Sets forth conditions on such authority.Repeals similar provisions regarding such authority set forth in the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999.Title V: Preservation of Affordable Housing - Preserving Affordable Housing for Senior Citizens and Families into the 21st Century Act - Subtitle A: Authorization of Appropriations for Supportive Housing for the Elderly and Persons With Disabilities - Amends the Housing Act of 1959 to authorize FY 2000 appropriations for supportive housing for the elderly.(Sec. 512) Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to authorize FY 2000 appropriations for supportive housing for persons with disabilities.(Sec. 513) Authorizes FY 2000 appropriations for: (1) grants for service coordinators for elderly and disabled residents of certain federally assisted multifamily housing; and (2) contracts for congregate services for certain federally assisted housing.Authorizes FY 2000 appropriations for renewal of grants made in prior fiscal years for service coordinators and congregate services for the elderly and disabled in public housing.Subtitle B: Expanding Housing Opportunities for the Elderly and Persons With Disabilities - Requires the Secretary of HUD to analyze, and report to Congress on, the net impact on the Federal budget deficit or surplus of forgiving indebtedness of sponsors of projects assisted under section 202 (supportive services for the elderly) of the Housing Act of 1959 (as in effect prior to enactment of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act) together with a reduction in the amount of Section 8 or other rental assistance provided to such a project.(Sec. 522) Amends the Housing Act of 1959 to authorize the Secretary to make grants for capital repairs of elderly housing projects or their conversion to assisted living facilities. Sets forth project eligibility and selection criteria, including inclusion of up to three unused or underused commercial properties. Authorizes FY 2000appropriations.(Sec. 523) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to authorize a recipient of section 8 housing assistance to use such assistance in an assisted living facility. Limits use to rental costs.Amends the Housing Act of 1959 to make multifamily projects that have converted elderly housing units to assisted living facilities eligible for section 8 project based assistance in the same manner as if they had not made such conversions. Sets forth rent calculation provisions.(Sec. 524) Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to provide that not more than 25 percent of fiscal year project rental assistance or capital advances for supportive housing for persons with disabilities may go to projects with more than 24 units.Directs the Secretary to conduct a study and report to Congress with respect to: (1) prior assistance provided to such projects; and (2) per-unit costs and benefits of specified project sizes assisted under the supportive housing for persons with disabilities program and the section 202 program under the Housing Act of 1959.(Sec. 525) Establishes the Commission on Affordable Housing and Health Care Facility Needs in the 21st Century. Directs the Commission to conduct a study and report to specified congressional committees on senior citizens' future affordable housing, assisted living, and health facility needs, and public and private sector capacities to meet such needs. Terminates the Commission as of June 30, 2002.Subtitle C: Renewal of Expiring Rental Assistance Contracts and Protection of Residents - Amends the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997, with respect to expiring project-based section 8 contracts, to base renewal rates upon comparable market rates. Provides for exception renewal rates based on: (1) the lower of adjusted existing rents or budget-based rents for certain projects exempt from mortgage restructuring; and (2) the lesser of adjusted existing rents, fair market rents, or comparable market rents for certain projects under the moderate rehabilitation program.Provides enhanced section 8 vouchers for residents of covered projects with expiring contracts. Authorizes FY 2000 through 2004 appropriations.Provides for continuation of expiring section 8 contract benefits to owners under specified conditions.Prohibits State or local limits on allowable project renewal distributions to owners, with exceptions.(Sec. 532) Amends the National Housing Act with respect to the rental and cooperative housing program to authorize: (1) interest reduction payments for project mortgage refinancing; and (2) project owners to retain excess income. Revises basic and market rent provisions.(Sec. 533) Amends the National Housing Act to permit multifamily project rehabilitation loans to be made from recaptured interest rate reduction payments.(Sec. 534) Amends the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997 to permit technical assistance for preservation of low-income housing for which project-based rental assistance is provided at below market rent levels and may not be renewed.(Sec. 535) Amends the Housing Act of 1937 to make section 8 renewals available for up to one year or any number of years, subject to appropriations.(Sec. 536) Amends the Housing and Community Development Amendments of 1978 to make residents of any project receiving flexible subsidy program assistance eligible for enhanced voucher assistance.(Sec. 537) Amends the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997 to extend grant and loan authority for management and disposition of multifamily properties and mortgages through FY 2000. Includes property construction among eligible activities.(Sec. 538) Amends Section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 to provide for enhanced voucher assistance for certain families in projects where mortgages have been prepaid, mortgage insurance contracts have been terminated Section 8 rental assistance contracts have expired or been terminated, or the transaction under which the project is preserved as affordable housing results in tenants being eligible for such assistance.Authorizes appropriations.Amends the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997 to provide for Section 8 enhanced voucher assistance for certain tenants in housing where Section 8 assistance is not renewed.Amends the Low-Income Housing Preservation and Resident Homeownership Act of 1990 to provide for Section 8 enhanced voucher assistance for certain tenants in housing where mortgages have been prepaid or insurance contracts have been terminated.</summary>
</bill>
