<bill session="104" type="h" number="4229" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Home Health Services Prospective Payment Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for prospective payment for home health services under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400205"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Introduced.
Medicare Home Health Services Prospective Payment Amendments of 1996 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for payments for home health services in accordance with a prospective payment system (including an episodic system) developed according to specified criteria, with a special rule for Christian Science providers. Requires the Medicare Prospective Payment Review Commission, during the first three years in which payments are made under this Act, to report annually to the Congress on the effectiveness of the payment methodology established. Amends SSA title XI to require review by peer review organizations of home health services provided under Medicare. Eliminates certain fiscal intermediary responsibilities under Medicare with regard to home health services. Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 and the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1986 to provide for a retroactive reinstatement of presumptive waiver of liability.</summary>
</bill>
