<bill session="104" type="h" number="3689" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the international narcotics control program under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to establish an additional certification standard for certain illicit drug producing countries and drug-transit countries and to establish an additional reporting requirement under that program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404996"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1996-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1996-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="404298" joined="1996-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="406082" joined="1996-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1996-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1996-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="1996-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1996-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/1996--Introduced.
Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to revise certification standards for waiver of the requirement that the Secretary of the Treasury instruct the U.S. Executive Director of each multilateral development bank to vote against the provision of assistance to a major illicit drug producing or drug-transit country under the international narcotic control program. Allows waiver of such requirement if during the previous year such a country has taken substantial steps, but has been unable, to fully cooperate with the United States, or has taken substantial, but inadequate, steps on its own, to achieve full compliance with the objectives established by the United Nations Convention Against Illicit Traffic in Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances. Requires the Secretary of State, in addition to other reporting requirements, to report annually to specified congressional committees on the list of objectives that such countries and the United States agree on for purposes of certification.</summary>
</bill>
