<bill session="104" type="hc" number="219" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Calling for the proper preservation of the memorial at the site of the Jasenovac concentration and death camp in Croatia in a way that accurately reflects the historical role of that site in the Holocaust.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400334" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1996-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Concentration camps"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Croatia"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/1996--Introduced.
Urges the Government of Croatia to properly preserve the memorial at the site of the Jasenovac concentration and death camp in Croatia in a way that maintains the fidelity of the site to its history. Condemns proposals which would vary from this history. Calls on the Secretary of State: (1) in conjunction with our allies, to condemn proposals which would undermine the accurate interpretation of the history of the Holocaust in Croatia; and (2) to monitor the development of proposals for the Jasenovac memorial. Calls on: (1) the Government of Croatia to work in concert with internationally recognized institutions of remembrance when developing plans for the preservation of the memorial; and (2) the Chairman of the Council to study the proposals for Jasenovac, to educate the public about the dangers of denial and revisionism relating to the Holocaust, and report to the Congress on such activities.</summary>
</bill>
