<bill session="106" type="hr" number="542" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-29T22:41:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-06-29T22:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1304) to ensure and foster continued patient safety and quality of care by making the antitrust laws apply to negotiations between groups of health care professionals and health plans and health insurance issuers in the same manner as such laws apply to collective bargaining by labor organizations under the National Labor Relations Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T23:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-709, by Mr. Goss.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T23:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1304 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-28T23:58:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="251">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 251.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29T20:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5617-5626" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29T20:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 542.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29T22:28:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 174, 3 Present (Roll no. 364).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2000-06-29T22:41:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="365" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 225 - 197 (Roll no. 365).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5617" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29T22:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="1304"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2000--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 1304 (antitrust law application to negotiations between health care professionals and health plans and insurance issuers).</summary>
</bill>
