<bill session="105" type="h" number="187" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congress 2000 Commission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a commission to make recommendations on the appropriate size of membership of the House of Representatives and the method by which Representatives are elected.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Political platforms"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Congress 2000 Commission Act - Establishes the Congress 2000 Commission to: (1) analyze the current size of the membership of the House of Representatives; (2) determine whether alternatives to the current method by which Representatives are elected would make the House a more representative body; (3) consider the continuing dissolution of adherence to the platforms and candidates of the Nation's two major political parties as well as to the reduction in electoral participation by the citizenry; (4) consider whether alternative methods of electing House Members might include more citizens in the electoral process; (5) the extent necessary, formulate proposals for changes in the size of the membership of, and the method of electing Representatives to, the House; and (6) by the end of the 106th Congress, report to the President and the Congress on its work, together with a draft of legislation to implement such proposals.</summary>
</bill>
