<bill session="107" type="h" number="4181" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vested Worker Protection Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prohibit pension plan amendments reducing the rate of future benefit accrual, subject to a safe harbor where the plan provides notice of the amendment and an election to continue benefit accruals under the former plan instead of the amended plan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400164"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="2002-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2002-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2002-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="2002-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2002-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400393" joined="2002-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2002--Introduced.
Vested Worker Protection Act of 2002 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to mandate that an "applicable pension plan" adopting any amendment that reduces rates of future benefits provide: (1) written notice meeting certain requirements to participants; and (2) that the participants be offered the chance to elect to continue to accrue benefits under the terms in effect immediately before the amendment. Defines "accrued benefit" as an early retirement benefit or retirement-type subsidy meeting certain standards. Defines "applicable pension plan" as a defined benefit plan or an individual account plan with at least 100 active participants meeting certain funding standards and other restrictions.Requires plans to inform participants of the option of staying under the old terms at least 90 days before the effective date of the amendment. Exempts a plan from the above requirements if its sponsor can show the Secretary of the Treasury that each employer contributing to the plan meets certain distress termination conditions under regulations of the Secretary.Imposes an excise tax on plans that adopt amendments decreasing benefits and do not let participants elect to continue to accrue benefits under the old terms. Makes the plan liable for such tax in the case of a multiemployer plan, and the employer liable in any other case.</summary>
</bill>
