<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="563" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:18-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2123" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2005-09-22T13:15:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-09-22"/>
  <description>Amendment revises the financial audit language to ensure that financial audit requirements for Head Start programs are consistent with those required under the Single Audit Act Amendments of 1986; clarifies that any health service available to children in Head Start may not be performed without the prior written consent of the parent; and includes a number of technical and conforming changes to the bill.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 109-229 to revise the financial audit language in Section 17 to ensure that financial audit requirements for Head Start programs are consistent with those required under the Single Audit Act Amendments of 1986. Specifically extends to 270 days the time frame for completing program audits; clarifiesthat, upon the availability of resources, audit partners (not auditors) must be rotated every 5 years; and waives the board selection of a certified public accountant when public auditors are assigned by State law.In addition the amendment builds on parental consent requirements included in H.R. 2123 as reported, to further clarify that any health service available to children in Head Start may not be performed without the prior written consent of the parent. Health services include but are not limited to any medical, dental, developmental, mental health, social, or behavioralscreening.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Castle.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8299-8301" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8299-8300" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2005-09-22T13:15:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Castle amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
