<bill session="107" type="h" number="3525" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">United States Border Security bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhanced Border Security and Visa Entry Reform Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Enhanced Border Security and Visa Entry Reform Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Enhanced Border Security and Visa Entry Reform Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Enhanced Border Security and Visa Entry Reform Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance the border security of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), International Relations, Ways and Means, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19T17:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19T17:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10465-10476" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19T17:34:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3525.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-12-19T18:15:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10465-10471" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19T18:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-19T18:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 3525.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-11">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-12">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2609-2623" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-15">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2643-2659" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-18">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2916-2932" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2002-04-18" how="roll" result="pass" roll="75" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Yea-Nay Vote. 97 - 0. Record Vote Number: 75.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR 4/22/2002 S3106-3108" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-04-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-07T17:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2137-2142" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-07T17:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments to H.R. 3525.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-07T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed until May 8.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2002-05-08T12:01:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="131" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 411 - 0, 2 Present (Roll no. 131).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2179-2180" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 05/07/2002 H2138" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-05-08T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-08T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of S. Con. Res. 106, enrollment corrections on H.R. 3525 have been made.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2002-05-08">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2002-05-08">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2002-05-14" type="public" number="107-173">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 107-173.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="hr" number="365"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="1885"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="3205"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="sc" number="106"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="sc" number="106"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="1618"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="1749"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Computer matching"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Flight crews"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign students"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Geographic information systems"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Motor bus lines"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Supervisors"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3126"/>
    <amendment number="s3127"/>
    <amendment number="s3128"/>
    <amendment number="s3131"/>
    <amendment number="s3160"/>
    <amendment number="s3161"/>
    <amendment number="s3162"/>
    <amendment number="s3163"/>
    <amendment number="s3164"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/18/2002--Passed Senate amended.
Enhanced Border Security and Visa Entry Reform Act of 2002 - Title I: Funding - Directs the Attorney General, during each of FY 2003 through 2006, to increase the number of Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) investigators and inspectors by at least 200 full-time employees over the number authorized by the USA PATRIOT ACT.Authorizes appropriations for INS, Border Patrol, and consular personnel, training, facilities, and security-related technology, effective October1, 2002. Provides for machine-readable visa fees.Title II: Interagency Information Sharing - Directs U.S. law enforcement and intelligence entities to share alien admissibility- and deportation-related information with INS and the Department of State until implementation of the information sharing plan provided for by this title.Amends the USA PATRIOT ACT to eliminate an Office of Homeland Security alien screening report requirement.Directs the President to: (1) report respecting admission- and deportation-related law enforcement and intelligence information needed by INS and the Department of State; and (2) develop a related information-sharing plan within 15 months of enactment of the USA PATRIOT ACT. Requires such plan to provide source and privacy protections. Provides criminal penalties for information misuse.Amends the USA PATRIOT ACT to advance the deadline from: (1) two years to one year for development and certification of a technology standard to certify the identity of alien applicants for admission; and (2) 18 months to six months for a related report.(Sec. 202) Directs: (1) INS to fully integrate its databases and data systems; and (2) the President to develop and implement an interoperable law enforcement and intelligence data system (Chimera system) (with name-matching and linguistic capacity, including at least four priority languages) for visa, admissibility, or deportation determination purposes, which shall include the INS integrated system.Directs the Central Intelligence Agency to issue certain reports and guidelines required under the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998.Authorizes appropriations for name search, linguistic, and reporting activities.(Sec. 203) Directs the President to establish the Commission on Interoperable Data Sharing, which shall: (1) monitor information misuse protections under the alien screening plan; (2) provide oversight of the interoperable data sharing system; and (3) report annually to Congress. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 204) Authorizes the Attorney General, respecting the Chimera system, to hire necessary scientific, technical, engineering, and other personnel. Directs the Attorney General to report to the appropriate congressional committees concerning intended uses of authority and Government organization and employee-related provisions being waived.Title III: Visa Issuance - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (Act) to direct the Secretary of State (Secretary), upon issuance of an alien visa, to provide INS with an electronic version of the alien's visa file prior to the alien's U.S. entry.(Sec. 302) Sets forth technology standard and interoperability requirements (including October 26, 2004 implementation deadlines) respecting development and implementation of the integrated entry and exit data system and related tamper-resistant, machine-readable documents containing biometric identifiers. Requires a visa waiver country, in order to maintain program participation, to certify by October 26, 2004, that it has a program to issue to its nationals qualifying machine-readable passports that are tamper-proof and contain biometric identifiers. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 304) Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a Terrorist Lookout Committee at each U.S. mission, and report to the appropriate congressional committees respecting such Committees; (2) provide consular staff with visa screening training; and (3) provide for the use of terrorist-related intelligence in such activities' performance. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 306) Prohibits the admission of an alien from a country designated to be a state sponsor of international terrorism (as defined by this Act) unless the Secretary has determined that such individual does not pose a risk or security threat to the United States.(Sec. 307) Conditions participation in the visa waiver program upon a country's timely reporting to the United States of its stolen blank passports. Reduces from five years to two years the required periodic evaluation of the program's effects on U.S. security and immigration interests.Requires INS to perform a check of lookout databases prior to permitting an alien's U.S. admission.(Sec. 308) Directs: (1) the Secretary and the Attorney General, as appropriate, within 72 hours of notification of a lost or stolen U.S. or foreign passport, to enter such passport's identification number into the interoperable data system; (2) the Attorney General to enter into the system such information on passports lost or stolen prior to the system's implementation; and (3) the Attorney General to enter such information into the interim system prior to the interoperable system's implementation.(Sec. 309) Directs the Attorney General to ensure that refugees and asylees are issued work authorizations, which shall contain fingerprint and photo identification.Title IV: Inspection and Admission of Aliens - Directs the President to study the feasibility of establishing a North American National Security Program (United States, Canada, Mexico), including consideration of alien preclearance and preinspection. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 402) Amends the Act to: (1) require commercial aircraft or vessels arriving at, or departing from, the United States to provide United States border officers (as defined by this Act) with specified passenger, other occupant, and crew manifest information; (2) prohibit carrier entry until such information has been provided; (3) provide monetary and non-entry penalties for noncompliance; (4) require electronic manifest transmission by January 1, 2003; (4) provide the Attorney General with waiver authority; and (5) direct the President to conduct a feasibility study and report to Congress regarding such provisions' extension to commercial land carriers.(Sec. 403) Directs INS to adequately staff ports of entry.(Sec. 404) Authorizes United States border inspections agencies, including INS, to conduct joint United States-Canada inspection projects to provide for alternative inspection services and harmonized inspection criteria. Directs the Attorney General and the Secretary of the Treasury to report annually to Congress.Title V: Foreign Students and Exchange Visitors - Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to direct the Attorney General to develop an electronic means of verifying and monitoring the foreign student and exchange visitor information program, including aspects of: (1) documentation and visa issuance; (2) U.S. admission; (3) institution notification; (4) documentation transmittal; and (5) registration and enrollment.Requires an institution to notify INS of the failure of a foreign student or exchange visitor to enroll within 30 days of the registration deadline.Increases student data collection requirements. Specifies information required for foreign student visa applications.Sets forth transitional foreign student monitoring requirements, including: (1) restrictions on visa issuance; (2) INS notification of visa issuance; (3) institution notification of U.S. entry; and (4) INS notification (by the institution) of failure to enroll. Directs the Attorney General to provide the Secretary with a list of institutions approved to accept foreign students or exchange visitors. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 502) Provides for INS and Department of State biennial review of institutions authorized to enroll or sponsor foreign students and exchange visitors.Provides that an institution's failure to comply with recordkeeping and reporting requirements shall result in termination or at least a one year suspension of its approval to receive such students or exchange visitors.Title VI: Miscellaneous Provisions - Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to extend the deadline for presentation of biometric border crossing identification cards.(Sec. 602) Directs: (1) the Comptroller General to determine the feasibility of requiring each nonimmigrant alien to report annually to INS respecting his or her address and employer's address; and (2) the Secretary and INS to study alternative approaches to for encouraging or requiring Mexico, Canada, and visa waiver countries to develop an intergovernmental network of interoperable international electronic data systems.(Sec. 604) States that this Act shall not be construed to impose requirements that are inconsistent with the North American Free Trade Agreement, or to require additional documents for certain nonimmigrant emergency or in-transit liens for whom documentary requirements are waived.(Sec. 605) Directs the Attorney General to report annually respecting aliens who fail to appear at removal proceedings after release on their own recognizance.(Sec. 606) Directs the Department of State to retain every nonimmigrant visa application in judicially and administratively admissible form for a period of seven years from the date of application.</summary>
</bill>
