<bill session="105" type="h" number="4618" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agriculture Disaster and Market Loss Assistance Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide emergency assistance to American farmers and ranchers for crop and livestock feed losses due to disasters and to respond to loss of world markets for American agricultural commodities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-24T19:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 551 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4618 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. The bill shall be considered in the House and shall be considered as read for amendment. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="551"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commodity Credit Corporation"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Livestock industry"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Emergency Assistance for Crop and Livestock Feed Losses Due to Disasters Title II: Market Loss Assistance Title III: Administration Agriculture Disaster and Market Loss Assistance Act of 1998 - Title I: Emergency Assistance for Crop and Livestock Feed Losses Due to Disasters - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to provide emergency financial assistance to producers with disaster-incurred 1998 or multiyear (1998 and previous) crop year losses. Requires producers without 1998 crop insurance to purchase insurance for the subsequent two years in order to qualify for such assistance. Requires such producers to pay any liquidated damages. (Sec. 103) Caps 1998 livestock feed assistance amounts. Title II: Market Loss Assistance - Directs the Secretary to use specified funds to provide 1998 market loss assistance to certain producers with production flexibility contracts. Title III: Administration - States that funds to carry out this Act shall be available only to the extent that the President submits to the Congress an official emergency designation budget request.</summary>
</bill>
