<bill session="104" type="h" number="1887" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY96-97, Customs Service</title>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY96-97, International Trade Commission</title>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY96-97, Trade</title>
    <title type="popular">Customs Service FY96-97 Authorization bill</title>
    <title type="popular">International Trade Commission FY96-97 Authorization bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Trade FY96-97 Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal years 1996 and 1997 for the International Trade Commission, the Customs Service, and the Office of the United States Trade Representative, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400085"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-06-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-06-27T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 104-161.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-06-27T20:44:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="78">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 78.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bolivia"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecuador"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade policy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Peru"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/1995--Reported to House amended.
Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to authorize appropriations for FY 1996 and 1997 for the United States International Trade Commission (ITC). Amends the Customs Procedural Reform and Simplification Act of 1978 to authorize appropriations for FY 1996 and 1997 for the United States Customs Service for: (1) noncommercial and commercial operations; and (2) the air and marine interdiction programs, including support to other Federal, State, and local agencies in their enforcement of customs and other laws and emergency humanitarian efforts. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to authorize appropriations for FY 1996 and 1997 for the Office of the United States Trade Representative. Amends the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act to repeal the mandate for an annual report regarding the economic impact of the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Program on U.S. industries and consumers. Amends the Andean Trade Preference Act to change from annual to biennial the ITC's report to the Congress regarding the Act's: (1) economic impact on U.S. industries and consumers; and (2) its effectiveness in promoting drug-related crop eradication efforts of the beneficiary countries (Bolivia, Ecuador, Colombia, and Peru). Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to repeal the mandate for the East-West Trade Statistics Monitoring System. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to require the President's annual report to the Congress on the trade agreements program and the national trade policy agenda to include: (1) a listing of trade agreements entered into by the United States since 1984 which afford increased market access or reduce barriers and other trade distorting practices by other parties to those agreements; and (2) a description of any actions taken during the preceding calendar year to ensure compliance with such agreements by those other parties.</summary>
</bill>
