<bill session="105" type="h" number="4834" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Northwest Salmon Recovery Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure salmon recovery in the Pacific Northwest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404375"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2163-2164"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Columbia River development"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Endangered animals"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Indian hunting and fishing rights"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International fishery management"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Power marketing administrations"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Salmon fisheries"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/1998--Introduced.
Northwest Salmon Recovery Act of 1998 - Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to develop a unified plan for salmon recovery in the Pacific Northwest region whose goal is to restore sustainable naturally reproducing salmon populations to support tribal and nontribal harvest, cultural, and economic practices. (Sec. 4) Requires such plan to address: (1) treaty, trust, and Endangered Species Act responsibilities; (2) specified statutory requirements governing fish mitigation and enhancement; (3) water quality standards under the Clean Water Act; and (4) the United States-Canada Pacific Salmon Treaty commitments. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretaries of Energy and of the Treasury to establish an accounting system for the Bonneville Power Administration that meets prescribed criteria. Directs the Secretaries of the Interior, Energy, Commerce, and the Army to implement a specified Memorandum of Agreement and Annex adopted in 1996, including procedures for effective regional involvement and accountability in the expenditure of moneys from the Administration's fund. Prescribes administrative procedures applicable to such Memorandum of Agreement and to the unified plan. Repeals the mandate to the Northwest Planning Council to appoint an Independent Scientific Review Panel. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a Natural Resources Recovery Fund for fish and wildlife restoration in the Pacific Northwest region, and for conservation and renewable energy projects. Directs the Administrator to assess specified fees and charges to ensure that the repayment costs of Washington Public Power Supply System debt is repaid and allocated to all Administration customers. Provides that such fees and charges shall be in addition to: (1) rates for power sales by the Administration; and (2) Administration transmission rates. (Sec. 7) Requires that all rates and charges received for the sale of electric energy by the Administration to its electric energy customers recover all federally incurred costs for electric energy generation and marketing, including meeting certain statutory responsibilities. (Sec. 8) Places the transmission of electric energy by the Administration within the purview of the Federal Power Act, and grants the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission jurisdiction over transmission rates, terms, and conditions. Requires rates charged by the Administration for electric energy transmission to be sufficient to recover all costs for compliance with specified statutory responsibilities. Prescribes procedures for cost recovery adjustments by the Administration.</summary>
</bill>
