<bill session="108" type="h" number="3652" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-12-08T17:28:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-12-08T17:28:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Archery Revenue Reform and Opportunity for Workers Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Archery Revenue Reform and Opportunity for Workers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the taxation of imported archery products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400351"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2003-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08T17:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08T17:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12867-12868" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08T17:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Ryan (WI) asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-12-08T17:28:00-05:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12867-12868" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2003--Passed House without amendment.
Archery Revenue Reform and Opportunity for Workers Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise provisions taxing bows and arrows by: (1) imposing on the sale by the manufacturer, producer, or importer of any bow which has a peak draw weight (currently, draw weight) of 30 (currently, 10) pounds or more, a tax equal to 11 percent of the sale price; (2) imposing on the sale by the manufacturer, producer, or importer of any part or accessory suitable for inclusion in or attachment to any such bow, and of any quiver or broadhead (currently, quiver) suitable for use with arrows described in clause three, a tax equal to 11 percent of the sale price; (3) maintaining the current provisions applicable to arrows; and (4) adding provisions which impose on the sale by the manufacturer, producer, or importer of any arrow (a shaft described in clause three to which additional components are attached), a tax equal to 12 percent of the sale price, subject to exception.</summary>
</bill>
