<bill session="107" type="h" number="492" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Military Voting Rights bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Armed Services Voting Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit a State from determining that a ballot submitted by an absent uniformed services voter was improperly or fraudulently cast unless the State finds clear and convincing evidence of fraud, to direct the Secretary of Defense to conduct a study of methods to improve the procedures used to enable absent uniformed services voters to register to vote and vote in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Election fraud"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Soldier voting"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2001--Introduced.
Armed Services Voting Improvement Act - Prohibits a State from refusing to count a ballot submitted in a Federal election by an absent uniformed services voter on the grounds that the ballot was improperly or fraudulently cast, unless the State finds clear and convincing evidence of fraud in the preparation or casting of the ballot by the voter.Directs the Secretary of Defense to study and report to Congress on methods to improve the procedures used to enable absent uniformed services voters to register to vote and to vote in Federal elections.</summary>
</bill>
