<bill session="106" type="h" number="1612" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Food Safety Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a comprehensive program to ensure the safety of food products intended for human comsumption which are regulated by the Food and Drug Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2000-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="2000-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1999-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E799-800"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
    <term name="Food contamination"/>
    <term name="Food handling"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food poisoning"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foodborne diseases"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Grocery trade"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Quality control"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Restaurants"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/1999--Introduced.
Consumer Food Safety Act of 1999 - Title I: National Food Safety Program - Declares that persons who produce or process food for human consumption are responsible for preventing or minimizing food safety hazards.Mandates a national program to protect human health by ensuring that the food industry has effective safety programs for food consumed in the United States. Includes in required program elements: (1) oversight procedures; and (2) health-based standards for possible food contaminants and safety and sanitation in food processing and handling.(Sec. 102) Requires that any food processing facility and importer register.(Sec. 103) Mandates regulations: (1) setting standards for sanitation and tolerances for biological, chemical, and physical hazards; (2) requiring process controls, recordkeeping, and sampling; and (3) providing for agency records access.(Sec. 104) Mandates unannounced inspections at least quarterly of processing and importing facilities.(Sec. 105) Mandates tolerances (including indicators) for contaminants, except for pesticide residues regulated under specified provisions of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FDCA).(Sec. 106) Authorizes assistance to a State in planning and implementing a food safety program (including advice, technical and laboratory assistance and training, and financial aid). Authorizes, under agreements with Federal, State, or local agencies, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, use of the personnel, services, and facilities of such agencies.(Sec. 107) Mandates a comprehensive and efficient system to ensure imported food safety, including routine inspections of processing facilities in exporting nations and of imports at ports of entry. Prohibits importing, or withdrawing from a warehouse for U.S. consumption, of a food that appears unsafe, adulterated, or misbranded, is not marked or labeled as required, or does not comply with this section. Deems foods not so prohibited to be, and requires that they be treated (except for origin labeling) as, domestic.Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into an agreement with any nation desiring to export food to the United States. Sets forth requirements for the agreement, including that the exporting nation agree to reciprocity regarding the treatment of food imports and exports between the United States and the exporting nation..Title II: Research and Education - Mandates: (1) inclusion of food in an active surveillance system and more accurate assessment of the frequency and sources of U.S. human illness associated with food; (2) establishment of guidelines for a sampling system; and (3) ranking of food categories based on their hazard to human health and identification of industry and regulatory approaches to minimize hazards.(Sec. 202) Requires: (1) a national food safety public education program; (2) regional and national food safety advisories; (3) standardized written and broadcast advisory formats; and (4) incorporation of State and local advisories into the national program.(Sec. 203) Mandates research to assist in the implementation of this Act.Title III: Enforcement - Amends the FDCA to require any person (other than an intended consumer) with a reasonable basis for believing that any food in interstate commerce (or held for sale after interstate shipment) may be in violation of this Act to notify the Secretary of the food's identity and location. Provides, if the Secretary finds that there is a reasonable probability that the food, if consumed, would present a public health threat, for voluntary and mandatory recalls.Authorizes civil monetary penalties for violations of this Act. Prohibits retaliation against employee or other whistleblowers or against a person who refuses to violate a law, rule, or regulation. Applies specified FDCA provisions to this Act for this Act's administration and enforcement.Authorizes the Secretary to impose traceability requirements on a type or class of food when necessary to assure the protection of public health.Allows any person to commence a civil action against: (1) any person who violated any rule, tolerance, order, or other action of the Secretary to ensure food safety; or (2) the Secretary for alleged failure to perform any nondiscretionary act or duty.Title IV: Authorization - Authorizes appropriations to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
