<bill session="105" type="h" number="221" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Reinvestment Improvement Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to reduce onerous recordkeeping and reporting requirements for regulated financial institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E68"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Bank fraud"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Community development banking"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Community Reinvestment Improvement Act of 1997 - Amends the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to set forth a modified evaluation procedure for certain mid-sized financial institutions which meet specified criteria. Requires the appropriate financial institutions supervisory agency to: (1) conduct a compliance evaluation in connection with its examination of such institutions or every two years, whichever is more frequent; and (2) provide public notice of such evaluation upon its commencement. Disqualifies from this Act's modified evaluation procedure for a ten-year period any institution that has intentionally submitted false information or willfully violated the requirements of this Act. Exempts from the evaluation requirements of this Act certain small-sized regulated financial institutions. Cites criteria under which a regulated financial institution's application for a deposit facility shall not be denied on the basis of its compliance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
