<bill session="104" type="hr" number="386" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-21T12:09:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-03-21T12:09:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 165) making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 1996, and for other purposes, and waiving a requirement of clause 4(b) of rule XI with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400265"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-03-20T21:22:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-489, by Mr. McInnis.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-20T21:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 165 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the joint resolution in the House. Upon adoption of this resolution, the requirement for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House shall be waived with respect to any resolution reported from that committee before April 1, 1996, and providing for consideration of a bill making a general appropriations; a further continuing resolution; or a bill or resolution increasing or waiving the debt limit. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-03-20T21:22:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="197">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 197.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21T10:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2565-2577" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21T10:28:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21T12:00:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 187 (Roll no. 80).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-03-21T12:09:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="81" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 237 - 183 (Roll no. 81).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21T12:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="hj" number="165"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/1996--Introduced.
Sets forth the closed rule for the consideration of H.J. Res. 165 (continuing appropriations). Waives provisions of rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives that require a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to resolutions reported by such Committee before April 1, 1996, to provide for the consideration or disposition of any of the following measures, including any amendment, conference report, or any amendment from conference in disagreement thereon: (1) a bill making general appropriations for FY 1996; or (2) a bill or joint resolution making further continuing appropriations for such fiscal year or increasing or waiving (for a temporary period or otherwise) the public debt limit.</summary>
</bill>
