<bill session="112" type="h" number="4297" updated="2013-07-14T19:19:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Workforce Investment Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Workforce Investment Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Adult Education and Family Literacy Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform and strengthen the workforce investment system of the Nation to put Americans back to work and make the United States more competitive in the 21st Century.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400643"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2012-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412427" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412446" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2012-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Agriculture, Energy and Commerce, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-17">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition and Horticulture .</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-12-05T14:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 112-699, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-05T14:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-05T14:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-05T14:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-05T14:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs for a period ending not later than Dec. 14, 2012.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-14T12:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-12-14T12:21:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="513">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 513.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Nutrition and Horticulture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2295"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2295"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3610"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3610"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3611"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3611"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2012--Introduced.
Workforce Investment Improvement Act of 2012 - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (WIA) to revise requirements and reauthorize appropriations for: (1) WIA title I, workforce investment systems for job training and employment services; and (2) WIA title II, adult education and family literacy education programs. Revises requirements to: (1) eliminate members of the state legislature and representatives of labor organizations from state workforce investment boards, and (2) specify that representatives of business on a board represent large and small businesses with immediate and long-term employment opportunities in in-demand industries and other occupations important to the state economy. Requires a state board to assist the state governor by developing: (1) policies and programs that support a comprehensive statewide workforce development system, and (2) a statewide workforce and labor market information system. Revises requirements for: (1) a state workforce development plan; (2) local workforce investment areas, boards, and plans; (3) one-stop delivery systems; and (4) the allotment of federal funds among states for employment and training activities. Eliminates specific funding for adult and dislocated worker employment and training. Specifies state use of federal funds to set up a Workforce Investment Fund. Revises requirements for: (1) within state allocations of funds; and (2) the use of funds for state and local employment and training activities, including statewide rapid response, youth challenge grants, and adults with barriers to employment grants. Converts the national emergency grants program into a national dislocated worker grants program. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to award national dislocated worker grants to spouses of active duty members of the Armed Forces or full-time duty members of the National Guard (or members who recently separated from such duties) and are in need of employment and training assistance to obtain or retain employment. Requires the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor to be the principal agency to administer WIA title I workforce investment systems for job training and employment services and title III (Job Corps). Revises requirements for the state unified plan for adult education and literacy programs. Amends the Wagner-Peyser Act to eliminate the U.S. Employment Service. Replaces the nationwide employment statistics system, which the Secretary is required to oversee, with a nationwide workforce and labor market information system. Repeals the Youth Conservation Corps Act of 1970 and specified other laws. Amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to require employment and training services to eligible members of households participating in the supplemental nutrition assistance program be provided through the statewide workforce development system, including the One-Stop delivery system. Amends the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (RA73) to: (1) redesignate the Commissioner of the Rehabilitation Services Administration the Director, and (2) require an eligible state to use a certain percentage of the federal share of the cost of vocational rehabilitation services to award grants to create practical job and career readiness and training programs and provide job placements and career advancement. Repeals the authority of the Commissioner of the Rehabilitation Services Administration in the Department of Education to make grants and contracts for: (1) vocational rehabilitation services to individuals with disabilities who are migrant or seasonal farmworkers; (2) recreational programs for such individuals; and (3) in-service training of vocational rehabilitation personnel. Repeals title VI (Employment Opportunities for Individuals with Disabilities) of the RA73. Revises requirements and reauthorizes appropriations for vocational rehabilitation services under the RA73.</summary>
</bill>
