<bill session="107" type="h" number="4725" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Tax Incentives Improvement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to promote the economic recovery of the District of Columbia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Divorcees"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Industrial development bonds"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Intangible property"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Separation (Law)"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax incentives"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2002--Introduced.
District of Columbia Tax Incentives Improvement Act of 2002 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to designate the entire District of Columbia as an enterprise zone which shall be treated as an empowerment zone.Excludes from gross income capital gains on sale or exchange of District assets held for more than two years (presently the figure is five years). Defines what constitutes a District business. Nullifies the exclusion of any trade or business from counting as a District business for reason of consisting predominantly of dealing in intangibles if: (1) at least 30 percent of the employees of such a business are District residents; and (2) at least 50 percent of the wages are paid to District residents.Extends time line for which provisions of enterprise zone treatment will last. Makes permanent provisions of law pertaining to the first-time homebuyer credit (currently, they last through December 31, 2003). Extends classification of "first-time homebuyer" to certain individuals buying residences due to divorce or separation, and directs the Secretary of Treasury to prescribe regulations to prevent abuses of such provision.Removes the limitation on the amount of tax-exempt enterprise zone facility bonds that can be issued.Exempts certain bonds and notes issued by the District Council and the interest thereon from all taxation (except for estate, inheritance, and gift taxes) by the United States, any State or political subdivision thereof, the District, or any possession of the United States.Sets the tax and withholding rates for nonresident aliens and foreign corporations at zero for payments made by an "exempt insurance company" with respect to a "DC Zone insurance policy" issued by such company (as such terms are defined by this Act). Relieves exempt insurance companies from reporting requirements with respect to amounts paid under a DC Zone insurance policy to foreigners in connection with risks located outside the United States.</summary>
</bill>
