<bill session="107" type="h" number="1478" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Personal Information Privacy Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the privacy of the individual with respect to the Social Security number and other personal information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2001-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-04">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E564-565"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2001--Introduced.
Personal Information Privacy Act of 2001 - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to redefine the term "consumer report" to exclude identifying information listed in a local telephone directory (thereby ensuring that the personal identification information in the credit headers accompanying credit reports of unlisted individuals remains confidential).Amends part A (General Provisions) of title XI of the Social Security Act to prohibit the commercial acquisition or distribution of an individual's social security number (or any derivative), as well as its use as a personal identification number, without the individual's written consent. Provides for: (1) civil money penalties and civil action in U.S. District Court by an aggrieved individual; and (2) coordination with criminal enforcement of identification document fraud.Amends the Federal criminal code to: (1) require State motor vehicle department uses of social security numbers to be consistent with uses authorized by the Social Security Act, the Privacy Act, and any other appropriate statutes; (2) prohibit marketing company use of social security numbers; and (3) prohibit, with an exception for specified law enforcement requests, State motor vehicle department release or disclosure of an individual's photograph without the individual's written consent.Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to prohibit a consumer reporting agency from providing a report in connection with a credit or insurance transaction not initiated by the consumer without the consumer's written consent. Requires full consumer disclosure before such consent shall be effective.Prohibits, with specified exceptions, a person doing business with a consumer from selling or transferring for marketing purposes any transaction or experience information without the consumer's written consent.</summary>
</bill>
