<bill session="108" type="h" number="2796" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Credit Protection Act Amendments of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to prohibit the use of consumer credit history for any insurance purpose and to require the disclosure of consumer reports and the credit scoring procedure in order to prevent inaccuracies and mistakes in consumer credit reports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2003--Introduced.
Consumer Credit Protection Act Amendments of 2003 - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to set forth impermissible uses of consumer credit scores by an insurance provider with respect to a consumer or insurance applicant. Mandates that any credit scoring system used to generate any risk or credit score be in compliance with the Equal Credit Opportunity Act. Requires a consumer reporting agency, upon request, to disclose to the consumer clearly and accurately all information in the consumer's file, including: (1) credit consumer reports and any information concerning reports and credit scores; (2) any other risk scores or predictors, including any credit scores used; and (3) a clear, concise summary of how the scores and predictors are derived. Cites circumstances that require a consumer reporting agency to furnish free disclosures upon request. Requires every consumer reporting agency taking adverse action based upon a consumer report to: (1) provide a copy of such report, including other risk scores or predictors, and credit scores used; and (2) provide a written summary of all consumer rights and how to exercise them.</summary>
</bill>
