<bill session="104" type="h" number="1937" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Advocacy Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate small business involvement in the regulatory development processes of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409633"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="917"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Regulatory reform"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Small Business Advocacy Review Title II: Peer Review Survey Small Business Advocacy Act of 1995 - Title I: Small Business Advocacy Review - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to designate an EPA employee who is a member of the Senior Executive Service and whose immediate supervisor is appointed by the President to serve as the chairperson of each Environmental Small Business Advocacy Review Panel established under this Act. Directs the Assistant Secretary for Occupational Safety and Health (OSHA) of the Department of Labor to designate an OSHA employee with such qualifications to serve as the chairperson of each Occupational Safety and Health Small Business Advocacy Review Panel established under this Act. Directs the appropriate chairperson, with respect to a proposed Federal agency rule (other than agency organization, management, or personnel rules), to determine whether such rule is significant (has an impact on small business and has an annual aggregate impact on government and the private sector of at least $50 million) and, if so, to notify the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget and the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration to appoint review panel members for evaluation of the rule. Requires each chairperson to notify panel members of the intent of an agency to issue a final rule, and to solicit comments from the panel with respect to the rule's effect on small business. Provides review panel administrative, procedural, and personnel matters. Directs each chairperson to submit to the appropriate Federal agency employees responsible for carrying out a significant rule and to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing the findings and recommendations of the review panel for such rule and a recommendation of whether to conduct a cross-section survey of the small businesses impacted by the rule. Prohibits: (1) the judicial review of review panel activities; or (2) the publication of a rule in the Federal Register until the appropriate chairperson has had an adequate opportunity for its review under this Act. Title II: Peer Review Survey - Provides that, if a review panel recommends that a survey be conducted, the Federal agency involved shall contract with a private sector firm or organization to conduct the survey. Requires the availability of survey results to each interested Federal agency and, upon request, to any other interested party.</summary>
</bill>
