<bill session="104" type="h" number="3169" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Job Corps Improvement Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Job Corps program under the Job Training Partnership Act to ensure a drug-free, safe, and cost-effective Job Corps, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400584"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E463-464"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alcohol"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/1996--Introduced.
Job Corps Improvement Act of 1996 - Amends the Job Training Partnership Act with respect to the Job Corps program. Directs the Secretary of Labor to require that Job Corps applicants be tested for drug and alcohol use and undergo appropriate background checks. Directs the Secretary to establish Job Corps standards of conduct that prohibit enrollee possession, distribution, or use of controlled substances, abuse of alcohol, acts of violence, and other related disruptive activities. Requires the director of a Job Corps center to take appropriate disciplinary measures against an enrollee, including immediate dismissal, upon determination that the enrollee has violated any such standard. Subjects such dismissal decisions by directors to expeditious appeal procedures established by the Secretary. Limits the portion of Job Corps funds which may be used for program administration. Directs the Secretary to: (1) review and report to the Congress on Job Corps activities; and (2) make improvements, based on review results, in the operation of the Job Corps program, including specified numbers of closings and relocations of centers. Prohibits closing a Job Corps center if it is the only one in a State or a region. Allows completion of planning or construction and beginning of operation of any uncompleted Job Corps center that received Federal funding for FY 1994 or 1995. Prohibits the Secretary from evaluating any such center sooner than three years after the first date of operation. Directs the Secretary to report biennially to the Congress on specified matters relating to the Job Corps program.</summary>
</bill>
