<bill session="106" type="h" number="5337" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Cruise Vessel Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To revise the laws of the United States relating to United States cruise vessels, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400149"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2000-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2000-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2000-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2000-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="2000-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Coastwise shipping"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Ferries"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flags of convenience"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Operations under Certificate of Documentation Title II: Other Provisions United States Cruise Vessel Act - Title I: Operations Under Certificate of Documentation - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to issue a certificate of documentation with a temporary coastwise endorsement for an eligible foreign-built cruise vessel to operate in domestic itineraries in the transportation of passengers in the coastwise trade between U.S. ports if such vessel meets certain requirements, including that: (1) the operator of the vessel promises that any repairs to it will be performed in a U.S. shipyard; and (2) such operator, with a specified exception, executes a contract with one or more U.S. shipyards for the construction of two or more cruise vessels with a total combined berth or stateroom capacity equal to at least that of the operator's vessel to which a certificate of documentation has been issued. Terminates the coastwise endorsement for an eligible cruise vessel 24 months after the delivery date for the replacement vessel(s) for it. Authorizes the operator of an eligible cruise vessel that has been issued a certificate of documentation, or a cruise vessel that has been constructed under contract, to place such vessel under foreign registry.Prohibits eligible cruise vessels operating in domestic itineraries from operating as a ferry, regularly carrying for hire both passengers and vehicles or other cargo, or operating between or among the Hawaiian Islands.Directs the Secretary to give priority to U.S.- built cruise vessels over other eligible foreign-built cruise vessels in a comparable market that have been issued a certificate of documentation if the Secretary, after notice and an opportunity for public comment, determines that the employment in the coastwise trade of an eligible foreign-built cruise vessel will adversely affect the coastwise trade business of any person operating a vessel not documented under this Act.Title II: Other Provisions - Requires new or otherwise available permits for U.S.-flag vessels carrying passengers for hire into Glacier Bay or other National Park Service areas.</summary>
</bill>
