<bill session="104" type="h" number="1696" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to exempt certain small landfills from the ground water monitoring requirements contained in landfill regulations promulgated by the Agency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402858"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Rain and rainfall"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to exempt from specified groundwater monitoring requirements any municipal solid waste landfill unit: (1) at which less than 20 tons of municipal solid waste is disposed of daily; (2) at which there is no evidence of existing groundwater contamination; and (3) which serves a community that experiences an annual interruption of at least three consecutive months of surface transportation that prevents access to a regional waste management facility or that has no waste management alternative and is in an area that receives 25 inches or less of precipitation annually. Allows a State to require groundwater monitoring of a unit otherwise exempt under this Act if necessary to protect groundwater resources and ensure compliance with a State groundwater protection plan if it determines that such monitoring will produce evidence of contamination. Allows, where such monitoring is required, use of a method other than groundwater monitoring wells. Allows exemption from the groundwater monitoring requirements of units of Native Alaska villages upon certification by the Governor of Alaska that their application would not be feasible, cost effective, or appropriate because of the unit's remote location. States the intent of the Solid Waste Disposal Act to immediately reinstate Environmental Protection Agency rules promulgated on October 9, 1991, regarding groundwater monitoring at municipal solid waste landfill units.</summary>
</bill>
