<bill session="105" type="h" number="2958" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor Act Amendments of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407465"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1997-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="1997-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="1462"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/1997--Introduced.
Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor Act Amendments of 1997 - Amends the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor Act of 1988 (the Act) to change the name of the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor to the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor. Includes among the Act's purposes enhancing economic development within the context of preservation. Modifies provisions regarding: (1) membership of, terms of office for, and confirmation of appointment to the Delaware and Lehigh National Corridor Commission; and (2) powers of the Commission to authorize the conveyance of real property acquired by the Commission to an appropriate nonprofit organization, to authorize the Commission to enter into cooperative agreements with a nonprofit organization, and to require any cooperative agreement to establish procedures for providing notice to the Commission of any action proposed by a nonprofit organization which may affect implementation of the Cultural Heritage and Corridor Management Plan. Authorizes the Commission to administer any grant or loan from amounts appropriated, donated, or otherwise made available to the Commission for the purpose of providing a grant or loan. Directs the Commission to implement the Plan by taking appropriate steps to preserve and interpret the cultural, natural, recreational, and scenic (currently, limited to historic) resources of the Canal and its surrounding area. Terminates the Commission ten years after the date of this Act's enactment. Requires specified actions by any Federal entity conducting or supporting activities directly affecting the historic, cultural, natural, recreational, or scenic resources of the Corridor (currently, the flow of the Canal or the natural resources of the Corridor). Reauthorizes and increases appropriations under the Act. Authorizes specified funds to implement the management action plan created by the Commission. Prohibits the Commission from interfering with private property rights or any local zoning ordinance or land use plan of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania or any political subdivision.</summary>
</bill>
