<bill session="104" type="h" number="3007" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Counterfeiting Prevention Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish an interagency task force to design and implement a plan for determining the extent to which United States currency is held in foreign countries and estimating the extent to which such currency is being counterfeited outside the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1996-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="1996-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/1996--Introduced.
International Counterfeiting Prevention Act of 1996 - Requires the Secretary of the Treasury (Secretary), the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Secretary of State to establish, and appoint the members of, an interagency task force to: (1) monitor the use and holding of U.S. currency in foreign countries; (2) produce a statistically valid estimate of the amount of counterfeit U.S. currency that is produced, passed, and possessed outside the United States each year; and (3) coordinate the activities of the agencies represented on the task force in carrying out such duties. Requires the task force to establish, implement, and report to the Congress on an effective international evaluation audit plan designed to enable the represented agencies to carry out their duties. Requires the Secretary of State to: (1) consider in a timely manner the request of the Secretary of the Treasury for the placement of Secret Service agents in posts in overseas embassies for the effective enforcement of prohibitions against international counterfeiting of U.S. currency; and (2) reach an agreement with the Secretary on such posts by December 31, 1996. Requires the Secretaries to each submit a written report, by February 1, 1997, to specified congressional committees explaining the reasons for any rejection of a proposed post and any failure to fill an approved post by such date. Requires the United States Sentencing Commission to amend its sentencing guidelines to provide an appropriate enhancement of the punishment (a maximum 20-year prison term) for a defendant convicted under the Federal criminal code of international counterfeiting of U.S. currency.</summary>
</bill>
