<bill session="107" type="h" number="3806" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Paul Revere Freedom to Warn Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to protect those who defend the United States by exercising their duty as patriots to warn against the existence of threats to weaknesses created by institutional failures that should be identified and corrected in a timely manner, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="2002-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2002-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="2002-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-02-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E213-214"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E529-530"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2002--Introduced.
Paul Revere Freedom to Warn Act - Allows any Federal employee aggrieved by a violation of the right to petition Congress or a Member of Congress, or to furnish information to either House of Congress, or to a congressional committee or committee Member, or by a violation of specified criminal law provisions relating to witness tampering, to bring a civil action (entitled to a jury trial) in the appropriate U.S. District Court, within three years from the date of such violation, against any person, organization, or employer responsible for the violation, for lost wages and benefits, reinstatement, costs and attorney fees, compensatory or punitive damages, and equitable, injunctive, or any other relief that the court considers appropriate.States that a District Court shall retain jurisdiction over any claim filed unless all parties voluntarily elect, after the complaint is filed, that the proceeding be resolved through mediation and, if necessary, that a decision by an arbitrator selected by mutual consent, with approval by the Court, be binding.</summary>
</bill>
