<bill session="107" type="h" number="4057" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Making Work Pay Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To replace the caseload reduction credit with an employment credit under the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400238"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="2058"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="2058"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Welfare work participation"/>
    <term name="Welfare-to-work"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2002--Introduced.
Making Work Pay Act - Amends part A (Temporary Assistance to Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA), with respect to rewards to States in which families leave welfare for work, to replace the caseload reduction credit with an employment credit. Requires the reduction of a State's minimum participation rate by the number of percentage points in the State's employment credit for the fiscal year.Allows States to receive partial credit toward their work participation rate for recipients engaged in part-time work for an average of at least half the minimum average number of hours per week.Removes from the work participation rate calculation for a entire year any TANF recipients who qualify for supplemental security income benefits under SSA title XVI.Grants States the option to include recipients of substantial child care or transportation assistance in the work participation rate.Repeals the separate work participation rate for two-parent families (thus lowering their rate to the one applied to one-parent families).</summary>
</bill>
