<bill session="104" type="hr" number="346" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives respecting the procedures of the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="406863" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="1996-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1996-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Legislative and Budget Process.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU02" subcommittee="Legislative Process" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional caucuses"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee membership"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Democratic Party"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Republican Party"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/1996--Introduced.
Amends rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require the respective party conference or caucus to each nominate to the House at the beginning of each Congress five members to serve on the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct. Limits an individual's membership on the Committee to two Congresses (currently, three Congresses in any period of five successive Congresses). Provides that of the Members nominated to serve on the Committee in the 105th Congress, two designated by the party conference and two designated by the party caucus shall only serve on the Committee during that Congress. Requires the senior majority and minority party members of the Committee to serve as its chairman and ranking minority member. Provides that if a complaint is filed with the Committee against a Member, officer, or employee of the House, the Committee shall determine if the complaint is properly filed and, if so, whether a preliminary investigation is warranted. Conditions such investigation on the approval of the Committee's members by an affirmative vote of the majority. Sets forth procedures for selecting members (excluding members of the Committee or any Member deemed by the conference or caucus to be exempt) to serve on an investigative panel with respect to the complaint. Requires the Committee to adopt rules providing for staff, funding, reports, proceedings, disbanding, and the disposition of the recommendations of investigative panels. Allows the Committee, at any time and by a majority vote, to determine that a complaint is frivolous if: (1) it deems that the complaint has no basis in fact; (2) the alleged violation is of such a minor and technical nature that it does not reflect discredit upon the House or its Members; (3) the complaint was filed for purely partisan reasons and not out of concern for maintaining the ethical standards of the House; or (4) the complaint is part of a pattern of abuse and misuse of the Committee. Requires the Committee, in the case of any complaint deemed frivolous, to determine the costs of its inquiry and report such costs to the House Committee on House Oversight, the Clerk of the House, and the public. Authorizes the Committee, by majority vote, to recommend to the House that any Member who has filed a frivolous complaint repay the costs of the inquiry over a period of greater than one year or be fined an appropriate amount.</summary>
</bill>
