<bill session="106" type="h" number="3631" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Broken Promises Retiree Health Coverage Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for an election for retirees 55-to-65 years of age who lose employer-based coverage to acquire health care coverage under the Medicare Program or under COBRA continuation benefits, and to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to provide for advance notice of material reductions in covered services under group health plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="2000-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2000-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2000-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="2000-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-02-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E116"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-10">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-10">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medigap"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Access to Medicare for Individuals Losing Retiree Health Coverage Title II: COBRA Protection for Early Retirees Subtitle A: Amendments to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 Subtitle B: Amendments to the Public Health Service Act Subtitle C: Amendments to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 Title III: Notice Requirements Broken Promises Retiree Health Coverage Act of 2000 - Title I: Access to Medicare For Individuals Losing Retiree Health Coverage - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to make certain individuals between the ages of 55 and 65 eligible to enroll in Medicare part A (Hospital Insurance) if the individual was covered as a qualified retiree under a group health plan which terminated such coverage. Outlines premium requirements.Provides for an open enrollment period under the Medicare supplemental health insurance policies (Medigap) program for certain retired workers enrolled in Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) and entitled to benefits under Medicare part A (Hospital Insurance) whose coverage under a group health plan is terminated.Title II: COBRA Protections for Early Retirees - Subtitle A: Amendments to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for COBRA (Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985) continuation coverage for certain retired workers whose coverage under a group health plan is terminated. Sets forth a special rule for certain dependents in such case as well as permits an increased level of premiums.Subtitle B: Amendments to the Public Health Service Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to set forth requirements analogous to those under subtitle A.Subtitle C: Amends to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to set forth requirements analogous to those under subtitle B.Title III: Notice Requirements - Amends ERISA and the IRC to mandate that advance notice of any material reduction in covered services or benefits provided under a group health plan relating to retiree health benefits be furnished to participants and beneficiaries as well as to the Secretary of Labor. Prescribes a civil penalty for violations of this title.</summary>
</bill>
