<bill session="106" type="hc" number="380" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress with respect to the relationship between eating disorders in adolescents and young adults and certain practices of the advertising industry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400178"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Clothing industry"/>
    <term name="Eating disorders"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Youth"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2000--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the advertising industry should, in using models in advertisements likely to be viewed by adolescents or young adults, take into account: (1) the influence that these advertising models have on the self-images of adolescents and young adults; (2) that such models frequently portray physiques that cannot or should not be achieved by many adolescents and young adults; and (3) the importance of taking action to reduce the extent to which such models influence adolescents and young adults to engage in unhealthy eating habits, whether the reduction is achieved by using models who more closely approximate average, healthy individuals, by providing for public service announcements to counteract negative health influences, or by taking other appropriate action.</summary>
</bill>
