<bill session="108" type="hc" number="18" updated="2013-07-14T19:03:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Calling on the Democratic People's Republic of Korea and the United States to return to an interim level of compliance with the Agreed Framework of 1994 while a more comprehensive and mutually acceptable agreement can be negotiated by those two nations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2003-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2003-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400181" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2003-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms control negotiations"/>
    <term name="Arms control verification"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Cameras"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Plutonium"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/28/2003--Introduced.
Calls on: (1) the Democratic People's Republic of Korea (North Korea) in a sign of good faith to allow International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) inspectors to return to North Korea, reinstall surveillance cameras, and reseal the country's plutonium reprocessing plant while a more comprehensive and mutually acceptable agreement can be negotiated with the United States; (2) the United States in a sign of good faith to resume monthly fuel oil shipments to North Korea while such agreement is worked out; (3) both countries to begin diplomatic talks and negotiations until a mutually acceptable binding treaty to resolve the current crisis has been agreed to by both parties; and (4) members of the Korean Peninsula Energy Development Organization (KEDO), and the Russian Federation, the Republic of Korea, Australia, Canada, and other concerned nations to support all diplomatic attempts by the United States and North Korea to achieve a peaceful resolution to the current crisis.Commends the IAEA for its efforts and calls on it to continue its negotiations with North Korea to allow its inspectors to return to the country.</summary>
</bill>
