<bill session="107" type="h" number="1916" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">21st Century Media Responsibility Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment, use, and enforcement of a consistent and comprehensive system for labeling violent content in audio and visual media products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400421"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2001-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Age (Law)"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motion picture industry"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Video games"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Violence in mass media"/>
    <term name="Youth"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2001--Introduced.
21st Century Media Responsibility Act of 2001 - Amends the Federal Cigarette Labeling and Advertising Act to state that it is the policy of Congress to provide for the establishment, use, and enforcement of a consistent and comprehensive system for labeling violent content in audio and visual media products, including the appropriateness of such products for minors.Authorizes manufacturers and producers of interactive video game, video program, motion picture, and sound recording products to submit to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) a joint proposal for a system for labeling violent content. Outlines labeling system requirements, including that: (1) such product shall specify a minimum age for purchase and viewing; and (2) the label should appear conspicuously on the product. Directs the FTC to establish its own labeling system if a proposal is not submitted.Prohibits a person from: (1) manufacturing or producing such a product unless it bears a label meeting requirements of this Act; or (2) selling such product to an individual under the minimum age specified under the labeling system.Provides civil penalties for violations.Renames the Federal Cigarette Labeling and Advertising Act as the Federal Cigarette and Media Violence Labeling and Advertising Act.</summary>
</bill>
