<bill session="104" type="h" number="3999" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Making Work Requirements Work Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that the States have sufficient funds to assure the effectiveness of the work requirements of the program of block grants for temporary assistance for needy families, to provide such funds through tax reforms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400300"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Depletion allowances"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family enterprises"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Holding companies"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Mineral industries"/>
    <term name="Minerals"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Nuclear engineering"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Welfare reform"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Grants to States for Operation of Work Programs Title II: Revenue Offsets Subtitle A: Corporate Reforms Subtitle B: Foreign Provisions Subtitle C: Accounting Provisions Title III: Repeal of Prototype Demonstration of Advanced Nuclear Reactor Technology Making Work Requirements Work Act of 1996 - Title I: Grants Grants to States for Operation of Work Programs - Amends title IV (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TEA) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, to establish a program of supplemental grants to States for operation of work programs. Makes appropriations for such grants for FY 1997 through 2002. Title II: Revenue Offsets - Amends the Internal Revenue Code in various ways to provide revenue offsets under subtitles A, B, and C. Subtitle A: Corporate Reforms - Repeals the percentage depletion allowance for certain nonfuel minerals mined on Federal lands. Subtitle B: Foreign Provisions - Revises the definition of foreign personal holding company income which is includable in gross income to include net income from notional principal contracts (except for dealers) as well as payments in lieu of dividends. Modifies foreign tax credit carryback and carryover periods to eliminate the second carryback year and add sixth and seventh carryover years. Modifies foreign tax credit rules applicable to dual capacity taxpayers state that certain amounts paid or accrued to a foreign country or U.S. possession shall not be considered a tax. Revises rules relating to foreign oil and gas income to: (1) provide for separate basket treatment for foreign tax credits; and (2) eliminate deferral for foreign oil and gas extraction income. Subtitle C: Accounting Provisions - Prohibits suspense accounts for family corporations required to use the accrual method of accounting. Requires a ten-year phase-out of existing accounts. Title III: Repeal of Prototype Demonstration of Advanced Nuclear Reactor Technology - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to repeal the mandate and authorization of appropriations for: (1) commercialization of advanced light water reactor technology; and (2) the prototype demonstration program for advanced nuclear reactor technology.</summary>
</bill>
