<bill session="106" type="h" number="3569" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Human Research Protection and Promotion Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish an independent office to be known as the Office for Protection of Human Research Subjects, and to assign to such Office responsibility for administering regulations regarding the protection of human subjects in Federal research projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400227"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2000-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2000-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2000-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2000-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2000-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Fetus"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="In vitro fertilization"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2000--Introduced.
Human Research Protection and Promotion Act of 2000 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Office for Protection of Human Research Subjects as an independent establishment in the executive branch, to be headed by a director appointed by the President.Requires the Office Director to establish criteria by regulation for the protection of human subjects in research conducted, supported, or otherwise subject to regulation by the Federal Government (Federal research projects). Provides that in the case of covered agencies: (1) such regulations supersede all regulations for such criteria that were in effect before this Act's enactment date; and (2) the Director has exclusive authority to issue such regulations after such date. Deems current regulations to have been promulgated by the Director and authorizes their continuation or modification by the Director.Applies such regulations to each Federal agency that: (1) as of October 1, 1999, was subject to the basic policy under current regulations for protection of human research subjects; and (2) takes appropriate administrative action after such date to provide that regulations under this Act apply to the agency. Authorizes the Director to exempt any Federal research project from such regulations. Continues exemptions under current regulations unless modified by the Director. Applies the following provisions under existing regulations to Federal research projects of an agency that currently is not subject to such provisions only to projects that are approved after this Act's enactment date: (1) additional protections pertaining to research, development, and related activities involving fetuses, pregnant women, and human in vitro fertilization; (2) additional protections pertaining to biomedical and behavioral research involving prisoners as subjects; and (3) additional protections pertaining to children as research subjects.Sets forth provisions similar to those under existing law that require entities applying to carry out Federal research projects to establish institutional review boards, but replaces the authority of the Secretary of Health and Human Services with that of the Director. Continues the existence of current institutional review boards that meet this Act's requirements.Requires the Director to establish an Interagency Coordinating Committee on Protection of Human Research Subjects to develop recommendations on carrying out this Act, review regulations, and report to specified congressional committees.Provides that, after this Act's enactment, any office or unit within an agency that was established for the protection of human research subjects in Federal research has only such duties as may be assigned by the Director and authorizes the Director to terminate such office or unit.</summary>
</bill>
