<bill session="105" type="hr" number="442" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-21T23:33:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-05-21T23:33:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the joint resolution (H.J.Res. 119) proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to limit campaign spending, and for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2183) to amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to reform the financing of campaigns for elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-05-20T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-545, by Mr. Linder.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-20T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 119 and H.R. 2183. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Upon the adoption of this resolution, the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 1(b) of rule XXIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union for consideration of H.J. Res. 119. General debate shall be limited to one hour. After general debate the joint resolution shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule and shall be considered as read. Bill is open to amendments. At any time after the adoption of this resolution the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 1(b) of rule XXIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the the bill H.R. 2183. General debate shall not exceed two hours. Befo...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-05-20T20:36:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="194">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 194.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T21:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3722-3733" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T22:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T23:33:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 208 - 190 (Roll No. 186).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-05-21T23:33:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T23:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hj" number="119"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="hj" number="119"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2183"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="2183"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/1998--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.J. Res. 119 (campaign spending limitation). Sets forth the rule (modified open) for the consideration of H.R. 2183 (campaign financing).</summary>
</bill>
