<bill session="104" type="h" number="3806" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Runaway and Homeless Youth Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend and amend the programs under the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act, to consolidate authorities for programs for runaway and homeless youth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1996-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="1996-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-07-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1275"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child molesting"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to territories"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Group homes for children"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homeless children"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Recreation centers"/>
    <term name="Runaway children"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/1996--Introduced.
Runaway and Homeless Youth Amendments of 1996 - Renames the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act the Comprehensive Runaway and Homeless Youth Services Act (the Act). Revises findings of the Act, including by specifying that services for runaway and homeless youth are needed in urban, suburban, and rural areas. Modifies the Act to require: (1) the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to entities to establish and operate comprehensive local runaway and homeless youth services programs and, in selecting among grant applicants, to ensure that at least 20 percent of the total amount available for such grants for each fiscal year be used for long-term residential care for older homeless youth through the provision of transitional living services; and (2) an applicant, to be eligible for such assistance, to propose to establish, strengthen, or fund an existing or proposed locally controlled comprehensive runaway and homeless youth services program that meets specified requirements. Permits a program eligible for assistance to be located in any urban, suburban, or rural area where a need for runaway and homeless youth is demonstrated. Specifies that youth eligible to receive services from such programs are individuals age 21 or younger. Modifies general plan requirements to require that applicants, to be eligible for assistance, provide or make referrals regarding: (1) alcohol and drug abuse prevention and education activities and services; and (2) appropriate medical, educational, social, recreational, and transportation services. Sets forth or modifies provisions concerning plan requirements for programs providing short-term emergency shelter and long-term residential services, approval of applications by the Secretary, evaluation authority, reporting requirements, and the authorization of appropriations. Directs the Secretary to develop and implement a system that provides information on the quality and quantity of services being provided by comprehensive runaway and homeless youth services programs. Requires grant recipients to cooperate with Federal data collection efforts and with triennial on-site monitoring activities. Repeals provisions regarding: (1) authority under the Act for street-based and home-based services; (2) temporary demonstration projects to provide services to youth in rural areas; (3) specified requirements regarding informational assistance to potential grantees; and (4) annual program priorities.</summary>
</bill>
