<bill session="107" type="h" number="4125" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-01T19:24:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-01T19:24:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Courts Improvement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Federal Courts Improvement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make improvements in the operation and administration of the Federal courts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2002-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-04-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E488-489"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-02">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-09-10">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-26T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Blunt asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Judiciary have until midnight on Sept. 30 to file a report on H.R. 4125. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-30T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 107-700.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-09-30T17:07:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="433">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 433.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6851-6854" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4125.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T16:59:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6884-6885" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-10-01T19:24:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="425" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 370 - 21 (Roll no. 425).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6851-6853" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administration of criminal justice"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Community service (Punishment)"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Disability retirement"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial districts"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Judicial tenure"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law libraries"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Magistrates"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Public defenders"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Sick leave"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court justices"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2002--Passed House amended.
Federal Courts Improvement Act of 2002 - Title I: Judicial Process Improvements - (Sec. 101) Authorizes bankruptcy administrators in Alabama and North Carolina to appoint bankruptcy case trustees and to serve in such capacity.(Sec. 102) Amends the Federal judicial code to authorize the holding of court for the Eastern District of Texas in Plano. Allows court for the Eastern District of Texas and the Western District of Arkansas to be held anywhere in the Federal courthouse in Texarkana that is located astride the State line between Texas and Arkansas.(Sec. 103) Modifies provisions regarding supervised release after imprisonment to limit the conditions under which custody by the Bureau of Prisons during nights, weekends, or other intervals of time may be imposed (limited to the first year of supervision, only when Bureau facilities are available to accommodate the individual, and only for a violation of a condition of supervised release).(Sec. 104) Requires judges to submit an annual report to the Administrative Office of the United States Courts regarding wiretap orders.(Sec. 105) Denies the district courts original jurisdiction based on diversity of citizenship where the matter in controversy is between a citizen of a State and a citizen or subject of a foreign state admitted to the United States for permanent residence and domiciled in the same State.(Sec. 106) Allows (currently, requires) a court to require an individual who does not respond to a jury summons to appear.(Sec. 107) Eliminates: (1) the automatic excuse from jury service for members of the armed forces, members of fire and police departments, and public officers; and (2) public drawing requirements for the selection of juror wheels.(Sec. 109) Makes the supplemental attendance fee for petit jurors serving on lengthy trials applicable where the juror is required to attend more than five (currently, 30) days in hearing one case.(Sec. 111) Establishes as a place of holding court: (1) St. Clairsville in the Southern District of Ohio; and (2) Plattsburgh in the Northern District of New York.Title II: Judicial Personnel Administration, Benefits, and Protections - (Sec. 201) Modifies the Federal judicial code to provide that any judge of the District Courts of Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands who has served at least five years and who retires or is removed upon the sole ground of mental or physical disability shall be entitled to receive during the remainder of that judge's life an annuity equal to 40 percent of the salary received when the judge left office or, in the case of a judge who has served at least ten years, an annuity equal to that proportion of such salary which the aggregate number of the judge's years of judicial service bears to 15.Entitles any retired judge who is eligible to receive an annuity to a cost-of-living adjustment that shall not exceed the salary of a judge in regular active service with the court on which the judge served before retiring.(Sec. 202) Authorizes the Director of the Federal Judicial Center to fix the compensation of four Center employees at levels equivalent to level IV of the Executive Schedule pay rates.(Sec. 203) Includes judicial branch executives within maximum annual leave limits applicable to members of the executive branch's Senior Executive Service.(Sec. 204) Authorizes the judiciary to establish a benefits program for judicial branch officers and employees, including justices and judges of the United States.(Sec. 205) Includes judicial branch personnel in the organ donor leave program.(Sec. 206) Increases maximum amounts of compensation for attorneys and for services other than counsel.(Sec.208) Sets forth criminal penalties for retaliating against a Federal judge by false claim or slander of title.(Sec. 209) Authorizes the judicial council of each circuit (currently, each court of appeals) to appoint a librarian.Title III: Additional Provisions - Urges the Judicial Conference to take steps to safeguard the privacy of officers and employees of the judicial branch.</summary>
</bill>
