<bill session="105" type="h" number="4585" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Northwest Straits Advisory Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400598"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="2488"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Endangered animals"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental degradation"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Salmon fisheries"/>
    <term name="Shellfish fisheries"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/1998--Introduced.
Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act - Establishes the Northwest Straits Advisory Commission to: (1) monitor the health of the Northwest Straits marine ecosystem; (2) develop scientifically sound economic measurements of ecosystem degradation and environmental protection costs; (3) identify trends and activities adversely affecting, or preventing the restoration of, that ecosystem; (4) develop scientifically sound restoration recommendations, informed by the economic measurements; (5) help facilitate recommendation implementation by developing broad support among the authorities, stakeholder groups, and the public; (6) provide a public forum for discussions of Federal, State, local, tribal, and Canadian policies and actions regarding that ecosystem; (7) inform authorities and the public about that ecosystem and related issues; and (8) consult with tribes in the region to ensure that Commission work does not violate treaty rights. Authorizes the Commission to provide financial assistance, with or without compensation, to any marine resource committee. Authorizes the council or commission of each of seven specified counties in the State of Washington to establish a marine resource committee to address marine ecosystem issues within its county and work to achieve the benchmarks of this Act. Directs the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to request the National Research Council to provide an independent review of, and report to the Congress, the Secretaries of Commerce and the Interior, and the Governor of the State of Washington on, the extent to which the Commission has fulfilled the benchmarks of this Act. Establishes the benchmarks, including broad county participation in the committees, net gain in highly ecologically productive nearshore, intertidal, and estuarine habitat, net reduction in shellfish harvest in closed contaminated areas, and increases in key marine indicator species. Mandates an annual Commission report to the public and a final report to the Congress and the President. Authorizes appropriations to carry out this Act. Terminates the Commission a specified period after enactment of this Act, unless it is reauthorized by the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
