<bill session="106" type="h" number="1786" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Education for the 21st Century (E-21) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enable America's schools to use their computer hardware to increase student achievement and prepare students for the 21st century workplace.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400346"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1999-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1999-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400613" joined="1999-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Middle schools"/>
    <term name="Political science"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="World Wide Web"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/1999--Introduced.
Education for the 21st Century (E-21) Act - Establishes assistance programs for middle school computer literacy and for high-quality educational software for all schools. (Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to States that integrate into the State curriculum the goal of making all middle school graduates in the State technology literate. Requires preference to be given to States which place a priority on training middle school teachers. Requires such grants to be used for teacher training in technology, with an emphasis on programs that prepare one or more teachers in each middle school in the State to become technology leaders who then serve as experts and train other teachers. Directs States to encourage schools that receive such assistance to provide matching funds. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 5) Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive grants to secondary school and college students working with university faculty, software developers, and experts in educational technology for the development of high-quality educational software and Internet web sites by such students, faculty, developers, and experts. Directs the Secretary to: (1) recognize outstanding educational software and Internet web sites developed with such assistance that focus on core curriculum areas; and (2) issue certificates to each student and faculty member who develops such recognized software or sites. Requires grant award priority to be given for developing such software or sites in the following core curriculum areas: (1) for the first year of awards, in mathematics, science, and reading; and (2) for the second and third years of awards, again in mathematics, science, and reading, but also in social studies, the humanities, and the arts. Requires: (1) such recognized educational software to be made available to local educational agencies for free downloading from the Department of Education's Internet web site; and (2) such recognized Internet web sites to be accessible to any World Wide Web user. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
