<bill session="105" type="h" number="3871" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National School Lunch Act to provide children with increased access to food and nutrition assistance during the summer months.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409228" joined="1998-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Food service"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/1998--Introduced.
Amends the National School Lunch Act with respect to the summer food service program to revise program eligibility criteria for a private nonprofit institution to: (1) increase from five to 25 the number of sites it may operate; and (2) eliminate requirements that it limit to 2,500 the total number of children served per day at all its sites, use its own facilities to prepare meals or obtain meals from a public facility or school participating in the school lunch program, and meet a March 1 deadline for indication of interest. Revises program requirements for food service management companies to: (1) allow private nonprofit organizations to contract with such companies; (2) make discretionary certain components of State registration and review; and (3) eliminate certain recordkeeping duties of the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to such companies that have been seriously deficient in program participation. Extends through FY 2003 the authorization of appropriations for the summer food service program.</summary>
</bill>
