<bill session="108" type="h" number="3958" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the extension of unconditional and permanent nondiscriminatory treatment (permanent normal trade relations treatment) to the products of Ukraine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400238"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E358"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on International Relations, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Emigration"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Racial violence"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2004--Introduced.
Authorizes the President to extend unconditional and permanent nondiscriminatory (permanent normal trade relations) treatment to the products of the Ukraine. Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States remain fully committed to a multifaceted engagement with Ukraine, including by: (1) urging Ukraine to fulfill its commitments as a participating member of the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), and to continue its current policy with regard to human rights, rule of law, and media freedoms; (2) working with Ukraine to improve in the areas of its legal regime and enforcement of internationally recognized labor rights; (3) supporting Ukraine's efforts to make substantial and meaningful progress in enacting and enforcing the protection of intellectual property rights; (4) working with Ukraine to ensure quick resolution of trade disputes that may arise, particularly in the poultry and other agricultural sectors; and (5) continued monitoring by the United States of human rights, rule of law, and media freedoms in Ukraine, including the issues described in this Act, providing assistance to nongovernmental organizations and human rights groups involved in human rights, democracy, and rule of law activities in Ukraine, and attempting to establish annual discussions with Ukraine regarding those issues, including the participation of United States and Ukrainian nongovernmental organizations in such discussions. Applies to Ukraine to the same extent as to the People's Republic of China, so long as the 1992 trade agreement between the United States and Ukraine remains in force, the requirement of the Trade Act of 1974 that the President proclaim increased duties or other import restrictions with respect to any product of Ukraine being imported into the United States in such increased quantities or under such conditions as to cause or threaten to cause market disruption to U.S. producers of a like or directly competitive product. Sets forth procedures with respect to: (1) notification by the President to Congress regarding U.S. entry into a bilateral agreement with Ukraine on the terms of accession by Ukraine to the World Trade Organization; (2) a resolution of disapproval of such agreement; and (3) procedures for consideration of the resolution.</summary>
</bill>
