<bill session="105" type="h" number="4243" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-14T11:55:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-14T11:55:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Waste, Fraud, and Error Reduction Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Federal Benefit Verification and Integrity Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Government Waste, Fraud, and Error Reduction Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce waste, fraud, and error in Government programs by making improvements with respect to Federal management and debt collection practices, Federal payment systems, and Federal benefit programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400506"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="1998-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-07-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-08-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14T11:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Horn moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10850-10855" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-10-14T11:55:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14T11:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-15">
      <text>See H.R.4857.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="4857"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="4857"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Black lung"/>
    <term name="Child support enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Collection agencies"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Computer matching"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Debit cards"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Garnishment"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Postage stamps"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel agents"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/1998--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: General Management Improvements Title II: Improving Federal Debt Collection Practices Title III: Sale of Debts Owed to United States Title IV: Treatment of High Value Nontax Debts Title V: Federal Payments Government Waste, Fraud, and Error Reduction Act of 1998 - Title I: General Management Improvements - Amends requirements regarding certain Federal agencies' (executive departments as well as the Environmental Protection Agency and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration) audited financial statements, including to: (1) extend the deadline for the preparation and submission of the first of such statements; and (2) provide for submission of such statements to the Congress and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (Director). (Currently, such statements are to be submitted to the Director.) Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury, if he or she determines that it will not interfere with the engraving and printing needs of the United States, to: (1) produce currency, postage stamps, and other security documents for foreign governments, subject to a determination by the Secretary of State that such production would be consistent with U.S. foreign policy; and (2) produce security documents for States and their political subdivisions. Amends the requirement regarding payment for Bureau of Engraving and Printing services to require the Secretary to impose charges for such services he or she provides to a foreign government, State, or political subdivision. (Currently, the Secretary imposes charges only for services provided to an agency.) (Sec. 102) Excludes lodging provided under Federal travel and subsistence expense provisions from an exception which prohibits agency heads from requiring employees or members of the uniformed services to occupy quarters on a rental basis. Directs each head of an executive agency to require, with respect to travel by agency employees in the performance of their duties, the use by such employees of travel management centers, authorized travel agents, and electronic reservation and payment systems for the purpose of improving efficiency and economy regarding travel by agency employees. Requires the Administrator of General Services to develop a plan regarding implementation of this requirement and to report to the Congress on such plan and the means by which such agency heads plan to ensure that employees use travel management centers, travel agents, and electronic reservation and payment systems. Title II: Improving Federal Debt Collection Practices - Makes technical amendments to financial management provisions relating to claims of the U.S. Government, including those that permit a State to collect by administrative offset certain payments under the Social Security Act, Black Lung Benefits Act, or railroad retirement laws for past due child support being enforced by a State. Prohibits the amounts received by a person for performing certain collection services for the Federal Government from being limited by State law. Sets forth provisions relating to the collection by private collection contractors through the use of garnishment of any debt owed to the United States, including to prohibit a private collection contractor, in attempting to collect through the use of garnishment any such debt, from being precluded from verifying the debtor's current employer, the location of the payroll office of the debtor's current employer, the period the debtor has been employed by the current employer, and the compensation received by the debtor from such employer. Requires collection contracts to include conditions under which contractors are: (1) subject to penalties for failures to comply with applicable law or for unreasonable or abusive collection practices; or (2) absolved from liability for damages or attorney's fees in certain cases. Amends provisions relating to contracts for collection services to authorize the Attorney General to make contracts retaining private counsel to furnish legal services in the case of any monetary claim, including claims for civil fines or penalties. (Under current law, such contracts are made only in the case of any claim of indebtedness owed the United States.) (Sec. 202) Bars certain delinquent Federal debtors from being eligible for the award or renewal of any: (1) Federal financial assistance in the form of a loan (other than a disaster loan), loan insurance, or guarantee; or (2) Federal permit or license. (Sec. 203) Prohibits an executive, judicial, or legislative agency head from discharging a debt or terminating collection action on a debt unless: (1) it has been referred to a private collection contractor, a debt collection center, or to the Attorney General for litigation; (2) it has been sold without recourse; (3) administrative wage garnishment has been undertaken; or (4) there is bankruptcy, death, or disability. Permits the Secretary, at an agency's request, to waive the application of such requirement with respect to any debt, or class of debts, if the waiver is in the best interest of the United States. Title III: Sale of Debts Owed to United States - Allows an executive, judicial, or legislative agency head to sell, using competitive procedures, any nontax debt owed to the United States that is administered by the agency. Specifies that such sales shall: (1) be for cash or cash and a residuary equity, joint venture, or profit participation, if the proceeds will be greater than the proceeds from a sale solely for cash; (2) be without recourse against the United States, but may include the use of guarantees if authorized by law; and (3) transfer to the purchaser all U.S. rights to demand payment of the debt, other than with respect to a residuary equity, joint venture, or profit participation. (Sec. 302) Sets forth requirements for the sale of certain: (1) delinquent nontax loans; (2) loans; and (3) nontax debts or class of debts. Title IV: Treatment of High Value Nontax Debts - Requires each agency head that administers a program that gives rise to a delinquent high value nontax debt (a nontax debt having an outstanding value that exceeds $1 million) to submit an annual report to the Congress that lists each such debt. (Sec. 402) Requires the Inspector General of each agency to: (1) review such annual report to the Congress and make such recommendations as necessary to improve the agency's performance; (2) periodically review and report to the Congress on the agency's debt collection management practices; and (3) as part of such reviews, examine agency efforts to reduce the aggregate amount of high value nontax debts that are resolved in whole or in part by compromise, default, or bankruptcy. Requires the President's Council on Integrity and Efficiency to report to specified congressional committees a summary of the reviews conducted by the Inspectors General. (Sec. 403) Requires an agency head authorized to collect a delinquent high value nontax debt to promptly seek seizure and forfeiture of assets pledged to the United States in any transaction giving rise to such a debt. Directs an agency, upon determining that seizure or forfeiture is not appropriate, to include a justification for such determination in the annual report. Title V: Federal Payments - Transfers from the Director to the Secretary responsibility for the prompt payment of proper invoices by Federal agencies. (Sec. 502) Includes within requirements of the Secretary's regulations regarding Federal payments that a required payment date may be waived to provide for early payment in cases where an agency will implement an electronic payment technology which improves agency cash management and business practice. Permits an executive agency head, subject to an agreement between the agency head and the applicable financial institution, to accept an electronic payment, including debit and credit cards, to satisfy a debt owed to the agency.</summary>
</bill>
