<bill session="107" type="h" number="5251" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Air Traffic Equity Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide equitable pay to air traffic managers, supervisors, and specialists of the Federal Aviation Administration at regional and headquarters locations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400252"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2002-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2002-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2002-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2002-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air traffic controllers"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employee-management relations in government"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Pay equity"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2002--Introduced.
Air Traffic Equity Act of 2002 - Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to adjust the annual rates of basic pay applicable to uncovered air traffic MSS employees (an air traffic controller assigned as a manager, supervisor, or staff specialist or any additional employee designated as critical to accomplishing the FAA air traffic control mission that is not covered by the air traffic control specialized compensation system). Requires such adjustment to align the rates with the annual rates of basic pay applicable to covered air traffic MSS employees (air traffic MSS employees covered by the air traffic control specialized compensation system). Sets forth certain basic pay adjustment requirements, including the payment of a lump sum to uncovered and former air traffic MSS employees. Entitles an individual aggrieved by a final determination under this Act to appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board, or through any contractual grievance procedure applicable to the employee as a member of a collective bargaining unit.</summary>
</bill>
