<bill session="105" type="hr" number="88" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-13T17:02:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-03-13T17:02:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 852) to amend chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, popularly known as the Paperwork Reduction Act, to minimize the burden of Federal paperwork demands upon small businesses, educational and nonprofit institutions, Federal contractors, State and local governments, and other persons through the sponsorship and use of alternative information technologies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-03-11T14:58:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-15, by Mrs. Myrick.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-11T14:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 852 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-03-11T14:59:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="5">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 5.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-03-13T15:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H990-995" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-13T15:52:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-13T16:34:00-05:00">
      <text>During the course of debate, Mr. Hefly demanded that certain words of Mr. Scarborough be taken down. The Clerk was instructed to report the words in question to the House. Subsequently, Mr. Scarborough asked unanimous consent to withdraw the words in question. Without objection, the request was agreed to.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-13T16:34:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-13T17:02:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 187 (Roll no. 49).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1997-03-13T17:02:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-03-13T17:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="852"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/1997--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 852 (Federal paperwork reduction).</summary>
</bill>
