<bill session="106" type="h" number="5101" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Affordable HIV/AIDS Medicines for Poor Countries Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require certain actions with respect to the availability of HIV/AIDS pharmaceuticals and medical technologies in developing countries, including sub-Saharan African countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2000-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2000-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2000-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2000-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2000-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2000-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2000-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2000-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2000-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Corporate philanthropy"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Patent agreements"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2000--Introduced.
Affordable HIV-AIDS Medicines for Poor Countries Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development, and the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) to encourage developing countries (including sub-Saharan African countries) and pharmaceutical companies to make HIV-AIDS pharmaceuticals and medical technologies available to people who live in such countries without charge or at affordable prices.Sets forth certain restrictions and limitations, including that: (1) appropriated funds made available to U.S. agencies may not be obligated to seek the revocation or revision of any intellectual property or competition law or policy of a developing country (including any sub- Saharan African country) that regulates HIV-AIDS pharmaceuticals or medical technologies if such law or policy promotes access to such drugs and technologies to the country's population; and (2) the USTR may not initiate a proceeding in the World Trade Organization (WTO) challenging and law or policy of a developing country (including a sub-Saharan African country) that promotes access to HIV-AIDS pharmaceuticals or medical technologies to the population of the country.Requires the President to direct the U.S. representative to the WTO to urge the WTO and member countries to exempt developing countries (including sub-Saharan African countries) from the application of any provision of the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights or any other international agreement relating to intellectual property rights that would prohibit or restrict such countries from establishing or implementing any law or policy that promotes access to HIV-AIDS pharmaceuticals or medical technologies to their population.</summary>
</bill>
