<bill session="105" type="h" number="1626" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require the licensing of certain unused channels for public safety uses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400166"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="1997-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E954-955"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/1997--Introduced.
Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to state that it shall be the policy of the Federal Communications Commission to waive any licensee eligibility and other applicable requirements with respect to a nonbroadcast channel in the 152-159 megahertz VHF frequency band or the 470-512 UHF frequency band allocated for one- or two-way common carrier mobile or point-to-multipoint common carrier use in order to permit the use of such channels for public safety purposes by a State or local government agency upon a showing that: (1) no other existing satisfactory channel is immediately available for such use; (2) the proposed use is technically feasible without harmful interference to existing stations within such frequency band; and (3) the use of such channel for such purposes is consistent with other existing public safety channel allocations in the geographic area.</summary>
</bill>
