<bill session="104" type="h" number="2534" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Corporate Responsibility Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to treatment of corporations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1995-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1995-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1996-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1996-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1995-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1996-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1995-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1995-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, National Security, Science, Resources, Commerce, Transportation and Infrastructure, Banking and Financial Services, and International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2039"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Native American and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power, and in addition to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII14" subcommittee="Native American and Insular Affairs" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Acreage allotments"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Export trading companies"/>
    <term name="Export-Import Bank of the United States"/>
    <term name="Farm production quotas"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Feed grain program"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian gambling operations"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International corporations"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Japanese studies"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="New Zealand"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Oilseeds"/>
    <term name="Overseas Private Investment Corporation"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Physics"/>
    <term name="Production engineering"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rice"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Semiconductor industry"/>
    <term name="Semiconductors"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding subsidies"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space stations"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Wheat"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/25/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Tax Subsidy Reform Title II: Agricultural and Grazing Subsidies Title III: Aerospace and High-Technology Industry Subsidies Title IV: National Parks Concession Reform Title V: Miscellaneous Industry Subsidies Title VI: Effective Dates Corporate Responsibility Act of 1995 - Title I: Tax Subsidy Reform - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to terminate the foreign tax credit. Allows the deduction of foreign taxes for which the credit is made unallowable by this Act. (Sec. 103) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe regulations regarding allocation of income and deductions which use a formulaic approach to clearly reflect income of multinational corporations. (Sec.104) Treats the gain or loss of a nonresident alien individual or foreign corporation that is a ten-percent shareholder in a domestic corporation upon disposition of such a corporation's stock as if the taxpayer were engaged during the taxable year in a trade or business within the United States and as if such gain or loss were attributable to a permanent U.S. trade or business establishment. Treats such gain or loss as from sources within the United States, notwithstanding source rules for personal property sales. Imposes a 26-percent minimum tax on nonresident alien individuals. Treats as stock, for purposes of these provisions, options or other rights to acquire a domestic corporation's stock, conversion features of debt instruments, and other interests in a domestic corporation other than those solely as a creditor. Treats as a dividend attributable to a domestic corporation's stock any gain which would be subject to tax but for a treaty and which results from a distribution in liquidation or redemption. Provides for the withholding of tax on such dispositions. Penalizes, and treats as tax evasion, the failure to pay the tax established by this Act where amounts were not deducted and withheld. Excepts such gain from the branch profits tax imposed on foreign corporations. Requires notice to the Secretary upon distributions by a U.S. person to a foreign person in redemption of stock or complete liquidation of a subsidiary. (Sec. 105) Removes the exemption of ten-percent shareholders from the tax on interest of nonresident alien individuals received from portfolio debt investments. Redefines portfolio interest as only interest paid on obligations issued by governmental entities. (Sec. 106) Terminates, effective with taxable years beginning January 1, 1996, the exclusion of foreign earned income and the housing cost amounts of U.S. citizens or residents living abroad. (Sec. 107) Terminates, effective with taxable years beginning January 1, 1996, the exclusion from gross income of exempt foreign trade income of foreign sales corporations. (Sec. 108) Revises rules for the determination of the income of controlled foreign corporations. Repeals provisions which reduce the controlled foreign corporation income of export trade corporations. (Sec. 109) Allows the Secretary to extend for an additional three years the limitation period for assessment of a foreign-related deficiency if the deficiency cannot be accurately assessed before the expiration of the usual three-year period because of delay or other taxpayer actions which prevented timely assessment of the deficiency. Defines a foreign-related deficiency as one: (1) of a 25-percent foreign-owned domestic corporation to the extent the deficiency is attributable to a transaction with a related party who is a foreign person; and (2) of a foreign corporation with respect to the tax on income for foreign corporations connected with U.S. business or the branch profits tax. Title II: Agricultural and Grazing Subsidies - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to decrease the $250,000 payment limitation under the farm commodity programs to $50,000. (Sec. 202) Repeals Title III (export enhancement program) of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978. (Sec. 203) Eliminates tobacco price support and production adjustment programs. (Sec. 204) Amends the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to repeal provisions for the market promotion program. (Sec. 205) Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to establish, beginning with the grazing season which commences on March 1, 1996, an annual domestic livestock grazing fee equal to fair market value with respect to certain National Forest lands where domestic livestock grazing is permitted under applicable law. Title III: Aerospace and High-Technology Industry Subsidies - Terminates Federal assistance for Sematech. (Sec. 302) Terminates Federal assistance under defense technology reinvestment programs. (Sec. 303) Terminates funding for the space station program. Title IV: National Parks Concession Reform - Repeals the Concessions Policy Act of 1965. (Sec. 405) Provides for a competitive selection process with respect to the provision of public accommodations, services, and facilities within the National Park System. Directs the Secretary to promulgate appropriate regulations establishing such process. (Sec. 406) Provides for the setting of franchise fees. (Sec. 407) Limits a concessions contract entered into pursuant to this Act for a term not to exceed ten years. (Sec. 408) Prohibits the transfer of a concessions contract without prior notification to, and approval of, the Secretary. (Sec. 409) Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) structures and facilities within a park; (2) recordkeeping; and (3) lease requirements. Title V: Miscellaneous Industry Subsidies - Requires sales of petroleum from the naval petroleum reserves to be made to the highest bidder at not less than the prevailing market price. (Sec. 502) Terminates the Tokamak Physics Experiment program of the Department of Energy. (Sec. 503) Amends the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 by eliminating funding for highway demonstration projects. (Sec. 504) Amends the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act by increasing from $1.5 million to $3 million the limit on amounts collected as fees from gaming activities to fund the National Indian Gaming Commission. (Sec. 505 Reduces from $75 billion to $37.5 billion the aggregate loan, guarantee, and insurance authority of the Export-Import Bank of the United States. Requires the Bank to charge and collect a fee (based on credit risk and not less than a fee that would be charged for a similar arms-length transaction in the private sector) for the provision of a guarantee, insurance, extension of credit, or for its participation in an extension of credit. (Sec. 506) Abolishes the Overseas Private Investment Corporation and transfers its functions relating to obligations effective on October 1, 1995, to the Department of State. Terminates all such remaining obligations when they expire. (Sec. 507) Terminates funding of nuclear weapons activities of the Department of Energy described under specified headings in Title III of the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act of 1995. (Sec. 508) Terminates funding for carrying out fossil and nuclear energy research and development for any fiscal year after FY 1997. (Sec. 509) Amends the Arms Export Control Act to provide for recoupment of nonrecurring costs for certain sales of major defense equipment. Excludes from recoupment the sale of major defense equipment that is at least 90 percent paid for from funds transferred under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 or from funds made available on a grant or other nonrepayable basis under such Act. Amends the Arms Export Control Act to eliminate the authority to reduce or waive charges for costs in foreign military sales for NATO member countries and certain other countries. Title VI: Effective Dates - Sets forth effective date provisions.</summary>
</bill>
