<bill session="108" type="h" number="3826" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Program Assessment and Results Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Program Assessment and Results Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the review of Government programs at least once every 5 years for purposes of evaluating their performance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2004-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2004-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E226"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Efficiency and Financial Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-06-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 108-768.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-10-08T16:00:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="474">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 474.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO19" subcommittee="Government Efficiency and Financial Management" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="2898"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2004--Reported to House amended.
(NOTE: This summary reflects language of the bill text as set forth in House Report 108-768, which differs from the language of the official bill text.) Program Assessment and Results Act - (Sec. 3) States as the purposes of this Act: (1) improving the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993 by implementing a process to determine the strengths and weaknesses of Federal programs, with a particular focus on results produced by individual programs; (2) using information to help the executive branch make informed management decisions and evidence-based funding requests; (3) providing Congress with the information necessary to conduct more effective oversight and make better-informed authorization and spending decisions. (Sec. 4) Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to the maximum extent practicable to conduct, jointly with agencies of the Federal Government, an assessment of each Federal program at least once every five fiscal years (program assessments). Requires the Director to: (1) coordinate with Federal agency heads to determine the programs to be assessed and to evaluate the purpose, design, strategic plan, management, and results of such programs; (2) develop criteria for identifying programs to be assessed each fiscal year; (3) assess certain higher priority programs more frequently than once every five years; (4) publish in electronic format and provide to Congress a list of programs to be assessed during a fiscal year and the criteria to be used to assess the programs, and allow interested person to comment on such programs; and (5) provide guidance to Federal agency heads for implementing the requirements of this Act. Requires the Director to report to Congress the results of program assessments conducted during a fiscal year at the same time the President submits the next budget after the end of such fiscal year. Provides for the submission of program assessments containing classified information. Requires that program assessment activities be performed only by Federal employees as inherently Governmental functions. Terminates program assessments after September 30, 2013. (Sec. 5) Changes: (1) the date by which the heads of each Federal agency are required to submit strategic plans for program activities to September 30 of each year following a presidential election, beginning with September 30, 2005; and (2) the period of coverage for strategic plans from five to four years.</summary>
</bill>
