<bill session="107" type="h" number="4586" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Brownfields Use Invigoration Land Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act and the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to authorize grants and other assistance to promote the redevelopment of certain remediated sites.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="2002-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2002-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2002-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2002-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2002-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="2002-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Brownfields"/>
    <term name="Community development corporations"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Marketing research"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2002--Introduced.
Brownfields Use Invigoration Land Development Act - Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make grants to a small business, a local organization that represents small businesses, or a local redevelopment agency chartered, established, or otherwise sanctioned by a State or local government to participate in the redevelopment of remediated sites (real property with respect to which requirements under Federal or State law for the remediation of hazardous substances, pollutants, and contaminants have been completed). Sets a maximum per-grant limit of $200,000. Increases to 90 percent of the amount of the outstanding financing the level of SBA participation in guaranteed loans made to small businesses on a deferred basis for small businesses located or locating on a remedial site.Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to: (1) authorize the SBA to provide assistance to State development companies for projects for the redevelopment of remediated sites; and (2) exempt from current outstanding leverage limits small business investment company investments in remediated sites.</summary>
</bill>
