<bill session="107" type="h" number="4170" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State Cooperative Health Care Access Plan Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for cooperative governing of health insurance policies by primary and secondary States and to provide assistance to States to promote the establishment of qualified high risk pools, to provide financial incentives to encourage health coverage for employees and individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="2002-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2002-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2002-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400212" joined="2002-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-11">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2002--Introduced.
State Cooperative Health Care Access Plan Act of 2002 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to set forth requirements for the cooperative governing of health insurance policies across States, including the establishment of high risk pools.Requires a health insurance issuer to follow the laws of the State of its primary business location (primary State) for a policy: (1) when filed and approved by such State; and (2) even when it is offered in a secondary State (all other States).Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to fund: (1) mechanisms for enforcement, including consumer fraud, and information exchange; and (2) matching grants to States according to a specified formula for the creation of qualified high risk pools.Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code to exclude small employer reimbursements to employees for the purchase of health insurance coverage in the individual market from the definition of "group health plan."Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) provide a refundable credit for specified qualified health coverage costs; (2) establish a program for making advance payments for health care coverage on behalf of eligible individuals; (3) allow full deductibility of health care coverage costs, subject to specified limitations; (4) allow carryover of unused benefits from cafeteria plans or flexible spending arrangements; and (5) treat amounts paid under a flexible spending plan for qualified health coverage as employer-provided coverage.</summary>
</bill>
