<bill session="104" type="h" number="1613" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Jesse Gray Housing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the United States Housing Act of 1937 to require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to administer a program of construction and revitalization of public housing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cooperative housing"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/1995--Introduced.
Jesse Gray Housing Act - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to carry out a program to construct new public housing units. Requires the Secretary to make financial assistance available for public housing projects, especially those likely to be disposed of or demolished. Prohibits the Secretary from approving a project demolition application. Requires public housing agencies to carry out job training and employment programs in connection with certain housing construction and revitalization projects. Reduces lower income rent contribution amounts under the National Housing Act, the United States Housing Act of 1937, the Housing Act of 1949, the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965, and the Housing and Urban-Rural Recovery Act of 1983. Excludes welfare or social security cost-of-living adjustments from such adjusted income determinations.</summary>
</bill>
