<bill session="106" type="h" number="3595" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-23T15:13:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-23T15:13:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the authorization of appropriations for the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="2000-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-836.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-12T16:14:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="494">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 494.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-10-23T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gibbons moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-23T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H10519-10520" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-23T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3595.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-10-23T15:13:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H10520" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-23T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Earthquake engineering"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/2000--Passed House amended.
Amends the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to: (1) delete a provision which included modification costs resulting from the nonperformance of reasonable dam structure maintenance as project costs reimbursable to the operating entity; (2) make reimbursable with respect to additional funds authorized to be appropriated by amendments made to the Act in 2000 costs incurred in the modification of structures resulting from new hydrologic or seismic data or changes in dam safety criteria; (3) include as reimbursable those costs allocated to irrigation without regard to the water users' ability to pay; (4) authorize the Secretary of the Interior to pay reimbursable costs pursuant to a repayment contract at any time prior to completion of construction; (5) extend through FY 2000 the authorization of appropriations for the above costs; and (6) decrease from 60 to 30 days after the Secretary has submitted a report on an existing dam the required waiting period before funds can be obligated to carry out actual construction to modify such dam.Requires the Secretary, before selecting a reclamation facility for modification, to notify project beneficiaries and solicit their participation in evaluating such modification. Authorizes the Secretary to negotiate agreements with such beneficiaries for the cooperative oversight of planning, design, cost containment, procurement, construction, and management of the modifications. Requires the Secretary to consider and, where appropriate, implement alternatives recommended by such beneficiaries (requiring the Secretary to respond to such recommendations within 30 days). Requires the Secretary to provide to requesting beneficiaries information concerning the status and costs of such modifications.</summary>
</bill>
