<bill session="107" type="h" number="5447" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Women Discharged From the Military Due to Pregnancy Relief Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To express the remorse of Congress for the policy of the Department of Defense in effect until 1976 providing for involuntary separation of female members of the Armed Forces who became pregnant while in service and to take certain steps to make amends for the effects of that policy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400513"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2002-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women soldiers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2002--Introduced.
Women Discharged From the Military Due to Pregnancy Relief Act of 2002 - Expresses the sense of Congress that women who served in the U.S. armed forces before February 23, 1976, should not have been involuntarily discharged due to pregnancy and expresses remorse for the women who endured unnecessary and discriminatory actions because they became pregnant while a member of the armed forces.Requires the Secretary of Defense to identify and pay each woman who was so discharged or separated between June 12, 1948, and February 23, 1976, an amount equal to the total pay and allowances that would have been due had such person not been involuntarily discharged.Directs the Secretary of Education to provide for the discharge or cancellation of the Federal student loan indebtedness of an offspring who was the cause of such a woman's discharge or separation.Makes health benefits provided as a result of military service available to such women and offspring.Requires the Secretary of Defense to establish a single standard discharge code for such women.Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense should establish policies to encourage such women to continue to serve the Nation.</summary>
</bill>
