<bill session="105" type="h" number="1760" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Television Viewing Information and Empowerment Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for the implementation of systems for rating the specific content of specific television programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1998-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="607"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="High definition television"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Television and children"/>
    <term name="Television frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Violence in television"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/1997--Introduced.
Family Television Viewing Information and Empowerment Act of 1997 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) from granting or renewing a license for a broadcast television station unless the license applicant submits to the FCC evidence of: (1) a plan for the implementation of a rating system for the content of programming to be broadcast by such station, in the case of a license grant application; or (2) the current implementation of such a rating system, in the case of application for license renewal. Prohibits the FCC from assigning transitional digital television frequencies to a broadcast television station unless the person licensed to operate such station submits to the FCC evidence of the implementation of a rating system. Directs the FCC to require a person assigned such frequencies, before the enactment of this Act, to surrender them to the FCC if the person does not submit to it evidence of the implementation of a rating system before using the frequencies. Outlines general and specific rating system elements, requiring FCC review of each such system.</summary>
</bill>
