<bill session="104" type="hr" number="503" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-08-02T10:11:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-08-02T10:11:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 3448) to provide tax relief for small businesses, to protect jobs, to create opportunities, to increase the take home pay of workers, to amend the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 relating to the payment of wages to employees who use employer owned vehicles, and to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to increase the minimum wage rate and to prevent job loss by providing flexibility to employers in complying with minimum wage and overtime requirements under that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-08-01T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-739, by Mr. Solomon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-01T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 3448. Upon adoption of this resolution all points of order against the conference report accompanying the bill and against its consideration shall be waived. The conference report shall be considered as read when called up.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-08-01T13:25:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="268">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 268.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T09:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9839-9846" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T09:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T10:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-08-02T10:11:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T10:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="3448"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/1996--Introduced.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the conference report on H.R. 3448 (small business income tax revisions and minimum wage increase).</summary>
</bill>
