<bill session="104" type="h" number="3752" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-26T18:58:00-04:00">PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-09-26T18:58:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Land Sovereignty Protection Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">American Land Sovereignty Protection Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To preserve the sovereignty of the United States over public lands and acquired lands owned by the United States, and to preserve State sovereignty and private property rights in non-Federal lands surrounding those public lands and acquired lands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="401587" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1996-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="403015" joined="1996-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="1996-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1996-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1996-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1996-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="1996-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1996-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="406343" joined="1996-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400510" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="1996-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1996-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400534" joined="1996-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="410067" joined="1996-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1996-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1996-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400398" joined="1996-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411178" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="1996-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1190"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-08">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-12">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 18 - 8.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24T21:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 104-835.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-09-24T21:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="456">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 456.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T14:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T14:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11273-11280, H11354" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T14:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T15:14:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="1996-09-26T18:58:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="442" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 246 - 178 (Roll no. 442).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States' rights"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/1996--Reported to House amended.
American Land Sovereignty Protection Act of 1996 - Amends the National Historic Preservation Act Amendments of 1980 to prohibit the Secretary of the Interior from nominating any Federal lands for inclusion on the World Heritage List pursuant to the Convention Concerning the Protection of the World Cultural and Natural Heritage unless such nomination is specifically authorized by law. Authorizes the Secretary to submit proposals for legislation authorizing such a nomination. Requires the Secretary to object to the inclusion of any property in the United States on the list of World Heritage in Danger (established under the Convention) unless the Secretary: (1) has submitted to specified congressional officials a report describing the necessity for such inclusion; and (2) is specifically authorized to assent to the inclusion by a joint resolution of the Congress enacted after the report is submitted. Requires the Secretary to report annually to the Chairman and Ranking Minority Member of specified congressional committees on each World Heritage Site within the United States regarding: (1) an accounting of all money expended to manage the Site; (2) a summary of Federal full time equivalent hours related to its management; (3) a list and explanation of all nongovernmental organizations contributing to such management; and (4) a summary and account of the disposition of complaints received by the Secretary related to it. (Sec. 4) Amends the National Historic Preservation Act Amendments of 1980 to prohibit Federal officials from nominating lands in the United States for designation as a Biosphere Reserve under the Man and Biosphere Program of the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization. Provides that such designation of an area in the United States shall not have, and shall not be given, any force or effect, unless the Biosphere Reserve: (1) is specifically authorized by a law enacted before December 31, 1999; (2) consists solely of federally-owned lands; and (3) is subject to a management plan that specifically ensures that the use of intermixed or adjacent non-Federal property is not limited or restricted as a result of that designation. Requires the Secretary of State to report annually to the Chairman and Ranking Minority Member of specified congressional committees on each Biosphere Reserve within the United States regarding: (1) an accounting of all money expended to manage the Reserve; (2) a summary of Federal full time equivalent hours related to its management; (3) a list and explanation of all nongovernmental organizations contributing to such management; and (4) a summary and account of the disposition of complaints received by the Secretary related to it. (Sec. 5) Prohibits, under any international agreement, the nomination, classification, or designation of: (1) federally-owned lands located within the United States for a special or restricted use unless authorized by law; (2) State or local government lands unless authorized by State or local law; or (3) privately owned lands without the owner's consent. Provides that such prohibition shall not apply to: (1) sites nominated under the Convention on Wetlands of International Importance Especially as Waterfowl Habitat (popularly known as the Ramsar Convention); (2) agreements established under the North American Wetlands Conservation Act; and (3) conventions referred to in the Fish and Wildlife Improvement Act of 1978.</summary>
</bill>
