<bill session="104" type="h" number="3723" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-10-11">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Economic Espionage Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Economic Espionage Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Economic Espionage Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to protect proprietary economic information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404996" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1996-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-09-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-16T12:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Livingston asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Judiciary have until 5:00 p.m. on Sept. 16 to file a report on H.R. 3723. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-16T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 104-788.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-09-16T17:24:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="426">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 426.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T15:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Buyer moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10460-10462, H10494-10495" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Buyer objected to the Yea - Nay vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-09-17T18:52:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="416" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 399 - 3 (Roll no. 416).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T18:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10882-10885" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 5384 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Specter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 5385 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Grassley to Amendment SP 5384.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 5385 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 5386 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Hatch to Amendment SP 5384.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 5386 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 5387 proposed by Senator Stevens for Senator Hatch to Amendment SP 5384.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 5387 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Amendment SP 5384 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1996-09-18" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28T22:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McCollum asked unanimous consent that the House agree with an amendment to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-09-28T22:51:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree with an amendment to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12137-12145" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28T22:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-30">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-02">
      <text>Senate agreed to the House amendment to the Senate amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12201-12216" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-10-02">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1996-10-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-10-04">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-10-11">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-10-11" type="public" number="104-294">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-294.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2538"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="982"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1331"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1332"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Business intelligence"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Cryptography"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Extortion"/>
    <term name="Extraterritoriality"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insanity defense"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Pleas (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Psychiatric hospitals"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rights of institutionalized persons"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5384"/>
    <amendment number="s5385"/>
    <amendment number="s5386"/>
    <amendment number="s5387"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/28/1996--House agreed to Senate amendment with amendment.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Protection of Trade Secrets Title II: National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996 Title III: Transfer of Persons Found Not Guilty By Reason of Insanity Title IV: Establishment of Boys and Girls Clubs Title V: Use of Certain Technology to Facilitate Criminal Conduct Title VI: Technical and Minor Amendments Economic Espionage Act of 1996 - Title I: Protection of Trade Secrets - Amends the Federal criminal code to prescribe penalties to be imposed on any person or organization that knowingly commits one of the following offenses, either intending or knowing that it will benefit any foreign government, instrumentality, or agent, or intending to convert a trade secret to the economic benefit of anyone other than the owner with the knowledge that the offense will injure the owner: (1) stealing or otherwise fraudulently obtaining a trade secret; (2) copying or conveying a trade secret without authorization; (3) receiving, buying, or possessing a trade secret, knowing it has been obtained or converted without authorization; or (4) attempting or conspiring to commit such an offense. Sets forth provisions regarding criminal forfeiture, civil proceedings to enjoin violations, conduct outside the United States, and non-preemption of other remedies under Federal, State, commonwealth, possession, or territory law. Directs: (1) the court to preserve the confidentiality of trade secrets; and (2) the Attorney General to report to the Congress on the amounts received and distributed from fines for offenses under this title deposited in the Crime Victims Fund. (Sec. 102) Permits the Attorney General to authorize an application for, and a Federal judge to grant, an order authorizing interception of wire, oral, or electronic communications, in cases involving protection of trade secrets. Title II: National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996 - Revises Federal criminal code provisions regarding fraud and related activity in connection with computers. Sets penalties with respect to anyone who having knowingly accessed a computer without authorization or exceeding authorized access, obtains specified restricted information or data and, with reason to believe that such information could be used to the injury of the United States or to the advantage of any foreign nation, willfully communicates, delivers, or transmits it to any person not entitled to receive it (or causes or attempts such communication) or willfully retains it and fails to deliver it to the U.S. officer or employee entitled to receive it. Sets penalties for: (1) intentionally accessing a computer without authorization or exceeding authorized access and thereby obtaining information from any U.S. department or agency, or from any protected computer if the conduct involved an interstate or foreign communication; (2) intentionally accessing, without authorization, any computer of a U.S. department or agency that is exclusively for use by or for the U.S. Government or, in the case of a computer not exclusively for such use, that is used by or for the U.S. Government if such conduct affects the use of the Government's operation of such computer; (3) knowingly, and with intent to defraud, accessing a protected computer without authorization or exceeding authorized access and furthering the intended fraud and obtaining anything of value, unless the object of the fraud and the thing obtained consists only of the use of the computer and the value of such use is not more than $5,000 in any one-year period; (4) knowingly causing the transmission of a program, information, code, or command and, as a result, intentionally causing damage without authorization to a protected computer, intentionally accessing a protected computer without authorization and recklessly causing damage, or intentionally accessing a protected computer without authorization and causing damage; and (5) transmitting in interstate or foreign commerce any communication containing a threat to cause damage to a protected computer with intent to extort from any person or legal entity any thing of value. Increases penalties for fraud and related activity in connection with computers. Title III: Transfer of Persons Found Not Guilty By Reason of Insanity - Authorizes: (1) the transfer of individuals who have been found not guilty by reason of insanity and who have been committed to a hospital for the mentally ill under the District of Columbia Code and for whom the United States has a continuing financial responsibility to the custody of the Attorney General for treatment in a suitable facility, unless the court finds that the proposed transfer would violate a right of such person under the Constitution; and (2) the Attorney General to establish custody over such persons, subject to specified requirements. Provides for the transfer of records from the District of Columbia and St. Elizabeth's Hospital to the Attorney General. Title IV: Establishment of Boys and Girls Clubs - Requires the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance of the Department of Justice to provide grants to the Boys and Girls Clubs of America to establish Boys and Girls Clubs in public housing projects and other distressed areas. Sets forth reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations. Allows sums authorized to be appropriated to be made available from the Violent Crime Reduction Trust Fund. Title V: Use of Certain Technology to Facilitate Criminal Conduct - Directs: (1) the Administrative Office of the United States courts to establish policies and procedures for the inclusion in all presentence reports of information that specifically identifies and describes any use of encryption or scrambling technology that would be relevant to an enhancement under provisions regarding obstructing or impeding the administration of justice of, or to offense conduct under, the Sentencing Guidelines; and (2) the United States Sentencing Commission to compile and analyze any information contained in such documentation relating to such use and to report annually to the Congress on the nature and extent of the use of such technology to facilitate or conceal criminal conduct. Title VI: Technical and Minor Amendments - Makes technical and minor amendments (such as changing the amounts of fines) to the Federal criminal code, the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994, and other Federal law. Amends mandatory victim restitution provisions of the code to authorize the court to order restitution to persons other than the victim of the offense if agreed to by the parties in a plea agreement. (Sec. 602) Repeals specified obsolete provisions of the code. (Sec. 606) Adjusts and makes uniform certain dollar amounts used in the code to distinguish between grades of offenses. (Sec. 607) Applies various offenses under the code and the Controlled Substances Act to U.S. possessions and territories.</summary>
</bill>
