<bill session="106" type="hr" number="210" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-22T16:24:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-06-22T16:24:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 659) to authorize appropriations for the protection of Paoli and Brandywine Battlefields in Pennsylvania, to direct the National Park Service to conduct a special resource study of Paoli and Brandywine Battlefields, to authorize the Valley Forge Museum of the American Revolution at Valley Forge National Historical Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-06-16T00:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-187, by Mr. Hastings (WA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-16T00:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 659 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill, the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Resources now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-06-16T00:49:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="70">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 70.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-06-22T16:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4698-4700" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-22T16:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 210.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1999-06-22T16:24:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-06-22T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="659"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="659"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/1999--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 659 (Paoli and Brandywine Battlefields and the Valley Forge National Historical Park).</summary>
</bill>
