<bill session="105" type="h" number="116" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Junk gun bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gun Safety Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To apply equal standards to certain foreign made and domestically produced handguns.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Firearms injuries"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Gun Safety Act - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit the transfer or possession of a junk gun that has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce. Defines a "junk gun" as any firearm that does not meet specified criteria for authorization by the Secretary of the Treasury for importation into the United States. Makes such provision inapplicable to: (1) the possession or transfer of any junk gun otherwise lawfully possessed under Federal law on the date of this Act's enactment; (2) any firearm or replica of a firearm that has been rendered permanently inoperative; (3) the transfer to, or possession by, the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State or a transfer to or possession by a law enforcement officer employed by such an entity for law enforcement purposes (whether on or off duty); or (4) the transfer or possession of a junk gun by a licensed manufacturer or licensed importer for the purposes of testing or experimentation authorized by the Secretary of the Treasury. Prohibits the manufacture or importation of a firearm that does not have as an integral part a device or devices that: (1) prevent a child under age seven from discharging it; (2) prevent a firearm that has a removable magazine from discharging when the magazine has been removed; and (3) in the case of a handgun other than a revolver, clearly indicate whether the magazine or chamber contains a round of ammunition. Makes an exception for the manufacture or importation of a firearm by or for the United States or a State. Sets penalties for violations.</summary>
</bill>
