<bill session="106" type="h" number="2131" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Taking Our Property Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to prohibit the imposition under that Act of any requirement to mitigate for the impacts of activities that occurred in the past.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4029"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public works"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1999--Introduced.
Stop Taking Our Property Act of 1999 - Amends the Endangered Species Act to provide that mitigation of effects on endangered or threatened species or critical habitat shall not be required for any covered agency action and the Secretary of the Interior or Commerce, as appropriate, may not require compliance with specified measures to mitigate impacts of any activity that occurred before the date of such action. Prohibits the Endangered Species Committee from establishing any mitigation and enhancement measures for such actions to mitigate impacts of any activity that occurred before the date of such an action. Defines "covered agency action" as any construction activity carried out or funded by a Federal agency and the issuance by a Federal agency of a permit that would authorize a State or local construction activity. Prohibits the Secretary from requiring a permittee for a public project to take any measures to mitigate impacts of an incidental taking of an endangered species or other activity that occurred before the date of issuance of the permit.</summary>
</bill>
