<bill session="107" type="h" number="5733" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Diplomacy Enhancement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to ensure that projects and activities carried out with United States assistance are appropriately identified overseas as "American Aid", and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400361"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2002--Introduced.
Public Diplomacy Enhancement Act of 2002 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to require that certain projects and activities that are partly or wholly funded by the United States under the Act, including development assistance and assistance to the independent states of the former Soviet Union, be identified in English and the appropriate local language as "American Aid" or "Assistance from the People of the United States" (Current law requires programs under the Act to be identified appropriately overseas as "American Aid"). Applies this Act to projects and activities under the Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989.Specifies examples of methods of complying with this Act, including use of print or broadcast media at the local, national, and regional levels. Requires the relevant contractors or aid recipients to provide plans to the United States describing how they will comply with the identification requirement under this Act. Permits a waiver of the identification requirement if complying would have an adverse impact on the objectives of a project or activity.</summary>
</bill>
