<bill session="104" type="h" number="2253" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Endangered Species Community Advisory Board Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to create a mechanism by which information may flow between local communities and governments and the Federal Government regarding the designation of critical habitat and the establishment of National Wildlife Refuges under that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400516"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-09">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1995--Introduced.
Endangered Species Community Advisory Board Act of 1995 - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish an Endangered Species Community Advisory Board in connection with the designation of an area under the Act as critical habitat or as a National Wildlife Refuge. Allows the Secretary, subject to the availability of appropriations, to make funds available to facilitate the participation of individuals from the private sector on such Boards to ensure public input into the designation of such areas or Refuges. Requires the Board to: (1) monitor and periodically report to the Secretary on progress made in the conservation and recovery of species for which the critical habitat or Refuge was designated; and (2) periodically review and report to the Secretary regarding the continued accuracy and sufficiency of the scientific findings that were the basis of such designation.</summary>
</bill>
