<bill session="108" type="h" number="1308" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Extend Tax Cuts bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Increased Child Tax Credit bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax Relief, Simplification, and Equity Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Tax Relief, Simplification, and Equity Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Relief for Working Families Tax Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Working Families Tax Relief Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to end certain abusive tax practices, to provide tax relief and simplification, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to enhance fairness in the internal revenue laws, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An act to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax relief for working families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19T11:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19T11:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1970-1976" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19T11:20:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-03-19T11:36:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1970-1974" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19T11:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-03-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="52">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 52.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7449-7459" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2003-06-05" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7456-7459" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Grassley; Nickles; Lott; Baucus; Lincoln.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>House agreed to Senate amendment to the title. House agreed to Senate amendment to the text with an amendment pursuant to H. Res. 270.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5330-5342" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5330-5335" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas moved that the House insist upon its amendment to the Senate amendment, and request a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House insist upon its amendment to the Senate amendment, and request a conference Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rangel moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5335-5336" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Rangel motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the managers on the part of the House to include in the conference report the provision of the Senate amendment that provides immediate payments to taxpayers receiving an additional credit by reason of the bill; the provision of the Senate amendment that provides families of military personnel serving in Iraq, Afghanistan, and other combat zones a child credit based on the earnings of the individuals serving in the combat zone; all of the other provisions of the Senate amendment and shall not report back a conference report that includes additional tax benefits not offset by other provisions; and to include, to the maximum extent possible, within the scope of the conference, other tax benefits for military personnel and the families of the astronauts who died</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 205 - 201 (Roll no. 275).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees for consideration of the House amendment and the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Thomas, DeLay, and Rangel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-16">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendments to Senate amendments and House requests a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-18">
      <text>Senate disagreed to House amendments, agreed to request for conference, and appointed conferees. Grassley; Nickles; Lott; Baucus; Lincoln.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8013" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>NOTICE OF MOTION TO INSTRUCT - Mr. Michaud formally notified the House of his intention to offer a motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. DeLauro moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6826-6834" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6826" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the DeLauro motion to instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House continued with debate on the DeLauro motion to instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T19:57:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeLauro motion to instruct conferees, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Weller demanded the yeas and nays and the Speaker pro tempore postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the motion until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 206 - 220 (Roll no. 370).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6903-6904" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T19:44:00-04:00">
      <text>NOTIFICATION OF MOTION TO INSTRUCT - Mr. Bell formally notified the House of his intention to offer a motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Michaud moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6985-6990" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Michaud motion to instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T20:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T20:43:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Michaud motion to instruct conferees, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Michaud demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the motion until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-17T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>NOTIFICATION OF MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES - Mr. Van Hollen notified the House of his intention to offer a motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-17T23:57:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 202 - 214 (Roll no. 390).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/18/2003 H7105-7106" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 7/16/2003 H6985" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-17T23:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18T00:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bell moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7106-7112" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7106-7107" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18T00:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Bell motion to instruct conferees to H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18T00:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18T00:51:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Bell motion to instruct conferees the Chair put the question on the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Bell asked for the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion to instruct until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 188 - 201 (Roll no. 396).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7147-7148" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Van Hollen moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7158-7162" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Van Hollen motion to instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18T16:56:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Van Hollen motion to instruct conferees the Chair put the question on the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Van Hollen asked for the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion to instruct until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-21T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 193 - 212 (Roll no. 398).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7158" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-21T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22T22:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ross moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22T22:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Ross motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22T23:22:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Ross motion to instruct conferees, the Speaker put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ross demanded the yeas and nays and the Speaker postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the motion until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24T01:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bishop (NY) moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7611-7612" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24T01:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Bishop (NY) motion to instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24T02:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Bishop (NY) motion to instruct conferees, the Speaker put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Bishop (NY) demanded the yeas and nays and the Speaker postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the motion until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T01:00:00-04:00">
      <text>MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES - Ms. Solis notified the House of her intention to offer a motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T02:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ross moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T02:59:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 202 - 214 (Roll no. 446).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T02:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T09:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Solis moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7622-7630" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T09:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Solis motion to instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T10:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T10:25:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Solis motion to instruct conferees, the Speaker put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Solis demanded the yeas and nays and the Speaker postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the motion until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T12:34:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 206 - 216 (Roll no. 447).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7644" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T12:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T12:49:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 202 - 221 (Roll no. 449).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7645-7646" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T12:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04T20:58:00-04:00">
      <text>NOTICE OF INTENT TO OFFER MOTION TO INSTRUCT - Mr. Ruppersberger notified the House of his intent to offer a motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04T22:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cooper moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H7922, H7930-7936" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H7930-7931" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04T22:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Cooper motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04T23:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04T23:00:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cooper motion to instruct conferees, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cooper demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the motion until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-05T09:39:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 186 - 210 (Roll no. 477).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H7954" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-05T09:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-05T14:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ruppersberger moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H7995-8001" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H7995-7996" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-05T14:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Ruppersberger motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-05T15:39:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-05T15:39:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ruppersberger motion, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ruppersberger demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the motion until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-09T21:21:00-04:00">
      <text>NOTICE OF MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES - Mr. Davis of Tennessee notified the House of his intention to offer a motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 206 - 213 (Roll no. 493).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8117" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T21:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis (TN) moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/11/2003 H8178-8182, H8190" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 9/11/2003  H8178" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T21:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Davis (TN) motion to instruct conferees which was noticed in the Congressional Record on Tuesday, September 9, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T21:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T21:38:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on the Davis (TN) motion to instruct, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Davis (TN) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the motion until later in the legislative day</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T23:09:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 195 - 214 (Roll no. 501).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T23:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-16T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>NOTICE MOTION TO INSTRUCT CONFEREES - Mr. Ryan of Ohio notified the House of his intention to offer a motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-17T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ryan (OH) moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8359-8361" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8359" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-17T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Ryan (OH) motion to instruct conferees which was noticed in the Congressional Record on Tuesday, September 16, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-17T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-17T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on the Ryan (OH) motion to instruct, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Ryan (OH) demanded the yeas and nays and pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the motion until Tuesday, September 23, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 199 - 214 (Roll no. 509).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8464-8465" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>NOTICE OF INTENT TO OFFER MOTION TO INSTRUCT - Mr. Pallone notified the House of his intent to offer a motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pallone moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8930-8935" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8930" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Pallone motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pallone motion to instruct conferees, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Pallone demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the motion until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-30T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 202 - 207 (Roll no. 525).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8990" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-30T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01T13:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis (AL) moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9067-9071" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9067" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01T13:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Davis (AL) motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01T14:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01T14:01:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At conclusion of debate on the Davis (AL) motion to instruct conferees, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Davis (AL) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the motion until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 207 - 219 (Roll no. 529).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9072-9073" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08T17:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crowley moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9346-9349" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9346" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08T17:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Crowley motion to instruct conferees which was noticed in the Congressional Record on Tuesday, October 7, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08T17:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08T17:26:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL VOTE - At the conclusion debate on the Crowley motion to instruct conferees, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Crowley demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the motion until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 203 - 204 (Roll no. 541).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9441" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Woolsey moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9784-9787" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9784" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Woolsey motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Woolsey motion to instruct conferees, the Speaker put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Woolsey demanded the yeas and nays and the Speaker postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the motion until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-28T19:48:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 208 (Roll no. 572).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9966-9967" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-28T19:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-05T19:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Becerra moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10434-10438" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H10434" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-05T19:27:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Becerra motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-05T20:02:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-05T20:03:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Becerra motion to instruct conferees, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Becerra demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the motion until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-06T16:31:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 207 (Roll no. 614).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10511-10512" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-06T16:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T19:22:00-04:00">
      <text>NOTICE OF INTENT TO OFFER MOTION TO INSTRUCT - Mr. Stenholm notified the House of his intention to offer a motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the managers on the part of the House to agree, to the maximum extent possible within the scope of conference, to a conference report that---(1) extends the tax relief provisions which expire at the end of 2004, and (2) does not increase the Federal budget deficit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20T19:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Stenholm moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H6101-6104" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20T19:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Stenholm motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20T19:46:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Stenholm motion to instruct the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Stenholm demanded the yeas and nays and made a point of no quorum. The Chair postponed further proceedings on the question and the point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22T21:21:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 198 - 222 (Roll no. 421).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6677-6678" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22T21:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08T18:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hill moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6859-6865" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08T18:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Hill motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the managers on the part of the House to agree, to the maximum extent possible within the scope of conference, to a conference report that (1) extends the tax relief provisions which expire at the end of 2004, and (2) does not increase the Federal budget deficit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08T19:28:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Hill motion to instruct conferees, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hill demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the motion until Thursday, September 9, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-09T12:18:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 203 - 216 (Roll no. 432).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6921" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-09T12:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Moore moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7399-7404" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7399" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the motion to instruct conferees, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Moore demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until Thursday, September 23, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-23">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-23T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 108-696 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7479-7509" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-23T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 794 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 1308. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-23T17:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 794 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-23T17:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas brought up conference report H. Rept. 108-696 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 794.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7531-7540" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-23T17:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report on H.R. 1308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-23T19:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="2004-09-23T19:27:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="472" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by recorded vote: 339 - 65 (Roll no. 472).</text>
    </vote>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2004-09-23" how="roll" result="pass" roll="188" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 92 - 3. Record Vote Number: 188.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9560-9580" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2004-09-23">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-10-04">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2004-10-04" type="public" number="108-311">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-311.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="hr" number="270"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="hr" number="270"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="794"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="5395"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="3019"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Astronautics"/>
    <term name="Astronauts"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional joint committees"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Cooperative societies"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Debt"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Depletion allowances"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Droughts"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Expatriation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hepatitis"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Joint Taxation"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medical savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Missing children"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Options (Contract)"/>
    <term name="Orphan drugs"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Real estate investment"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Research and development tax credit"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Separation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Sheltered workshops"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Support of dependents"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax auditing"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban economic development"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Weather"/>
    <term name="Welfare work participation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
    <term name="Working poor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s862"/>
    <amendment number="s863"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/4/2004--Public Law.
Working Families Tax Relief Act of 2004 - Title I: Extension of Family Tax Provisions - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (Code) to repeal: (1) the scheduled reductions, in 2005 through 2009, of the $1,000 child tax credit; (2) the scheduled reductions, in 2005 through 2008, of the standard deduction for married taxpayers; (3) the scheduled reductions, in 2005 through 2007, of the threshold taxable income level applicable to married taxpayers eligible for the 15 percent tax bracket; (4) the reduction, for taxable years between 2005 and 2008, of the threshold taxable income level applicable to married taxpayers eligible for the ten percent tax bracket. Provides for an inflation adjustment to the threshold taxable income level for the ten percent tax bracket. (Sec. 102) Repeals the scheduled reduction (15 to 10 percent) for taxable years beginning before January 1, 2005, of the refundability of the child tax credit. (Sec. 103) Extends through 2005 the increased exemption from the alternative minimum tax for individual taxpayers. (Sec. 104) Treats combat zone compensation (otherwise excludable from gross income) as earned income for purposes of calculating the refundable portion of the child tax credit. Allows taxpayers to elect, in 2004 and 2005, to treat combat zone compensation as earned income for purposes of the earned income tax credit. (Sec. 105) Provides that the amendments made by this title shall be subject to the sunset provisions of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 (i.e., December 31, 2010). Title II: Uniform Definition of Child - Redefines "dependent" to mean: (1) a qualifying child; or (2) a qualifying relative, for purposes of applying the dependency exemption, the child tax credit, the earned income tax credit, the dependent care tax credit, and the head of household filing status. Sets forth a test for determining whether a child is a qualifying child based upon: (1) relationship of the child to the taxpayer; (2) residence of the child with the taxpayer for for more than one-half of the taxable year; and (3) age of the child. Sets forth a similar test for qualifying relatives. Sets forth exceptions and special rules applicable to: (1) handicapped dependents; (2) divorced parents; (3) adopted children; and (4) missing children. Title III: Extensions of Certain Expiring Provisions - Extends through 2005 the following expiring tax provisions: (1) the tax credit for increasing research activities; (2) the work opportunity tax credit; (3) the welfare-to-work tax credit; (4) the authority for issuance of qualified zone academy bonds; (5) the charitable deduction for donations by corporations of computer technology and equipment used for educational purposes; (6) the tax deduction for certain expenses of elementary and secondary school teachers; (7) the expensing of environmental remediation costs; (8) the designation of a District of Columbia enterprise zone, the authority to issue tax-exempt economic development bonds within a District of Columbia Enterprise Zone, the exclusion of gain from the sale or exchange of a District of Columbia Enterprise Zone asset held for more than five years, and the tax credit for first-time District of Columbia home buyers; (9) the authority for disclosures of taxpayer identity information to States under the combined Federal and State employment tax reporting program; (10) the allowance of certain nonrefundable tax credits against income and alternative minimum tax liabilities; (11) the placed-in-service dates relating to certain facilities (i.e., wind, closed-loop biomass, and poultry waste facilities) for purposes of the tax credit for producing electricity from certain renewable resources; (12) the suspension of the taxable income limit on percentage depletion for oil and natural gas from marginal properties; (13) the Indian employment tax credit; (14) accelerated depreciation for certain business property on Indian Reservations; (15) the authority for disclosing certain tax return information to the Department of Education for taxpayers seeking student loan repayment plans based on income; (16) the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to disclose taxpayer return information that may be related to terrorism. Specifies that a taxpayer's identity shall not be treated as nondisclosable taxpayer return information for purposes of disclosures related to terrorism; (17) certain eligibility provisions for Archer medical savings (MSA) accounts. Treats the report of the MSA Trustee due on August 1, 2004, as timely if made before the close of the 90-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act. (Sec. 302) Extends through December 31, 2005, provisions of the Code, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Public Health Service Act requiring parity in the application of group health plan limits to mental health benefits. (Sec. 305) Extends until January 1, 2006, the increased amount ($13.25, instead of $10.50) of excise tax on distilled spirits required to be paid back (covered) to the Treasuries of Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands. (Sec. 309) Extends through 2009 the authority to issue New York Liberty Bonds and, through 2005, advanced refundings for such bonds. (Sec. 318) Eliminates, in 2004 and 2005, the partial phase-out of the tax credit for qualified electric vehicles and the partial phase-out for the tax deduction for clean-fuel vehicle property. (Sec. 321) Extends for an additional year (before June 1, 2005) the annual review and report of the Joint Committee on Taxation of the strategic plans and budget for the Internal Revenue Service. Title IV: Tax Technical Corrections - (Sec. 401) Amends provisions of the Code enacted by the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 to exclude: (1) the additional tax on distributions from health savings accounts not used for qualified medical expenses from the definition of regular tax liability for purposes of determining refundability of tax credit amounts; and (2) amounts distributed from health savings accounts for purposes of determining the allowable amount of the tax credit for health insurance costs. (Sec. 402) Amends provisions of the Code enacted by the Jobs and Growth Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2003 to: (1) provide that the determination of net capital gains, for purposes of determining the amount taxed at the 25 percent tax rate, is made without regard to qualified dividend income; (2) modify holding period requirements for the dividends-received deduction; (3) apply the tax deduction for estate taxes on income in respect of a decedent to qualified dividend income; (4) apply the extraordinary dividend rule to trust and estates; (5) revise provisions relating to the tax treatment of dividends received from a regulated investment company (RIC) or a real estate investment trust (REIT); and (6) extend the period for notifying shareholders of the amount of qualified dividend income distributed by a RIC or a REIT. (Sec. 403) Amends provisions of the Code enacted by the Job Creation and Worker Assistance Act of 2002 relating to: (1) bonus depreciation; (2) net operating loss carryback rules; (3) New York Liberty Zone bonus depreciation and expensing rules; (4) interest rates for defined benefit plan funding requirements; and (5) the tax exclusion for employer-provided adoption assistance. (Sec. 404) Amends provisions of the Code enacted by the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 relating to: (1) Coverdell education savings accounts; (2) the Indian employment tax credit; and (3) tax-qualified retirement plans. (Sec. 405) Amends provisions of the Code enacted by the Community Renewal Tax Relief Act of 2000 to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe regulations relating to the tax treatment of certain securities futures contracts and options. (Sec. 406) Amends provisions of the Code enacted by the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997 relating to: (1) beneficiaries of qualified tuition programs and Coverdell education savings accounts; (2) basis adjustments for qualified zone academy bonds held by S corporations; and (3) the tax treatment of net capital gains under the alternative minimum tax. (Sec. 407) Amends provisions of the Code enacted by the Business Job Protection Act of 1996 to: (1) provide that any increases to the income of a Subchapter S corporation resulting from an audit during the corporation's 120-day post-termination transition period shall not cover losses of the corporation carried over from a previous taxable year; and (2) allow tax-free distributions by an S corporation during the 120-day period only to the extent of any increase in the corporation's accumulated adjustments account resulting from an audit. Provides that the amendments made by this title shall take effect as if included in the Act in which they were originally enacted.</summary>
</bill>
