<bill session="104" type="h" number="3811" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Endangered Species Incentive Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide incentives for the conservation and recovery of endangered species.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400368"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in government"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/1996--Introduced.
Endangered Species Incentive Act of 1996 - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a voluntary conservation agreement for up to five years with any State, Indian tribe, or local government, if requested, with the goal of preventing endangerment. Requires agreements to contain specified information, including: (1) objective, measurable scientific criteria which, if met, would prevent endangerment; (2) a description of actions that will be taken to minimize any adverse social or economic impacts; and (3) a method of monitoring the success of the agreement. Directs the Secretary to establish a Conservation Assistance Fund. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to: (1) seek to work cooperatively with private landowners in the conservation of threatened and endangered species; and (2) establish a Community Assistance Program within each field office of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, a private landowner cooperative agreement program, and voluntary incentive programs for conserving species on private lands. (Sec. 5) Allows habitat conservation plans to cover multiple species or habitats. Directs the Secretary to issue standards and guidelines for the development and approval of such plans. (Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary to provide technical advice and assistance to non-Federal persons who wish to participate in achieving the conservation objectives for a species under the Act. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to: (1) prepare and make publicly available a manual providing guidance to States and local communities regarding the establishment of a community-based recovery planning process; (2) publish reliable and timely information regarding upcoming listings of species, designations of critical habitat, and issuance of recovery plans; (3) provide technical assistance and guidance regarding how to conserve endangered species and their habitats, how the Act affects landowners, and how to obtain permits authorizing incidental takings; and (4) identify and publish, upon the inclusion of a species in a list of endangered species, lists of known activities affecting the species or its habitat that are and are not prohibited under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
