<bill session="106" type="h" number="4578" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-11">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2001, Interior</title>
    <title type="popular">Interior Department FY2001 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Boise Laboratory Replacement Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Cabin User Fee Fairness Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">First Ladies National Historic Site Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">National Underground Railroad Freedom Center Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Palace of the Governors Annex Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Wheeling National Heritage Area Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Department of the Interior and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400334"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-06-01T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-646, by Mr. Regula.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-01T15:04:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="356">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 356.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-12T20:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 524 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4578 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-13T21:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 524 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-13T21:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 524.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4314-4320" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-13T21:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4578 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-13T21:52:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 524 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-13T21:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steven C. LaTourette to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-13T21:52:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4578.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-13T22:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4578 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-14T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4437-4480" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-14T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-14T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sununu demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 524, the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-14T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hefley demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 524, the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-14T18:15:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that proceedings would resume on the question of adoption of amendments debated earlier and on which recorded votes had been demanded.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-14T19:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Hansen stated that the provisos on page 18, beginning on line 6 and ending on line 19, sought to impose new duties on the Secretary of Interior and as such, sought to change existing law and constituted legislation on an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-14T20:03:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED CONSIDERATION - Mr. Regula asked unanimous consent that all debate and votes on the Dicks amendment and all amendments thereto, be put aside without prejudice until after 9:30 p.m. today. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-14T20:39:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. DeFazio demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 524, the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-14T22:00:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Wu demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 524, the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-14T22:07:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the Committee would proceed with the unfinished business of the question of adoption of two amendments debated earlier and on which recorded votes had been requested.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-14T23:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4578 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T10:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4498-4585" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T10:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T10:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement reached on Wednesday, the Committee of the Whole will proceed with an opening statement by Mr. Dicks on behalf of his amendment and a time limitation of one hour of debate on each of subsequent amendments to the Dicks amendment, if offered by Mr. Nethercutt and Mr. Hansen.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T10:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Nethercutt amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T12:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee is considering the bill under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T12:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Hansen amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T14:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Stearns amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Stearns demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 524, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Dicks demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 524, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T16:43:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier in the day and on which recorded votes had been requested.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T17:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Failed by recorded vote: 183 - 218 (Roll no. 284).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4540-4541" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T18:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Royce demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 524, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Regula demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 524, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T19:45:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Regula demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 524, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T19:46:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments that had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T20:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Doggett moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T20:43:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Failed by recorded vote: 169 - 214 (Roll no. 287).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4556-4557" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-15T23:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Weldon (FL) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-16T00:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4578.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-16T00:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-16T00:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-16T00:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Dicks moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-16T00:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dicks motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-16T00:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-16T00:55:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 184 - 188 (Roll no. 290).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/15/2000 H4584-4585" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-06-16T01:10:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="291" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 204 - 172 (Roll no. 291).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-06-16T01:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-20">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Interior. Approved for full committee consideration with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported by Senator Gorton with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 106-312.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-06-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="628">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 628.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6302-6324, S6328" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6302-6315" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-12">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6498-6538" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-17">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7007-7009, S7014-7043, S7055-7057" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7083, S7085-7103" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-07-18" how="roll" result="pass" roll="211" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 97 - 2. Record Vote Number: 211.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/19/2000 S7264-7279" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Gorton, Stevens, Cochran, Domenici, Burns, Bennett, Gregg, Campbell, Byrd, Leahy, Hollings, Reid, Dorgan, Kohl and Feinstein.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T20:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Regula asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T20:46:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H6927-6928" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T20:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Dicks moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T20:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained in the motion require the managers on the part of the House to insist on funding for the Institute of Museum and Library Services at a level not less than the $24,907,000 provided in the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T20:51:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T20:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T20:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Regula, Kolbe, Skeen, Taylor (NC), Nethercutt, Wamp, King (NY), Peterson (PA), Young (FL), Dicks, Murtha, Moran (VA), Cramer, Hinchey, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Regula asked unanimous consent that managers on the part of the House have until midnight on Sept. 28 to file a conference report on H.R. 4578. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-29T12:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 106-914 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8472-8550" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-02T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 603 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 4578 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 603 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Regula brought up conference report H. Rept. 106-914 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 603.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8649-8657" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 4578.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="2000-10-03T14:33:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="507" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 348 - 69 (Roll no. 507).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03T14:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9683" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9796-9820, S9842-9848, S9869-9873" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04">
      <text>Cloture motion on the conference report to accompany H.R. 4578 presented in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-05">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9879-9917" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-05">
      <text>Cloture on the conference report to accompany H.R. 4578 invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 89 - 8. Record Vote Number: 265.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-10-05" how="roll" result="pass" roll="266" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 83 - 13. Record Vote Number: 266.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-05">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-05">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-07">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-10-11">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-10-11" type="public" number="106-291">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-291.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP06" subcommittee="Interior" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="524"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="603"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Acid mine drainage"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Ambulances"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Barges"/>
    <term name="Beach pollution"/>
    <term name="Beaches"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Black history"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Caves"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Columbia River development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commission of Fine Arts"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Coral reef conservation"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Desert conservation"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Elephants"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Endangered animals"/>
    <term name="Endangered plants"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Everglades"/>
    <term name="Eviction"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to territories"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fish culture"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Forestry"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Global climate change"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Highway snow and ice control"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian gambling operations"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Insect control"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Limited access highways"/>
    <term name="Lincoln Administration"/>
    <term name="Literature"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Materials research"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Military base conversion"/>
    <term name="Mine wastes"/>
    <term name="Mineral industries"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National Capital Planning Commission"/>
    <term name="National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="National scenic areas"/>
    <term name="National seashores"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Nuclear exports"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Ocean mining"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution control"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution of the sea"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Old growth forests"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Palau Islands"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Presidential families"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Private forests"/>
    <term name="Private legislation"/>
    <term name="Probate law and practice"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad land grants"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Reforestation"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Restaurants"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Revegetation"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rhinoceroses"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Second homes"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="Snakes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Streets"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Sustainable agriculture"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Tigers"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="U.S. Holocaust Memorial Council"/>
    <term name="Underground movements"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban planning"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Volcanoes"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in rivers, lakes, etc."/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland ecology"/>
    <term name="White House (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Wild horses"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
    <term name="Zoos"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h796"/>
    <amendment number="h797"/>
    <amendment number="h798"/>
    <amendment number="h799"/>
    <amendment number="h800"/>
    <amendment number="h801"/>
    <amendment number="h802"/>
    <amendment number="h803"/>
    <amendment number="h804"/>
    <amendment number="h805"/>
    <amendment number="h806"/>
    <amendment number="h807"/>
    <amendment number="h808"/>
    <amendment number="h809"/>
    <amendment number="h810"/>
    <amendment number="h811"/>
    <amendment number="h812"/>
    <amendment number="h813"/>
    <amendment number="h814"/>
    <amendment number="h815"/>
    <amendment number="h816"/>
    <amendment number="h817"/>
    <amendment number="h818"/>
    <amendment number="h819"/>
    <amendment number="h820"/>
    <amendment number="h821"/>
    <amendment number="h822"/>
    <amendment number="h823"/>
    <amendment number="h824"/>
    <amendment number="h825"/>
    <amendment number="h826"/>
    <amendment number="h827"/>
    <amendment number="h828"/>
    <amendment number="h829"/>
    <amendment number="s3771"/>
    <amendment number="s3772"/>
    <amendment number="s3773"/>
    <amendment number="s3774"/>
    <amendment number="s3776"/>
    <amendment number="s3778"/>
    <amendment number="s3779"/>
    <amendment number="s3780"/>
    <amendment number="s3781"/>
    <amendment number="s3782"/>
    <amendment number="s3783"/>
    <amendment number="s3784"/>
    <amendment number="s3785"/>
    <amendment number="s3786"/>
    <amendment number="s3787"/>
    <amendment number="s3788"/>
    <amendment number="s3789"/>
    <amendment number="s3790"/>
    <amendment number="s3791"/>
    <amendment number="s3792"/>
    <amendment number="s3793"/>
    <amendment number="s3795"/>
    <amendment number="s3797"/>
    <amendment number="s3798"/>
    <amendment number="s3799"/>
    <amendment number="s3800"/>
    <amendment number="s3801"/>
    <amendment number="s3802"/>
    <amendment number="s3803"/>
    <amendment number="s3804"/>
    <amendment number="s3806"/>
    <amendment number="s3807"/>
    <amendment number="s3808"/>
    <amendment number="s3809"/>
    <amendment number="s3810"/>
    <amendment number="s3811"/>
    <amendment number="s3812"/>
    <amendment number="s3813"/>
    <amendment number="s3814"/>
    <amendment number="s3883"/>
    <amendment number="s3884"/>
    <amendment number="s3885"/>
    <amendment number="s3886"/>
    <amendment number="s3887"/>
    <amendment number="s3889"/>
    <amendment number="s3890"/>
    <amendment number="s3891"/>
    <amendment number="s3892"/>
    <amendment number="s3893"/>
    <amendment number="s3894"/>
    <amendment number="s3895"/>
    <amendment number="s3896"/>
    <amendment number="s3897"/>
    <amendment number="s3898"/>
    <amendment number="s3899"/>
    <amendment number="s3900"/>
    <amendment number="s3901"/>
    <amendment number="s3902"/>
    <amendment number="s3903"/>
    <amendment number="s3904"/>
    <amendment number="s3905"/>
    <amendment number="s3906"/>
    <amendment number="s3907"/>
    <amendment number="s3908"/>
    <amendment number="s3910"/>
    <amendment number="s3911"/>
    <amendment number="s3912"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/29/2000--Conference report filed in House.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of the Interior Title II: Related Agencies Title III: General Provisions Title IV: Wildland Fire Emergency Appropriations Title V: Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Title VI: User Fees Under Forest System Recreation Residence Program Title VII: Treatment of Certain Funds for Miner Benefits Title VIII: Land Conservation, Preservation and Infrastructure Improvement Title IX: Department of the Treasury Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001 - Makes appropriations for the Department of the Interior and related agencies for FY 2001.Title I: Department of the Interior - Makes appropriations for the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for: (1) land and resource management; (2) wildland fire management; (3) remedial action of hazardous waste substances; (4) construction; (5) payments in lieu of taxes to local governments; (6) land acquisition; (7) Oregon and California grant lands; (8) range improvements; (9) service charges, deposits, and forfeitures with respect to public lands; and (10) miscellaneous trust funds.Appropriates funds for the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service for: (1) resource management; (2) construction; (3) land acquisition; (4) expenses related to carrying out the Endangered Species Act of 1973; (5) the National Wildlife Refuge Fund; (6) expenses related to carrying out the North American Wetlands Conservation Act; (7) the Wildlife Conservation and Appreciation Fund; and (8) expenses related to carrying out the African Elephant Conservation Act, the Asian Elephant Conservation Act of 1997, and the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act of 1994.Makes appropriations for the National Park Service (NPS) for: (1) the National Park System; (2) the U.S. Park Police; (3) national recreation and preservation activities; (4) expenses related to carrying out the Urban Park and Recreation Recovery Act of 1978; (5) expenses related to carrying out the Historic Preservation Act of 1966 and the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996; (6) construction; and (7) land acquisition and State assistance from the Land and Water Conservation Fund.Rescinds specified contract authority to obligate funds from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for FY 2001.Makes appropriations for: (1) the U.S. Geological Survey for surveys, investigations, and research; (2) the Minerals Management Service for royalty and offshore minerals management and oil spill research; (3) the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement for regulation and technology and the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund; (4) the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) for operation of Indian programs, construction, Indian land and water claim settlements and miscellaneous payments to Indians, and Indian guaranteed loans; (5) assistance to U.S. territories and for carrying out the Compacts of Free Association with respect to Micronesia, the Marshall Islands, and Palau; (6) departmental management and the Offices of the Solicitor and the Inspector General; (7) trust programs for Indians; (8) a program for consolidation of fractional interests in Indian lands by direct expenditure or cooperative agreement; and (9) natural resource damage assessment.Sets forth authorized and prohibited uses of specified funds.(Sec. 107) Prohibits the use of funds provided in this title for specified offshore leasing and related activities.(Sec. 112) Bars the NPS from developing a reduced entrance fee program to accommodate non-local travel through a unit. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) to provide for and regulate local non-recreational passage through National Park System units, allowing each unit to develop guidelines and permits for activity appropriate to such unit.(Sec. 116) Authorizes the renewal of grazing permits and leases which expire or are transferred until the Secretary completes processing, at which time a permit or lease may be canceled, suspended, or modified to meet requirements of applicable laws and regulations.(Sec. 117) Provides that for purposes of reducing the backlog of Indian probate cases in the Department of the Interior, certain hearing requirements under provisions regarding descent and distribution of Indian lands are deemed satisfied by a proceeding conducted by an Indian probate judge appointed by the Secretary without regard to provisions governing competitive service appointments.(Sec. 118) Allows the Secretary to redistribute any Tribal Priority Allocation funds to alleviate tribal funding inequities by transferring funds to address identified, unmet needs, dual enrollment, overlapping service areas, or inaccurate distribution methodologies. Bars any tribe from receiving a reduction in such funds of more than ten percent in FY 2001. Makes such percentage limitation inapplicable under circumstances of dual enrollment, overlapping service areas, or inaccurate distribution methodologies.(Sec. 119) Prohibits the use of funds in this Act to establish a new National Wildlife Refuge in the Kankakee River basin that is inconsistent with Army Corps of Engineers' efforts to control flooding and siltation in that area. Requires written certification of such consistency to be submitted to specified congressional committees prior to refuge establishment.(Sec. 120) Names the Great Marsh Trail at the Mason Neck National Wildlife Refuge in Virginia the Joseph V. Gartlan, Jr. Great Marsh Trail.(Sec. 122) Requires amounts provided for tribal priority allocations in Alaska to be provided only to tribes the membership of which on June 1, 2000, is composed of at least 25 individuals who are Natives (as defined in the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act) who reside in the village for the tribe. Requires amounts that would have been available for such purposes but for the limitation to be provided to the respective Alaska Native regional nonprofit corporation for the respective region in which a tribe subject to such limitation is located.(Sec. 123) Requires the Secretary to ensure that the lands comprising the Huron Cemetery in Kansas are used only for religious and cultural uses compatible with the use of such lands as a cemetery and as a burial ground.(Sec. 124) Makes funds provided in this Act unavailable for transferring land into trust status for the Shoalwater Bay Indian Tribe in Clark County, Washington, until the tribe and county reach a legally enforceable agreement that addresses the financial impact of new development on the county, school and fire districts, and other local governments and the impact on zoning and development.(Sec. 125) Bars the use of funds provided in this Act to implement specified provisions of the secretarial order entitled "American Indian Tribal Rights, Federal-Tribal Trust Responsibilities, and the Endangered Species Act."(Sec. 126) Bars the use of funds appropriated for the Department of the Interior by any Act to study or implement any plan to drain Lake Powell or to reduce the water level of the Lake below the range of water levels required for the operation of the Glen Canyon Dam.(Sec. 129) Requires the Secretary to designate Anchorage, Alaska, as a port of entry for purposes of Endangered Species Act provisions authorizing importation or exportation of fish, wildlife, or plants at designated ports.(Sec. 130) Amends a provision of law regarding Sitka National Historical Park in Alaska to: (1) adjust the Park boundary; and (2) remove certain limitations on the authorization of appropriations under such law and to authorize such sums as necessary.(Sec. 131) Requires all proceeds of Oil and Gas Lease sale 991, held by the BLM on May 5, 1999, or subsequent lease sales in the National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska attributable to a specified area subject to withdrawal for Kuukpik Corporation's selection under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to be deposited in a special fund in the Treasury. Makes such fund available to the Secretary to pay the Arctic Slope Regional Corporation and the State of Alaska the amount of their entitlement.(Sec. 132) Directs the Secretary to convey all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to specified lands in Seward Meridian, Alaska, to Harvey R. Redmond.(Sec. 134) Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, to provide Dubuque Barge &amp; Fleeting Services, Inc. a notice that identifies parcels of land or interests in land that: (1) are of a value approximately equal to the value of the parcel of a strip of land on the northern half of Mississippi River Island No. 228; and (2) the Secretary would consider acceptable in exchange for all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to that parcel. Includes land or interests in land that would be suitable for inclusion in the Upper Mississippi River Wildlife and Fish Refuge in land or interests in land that may be considered acceptable. Requires the Secretary, after Dubuque offers land or interests in land identified under this section, to convey all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the parcel described under this section in exchange for the land or interests in land offered by Dubuque and to permanently discontinue barge fleeting at the Mississippi River island in Illinois commonly known as Pearl Island.(Sec. 135) Expresses the sense of the Senate that the Secretary should work with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to secure funding for repayment of the judgment in Ramah Navajo Chapter v. Lujan within the budgets of the agencies that did not pay indirect costs to plaintiffs during 1988 to 1993 or paid indirect costs at less than rates provided under the Indian Self-Determination Act during such period.(Sec. 136) Requires the Fish and Wildlife Service to implement a fee schedule to permit a return to the Service for forensic laboratory services provided to non-Department of the Interior entities.(Sec. 137) Excludes certain private lands from the Argus Range Wilderness in the California Desert Conservation Area.(Sec. 138) Directs the Secretary to remove certain land from the Columbia National Wildlife Refuge for transfer to the City of Othello, Washington. Requires such property to be used for public housing or other public purposes.(Sec. 141) Designates the visitors center in Chincoteague National Wildlife Refuge on Assateague Island, Virginia, as the Herbert H. Bateman Educational and Administrative Center.(Sec. 144) Validates all conveyances to the city of Valley City, a municipal corporation of Barnes County, North Dakota, of certain lands that formed part of the railroad right-of-way granted to the Northern Pacific Railroad Company. Provides that the United States reserves federally owned mineral rights in such lands, except the right of surface entry to the mineral estate.First Ladies National Historic Site Act of 2000 - Establishes the First Ladies National Historic Site in Canton, Ohio. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into an agreement with the National First Ladies Library under which the Library may operate and maintain the site.(Sec. 146) Requires the Secretary to make grants to contribute funds for the establishment in Springfield, Illinois, of an interpretive center to preserve and make available to the public materials related to the life of President Abraham Lincoln and to provide interpretive and educational services which communicate the meaning of Lincoln's life.Requires the entity selected by the Secretary to receive such grants to submit a plan and design for the center within 18 months after enactment of this Act. Prohibits: (1) providing such a grant until such entity certifies that funds equal to at least double the grant amount have been contributed by non-Federal sources; (2) the use of grant amounts for the maintenance or operation of the center; and (3) the Secretary from being involved in actual operation of the center, except at the request of the operating entity.Authorizes appropriations.Palace of the Governors Annex Act - Requires the Secretary, subject to the availability of appropriations, to make a grant to the State of New Mexico Office of Cultural Affairs to pay 50 percent of the costs of the final design, construction, management, inspection, furnishing, and equipping of the Annex for the Palace of the Governors of the Museum of New Mexico in Santa Fe. Directs the Office, in order to a receive a grant, to: (1) submit a copy of the architectural blueprints for the Annex to the Secretary; and (2) enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Secretary that provides for a competitive bidding process for the construction contract and specifies a completion date.Authorizes appropriations. Conditions appropriations on: (1) the State appropriating at least $8 million to pay costs described by this Act before January 1, 2010; and (2) other non-Federal sources providing funds sufficient to pay the remaining 50 percent non-Federal share of such costs.(Sec. 148) Extends the Southwestern Pennsylvania Heritage Preservation Commission and authorizes appropriations for the Commission through FY 2010.(Sec. 149) Redesignates the Cuyahoga Valley National Recreation Area as the Cuyahoga Valley National Park.National Underground Railroad Freedom Center Act - Authorizes and directs the Secretary to provide financial assistance to the National Underground Railroad Freedom Center, founded in 1995, to pay the Federal share (up to 20 percent of the project budget) of the costs of authorized Center activities. Authorizes the Secretary to assist in the construction of the Center facility and the development of programs and exhibits funded primarily through private and non-Federal funds on property owned by the city of Cincinnati, Hamilton County, and the State of Ohio.Authorizes appropriations.Requires annual reports from the Center to Congress.Amends the National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom Act of 1998 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to make grants for the preservation and restoration of historic buildings or structures associated with the Underground Railroad and for related research to sites, programs, or facilities that have been included in the national network. Requires grants to be matched by equal or greater non-Federal funds. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 151) Makes an amount available for expenses necessary to reclaim abandoned coal mine sites and for acid mine drainage remediation caused by past coal mining practices in the anthracite region of Pennsylvania.(Sec. 153) Requires the Secretary to carry out a demonstration program to provide grants to Indian tribes for the construction of tribally controlled schools.(Sec. 154) Directs the Administrator of General Services to sell all right, title, and interest of the United States in specified improvements and equipment situated at the White River Oil Shale Mine in Utah. Makes sale proceeds available to reimburse the Administrator for the direct costs of the sale and the BLM (Utah State office) for costs of closing and rehabilitating the Mine.(Sec. 155) Designates the Blue Ridge Parkway headquarters building located at 199 Hemphill Knob in Asheville, North Carolina, as the Gary E. Everhardt Headquarters Building.(Sec. 156) Bars the use of funds in any Act by the Secretary to promulgate final rules to revise regulations regarding surface management, except final rules to amend such regulations which are not inconsistent with the recommendations contained in the National Research Council report entitled "Hardrock Mining on Federal Lands" so long as these regulations are also not inconsistent with statutory authorities.Wheeling National Heritage Area Act of 2000 - Establishes the Wheeling National Heritage Area in Wheeling, West Virginia.Makes the Wheeling National Heritage Corporation the management entity for the Area, which shall implement and coordinate the recommendations contained in the Plan for the Wheeling National Heritage Area dated August 1992 and conserve and interpret historic and cultural resources of the Area.Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance to the management entity and make grants and cooperative agreements to and with any person.Authorizes appropriations.Prohibits grants or assistance under this Act after September 30, 2015.Title II: Related Agencies - Makes appropriations for the Department of Agriculture for the Forest Service for: (1) forest and rangeland research; (2) State and private forestry; (3) the National Forest System; (4) wildland fire management; (5) capital improvement and maintenance; (6) land acquisition; (7) range rehabilitation and improvement; (8) gifts, donations and bequests for forest and rangeland research; and (9) management of Federal lands in Alaska for subsistence uses.Appropriates an amount for the Southeast Alaska Economic Disaster Fund for distribution to the city of Craig.Defers a certain amount of funds made available for obligation in prior years for Department of Energy (DOE) clean coal technology projects until FY 2002.Makes appropriations for DOE for: (1) fossil energy research and development activities; (2) engineering studies to determine the cost of development, the predicted rate and quantity of petroleum recovery, the methodology, and equipment specifications for development of Shannon Formation at Naval Petroleum Reserve Numbered 3, utilizing a below-the-reservoir production method; (3) payment to the State of California for the State Teachers' Retirement Fund from the Elk Hills School Lands Fund; (4) energy conservation activities;(5) economic regulation activities of the Office of Hearings and Appeals; (6) the Strategic Petroleum Reserve; and (7) the Energy Information Administration.Rescinds specified amounts for alternative fuels production.Makes unobligated funds remaining from prior years available for naval petroleum and oil shale reserve activities.Makes appropriations for the Department of Health and Human Services for the Indian Health Service and Indian health facilities.Makes appropriations for: (1) the Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation; (2) the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development; (3) the Smithsonian Institution, including amounts for repair and restoration of facilities owned or occupied by the Smithsonian and for construction; (4) the National Gallery of Art, including an amount for repair and restoration of facilities owned or occupied by the National Gallery; (5) operations, maintenance, and construction expenses of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts; (6) carrying out the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Act of 1968; (7) the National Endowment for the Arts (NEA); (8) the National Endowment for the Humanities; (9) the Institute of Museum and Library Services; (10) Challenge America grants administered by the NEA; (11) the Commission of Fine Arts; (12) national capital arts and cultural affairs; (13) the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation; (14) the National Capital Planning Commission; (15) the Holocaust Memorial Council; and (16) the Presidio trust.Sets forth provisions regarding uses of, and limitations on, funds appropriated under this title.Title III: General Provisions - Sets forth limitations on the use of funds under this Act.(Sec. 308) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for: (1) planning or offering timber from giant sequoias on BLM or Forest System lands for sale in a manner different than such sales were conducted in FY 2000; (2) entering into a concession contract (by the NPS) which provides for the removal of the underground lunchroom at Carlsbad Caverns National Park; (3) the AmeriCorps program unless the relevant agencies of the Departments of the Interior and Agriculture follow appropriate reprogramming guidelines; (4) demolishing the bridge between Jersey City, New Jersey, and Ellis Island or preventing pedestrian use of such bridge; and (5) accepting or processing applications for a patent for mining or mill site claims located under the general mining laws, unless the Secretary takes specified actions.(Sec. 313) Authorizes the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior to limit competition for watershed restoration project contracts as part of the President's Forest Plan for the Pacific Northwest to individuals and entities in timber-dependent areas in Washington, Oregon, northern California, and Alaska that have been affected by reduced timber harvesting on Federal lands.(Sec. 316) Bars the use of funds made available in any Act to designate any portion of Canaveral National Seashore in Brevard County, Florida, as a clothing-optional area or area in which public nudity is permitted if such designation would be contrary to county ordinance.(Sec. 317) Requires the Chairperson of the NEA to: (1) award grants only for literature, National Heritage, or American Jazz Masters fellowships; and (2) establish procedures to ensure that no funding provided through a grant, except one made to a State or local arts agency or regional group, may be used to make a grant to any other individual or organization to conduct activities independent of the grant recipient.Prohibits NEA grants from being used for seasonal support to a group unless the application is specific to the contents of the season.(Sec. 319) Requires the Chairperson of the NEA to establish a grant category for programs that are of national impact or availability or are able to tour several States. Prohibits the Chairperson from making grants exceeding 15 percent, in the aggregate, of NEA funds appropriated by this Act, to any single State, excluding grants made under this section.(Sec. 320) Establishes the Forest Counties Payments Committee, which shall terminate three years after enactment of this Act, to develop recommendations to ensure that States and counties in which Federal lands are situated receive adequate Federal payments for public education and other public purposes. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture, at the request of the Executive Director of the Committee, to provide funding for the Committee for FY 2001.(Sec. 328) Sets forth requirements for the sale of timber in Region 10 of the Forest Service, including those regarding the volume of western red cedar timber available for processors.(Sec. 329) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated by this Act to propose or issue rules or orders for implementing the Kyoto Protocol.(Sec. 330) Authorizes the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture to pilot test joint permitting and leasing programs, subject to annual congressional review, and promulgate special rules to test the feasibility of issuing unified permits, applications, and leases.(Sec. 331) Allows the Secretary of Agriculture to permit the Colorado State Forest Service to perform watershed restoration and protection services on National Forest System lands when similar and complementary watershed restoration and protection services are being performed by the State Forest Service on adjacent State or private lands.(Sec. 333) Requires the Forest Service to review Forest Service campground concessions policy to determine if modifications can be made to Forest Service contracts for campgrounds so that such concessions are exempted from the Service Contract Act. Requires the Forest Service to offer such exemptions in FY 2001.(Sec. 335) Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to change one of the conditions under which Federal agencies may enter into multiyear energy savings performance contracts for up to 25 years, without funding of cancellation charges before cancellation, to apply a certain notification requirement to contracts with a cancellation ceiling in excess of $10 million (currently, $750,000).(Sec. 336) Extends the authority to collect fees under the recreational fee demonstration program through FY 2002. Makes funds available in accounts established under such program through FY 2005.(Sec. 337) Prohibits the use of funds in this Act by the Secretary to issue a prospecting permit for hardrock mineral exploration on Mark Twain National Forest land in the Current River-Jack's Fork River Eleven Point Watershed.(Sec. 338) Expands Forest Service authority to enter into stewardship and end result contracts to authorize an additional 28 contracts, with at least nine allocated to Region 1 and three to Region 6.(Sec. 340) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this Act by the Secretaries of the Interior or Agriculture to implement a final rule for estimating fair market value land use rental fees for fiberoptic communications rights-of-way on Federal lands that amends the linear right-of-way rental fee schedule published on July 8, 1987. Requires the Secretaries, in determining such fees, to use the rates contained in the linear right-of-way rental fee schedules in place on May 1, 2000.(Sec. 341) Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to limit competition for fire and fuel treatment and watershed restoration contracts in the Giant Sequoia National Monument and the Sequoia National Forest. Gives employment preference to dislocated and displaced workers in Tulare, Kern, and Fresno Counties, California, for work associated with the establishment of the Giant Sequoia National Monument.(Sec. 345) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to close permanently an aircraft landing strip on Federal land administered by the Secretaries of the Interior or Agriculture that is commonly known and consistently used for aircraft landing and departure activities without public notice, consultation with State and Federal aviation officials, and the consent of the Federal Aviation Administration. Considers a landing strip to be closed permanently if the intended duration of the closure is more than 180 days in any calendar year.(Sec. 346) Amends the Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area Act to set forth appraisal requirements for land within special management areas acquired or conveyed under such Act.Terminates the application of certain special rules pertaining to land acquisition in special management areas and nonapplicability of land use ordinances to land offered for acquisition after March 31, 2000.Provides for notice of the amendments made by this section to private landowners in the special management areas.Extends the time frame in which the Secretary is authorized to make payments to local governments for lands acquired within such areas.(Sec. 347) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to Kern County, California, four parcels of land (known as Camp Owen, Wofford Heights Park, the French Gulch maintenance yard, and Kernville Fish Hatchery) under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service in Kern County in exchange for: (1) approximately 52 acres of Greenhorn Mountain Park in Kern County for inclusion in Sequoia National Forest; (2) a replacement storage facility (for the French Gulch maintenance yard facility) at the Greenhorn Ranger District Lake Isabella Maintenance Yard property; and (3) a cash equalization payment specified by the Secretary.Directs the County, upon receipt of such lands, to grant an easement and to record such easement in the appropriate office for permitted or licensed uses of those lands that are unrecorded as of the date of such conveyance.(Sec. 348) Requires the Secretary to cause to be established an advisory group to provide expert advice and counsel to the Director of the National Energy Technology Laboratory (NETL) with respect to NETL research and development activities.(Sec. 349) Appropriates an amount from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for the Umpqua Land Exchange Project (ULEP). Makes such amount available to the Foundation for Voluntary Land Exchanges to complete a Final Land Ownership Adjustment Plan for the Coast Range-Umpqua River Basin.Requires the Secretary and the Foundation to report to specified congressional committees on land exchanges or purchases identified to implement the Plan.Directs the Secretary to consummate land exchanges necessary to implement the Plan.(Sec. 350) Authorizes the Indian Health Service to provide additional contract health service funds to Ketchikan Indian Corporation's recurring budget for hospital-related services for patients of the Corporation and the Organized Village of Saxman.Boise Laboratory Replacement Act of 2000 - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to sell or exchange the Boise (Idaho) laboratory (laboratory) site (as defined by this Act), and use the resultant funds to acquire land and facilities to: (1) co-locate the laboratory with one of the Boise-area State institutions of higher learning; (2) replace other laboratory functions; and (3) acquire other land or interests in Idaho.Grants right of first refusal for the laboratory site to the University of Idaho or a related nonprofit organization, and provides, if such option is exercised, for Federal cooperation with the University to develop a multiagency research and education facility at such site.Title IV: Wildland Fire Emergency Appropriations - Makes additional amounts available for BLM and Forest Service wildland fire management.Authorizes the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture, in expending funds provided under this title for hazardous fuels reduction, to conduct fuel reduction treatments on Federal lands using all available contracting and hiring authorities.Requires the Secretaries to publish in the Federal Register lists of urban wildland interface communities within the vicinity of Federal lands that are at high risk from wildfire, including those excluded from hazardous fuel reduction treatment, and to identify reasons why no treatments are being prepared for communities that are excluded.Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to publish in the Federal Register the Forest Service's Cohesive Strategy for Protecting People and Sustaining Resources in Fire-Adapted Ecosystems .Requires funds to be used as necessary by the Secretaries of the Interior, Agriculture, and Commerce and the Council of Environmental Quality to implement expedited procedures for hazardous fuel reduction and post-burn treatments on Federal lands.Title V: Emergency Supplemental Appropriations - Makes additional funds available for: (1) BLM management of lands and resources; (2) Fish and Wildlife Service resource management and construction; (3) NPS construction to repair sites damaged by natural disasters; (4) Geological Survey surveys, investigations, and research for repair and replacement of stream monitoring equipment and facilities damaged by natural disasters; (5) BIA operation of Indian programs for repair of the Yakama Nation's Signal Peak Road; (6) the Office of Special Trustee for American Indians for unanticipated trust reform projects and costs relating to the Cobell litigation; and (7) the Forest Service for the Alaska Railroad and expenses from windstorm damage in the National Forest System.Title VI: User Fees Under Forest System Recreation Residence Program - Cabin User Fee Fairness Act of 2000 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, to ensure that the basis and procedure for calculating cabin user fees on National Forest System lands results in a fee that reflects a lot's market value and regional and local economic influences.Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) appraisal requirements and right of second appraisals; (2) cabin user fees and annual adjustments; and (3) right of appeal and judicial review.Title VII: Treatment of Certain Funds for Miner Benefits - Requires interest credited to the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund (Fund) for FY 1992 through 1995 not transferred to the United Mine Workers of America Combined Benefit Fund (Combined Fund) prior to this Act's enactment date to be transferred to the Combined Fund in: (1) such amounts as estimated by Fund trustees to offset any deficit in net assets in the Combined Fund through August 31, 2001; (2) the amount of $2.2 million for purposes of the Combined Fund providing a refund of any premium to certain signatory operators or persons related to such operators who were denied refunds as the result of final judgments or settlements; and (3) such amounts as necessary for purposes of the Combined Fund providing a monthly refund of any premium paid by certain assigned operators commencing with the first monthly premium due date after this Act's enactment and ending August 31, 2001.Title VIII: Land Conservation, Preservation and Infrastructure Improvement - Provides an additional $686 million for acquisition, conservation, and maintenance of Federal and non-Federal lands and resources and for payments in lieu of taxes.(Sec. 801) Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) to establish discretionary spending limits for the conservation spending category and specified subcategories for FY 2002 through 2006.Requires any funds not appropriated within the discretionary spending limits of such category or subcategories to be added to such limits in the following fiscal year. Prohibits the total amount provided for any conservation activity within such category from exceeding any authorized ceiling.Title IX: Department of the Treasury - Provides for the deposit of an additional $5 billion into the account to reduce the public debt.</summary>
</bill>
