<bill session="107" type="h" number="5531" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-21">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sudan Peace Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Sudan Peace Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Sudan Peace Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate famine relief efforts and a comprehensive solution to the war in Sudan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400394"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="2002-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2002-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2002-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2002-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2002-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2002-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2002-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2002-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2002-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2002-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2002-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2002-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2002-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7102-7109" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate H.R. 5531.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7130-7131" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-10-07T19:11:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="443" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 359 - 8 (Roll no. 443).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7102-7104" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T19:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2002-10-09" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10232" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2002-10-09">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2002-10-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2002-10-11">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2002-10-21">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2002-10-21" type="public" number="107-245">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 107-245.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="2052"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="180"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aerial bombing"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Islamic fundamentalism"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2002--Passed House amended.
Sudan Peace Act - (Sec. 4) Condemns violations of human rights on all sides of the conflict in Sudan (including the Government of Sudan), the ongoing slave trade there, the Government's use and organization of "murahalliin" (or "mujahadeen"), Popular Defense Forces (PDF), and regular Sudanese Army units into raiding and slaving parties in Bahr al Ghazal, the Nuba Mountains, Upper Nile, and Blue Nile regions, and its aerial bombardment of civilian targets. Recognizes that the use of raiding and slaving parties is a tool for creating food shortages as a systematic means to destroy the societies, culture, and economies of the Dinka, Nuer, and Nuba peoples in a policy of low-intensity ethnic cleansing.(Sec. 5) Authorizes the President to provide increased assistance to areas of Sudan that are not controlled by the Government of Sudan to prepare the population for peace and democratic governance. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2003 through 2005.(Sec. 6) Declares that Congress recognizes that: (1) a single, viable internationally and regionally sanctioned peace process holds the greatest opportunity to promote a negotiated, peaceful settlement to the war in Sudan; and (2) resolution to the conflict there is best made through a peace process based on the Declaration of Principles reached in Nairobi, Kenya, on July 20, 1994, and on the Machakos Protocol in July 2002. Commends the efforts of Special Presidential Envoy, Senator Danforth, and his team in working to assist the parties to the conflict in Sudan in finding a just, permanent peace to the conflict in Sudan.Requires the President to take specified actions against Sudan if the President determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the Government of Sudan has not engaged in good faith negotiations with the Sudan People's Liberation Movement (SPLM) to achieve a peace agreement, or is not in compliance with the terms of any negotiated peace agreement with the SPLM. Requires specified reports to Congress.(Sec. 7) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the United Nations (UN) should help facilitate peace and recovery in Sudan; and (2) the President should seek to end the Government of Sudan's veto power over relief flight plans by Operation Lifeline Sudan (OLS) and take appropriate measures to end slavery and aerial bombardment of civilians by the Government of Sudan.(Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary of State to report annually to the appropriate congressional committees on the conflict in Sudan.(Sec. 9) Declares the sense of Congress that the President should continue to increase the use of non-OLS agencies in relief supply distribution in southern Sudan. Requires the President to submit a progress report to the appropriate congressional committees.(Sec. 10) Directs the President to develop a contingency plan to provide, outside UN auspices, the greatest amount of U.S. Government and privately donated relief to all affected areas in Sudan, including the Nuba Mountains, Upper Nile, and the Blue Nile regions, in the event the Government of Sudan imposes a ban on OLS air transport relief flights. Authorizes the President to reprogram up to 100 percent of funds for OLS operations for purposes of such contingency plan.(Sec. 11) Directs the Secretary to collect information and report to the appropriate congressional committees about possible war crimes by all parties to the conflict in Sudan, including slavery, rape, and aerial bombardment of civilian targets.</summary>
</bill>
