<bill session="106" type="h" number="2148" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical corrections regarding the applicability of certain amendments made by Public Law 105-392 to the Health Education Assistance Program under the Public Health Service Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1999-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1999--Introduced.
Amends the Nursing Education and Practice Improvement Act of 1998 (NEPIA) to change to November 13, 1998, (instead of six months after such date) the effective date of provisions: (1) removing mandatory performance standards for lenders and holders of loans under the health education assistance loan (HEAL) program under the Public Health Service Act; and (2) allowing Federal payment of a HEAL loan after default, unless the lender, holder, or servicer has a compliance performance rating under 97 percent, in which case payment must be made at 98 percent of the loss. Provides that: (1) such provisions apply to any HEAL program loan to graduate students made by an eligible lender and insured by the Secretary of Health and Human Services on or after November 13, 1998; and (2) the HEAL program provisions superseded by NEPIA, as in effect on November 12, 1998, apply to a HEAL loan made by an eligible lender and insured by the Secretary before November 13, 1998.</summary>
</bill>
