<bill session="108" type="h" number="2122" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-16T17:07:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-07-16T17:07:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Vaccine Compensation bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Project BioShield Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Project BioShield Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Project BioShield Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance research, development, procurement, and use of biomedical countermeasures to respond to public health threats affecting national security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2003-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Government Reform, and Homeland Security (Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
      <reference ref="Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T20:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 108-147, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T20:50:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Government Reform Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 13, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T20:50:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Homeland Security (Select) Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 13, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Armed Services for a period ending not later than June 11, 2003 pursuant to clause 1(c), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T14:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 108-147, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-13T15:37:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Homeland Security (Select) Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 27, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-27T13:46:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Homeland Security (Select) Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 8, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-08T20:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security (Select). H. Rept. 108-147, Part III.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-07-08T20:14:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="98">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 98.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated by previous order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by previous order of the House.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6908-6941" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6908-6920" label="text as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T14:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 90 minutes of debate on H.R. 2122, equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6946" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6946" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on H.R. 2122, as amended, the Chair put the question on passage of the bill, as amended, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cox demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of passage until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T17:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6947-6948" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-07-16T17:07:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="373" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 421 - 2 (Roll no. 373).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-07-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="214">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 214.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security (Select)" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="15"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="1504"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Smallpox"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h251"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/16/2003--Passed House amended.
Project BioShield Act of 2003 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Public Health Service Act regarding preparations for public health emergencies affecting national security, including a bioterrorist attack. Makes biocontainment laboratories and specialized research facilities available as needed to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) in public health emergencies affecting national security if the owners of such a facility have entered into a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement with the Secretary under the provisions of this Act pertaining to biomedical countermeasure research and development. Grants the Secretary certain authority with respect to the research and development of qualified countermeasures, including: (1) expedited procurement authority; (2) expedited peer review authority; (3) authority for personal services contracts; and (4) streamlined personnel authority. Defines a qualified countermeasure as a priority countermeasure that affects national security. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, to maintain a stockpile of drugs, vaccines (including smallpox vaccine), and other supplies to provide for the emergency health security of the United States in the event of a bioterrorist attack or other public health emergency. Directs the Secretary to: (1) review and revise the contents of the stockpile on a regular basis; (2) award grants to ensure that the stockpile contains an adequate amount of smallpox vaccine; and (3) assess, on an ongoing basis, the potential public health consequences from the use of chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear agents and determine the agents for which countermeasures are necessary. Permits the Secretary and the Secretary of Homeland Security to jointly submit to the President proposals for the development of needed security countermeasures. Defines security countermeasures as priority countermeasures against a chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear agent that meet one of certain criteria (including having been approved or cleared under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act as countermeasures against a chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear agent). Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize appropriations for: (1) the procurement of security countermeasures; (2) the carrying out of terror threat assessment responsibilities; and (3) the acquisition and deployment of secure intelligence sharing facilities. (Sec. 4) Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to allow the Secretary to declare a national emergency under specified conditions and authorize the release of a drug, device, or biological product intended for use in an emergency. Directs the Secretary to impose requirements on the authorization, including ensuring that health care professionals administering the product and persons to whom the product is administered are fully informed about the benefits and risks involved and other alternatives. Requires the Secretary to periodically review an authorization under this Act, and authorizes the Secretary to revoke such an authorization if circumstances so warrant. Allows the President, with regard to the Armed Forces, to waive the requirement that individuals be allowed to refuse administration of a countermeasure if complying with such requirement is: (1) not feasible; (2) contrary to the best interests of such individuals; or (3) not in the interests of national security. Allows the Secretary to withhold from members of the Armed Forces information about the benefits and risks of a countermeasure and alternatives to its use if such information is provided to such individuals within 30 days of the administration of the countermeasure and is recorded in the medical records of such members. Requires: (1) reports from the Secretary regarding authorities under this Act; (2) the Secretary to request the National Academy of Sciences to review biomedical countermeasure research and development activities under this Act; and (3) review by the General Accounting Office. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to ensure that diverse institutions, including Historically Black Colleges and Universities and those serving other underrepresented populations, are meaningfully aware of research, contracts, cooperative agreements, and development grants and procurements conducted under this Act. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to determine whether, for any grant, contract, or cooperative agreement awarded under this Act for the research, development, or procurement of a qualified countermeasure or a security countermeasure, the countermeasure involved is subject to existing export-related controls. Allows the Secretary to make a recommendation to the appropriate agency or agencies that a countermeasure should be subject to such controls if it is not already. (Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Defense to ensure that the activities of their respective Departments coordinate, complement, and do not unnecessarily duplicate programs designed to protect the homeland from biological, chemical, radiological, and nuclear agents. Directs such Secretaries to each appoint an official to coordinate such programs for their respective Departments.</summary>
</bill>
