<bill session="104" type="h" number="53" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Health Pesticides Protection Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act with respect to public health pesticides.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400112"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403864" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1995-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from EPA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-01">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, HHS.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-23">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.1627.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG26" subcommittee="Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1627"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Insect control"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Rodenticides"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Public Health Pesticides Protection Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to consider the risks and benefits of public health pesticides separately from the risks and benefits of other pesticides. Requires the Administrator, in weighing any regulatory action concerning a public health pesticide, to weigh any risks of the pesticide against the health risks to be controlled by the pesticide. Defines: (1) a "public health pesticide" as a minor use pesticide registered for use and used predominantly in public health programs for vector control or other health protection uses; and (2) "vector" as any animal capable of transmitting the causative agent of human disease or of producing human discomfort or injury. Exempts from reregistration fees public health pesticides of which more than 50 percent of usage (or at least 50 percent in the case of certain end use products) is devoted to the promotion of public health. Provides for expedited processing and review of pesticide applications that propose the initial or amended registration of an end use pesticide that, if registered as proposed, would be used as a public health pesticide. Provides for review by the Secretary of Health and Human Services of registrations of public health pesticides proposed for cancellation. Directs the Administrator to identify pests of significant public health importance and to implement programs to improve and facilitate the safe use of methods to combat such pests. Requires the Administrator to consult with the Secretary prior to taking final action to suspend or cancel a registration. Directs the Administrator to determine whether the potential benefits of continued use of a pesticide for public health purposes are of such significance as to warrant studies to support continued registration. Requires the Secretary to make arrangements for the conduct of studies and submission of data. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
