<bill session="106" type="h" number="2728" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Two Floods and You Are Out of the Taxpayers' Pocket Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to reduce losses to properties for which repetitive flood insurance claim payments have been made.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1999-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1999-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400383" joined="1999-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Dikes (Engineering)"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
Two Floods and You Are Out of the Taxpayers' Pocket Act of 1999 - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to require the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, in awarding grants for mitigation activities, to give priority to properties for which repetitive flood insurance claim payments have been made (repetitive claim properties). Authorizes the Director to waive mitigation assistance limits when the State or community has repetitive claim properties and such waiver is cost-effective and in the best interests of the National Flood Insurance Fund.Increases amounts credited to the National Flood Mitigation Fund from the National Flood Insurance Fund, such amounts to be used only for repetitive claim properties.Extends through FY 2004 the authority to enter into flood insurance contracts and the authorization of appropriations for the national flood insurance program.Provides chargeable national flood insurance premium rates for: (1) repetitive claim properties; and (2) certain coastal and river properties leased from the Government. Authorizes annual premium increases with respect to such properties.Amends the National Flood Insurance Reform Act of 1994 to prohibit Federal disaster relief assistance from being used for repair, replacement, or restoration of any property in the area for which: (1) repetitive claim payments have been made; and (2) Federal mitigation assistance has been offered to, but refused by, the property owner.Authorizes the Director to provide for funding for mitigation actions that reduce flood damages to repetitive claim properties, under certain conditions. Provides funding for such assistance from the National Flood Insurance Fund.</summary>
</bill>
