<bill session="108" type="h" number="2395" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide suitable alternative grazing arrangements on National Forest System land to persons that hold a grazing permit adversely affected by the standards and guidelines contained in the Record of Decision of the Sierra Nevada Forest Plan Amendment and pertaining to the Willow Flycatcher and the Yosemite Toad.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2003-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2003-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2003-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400304" joined="2003-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Amphibians"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2003--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to provide alternative grazing arrangements on National Forest System land to a person with a System grazing permit if such permittee's grazing privileges will be limited by implementation of the guidelines for the willow flycatcher and the Yosemite Toad (contained in the Record of Decision of the Sierra Nevada Forest Plan Amendment). States that such guidelines shall not apply in 2003 for grazing activities for which the Secretary is unable to provide alternative arrangements in specified allotments on the Humboldt-Toiyabe, Lassen, Plumas, Tahoe, Stanislaus, and Sierra National Forests.Authorizes the Secretary to provide certain environmental exclusions for such alternative grazing arrangements without first administratively establishing an applicable category of excluded actions.</summary>
</bill>
