<bill session="105" type="h" number="4120" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Savings and Investment Relief Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to provide for an annual limit on the amount of certain fees which may be collected by the Securities and Exchange Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1998-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1231-1232"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="h" number="4213"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Stock exchanges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/1998--Introduced.
Savings and Investment Relief Act of 1998 - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 with respect to transaction fees for both exchange-traded and exchange-regulated securities and off-exchange trades of last-sale-reported securities. Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to prescribe annually a fiscal year fee limitation based upon the pro rata share of the aggregate dollar amount of securities sales, so that total fee payments will not exceed specified limits. Requires each national securities exchange and national securities association to adopt implementing rules which provide fee reductions for all market participants. Directs the SEC to report annually to the Congress on the total amount of transaction fees collected by each national securities exchange and national securities association. Authorizes future appropriations Acts to increase such fee limitations in any year in which the total fees collected are insufficient for SEC budget authority provided under such Acts.</summary>
</bill>
