<bill session="107" type="hc" number="453" updated="2013-07-14T18:59:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress relating to the increasingly dire food security situation in Zimbabwe and the failure of the Mugabe regime to take appropriate measures to mitigate the impact of its failed policies on the nutritional well-being of the people of Zimbabwe and of other countries in the Southern Africa region.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2002-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Famines"/>
    <term name="Food as a weapon"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Grain"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Land tenure"/>
    <term name="Monopolies"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Zimbabwe"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2002--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the land confiscation campaign in Zimbabwe and the state-sponsored campaign of violence, torture, and intimidation led by Robert Mugabe is a calculated and depraved attempt to cling to power at the expense of the Zimbabwean people; (2) the economic and nutritional status of the Zimbabwean people will be harmed further by the pursuit of failed policies by Mugabe; and (3) absent any corrective action, Mugabe's legacy will be defined by his responsibility for the suffering and death by famine of tens of thousands of Zimbabweans.Calls for Mugabe to: (1) cease the state monopoly on grain imports and allow market forces to deliver food to areas of Zimbabwe in need; (2) allow the unfettered access of the indigenous and international non-governmental community, including the United Nations, to assist Zimbabwean people; and (3) cease withholding food deliveries from certain regions of Zimbabwe.</summary>
</bill>
