<bill session="106" type="h" number="1817" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve cellular telephone service in selected rural areas and to achieve equitable treatment of certain cellular license applicants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1999-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-05-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E977-978"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1130"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/1999--Introduced.
Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), notwithstanding its order in the proceeding in re Applications of Cellwave Telephone Services L.P., Futurewave General Partners L.P., and Great Western Cellular Partners, to: (1) reinstate each of three specified applicants as a selectee under the covered rural service area licensing proceeding; and (2) permit application amendments, at any time before final licensing action in the covered rural service area, in order to update factual information and comply with FCC rules. Prohibits the submission of petitions to deny such applications. Directs the FCC to: (1) award licenses under such proceeding within 90 days after enactment of this Act; (2) require such applicant to provide cellular radiotelephone service to subscribers in accordance with FCC rules (reducing from five to three years the period in which such applicant may expand the system within that market); and (3) establish a fee for each of the licenses under the proceeding (requiring each applicant to pay such fee within 18 months after its application is granted). Prohibits the FCC, during the five-year period after an application license is granted, from authorizing the transfer or assignment of that license.</summary>
</bill>
