<bill session="106" type="h" number="4013" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Upper Mississippi River Basin Conservation Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a cooperative effort of the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior to reduce sediment and nutrient loss in the Upper Mississippi River Basin.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2000-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2000-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2000-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2000-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2000-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="2000-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2000-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400517" joined="2000-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2000-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="2000-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2000-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2000-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2000-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2000-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="2000-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="2000-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2000-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2000-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="2000-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="2000-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2000-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2000-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2000-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400519" joined="2000-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2000-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2000-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="2000-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities, Resource Conservation and Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSAG23" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Resource Conservation and Credit" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural runoff"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer simulation"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Eutrophication"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Farm management"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Sedimentation"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Sediment and Nutrient Monitoring Network Title II: Initiative Grant, Demonstration, and Outreach Programs Title III: Financial and Technical Assistance Under Department of Agriculture Conservation Programs Title IV: Protection of Personal Data Title V: Advisory Council on the Upper Mississippi River Stewardship Initiative Title VI: Interagency Working Group on Upper Mississippi River Stewardship Initiative Title VII: Authorization of Appropriations Upper Mississippi River Basin Conservation Act of 2000 - Title I: Sediment and Nutrient Monitoring Network - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary), through the United States Geological Service, to establish a nutrient and sediment monitoring network for the Upper Mississippi River Basin, to be headquartered at the Upper Midwest Environmental Sciences Center in La Crosse, Wisconsin.(Sec.102) Directs the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture and other involved parties, to establish guidelines for related data collection and storage activities.(Sec. 104) Directs the Secretary to: (1) collaborate with other public and private monitoring efforts in establishing the nutrient and sediment monitoring program; and (2) target resources of the State Water Resources Research Institute Program to promote nutrient and sediment studies in the Basin.Title II: Initiative, Grant, Demonstration, and Outreach Programs - Requires the Director of the United States Geological Survey, in collaboration with the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service, to establish a computer modeling program of nutrient and sediment sources in the Basin, which shall include models of: (1) processes affecting field sediment and nutrient loss; (2) watersheds; (3) river channels; and (4) connections between sediment and nutrient yields and sources, land uses, and management practices. States that such information shall be headquartered at the Center in La Crosse, Wisconsin.(Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) work with public and private entities to evaluate best management practices designed to reduce nutrient and sediment loss; and (2) assess such practices' economic risks.(Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to administer a grant program to supplement non-Federal funds being used by public and private entities to demonstrate new best management practices to reduce nutrient and sediment loss in the Basin.(Sec. 204) Requires the Director to: (1) establish an Internet-based system to distribute information about nutrient and sediment loss reduction projects, including Basin projects, and nutrient and sediment levels in the Upper Mississippi River and its tributaries; and (2) report with respect to monitoring and modeling activities.Title III: Financial and Technical Assistance under Department of Agriculture Conservation Programs - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to increase assistance for nutrient and sediment reduction in the Basin, including new assistance to Basin subwatersheds that are nutrient and sediment sources.(Sec. 302) Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to designate the Basin as a conservation priority area.(Sec. 303) Increases enrollment authority under the conservation reserve and the wetland reserve programs.(Sec. 304) Amends the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act to increase funding for the wildlife habitat incentives program.Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to increase funding for the environmental quality incentives program.(Sec. 305) Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into cooperative agreements with public and private agencies, including agreements for goods and services (and personal services).Title IV: Protection of Personal Data - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to provide for privacy of personal data received by the Department of Agriculture and data collection locations with respect to natural resources conservation programs. Sets forth limited disclosure exceptions. Subjects disclosure violations to specified penalty provisions of such Act.Title V: Advisory Council on the Upper Mississippi River Stewardship Initiative - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish the Advisory Council on the Upper Mississippi River Stewardship Initiative. Authorizes the Advisory Council to establish specified task groups.Title VI: Interagency Working Group on Upper Mississippi River Basin Initiative - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to establish an Interagency Working Group to coordinate Federal nutrient and sediment reduction efforts in the Basin.Title VII: Authorization of Appropriations - Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
