<bill session="106" type="h" number="1184" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-21T13:15:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-04-21T13:15:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Earthquake Hazards Reduction bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Earthquake Hazards Reduction Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Earthquake Hazards Reduction Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Earthquake Hazards Reduction Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for carrying out the Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977 for fiscal years 2000 and 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-04-19T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 106-99, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-19T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Resources Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than April 19, 1999.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-19T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-04-19T17:02:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="56">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 56.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-04-20T17:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 142 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1184 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21T12:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 142 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 142.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2219-2225" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1184 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 142 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ray LaHood to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1184.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1184.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-04-21T13:15:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="95" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 414 - 3 (Roll no. 95).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="142"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1639"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Earthquake engineering"/>
    <term name="Earthquake prediction"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seismology"/>
    <term name="Simulation methods"/>
    <term name="Single-parent families"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Test facilities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h49"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/21/1999--Passed House amended.
Earthquake Hazards Reduction Authorization Act of 1999 - Amends the Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977 to authorize appropriations to the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) for earthquake hazards reduction for FY 2000 and 2001. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2000 and 2001 to the Secretary of the Interior for carrying out, through the Director of the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), responsibilities assigned under the Act, with specified amounts available for the Global Seismic Network and the Scientific Earthquake Studies Advisory Committee. Makes specified amounts available for FY 2000 and 2001 for a related USGS grant program. Authorizes additional appropriations for FY 2000 and 2001 for a USGS program to develop a prototype real-time seismic warning system. Authorizes appropriations under the Act for FY 2000 and 2001 for National Science Foundation (NSF) engineering and geosciences research and for the National Institute of Standards and Technology. Repeals a provision regarding non-Federal cost sharing for supplemental funds. Requires the USGS Director to: (1) establish an Advanced National Seismic Research and Monitoring System to modernize, standardize, and stabilize the national, regional, and urban seismic monitoring systems in the United States into a coordinated system; and (2) transmit a five-year management plan for the System to Congress. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the NSF Director to establish a Network for Earthquake Engineering Simulation that will upgrade, link, and integrate a system of geographically distributed experimental facilities for earthquake engineering testing of full-sized structures and their components and partial-scale physical models. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the USGS Director to establish a Scientific Earthquake Studies Advisory Committee. Requires the FEMA Director to report to Congress on elements of the earthquake hazards reduction program that specifically address the needs of at-risk populations, including the elderly, persons with disabilities, non-English-speaking families, single-parent households, and the poor. Requires such report to make recommendations for additional legislative authority required to address such needs. Sets forth Buy American requirements with respect to assistance expended by entities under this Act. Expresses the sense of Congress that entities receiving assistance under this Act should purchase only American-made equipment and products with such assistance. Makes persons who have labeled products not made in the United States as "Made in America" ineligible for contracts made with funds provided by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
