<bill session="106" type="h" number="5493" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gateway Communities Cooperation Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the ability of local communities to participate in Federal land management planning conducted by the Forest Service and agencies of the Department of the Interior and to respond to the local impacts of the heavy public use of the Federal lands administered by these agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400330"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-18">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-18">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/18/2000--Introduced.
Gateway Communities Cooperation Act of 2000 - Declares that it is Federal Government policy that Federal land managers should support and coordinate with gateway communities (communities adjacent to or near Federal lands) to: (1) improve the relationship between such managers and elected officials and residents of such communities; (2) enhance such communities' facilities and services available to visitors of such Federal lands; and (3) result in better land use decisions.Requires such a manager undertaking land management planning to: (1) seek the participation of elected officials, businesses, and other interested persons in neighboring gateway communities; and (2) provide such persons with an opportunity to participate in the development and implementation of the resulting land management decisions.Permits such a manager to: (1) enter into a cooperative agreement with the local government of a certified gateway community to coordinate land management and development plans; and (2) make grants to assist such communities with respect to the Federal land use planning process.</summary>
</bill>
