<bill session="107" type="h" number="3958" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-04-09T19:28:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-04-09T19:28:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bear River Migratory Bird Refuge Settlement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Bear River Migratory Bird Refuge Settlement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Bear River Migratory Bird Refuge Settlement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a mechanism for the settlement of claims of the State of Utah regarding portions of the Bear River Migratory Bird Refuge located on the shore of the Great Salt Lake, Utah.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-03-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-386.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-04-09T14:08:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="224">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 224.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1100-1101" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3958.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T19:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1112-1113" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-04-09T19:28:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="82" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 396 - 6 (Roll no. 82).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1100-1101" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T19:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Jeffords without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-06-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="461">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 461.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2002--Passed House amended.
Bear River Migratory Bird Refuge Settlement Act of 2002 - Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior from entering into an agreement with the State of Utah for the transfer of lands or interests in land within the Bear River Migratory Bird Refuge unless the agreement requires: (1) the State to support the U.S. application to add an enlarged Hyrum Reservoir or another storage facility as an alternate place of storage under the Refuge's existing 1000 cubic feet per second State certified water right, contingent upon demonstration by the United States that no injury to water rights shall occur; (2) the State, if it prevails in a suit against the United States challenging the validity of the deed issued pursuant to such agreement, to pay the United States for property improvements, such as water control structures and buildings, and to repay amounts paid to the State by the United States pursuant to the agreement or because of U.S. ownership of the land; and (3) the Secretary to agree to pay $15 million to the State upon delivery of a quitclaim deed that meets Justice Department standards and covers all lands and interests claimed by the State within the Refuge, subject to the condition that the State use such payment for the purposes and in the amounts specified below.Requires the State to deposit $10 million into the Wetlands and Habitat Protection Account.Authorizes the Executive Director of the Utah Department of Natural Resources to use the interest on such amount for wetland or open space protection and for enhancement and acquisition of wildlife habitat in and near the Great Salt Lake.Authorizes the use of $5 million for: (1) the development, improvement, and expansion of motorized and non-motorized recreational trails on public and private lands (with priority given to providing trail access to the Lake as part of the proposed Shoshone and Ogden-Weber trail systems); and (2) preservation, reclamation, enhancement, and conservation of streams.Requires the Executive Director to maximize the use of such funds through coordination with nonprofit organizations, Federal agencies, other agencies of the State, and local governments, giving priority to those projects that include Federal, State, or private matching funds.Authorizes appropriations for such payment.</summary>
</bill>
