<bill session="108" type="h" number="3589" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-22T19:03:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-22T19:03:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create the Office of Chief Financial Officer of the Government of the Virgin Islands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400073"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2426"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-04">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-07-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-07T15:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-645.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-09-07T15:54:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="389">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 389.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Neugebauer moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7397-7399" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3589.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-09-22T19:03:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7397-7398" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Chief financial officers"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Local budgets"/>
    <term name="Management information systems"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2004--Passed House amended.
(Sec. 1) Requires the Governor of the Virgin Islands to appoint a Chief Financial Officer, with the advice and consent of the Legislature of the Virgin Islands, from a list required by this Act. States that if: (1) the Legislature has not confirmed a nominee within 90 days the Governor shall appoint an Acting Chief Financial Officer until the Legislature consents to a Chief Financial Officer; and (2) a Chief Financial Officer has not been appointed within 180 days the Virgin Islands Chief Financial Officer Search Commission shall appoint from such list an Acting Chief Financial Officer until a Chief Financial Officer is appointed. Sets forth the Chief Financial Officer's duties, including: (1) assumption of the functions and authority of the Office of Management and Budget; and (2) budget and financial management systems oversight. Transfers the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to the Chief Financial Officer. Alters the position of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to that of the Deputy Chief Financial Officer. Implements such changes for a five-year period. (Sec. 2) Establishes the Virgin Islands Chief Financial Officer Search Commission to recommend at least three candidates for the Chief Financial Officer position. Terminates the Commission 210 days after its first meeting. (Sec. 3) Authorizes appropriations for the installation of a Financial Management System, including appropriate computer hardware and software, to the Government of the Virgin Islands. States that such system shall be available to the Chief Financial Officer, and five years after the date of enactment of this Act, to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget of the Virgin Islands. (Sec. 5) States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to permit the Governor and Legislature of the Virgin Islands to delegate or otherwise alter the powers and authority of the Office of Management and Budget established under the laws of the Virgin Islands.</summary>
</bill>
