<bill session="104" type="h" number="1900" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Clean Air Act to exempt agriculture-related facilities from certain permitting requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="1996-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400578" joined="1995-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1995-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="1995-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1995-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1995-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="490"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agricultural industries"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control equipment"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Grain storage"/>
    <term name="Grain trade"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Clean Air Act to add specified definitions relating to agriculture-related facilities (grain elevators, grain, feed, or rice mills, or grain processing facilities). Defines "potential to emit" as the potential of a facility to emit during a one-year period under maximum realistic operation. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in determining the maximum realistic operation of an agriculture-related facility, to consider: (1) the cyclical or seasonal nature of the facility; and (2) the maximum hours of operation of the facility that actually occurred during any of the preceding five years in the case of a facility in operation on the date of determination. Requires the Administrator to consider the effect of control equipment and techniques in lowering the potential to emit of an agriculture-related facility. Exempts a source from permitting requirements if the source is not a major source and is subject to emissions standards for new stationary sources or requirements for stationary sources of hazardous air pollutants.</summary>
</bill>
