<bill session="105" type="h" number="3439" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Credit Union Community Reinvestment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to require insured credit unions to meet the credit needs of the community served by the credit union.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1998-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Community development banking"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/1998--Introduced.
Credit Union Community Reinvestment Act - Amends the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to declare that: (1) the field of membership of a credit union shall be treated as the community served by such union; and (2) insured credit unions have a continuing and affirmative obligation to help meet the credit needs of the community served by such unions. Directs the National Credit Union Administration Board to: (1) exercise its authority under the Federal Credit Union Act to encourage any insured credit union whose total assets exceed $25 million to help meet the credit needs of the community it serves; and (2) take such a credit union's record of meeting those needs into account in its evaluation of any application to expand the credit union's field of membership or to establish a deposit facility. Authorizes Board deference to the State regulator of a credit union for enforcement of any State law requirements that are no less stringent than those of the Act.</summary>
</bill>
