<bill session="105" type="h" number="99" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:25-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bipartisan Commission on Campaign Practices Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a temporary commission to recommend reforms in the laws relating to elections for Federal office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1997-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1997-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1997-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Rules and Organization of the House.</text>
      <committee name="House Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSRU" name="House Rules"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" name="House Rules" subcommittee="Rules and Organization of the House"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Incumbency"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>01/07/1997--Introduced.
Bipartisan Commission on Campaign Practices Act of 1997 - Establishes the Bipartisan Commission on Campaign Practices. Directs the Commission to study the laws relating to elections for Federal office and to report and recommend legislation to reform those laws. (Sec. 7) Requires the Commission to report on its activities to the Congress not later than 90 days after the selection of the Chair of the Commission. Directs that if seven or more members concur on a recommendation, those members shall prepare and submit with the report legislation to implement the recommendation. Provides for expedited congressional consideration of any legislation the substance of which implements a recommendation of the Commission. (Sec. 8) Sets forth the primary objectives of the Commission. (Sec. 9) Terminates the Commission 60 days after the submission of its report. (Sec. 10) Authorizes to be appropriated to the Commission such sums as are necessary to carry out its duties.</summary>
</bill>
