<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="137" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:05-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="1904" sequence="2"/>
  <status datetime="2003-05-20T16:00:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-05-20"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to add the text of the Hazardous Fuels Reduction Act; allow projects within 1/2 mile of threatened communities to be excluded from the National Environmental Policy Act; codify guidance regarding environmental documents for projects outside the 1/2 mile zone; provide a process that brings communities and Federal land managers together to identify areas in need of thinning; give new authority for Federal land managers to enter into cooperative agreements with local governments and communities to plan projects across public and private ownership boundaries; and require that 85 percent of funding be used for areas close to homes, communities, and watersheds.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Part B of House Report 108-239 would allow for projects within one-half mile of threatened communities to be "categorically excluded" from the National Environmental Policy Act; to codify the Bush Administration's guidance to regarding the preparation environmental documents for projects in watersheds and outside of the one-half mile zone; would focus critical federal resources on the need to protect communities; would provide for an up-front collaborative process that brings communities and federal land managers together to identify and prioritize areas most in need of thinning; would give new authority to federal land managers to enter into cooperative agreements with local and state governments, local fire districts, and homeowner associations to plan projects across ownership boundaries; and would require that 85 percent of funding be spent around homes, communities, or in a watershed.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. George Miller.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4310-4322" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4310-4312" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2003-05-20T16:00:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="198">
      <text>On agreeing to the Miller, George amendment (A002) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 184 - 239 (Roll no. 198).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
