<bill session="104" type="h" number="3972" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Women Veterans' Health Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve health care services provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs to women veterans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1996-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Breast cancer"/>
    <term name="Cancer research"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular diseases"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Demography"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Gynecology"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Homeless veterans"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Mammography"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Psychiatry"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Reproduction"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in medicine"/>
    <term name="Women veterans"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/1996--Introduced.
Women Veterans' Health Act of 1996 - Specifies the services to be included as women's health services in the Department of Veterans Affairs. Allows those services provided on an ambulatory or outpatient basis to be procured by contract when Department facilities are not capable of furnishing economical hospital care or medical services because of geographical inaccessibility or otherwise. (Sec. 3) Makes permanent (currently terminates on December 31, 1998) a Department program providing sexual trauma counseling and treatment to women veterans. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to report to the veterans' committees on the provision of health care services and the conduct of research carried out by the Department relating to women veterans. Requires such report to be prepared through the Center for Women Veterans. (Sec. 5) Authorizes the Secretary to waive a requirement that women and other minority veterans be included as subjects in Department clinical health research. Directs the Secretary to foster and encourage research on specified gender-specific matters relating to women (breast cancer, gynecological and reproductive health, and sexual trauma), as well as non-gender-specific matters (HIV and AIDS, substance abuse, aging, and cardiac care). Requires certain Department personnel to be involved in such research. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to study and report to the veterans' committees concerning the needs of women veterans for health care services. Requires a representative sampling of all categories of women veterans in such study. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to ensure that: (1) homeless women veterans are included in homeless veterans' outreach programs and services; and (2) women veterans who receive Department psychiatric treatment, especially for sexual trauma, receive such treatment in a safe and effective manner that recognizes their privacy needs. (Sec. 9) Makes applicable to Department mammography services and facilities the mammography quality standards promulgated under the Public Health Service Act. Extends the deadline for meeting such requirements. (Sec. 10) Requires, with respect to the Center for Women Veterans: (1) adequate clerical support to carry out the functions of the Director of the Center; and (2) an Associate Director.</summary>
</bill>
