<bill session="106" type="h" number="248" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Cruise Tourism Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit the transportaion of passengers between United States ports by certain foreign-flag vessels and to encourage United States-flag vessels to participate in such transportation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400607"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1999-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="1999-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Coastwise shipping"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flags of convenience"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine insurance"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
United States Cruise Tourism Act of 1999 - Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to approve the transportation of passengers on foreign-flag cruise vessels not otherwise qualified to engage in the coastwise trade between ports in the United States, directly or by way of a foreign port, except with respect to coastwise trade served by a U.S.-flag cruise vessel. Requires termination of any such foreign-flag cruise vessel passenger service within three years after a U.S.-flag cruise vessel commences such service between the same ports. Requires the owner or charterer of a qualified foreign-flag cruise vessel to have any vessel repairs performed in the United States, unless the vessel requires repairs or service while at a distant foreign port. Directs the Secretary to terminate the coastwise trade privileges of the owner or charterer of a foreign-flag cruise vessel if such repairs have not been made in the United States. Provides for a waiver of such requirements in emergencies. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize an immigration officer to extend for a period or periods of up to six months each a conditional permit to land temporarily in the United States granted to an alien crewman employed on a vessel, if the vessel owner or charterer requests the extension and the immigration officer determines that it is necessary to maintain the vessel in the coastwise trade between ports in the United States, directly or by way of a foreign port.</summary>
</bill>
