<bill session="108" type="h" number="2596" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-26T18:53:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-26T18:53:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Savings and Affordability Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Health Savings and Affordability Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a deduction to individuals for amounts contributed to health savings security accounts and health savings accounts, to provide for the disposition of unused health benefits in cafeteria plans and flexible spending arrangements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26T06:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 299 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1 and H.R. 2596 with 3 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. Amendment in the nature of a substitute by, and if offered by, Mr. Rangel is debatable for one hour. H.R. 2596 shall be considered in the House and after final adoption, shall be appended to the text of H.R. 1. H.R. 2596 will then be laid on the table. Concurrent resolutions providing for adjournment of the House and Senate in July shall be in order for consideration. Finally, the Committee on Appropriations shall have until midnight on Thursday, July 3, 2003 to file a report making appropriations for</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 299 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26T17:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 299.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5952-6006" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26T17:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1 and H.R. 2596 with 3 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. Amendment in the nature of a substitute by, and if offered by, Mr. Rangel is debatable for one hour. H.R. 2596 shall be considered in the House and after final adoption, shall be appended to the text of H.R. 1. H.R. 2596 will then be laid on the table. Concurrent resolutions providing for adjournment of the House and Senate in July shall be in order for consideration. Finally, the Committee on Appropriations shall have until midnight on Thursday, July 3, 2003 to file a report making appropriations for</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26T17:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 2596.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-06-26T18:53:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="328" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 237 - 191 (Roll no. 328).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5992-5997" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-27T02:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 299, the text of H.R. 2596 was appended to the text of H.R. 1 as new matter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-27T02:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 299, H.R. 2596 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="hr" number="299"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="299"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="hr" number="299"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="1"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="1"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Preferred provider organizations (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2003--Passed House without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)Health Savings and Affordability Act of 2003 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a limited deduction (to both itemizers and nonitemizers) for contributions to health savings security accounts (accounts for medical expenses for anyone, except those with an individual deductible under $500 or $1,000 for a family) and health savings accounts (accounts for medical expenses for those in a high deductible plan, a plan with an individual deductible of $1,000 to $2,250 or $2,000 and $4,500 for a family and with individual out-of-pocket expenses not exceeding $3,000 or $5,500 for a family). Provides for cost-of-living adjustments to such amounts. Exempts such accounts, and distributions from such accounts, from taxation.Subjects employers making contributions to such accounts to an excise tax, if they do not make comparable contributions on behalf of all employees.(Sec. 3) Allows up to $500 of unused health benefits in cafeteria plans and flexible spending arrangements to be carried forward to the next year, contributed to a health savings security or health savings account, or contributed to a qualified retirement plan.(Sec. 4) Exempts flexible spending arrangements and health reimbursement arrangements treated as employer-provided coverage from information reporting requirements related to certain health arrangements.</summary>
</bill>
