<bill session="107" type="hj" number="64" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-09-14T23:17:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-09-14T23:17:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Authorization for Use of Military Force</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Authorization for Use of Military Force</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the use of United States Armed Forces against those responsible for the recent attacks launched against the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="2001-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-14T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. Diaz-Balart asked that it shall be in order at any time without intervention of any point of order to consider in the House H.J. Res 64; the joint resolution shall be considered as read; the previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) five hours of debate on the joint resolution equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on International Relations; and (2) one motion to recommit; and upon passage of the joint resolution, the House shall be considered to have passed S. J. Res. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-14T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated by previous order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-14T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by previous order of the House.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5638-5683" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-14T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order, the House preceeded with five hours of debate on H.J. Res 64.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-14T22:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-14T22:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Tierney moved to recommit with instructions to International Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5681-5682" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5681" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-14T22:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion. The instructions contained in the motion require the committee on International Relations to report the bill back to the House with an amendment adding a new section 3 to the Joint Resolution. The proposed section 3 would require the President to report to Congress at least once every 60 days after the enactment of the joint resolution on the status of efforts made to carry out the resolution and to further stipulate that reporting and consultation requirements of the War Powers Act be adhered to.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-14T22:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-14T22:49:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-09-14T23:17:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="342" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 420 - 1 (Roll no. 342).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-09-14T23:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-14T23:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Laid on the table. See S.J. Res. 23 for further action.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="sj" number="23"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="President as Commander-in-Chief"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2001--Passed House without amendment.
Authorization for Use of Military Force - Authorizes the President to use all necessary and appropriate force against those nations, organizations, or persons he determines planned, authorized, committed, or aided the terrorist attacks that occurred on September 11, 2001, or harbored such organizations or persons, in order to prevent any future acts of international terrorism against the United States by such nations, organizations, or persons.States that this Act is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within the meaning of the War Powers Resolution.</summary>
</bill>
