<bill session="104" type="h" number="2170" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the establishment of the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Authority, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1995-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1995-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1995-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1995-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1995-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1995-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-08">
      <text>See H.R.2274.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2274"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Interstate commissions"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/1995--Introduced.
Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Act of 1995 - Grants consent to the Commonwealth of Virginia, the State of Maryland, and the District of Columbia to enter into an interstate agreement or compact (compact) to establish the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Authority and to designate its governance, powers, and duties. Considers the Authority to be established upon execution of the compact and an agreement between the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) and the signatories regarding the Federal share of the project's cost (agreement) and the terms and conditions related to the timing of the Bridge's transfer to the Authority. (Sec. 6) Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) governance by a board of directors (Board); (2) qualifications of Board members; (3) failure of a Capitol region jurisdiction to appoint a member; (4) personal liability of members; and (5) a residency requirement for members. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary, after the signatories enter into the agreement, to convey all right, title, and interest (rights) of the Department of Transportation in and to the Bridge to the Authority, subject to specified interim responsibilities. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to transfer to the Authority all rights in and to such land under or adjacent to the Bridge as necessary to carry out the project. (Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary and the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration (FHA) to: (1) continue working with the parties which comprise the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Coordination Committee (established and chaired by the FHA and comprised of representatives of Federal, State, and local governments) or with the Authority to complete, at the earliest possible date, environmental studies and documentation, planning, preliminary engineering efforts, and related work, consistent with applicable Federal law; and (2) on or before October 1, 1996, transmit to the Congress a report on the selected alternative, implementation schedule, and costs of the project, and a recommended Federal share of the project cost. (Sec. 9) Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) additional powers and responsibilities of the Authority; (2) funding; and (3) availability of prior authorizations. Repeals provisions of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 regarding authorization for bridge rehabilitation.</summary>
</bill>
