<bill session="108" type="h" number="3525" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Citizen Legislature and Political Freedom Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to reform the financing of campaigns for election for Federal office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="2003-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400169" joined="2003-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2003-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2003-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="2003-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2003-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-19">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-19">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Checkoff"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2003--Introduced.
Citizen Legislature and Political Freedom Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to terminate limitations on Federal election campaign contributions after 2004. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to terminate after December 31, 2003, the designation of income tax payments to the Presidential Election Campaign Fund. Terminates the Fund itself and the Presidential Primary Matching Payment Account after December 31, 2004, and transfers any amounts remaining in the Fund to the general fund of the Treasury. Amends FECA, as amended by the Bipartisan Campaign Reform Act of 2002, to require any political committee of a State or local political party to file with the Federal Election Commission a copy of any report on disbursements it is required under a State or local law, rule, or regulation to submit to the State or local government. Revises current deadlines for notification of contributions by a campaign committee. Requires a campaign committee to report within 24 hours all contributions, regardless of amount, made to any political committee within 90 days before an election. Declares that the "best efforts" exception to noncompliance with FECA shall not apply with respect to information regarding the identification of any contributor of more than $200 in the aggregate during a calendar year (thus requiring strict observance of reporting deadlines for all such contributions).</summary>
</bill>
