<bill session="106" type="h" number="1678" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airline Competition and Fairness Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Transportation to initiate investigations of unfair methods of competition by major air carriers against new entrant air carriers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1999-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="1999-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="1999-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airline rates"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/1999--Introduced.
Airline Competition and Fairness Act of 1999 - Amends Federal aviation law to direct the Secretary of Transportation, whenever a major air carrier is competing with a new entrant air carrier in providing air transportation on a route between a hub airport and another airport, to investigate whether the major air carrier has been or is engaged in an unfair method of competition if: (1) the major air carrier has added seat capacity on the route and has sold such a large number of seats on it at very low fares that the ensuing self-diversion of revenue has resulted in lower local revenue than would have resulted from a reasonable alternative response by the major air carrier to the competition; or (2) the number of passengers that the major air carrier has carried on the route at the new entrant air carrier's low fares has exceeded the new entrant air carrier's total seat capacity (or the number of low-fare passengers carried by the new entrant carrier) on such route, resulting in lower local revenue than would have resulted from a reasonable alternative response by the major air carrier to the competition.</summary>
</bill>
