<bill session="107" type="hc" number="427" updated="2013-07-14T18:59:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the imposition of trade sanctions on nations that are undermining the effectiveness of conservation and management measures for Atlantic marlin adopted by the International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas and that are threatening the continued viability of United States commercial and recreational fisheries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400149"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2002-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="2002-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International fishery management"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2002--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should: (1) direct the U.S. Commissioners to the International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas to make Atlantic marlin conservation their highest priority; (2) encourage countries that fish in Commission regulatory areas to make every effort to end illegal, unregulated, and unreported fishing, including fishing that is not in compliance with Commission conservation recommendations especially with regard to Atlantic marlin mortality; (3) make full use of all appropriate diplomatic mechanisms, relevant international laws and agreements, and other appropriate mechanisms to ensure Commission compliance with conservation recommendations for all species under the Commission's management authority, including Atlantic marlin; and (4) encourage the Commission to adopt conservation recommendations authorizing the use of enforceable measures, including World Trade Organization-consistent trade measures and imposition of an import embargo, to prevent such nations that fish in the Commission regulatory area from taking actions that would undermine the effectiveness of conservation recommendations of the Commission.Declares that, if any vessel of a nation fishes in the Atlantic Ocean without complying with the Commission's conservation recommendations, such fishing should be considered to diminish the effectiveness of international fishery conservation recommendations and, therefore, such nation should be considered to be subject to import embargo under the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975 and certifiable under the Fishermen's Protective Act of 1967.</summary>
</bill>
