<bill session="106" type="h" number="1334" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FQPA Implementation Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the enhanced implementation of the amendments made to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act by the Food Quality Protection Act of 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400228"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="1999-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="1999-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1999-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400592" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1999-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1999-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1999-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="1999-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1999-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, EPA.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received from EPA.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pesticide residues in food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1999--Introduced.
FQPA Implementation Act of 1999 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, upon determining that there may be grounds for modifying, suspending, or revoking a tolerance or exemption for a pesticide chemical residue in or on food, from taking any such action until considering any additional data submitted to support the continuation of a tolerance or exemption. Makes certain requirements for the Administrator's review of tolerances and exemptions for pesticide chemical residues in effect before the enactment of the Food Quality Protection Act of 1996 (FQPA) that relate to periods of time applicable only to the extent determined by the Administrator to be in the public interest. (Current law requires specified percentages of such tolerances and exemptions to be reviewed by certain dates.) Authorizes the Administrator to issue a tolerance or exemption associated with an emergency exemption without regard to other tolerances or exemptions for the pesticide chemical residue and before reassessing such tolerances and exemptions if the Administrator determines that any incremental exposure that may result from the tolerance or exemption associated with the emergency exemption alone will not pose any significant dietary risk. Directs the Administrator to report to Congress on financial resources needed for FY 2001 through 2005 to carry out the amendments made by the FQPA to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to report to Congress the financial resources needed for such fiscal years in order to carry out responsibilities under the FQPA. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a program to monitor continuously the competitive strength of major U.S. agricultural commodity sectors in the international marketplace; (2) examine factors pertinent to assessing, by sector, the sustainability and competitive strength in the international marketplace and the relationship of such factors to regulatory decisions issued under the amendments made by the FQPA; and (3) submit periodic reports on such requirements and factors to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
