<bill session="107" type="h" number="2513" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State Prescription Drug Flexibility Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to clarify that the Secretary of Health and Human Services has the authority to treat certain State payments made in an approved demonstration project as medical assistance under the Medicaid Program for purposes of a rebate agreement under section 1927 of the Social Security Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400007"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="2001-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="2001-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2001-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2001--Introduced.
Access to Affordable Prescription Drugs Act of 2001 - Amends title XI of the Social Security Act (SSA) with respect to any State-conducted demonstration project approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services before January 1, 2001, that waives compliance with, or makes inapplicable, certain State plan requirements for establishing an outpatient prescription drug program for residents of the State not otherwise eligible for medical assistance under Medicaid (SSA title XIX). Provides that any expenditures by the State for covered outpatient drugs under the demonstration project will be treated as payments under the State Medicaid plan for covered outpatient drugs for purposes of a rebate agreement, regardless of whether such expenditures are offset or reimbursed, in whole or in part, by rebates received under such an agreement. States that such expenditures are consistent with the objectives of the Medicaid program and are to be considered amounts expended for medical assistance in the form of prescribed drugs under the State Medicaid plan. Makes certain Medicaid requirements inapplicable to any enrollment fees, premiums, deductions, copayments, cost sharing, or similar charges imposed upon individuals participating in the demonstration project.</summary>
</bill>
