<bill session="107" type="h" number="5456" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to maintain flight restrictions over major sporting events and other major open assemblies of people.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400414"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2002-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports facilities"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2002--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Transportation to maintain the restrictions imposed under specified Federal Aviation Administration Notices to Airmen (relating to flight restrictions over major sporting events and other major open assemblies of people). Cancels any existing waiver of or exemption from such restrictions. Prohibits the Secretary from granting any new waivers or exemptions to waivers for aircraft, except a waiver to any aircraft, approved by the Under Secretary for Security of the Transportation Security Administration, to provide aerial television coverage and an aerial security platform for security personnel for any event covered under the Notices. Requires in such an instance that such Notices adhere to security requirements set forth by the Transportation Security Administration.</summary>
</bill>
