<bill session="104" type="h" number="621" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Act of January 26, 1915, establishing Rocky Mountain National Park, to provide for the protection of certain lands in Rocky Mountain National Park and along North St. Vrain Creek and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409954"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300003" joined="1996-05-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E144"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-26">
      <text>Measure incorporated in H.R. 2292.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/20/1995--Introduced.
Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior or any other Federal agency or officer from approving or issuing any permit for, or providing any assistance for, the construction of any new dam, reservoir, or impoundment on any segment of North St. Vrain Creek or its tributaries within the boundaries of the Rocky Mountain National Park or on the main stem of the Creek downstream to the point at which it crosses the elevation 6550 feet above mean sea level. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent the issuance of any permit for the construction of a new water gaging station on the Creek at the point of its confluence with Coulson Gulch. Directs the Secretary to seek to acquire by donation or exchange certain lands within the boundaries of the Park owned by Longmont, Colorado. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to pursue and report to the Congress biennially on negotiations with Longmont, Colorado, concerning the city's proposed exchange of lands located in and near Coulson Gulch for Federal lands.</summary>
</bill>
