<bill session="104" type="h" number="1481" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the regulatory authority of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation with respect to deposit insurance fund management, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E855, E857"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Financing Corporation"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Resolution Trust Corporation"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/1995--Introduced.
Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Home Loan Bank Act (FHLBA) to require the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC), after consultation with the Financing Corporation (FICO), (currently, FICO, with FDIC Board approval) to place a prescribed assessment against each Savings Association Insurance Fund (SAIF) member in order to cover interest payments, issuance costs, and custodial fees of certain FICO obligations. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (FDIA) to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to provide to the FDIC, upon its request, certain funds not needed by the Resolution Trust Corporation (RTC), in order to cover the same FICO costs. Authorizes the FDIC to transfer, for an appropriate period of time, up to a certain percentage of a fund's assessment base between the Bank Insurance Fund (BIF) and the SAIF as necessary to achieve or maintain the designated reserve ratio of the transferee fund. Amends the FDIA to authorize the FDIC to impose a one-time special SAIF capitalization assessment. Reformulates the designated reserve ratio for each deposit insurance fund to establish a minimum instead of a target amount. Empowers the FDIC Board of Directors to reduce semiannual assessments if an insurance fund's reserve ratio is equal to or greater than its minimum designated reserve ratio. Mandates that insurance assessments be used primarily for insurance fund purposes and not be unduly diverted to other uses. Amends the FHLBA to include within FICO assessment authority specified SAIF members as well as BIF members whose deposits are treated as insured by the SAIF. Amends the FDIA to repeal the minimum assessment requirements for any insured deposit insurance fund (including the SAIF).</summary>
</bill>
