<bill session="106" type="hr" number="292" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-28T14:22:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-09-28T14:22:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the referendum in East Timor, calling on the Government of Indonesia to assist in the termination of the current civil unrest and violence in East Timor, and supporting a United Nations Security Council-endorsed multinational force for East Timor.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1999-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="1999-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1999-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1999-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1999-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1999-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1999-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1999-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-09-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8155"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28T10:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28T10:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8879-8886, H8908" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28T10:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 292.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28T11:11:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28T14:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1999-09-28T14:22:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="454" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 390 - 38, 1 Present (Roll no. 454).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Annexation (International law)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="East Timor"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Logistics"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="National self-determination"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations employees"/>
    <term name="United Nations technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1999--Passed House amended.
Congratulates the people of East Timor on their participation in the August 30, 1999, popular consultation and commends United Nations (UN) Mission in East Timor (UNAMET) personnel for their support. Recognizes the expression of the people of East Timor in favor of independence from Indonesia. Condemns the violent efforts of East Timor militias and elements of the Indonesian military to overturn the results of the vote and notes the failure of the Government of Indonesia to guarantee the security of the people of East Timor. Calls upon such Government to: (1) recognize its responsibilities to cooperate with appropriate UN authorities in the restoration of order in, and the safe return of refugees and other displaced persons to, East Timor; and (2) allow unrestricted access to refugees and displaced persons in West Timor and elsewhere and to guarantee their safety. Urges the international community to investigate the human rights abuses and atrocities which occurred with respect to the situation in East Timor subsequent to August 30 and calls upon the Indonesian Government to hold those responsible accountable. Expresses approval of: (1) the U.S. decision to suspend military relations with, and the sale of military weapons or equipment to, the Indonesian Government until the Indonesian military has effectively cooperated with the international community in facilitating East Timor's transition to independence; (2) Indonesia's belated decision to allow the UN Security Council-endorsed multi-national force into East Timor; and (3) U.S. logistical and other technical support for deployment of such force. Expresses support for a rapid and effective deployment (but declares that this shall not constitute a waiver, or be construed as authority, under the War Powers Act), commends Australia for its willingness to lead the force and for rapidly deploying its initial contingent, and welcomes and commends other specified nations that will participate in this force. Urges: (1) the United States to consider additional measures, including the suspension of bilateral and international financial assistance to the Indonesian Government should it curtail or suspend cooperation with the multi-national force in East Timor, interfere with the full deployment of the multi-national force, hinder the operation of UNAMET, hinder the safe return of refugees and displaced persons to East Timor, or otherwise interfere with the restoration of order and respect for human rights in East Timor; and (2) the Indonesian People's Consultative Assembly to expeditiously ratify the August 30 vote and to otherwise speed the transition to full independence for East Timor. Recognizes that an effective U.S. policy for the region requires both an effective near-term response to the ongoing humanitarian crisis in, and progress toward independence for, East Timor and a long-term strategy for supporting stability, security, and democracy in Indonesia and East Timor.</summary>
</bill>
