<bill session="104" type="h" number="2690" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Genetic Privacy and Nondiscrimination Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish limitation with respect to the disclosure and use of genetic information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1996-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404298" joined="1996-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="404634" joined="1996-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404869" joined="1996-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1996-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="406082" joined="1996-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1996-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1996-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1996-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400398" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1996-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Government Reform and Oversight, and Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2844-2845"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6426-6427"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="1416"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Bioethics"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="DNA fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Death and dying"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Genetic screening"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Human genetics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Juvenile courts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Paternity"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/29/1995--Introduced.
Genetic Privacy and Nondiscrimination Act of 1995 - Establishes limitations with respect to the disclosure and use of genetic information. Prohibits disclosure of genetic information about an individual unless specifically authorized by the individual involved, or the individual's legal representative, through a written authorization which includes a description of the information being disclosed, the name of the individual or entity to whom the disclosure is being made, and the purpose of the disclosure. Allows such a disclosure if it is: (1) authorized under Federal or State criminal laws relating to the identification of individuals, or as is necessary for the purpose of a criminal or death investigation, a criminal or juvenile proceeding, an inquest, or a child fatality review by a multidisciplinary child abuse team; (2) required under the specific order of a Federal or State court; (3) authorized under Federal or State law for the purpose of establishing paternity; (4) intended to furnish genetic information relating to a decedent to the decedent's blood relatives for the purpose of medical diagnosis; or (5) intended for the identification of bodies. (Sec. 5) Prohibits any employer from seeking to obtain, obtaining, or using the genetic information of an employee or a prospective employee, or requiring a genetic test of an employee or prospective employee, to distinguish between or discriminate against or restrict any right or benefit otherwise due or available to the employee or prospective employee. Provides for enforcement of such prohibition through the same powers, procedures, and remedies that are provided to a person alleging a violation under specified provisions of the Civil Rights Act of 1964. (Sec. 6) Prohibits an insurer offering health insurance from using genetic information to reject, deny, limit, cancel, refuse to renew, increase the rates of, or otherwise affect health insurance. Requires, if an insurer requests that an insurance applicant (other than a health insurance applicant) take a genetic test, that: (1) the use of the results of such test be disclosed to the applicant; and (2) the insurer obtain the applicant's specific written authorization for such disclosure. Prohibits an insurer from using such a genetic test as an inducement for the purchase of insurance. (Sec. 7) Directs the National Bioethics Advisory Commission to report to the appropriate congressional committees its recommendations on the development and implementation of appropriate standards: (1) to provide increased protection for the collection, storage, and use of identifiable DNA samples and genetic information obtained from those samples; and (2) for the acquisition and retention of genetic information in all settings, including appropriate exceptions.</summary>
</bill>
