<bill session="104" type="h" number="1318" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Education Elimination Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the elimination of the Department of Education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1995-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="405033" joined="1995-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1995-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1995-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/1995--Introduced.
Department of Education Elimination Act of 1995 - Eliminates the Department of Education as of January 1, 1998. Directs the Secretary of Education, prior to such date, to: (1) consolidate into a block grant program those programs that are administered by the Department and are appropriate for States to administer; and (2) otherwise provide for the complete elimination of the Department. Directs the Secretary to submit to the Congress: (1) a strategic plan with recommendations for legislation to carry out such elimination and block grant program, and for transfers of functions and activities to other Federal or State agencies; and (2) a report with a plan and recommendations for such transfer of programs and agencies considered appropriate for continued Federal administration to other existing departments and abolishment of unnecessary programs and agencies, and with a description of projected cost savings to the Federal Government. Requires the Director of the Congressional Budget Office to submit to a specified congressional committee a list of recommendations for minimizing the cost of Federal education programs through the elimination of the Department. Directs the Comptroller General to report to such congressional committee with recommendations for the most efficient means of achieving the complete elimination of the Department and the transfer of appropriate functions to other existing or successor Federal or State agencies.</summary>
</bill>
