<bill session="104" type="h" number="43" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bombing Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the regulation of explosives and explosive materials, and to prevent the use of explosives against persons and the unlawful use of explosives against property.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1996-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1995-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1995-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404298" joined="1995-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1995-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1995-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1996-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1995-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1996-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1995-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1995-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1995-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1995-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1995-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1995-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="411314" joined="1995-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9384"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Plastics"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: General Reforms Title II: Plastic Explosives Bombing Prevention Act - Title I: General Reforms - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit the transport, shipment, or receipt of explosive materials without a permit or the distribution of explosive materials to anyone other than a licensee or permittee. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to notify the States of the regulations so that they may consider revising their explosives laws. (Sec. 102) Requires applicants for licenses and user permits to import, manufacture, or deal in explosive materials to provide fingerprints and a photograph. Sets fees of up to $300 for an applicant for a license and up to $100 for an applicant for a permit. (Currently, the fee is up to $200 for each license or permit.) (Sec. 103) Authorizes the Secretary to use the national instant criminal background check system established under the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to investigate applicants for licenses or permits. (Sec. 104) Repeals exceptions from specified explosive materials requirements with respect to components of small arms ammunition and small quantities of black powder or smokeless powder. (Sec. 105) Directs the United States Sentencing Commission to promulgate amendments to the sentencing guidelines to appropriately enhance the penalties for violations of Federal explosive materials provisions so that such penalties are the same as those for comparable violations of Federal firearms laws. (Sec. 106) Permits: (1) the destruction of seized explosives that are unsafe under specified circumstances; and (2) the owner to apply to the Secretary for reimbursement of any destroyed property where the claimant establishes that the seizure was wrongful. (Sec. 107) Subjects to civil forfeiture (with exceptions) any property involved in a violation of explosive materials provisions, or in a conspiracy to commit such a violation, and any other property traceable to such property. Directs the court to order a person convicted of a violation of Federal explosive materials provisions or of conspiring to commit such a violation to forfeit any property involved and any traceable property. Title II: Plastic Explosives - Prohibits the manufacture, import, export, shipment, transport, transfer, receipt, or possession of any plastic explosive which does not contain a detection agent (with exceptions). Authorizes the Secretary to investigate violations. Directs the Attorney General to exercise authority over such violations only when they are committed by a member of a terrorist or revolutionary group (in which case the Attorney General shall have primary investigative responsibility and the Secretary shall assist as requested). Prohibits any person possessing any plastic explosive, other than an agency of the United States or the National Guard of any State, from failing to report to the Secretary the quantity of such explosive possessed, the manufacturer or importer, and any identifying marks on such explosives. (Sec. 203) Provides for a fine and up to ten years' imprisonment for violations of Federal explosive materials laws. (Sec. 204) Sets forth affirmative defenses for Federal explosive materials laws.</summary>
</bill>
