<bill session="105" type="h" number="4201" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Assistant United States Attorneys Retirement Benefit Equity Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that the provisions of subchapter III of chapter 83 and chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, that apply with respect to law enforcement officers be made applicable with respect to Assistant United States Attorneys.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/1998--Introduced.
Assistant United States Attorneys Retirement Benefit Equity Act of 1998 - Makes applicable to Assistant United States Attorneys the provisions of the Civil Service Retirement System and the Federal Employees Retirement System that apply to law enforcement officers. Directs the Department of Justice to provide notice to incumbent Assistant U.S. Attorneys of their election rights under this Act and the consequences of making or not making a timely election. Allows such incumbents to elect the option to be treated either: (1) in accordance with the amendments made by this Act; or (2) in the same way as if this Act had never been enacted. Treats failure to make a timely election in the same way as an election made under the first option on the last day allowable. Makes an election ineffective unless it is made before the 90th day after the date on which the notice is provided or the date on which the incumbent separates from service, whichever is earlier. Applies the amendments made by this Act retroactively in the case of any incumbent who elects the first option and provides for makeup contributions.</summary>
</bill>
