<bill session="105" type="h" number="3299" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Genetic Privacy and Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish limitation with respect to the disclosure and use of genetic information in connection with group health plans and health insurance coverage, to provide for consistant standards applicable in connection with hospital care and medical services provided under title 38 of the United States Code, to prohibit employment discrimination on the basis of genetic information and genetic testing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1998-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bioethics"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="DNA"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Genetic screening"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical genetics"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/1998--Introduced.
Family Genetic Privacy and Protection Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to prohibit a group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group coverage, from discriminating in eligibility based on a request for, or receipt of, genetic information or a genetic test. Prohibits such entities from: (1) using genetic information to discriminate in issuance, renewal, premium rates, or benefits; or (2) disclosing or being compelled, by subpoena or any other means, subject to exception, to disclose genetic information about an individual unless authorized by the individual. Amends the Public Health Service Act to apply these prohibitions to coverage in the individual market. Amends Federal law relating to veterans' benefits to mandate standards, consistent with the prohibitions in this Act, regarding genetic information use and disclosure in connection with medical care provided under those provisions. Makes it an unlawful employment practice for an employer to attempt to acquire, acquire, or use genetic information, or to require a genetic test, of an employee or applicant to discriminate or restrict any right or benefit. Regulates employer disclosure of and access to genetic information. Provides for enforcement through the powers, remedies, and procedures in specified provisions of the Civil Rights Act of 1964. Establishes the National Bipartisan Commission on the Use of Genetic Information to make recommendations with respect to the development and implementation of standards: (1) to provide increased protection for the collection, storage, and use of identifiable DNA samples and genetic information obtained from those samples; and (2) for the acquisition and retention of genetic information in all settings, but in particular clinical settings, including appropriate exceptions. Requires the Commission to report to the President and the Congress on its recommendations, findings, and conclusions. Terminates the Commission 30 days after submission of such report.</summary>
</bill>
