<bill session="104" type="h" number="2007" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles 5, 31, and 37 of the United States Code to provide for the continuance of pay and the authority to make certain expenditures and obligations during lapses in appropriations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400544"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400569" joined="1995-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="1995-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1995-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="1995-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1995-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1995-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1995-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400609" joined="1995-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1995-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government employees' life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/1995--Introduced.
Amends Federal civil service law to provide for the continuance of civilian pay at current levels during periods of lapsed appropriations. Provides for an automatic continuing appropriation for the U.S. Government whenever a regular appropriation bill for a fiscal year does not become law prior to the beginning of such fiscal year. Provides that such funds shall be appropriated at a rate not in excess of the lower of the rate provided for such expenditure or obligation in the corresponding appropriation Act for the preceding fiscal year or the rate provided for in the House or Senate appropriation bill for the present fiscal year. Sets forth the terms and conditions relating to such continuing appropriations. Excludes certain operations from the provisions of this Act if during the fiscal year any other provision of law: (1) makes an appropriation, makes funds available, or grants continuation authority for such project or activity for such period; or (2) specifically prohibits funding or authority for such project or activity for such period. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to develop a plan for the orderly shutdown of all or any part of the Government during a period of lapsed appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
