<bill session="104" type="h" number="4266" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">White Collar Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to prescribe a salary base for an exemption of an employee from the wage requirements of such Act and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400318"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1789-1790"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="White collar workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Introduced.
White Collar Reform Act - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exempt from its wage requirements employees whose rate of annual compensation, including specified elements, is at least $40,000. Revises requirements for exemptions based on an employee's administrative capacity to provide that the determination of whether such capacity is bona fide shall not take into consideration the relationship between an employee's job duties and the management policies or general business operations of the employer or the employer's customers. Prohibits, in determining whether the employee is exempt, consideration: (1) of the fact that an employee is subject to deductions in pay for absences of less than a full day or of less than a full pay period, when there has not been an actual reduction in pay for the pay period; and (2) of the payment of overtime compensation or other additions to compensation based on hours worked in excess of a daily or weekly amount.</summary>
</bill>
