<bill session="106" type="h" number="2795" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Shivwits Plateau National Conservation Area Establishment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Shivwits Plateau National Conservation Area in the State of Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400504"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400500" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400127" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400534" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1999-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1780-1781"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested From the Department of Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
    <term name="Coal reserves"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Copper"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Molybdenum"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Natural gas reserves"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Plant ecology"/>
    <term name="Platinum"/>
    <term name="Reforestation"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Silver"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="Zinc"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Shivwits Plateau National Conservation Area Title II: Land Restoration and Conveyances Shivwits Plateau National Conservation Area Establishment Act - Title I: Shivwits Plateau National Conservation Area - Establishes the Shivwits Plateau National Conservation Area in Arizona.(Sec. 103) Requires the administration of the conservation area to be exercised by the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management. Prohibits the Secretary from using the National Park Service or the Fish and Wildlife Service to administer the Conservation Area or to include the area as a unit of the National Park System or the National Wildlife Refuge System, except by express congressional authorization.Requires the Secretary to prepare a management plan for administration and use of the conservation area.Establishes the Shivwits Plateau National Conservation Area Advisory Committee to advise on the preparation and implementation of the management plan.(Sec. 104) Provides that the designation of the conservation area shall not be construed to alter the existing authorized uses or rights to use Federal lands included in the area. Treats a land use as an existing land use if it was authorized as of January 1, 1999, was a historical or traditional use, or was a right of use as of such date.Permits hunting, trapping, and fishing on conservation area lands and waters. Authorizes grazing within the area to the same extent as was permitted during calendar year 1998. Guarantees grazing permit holders the right to create new improvements for grazing operations. Permits aircraft and helicopter overflights of lands and landings within the area to the same extent as was permitted during calendar year 1998.(Sec. 105) Describes procedures for the acquisition of State or private lands within the conservation area.(Sec. 106) Requires the Secretary to assess the oil, gas, coal, and other mineral potential on Federal lands in the conservation area in order to expand the data base with respect to the mineral potential of the lands. Subjects the mineral assessment program to review and approval by the Arizona State Department of Mines and Mineral Resources.Bars the Secretary from making, modifying, or extending any mineral withdrawal authorized by law within the conservation area after January 1, 1999, until the assessment, consultation with, and review by, the State are completed. Permits the removal of minerals from the conservation area after completion of such requirements.(Sec. 107) Requires the Secretary, subject to the availability of funds, to carry out ecological resources restoration projects within the conservation area. Prohibits such projects from adversely affecting grazing allotments for more than three years unless an extension has been agreed upon by the permittee. Requires the Secretary, to the extent that a project affects such an allotment, to provide alternative allotments within the same grazing district to affected permittees so that the total number of animal unit months is unaltered.Sets forth provisions regarding control of plant growth and road maintenance and improvement within the conservation area.(Sec. 110) Directs the Secretary to conduct a survey of the conservation area, noting all sites of archaeological, historical, or scientific interest. Makes survey results publicly available.(Sec. 111) Authorizes appropriations to carry out this title.Title II: Land Restoration and Conveyances - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, to the extent possible, to implement the recommendations contained in the April 1999 report of the Sonoran Institute regarding the Arizona Strip-Southern Utah Restoration Area.Authorizes the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior, as a demonstration project, to apply all or a part of the revenues received for timber and other resources removed from lands designated as such restoration area under stewardship end-result contracts as an offset against the costs of stewardship services.Requires the Secretaries to designate an independent scientific review panel to review and approve all projects under this section. Terminates the authority to conduct projects seven years after this Act's enactment date.(Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey, without consideration, all U.S. right, title, and interest in and to specified lands to Colorado City, Arizona, Fredonia, Arizona, Mohave County, Arizona, and the Kaibab Band of Paiute Indians.(Sec. 203) Authorizes appropriations to carry out this title.</summary>
</bill>
