<bill session="104" type="h" number="3770" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health-Care Professionals Coalition Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make the antitrust laws inapplicable to the negotiations between a coalition of health-care professionals and a health-care service plan regarding the wages, rates of pay, hours of work, and other terms and conditions of a contract between a member of such health-care professionals coalition and a health-care service plan, and to their carrying out such terms and conditions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400573"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical associations"/>
    <term name="Professional corporations"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/1996--Introduced.
Health-Care Professionals Coalition Act of 1996 - Makes the antitrust laws inapplicable to: (1) negotiations between a coalition of health-care professionals and a health-care service plan regarding the wages, rates of pay, hours of work, and other terms and conditions of a contract that requires members of the coalition to provide health-care services to beneficiaries of the plan; and (2) the coalition in carrying out such terms and conditions. Limits such exemption to a line of service: (1) of health-care professionals and health-care professionals groups who are members of such a coalition; and (2) with respect to which there is in the relevant market a presumption of market power held by health-care service plans with which the coalition negotiates such terms and conditions.</summary>
</bill>
