<bill session="106" type="h" number="5527" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Missouri River Restoration Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide assistance for efforts to improve conservation of, recreation in, erosion control of, and maintenance of fish and wildlife habitat of the Missouri River in the State of South Dakota, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1890-1891"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Sedimentation"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/24/2000--Introduced.
Missouri River Restoration Act of 2000 - Establishes: (1) a Missouri River Trust committee to vote on approval of a plan for the use of payments to it and to recommend proposals to be funded by its Executive Committee; and (2) a Missouri River Restoration Trust Fund into which the Secretary of the Treasury (Secretary) shall deposit $300 million on the first day of the eleventh fiscal year beginning after the enactment of this Act.Requires the Secretary to: (1) invest such portion of the Fund not required to meet current withdrawals in interest-bearing U.S. obligations or obligations guaranteed by the United States; (2) designate the aggregate amount of interest deposited in the Fund for the preceding fiscal year as available for making payments as requested by the Trust; and (3) make requested payments only after the Trust has adopted its plan. Requires the Federal share of the cost of any project carried out under this Act to be 80 percent of the project's total cost.Requires the Trust to prepare a plan for the use of such payments for carrying out Missouri River projects and programs to promote: (1) conservation practices; (2) the control and removal of sediment; (3) the protection of recreation on the River from sedimentation; (4) the protection of Indian and non-Indian historical and cultural sites along the River from sedimentation; (5) the conservation of fish and wildlife; or (6) erosion control. Provides for: (1) public review and comment; and (2) an audit of the Trust's activities.Requires the Secretary of the Army, within one year after funding under this Act becomes available, to report on: (1) the impact of the siltation of the Missouri River in the State of South Dakota; (2) the status of such historical and cultural sites; and (3) the extent of erosion along the River in the State.Authorizes the Secretary to use funds appropriated to the operations and maintenance account of the Corps of Engineers and available for use with respect to a water resources development project along the Missouri River to: (1) reduce the siltation of the River in South Dakota; (2) protect recreation on, water quality in, and Indian and non-Indian historical and cultural sites along the River from sedimentation; and (3) improve erosion control along the River.Prohibits any funds appropriated to carry out this Act from being used to purchase or otherwise acquire property unless the acquisition is from willing sellers.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
