<bill session="106" type="h" number="3234" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-10T16:34:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-10T16:34:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To exempt certain reports from automatic elimination and sunset pursuant to the Federal Reports and Elimination and Sunset Act of 1995.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400586"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-11-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2275"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10T16:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodling moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10T16:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11902-11904" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10T16:31:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3234.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-11-10T16:34:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10T16:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Art and state"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Deaf"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disabled students"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the aged"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Head Start programs"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Long-term care facilities"/>
    <term name="Longshoremen"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Pension trust guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Removal of officials"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/1999--Passed House amended.
Exempts certain reports within the jurisdiction of the Committee on Education and the Workforce from automatic elimination and sunset provisions under the Federal Reports and Elimination and Sunset Act of 1995.Includes among such reports those submitted under specified provisions of: (1) the General Education Provisions Act, on effectiveness of applicable programs; (2) the Department of Education Organization Act, on promulgation of rules and regulations, and Departmental activities; (3) the Higher Education Act of 1965, on the National Advisory Committee on Institutional Evaluation and Integrity, waivers, budget submissions, audits, notices of failures to comply with master calendar deadlines, the student loan data system, and the Javits Fellows Program Fellowship Board; (4) the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965, on the state of the arts and of the humanities in the Nation, and activities of the National Endowments of the Arts and of the Humanities; (5) the Arts and Artifacts Indemnity Act, on certification of validity of claims, and to claims and contracts; (6) the National Commission on Libraries and Information Science Act, on activities of the National Commission on Libraries and Information Science; (7) the Education of the Deaf Act of 1986, on certain indirect costs; (8) the United States Institute of Peace Act, on audits and progress; (9) the Education Amendments of 1978, on review of or proposed closure or consolidation of schools operated by the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA), plans to bring Indian educational facilities into compliance with health and safety standards, the status of educational, programs administered by the BIA and educational problems encountered; (10) the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988, on applications received and actions taken on grants for tribally controlled schools; (11) the Helen Keller National Center Act, on evaluation of such Center's operation; (12) the Older Americans Act of 1965, on results of evaluative research and program evaluation, activities, and State long-term care ombudsman programs; (13) both the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 and the Civil Rights Act of 1964, related to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC); (14) the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, on activities, program performance analysis, the status of disability policy, the Access Board, and the Interagency Disability Coordinating Council; (15) the National Labor Relations Act, on case activities and operations of the National Labor Relations Board; (16) specified Federal law, on the Bureau of Labor Statistics; (17) the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, on implementation and the curtailment of employment opportunities; (18) the Longshore and Harbor Workers' Compensation Act, on implementation; (19) specified Federal law, on implementation relating to compensation for work injuries; (20) the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSHA), on implementation; (21) the Wagner-Peyser Act, on evaluation of the United States Employment Service; (22) the Federal Coal Mine Health and Safety Act of 1969, on coal mine health and safety; (23) the Labor Management Relations Act of 1947, by the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service; (24) OSHA, by the National Institute of Occupational Safety and Health; (25) specified Federal law, by the Secretary of Labor respecting compliance with certain requirements; (26) the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), on variances granted for vesting or funding, status of enforcement cases, and recommendations received from the Advisory Council or for further legislation; (27) ERISA, on Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) financial statements, activities, and actuarial evaluations; (28) the Head Start Act, operation of Head Start programs; and (29) the Inspector General Act, on audits conducted by the Office of the Inspector General, and on reasons for removal or transfer of the Inspector General, for the PBGC, the Department of Labor, or the EEOC.</summary>
</bill>
