<bill session="105" type="h" number="4597" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Save Social Security and Taxpayer Relief Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">American Community Renewal Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Renewing American Communities Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide tax relief for individuals, families, and farming and other small businesses, to provide tax incentives for education, to extend certain expiring provisions, to protect the solvency of the Social Security system, to reserve Social Security surpluses solely for the Social Security system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400021" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="1998-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1998-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400600" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400300" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1998-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="1998-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1998-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="409954" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1998-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400613" joined="1998-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1998-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1998-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-09-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1767"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accident insurance"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Casualty insurance"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development corporations"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Corporate liquidations"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Farmland protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Holding companies"/>
    <term name="Home offices"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Industrial development bonds"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor supply"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Property insurance"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public schools"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Real estate investment"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Research and development tax credit"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Retirement income"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Schools"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social security beneficiaries"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Summer employment"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Taxicabs"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Welfare-to-work"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Provisions Primarily Affecting Individuals and Families Subtitle A: General Provisions Subtitle B: Provisions Relating to Education Subtitle C: Provisions Relating to Social Security Title II: Provisions Primarily Affecting Farming and Other Businesses Subtitle A: Increase in Expense Treatment for Small Businesses Subtitle B: Provisions Relating to Farmers Subtitle C: Increase in Volume Cap on Private Activity Bonds Title III: Extension and Modification of Certain Expiring Provisions Subtitle A: Tax Provisions Subtitle B: Generalized System of Preferences Title IV: Revenue Offset Title V: Technical Corrections Title VI: American Community Renewal Act of 1998 Subtitle A: Designation and Evaluation of Renewal Subtitle B: Tax Incentives for Renewal Communities Title VII: Tax Reductions Contingent On Saving Social Security Taxpayer Relief Act of 1998 - Title I: Provisions Affecting Individuals and Families - Subtitle A: General Provisions - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to: (1) make the basic standard deduction on a joint return equal to twice the deduction of a single return; (2) make the aged or blind additional deduction amounts the same for married and unmarried individuals; (3) as a general rule, exclude from gross income up to $200 ($400 in the case of a joint return) of dividends and interest received by an individual; (4) revise provisions concerning the aggregate amount of nonrefundable personal credits allowed to provide that the aggregate amount of such credits shall not exceed the sum of the taxpayer's regular tax liability and the alternative minimum tax; (5) allow for the deduction of 100 percent of the health insurance costs of self-employed individuals; (6) set forth a special rule for members of the uniformed services and foreign service in determining the exclusion of gain from the sale of a principal residence; and (7) accelerate the $1 million exemption from the estate and gift taxes. Subtitle B: Provisions Relating to Education - Permits private educational institutions to maintain qualified tuition programs which are comparable to qualified State tuition programs. Modifies arbitrage rebate rules applicable to public school construction bonds. Subtitle C: Provisions Relating to Social Security - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act to: (1) increase the limit on earnings before there is a reduction in benefits for individuals who have attained retirement age but who are under age 70; and (2) provide for the recomputation of benefits resulting from earnings after reaching retirement age. Title II: Provisions Primarily Affecting Farming and Other Businesses - Subtitle A: Increase in Expense Treatment for Small Businesses - Amends the IRC to accelerate the increase in the dollar limitation on the cost of property which may be expensed by businesses as depreciable assets. Subtitle B: Provisions Relating to Farmers - Amends the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997 to permanently extend income averaging for farmers. Amends the IRC to provide a five-year carryback period for farming losses. Amends the Agricultural Market Transition Act to disregard the payment option provided by the Emergency Farm Financial Relief Act. Subtitle C: Increase in Volume Cap on Private Activity Bonds - Amends IRC provisions concerning State private activity bond volume limits to repeal the adjustment for years after 1987. Title III: Extension and Modification of Certain Expiring Provisions - Subtitle A: Tax Provisions - Extends, for a limited period, the: (1) credit for increasing research activities; (2) work opportunity credit; and (3) welfare-to-work credit. Extends permanently the special rule for contributions of stock for which market quotations are readily available. Establishes rules for the public inspection of the returns of private foundations. Revises provisions concerning the special rule for income derived in the active conduct of banking, financing, or similar businesses to provide, as general rule, that foreign personal holding company income shall not include qualified banking or financing income of an eligible controlled foreign corporation. Revises the definition of insurance income and provides that, as a general rule, foreign personal holding company income shall not include qualified insurance income of a qualifying insurance company. Subtitle B: Generalized System of Preferences - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to extend the Generalized System of Preferences through February 29, 2000. Provides for the retroactive application of certain liquidations and reliquidations. Title IV: Revenue Offset - Amends IRC provisions concerning the complete liquidations of subsidiaries to provide that if a corporation receives a distribution form a regulated investment company or a real estate investment trust which is considered as being in complete liquidation of such company or trust, then such corporation shall treat as a dividend from such trust or company an amount equal to the deduction for dividends paid allowable to such company or trust by reason of such distribution. Title V: Technical Corrections - Revises provisions of the IRC, the Internal Revenue Service Restructuring and Reform Act of 1998, the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997, the Tax Reform Act of 1984, and the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century. Title VI: American Community Renewal Act of 1998 - American Community Renewal Act of 1998 - Subtitle A: Designation and Evaluation of Renewal Communities - Renewing American Communities Act of 1998 - Amends the IRC to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to designate (upon local or State nomination) up to 20 renewal communities, of which at least 20 percent shall be in rural areas. Requires for nomination purposes that: (1) the area be experiencing high rates of poverty and unemployment and general distress; and (2) State and local governments enter into written contracts with community organizations to promote specified economic growth and employment activities. Treats renewal communities as labor surplus areas for all Federal law purposes. Subtitle B: Tax Incentives for Renewal Communities - Excludes from gross income capital gains on the sale or exchange of a qualified community asset (stock, business property, or partnership interest) held for more than five years. Allows a specified deduction for amounts paid into a family development account on behalf of an individual or another qualified individual who is a renewal community resident. Excludes from gross income account distributions used for qualified family development expenses (postsecondary education, first-home purchase, business capitalization, medical, and rollovers). Provides a penalty (with exceptions) in addition to inclusion as gross income for nonqualifying distributions. Provides for designation of up to 25 percent of qualifying renewal communities as matching demonstration areas eligible to receive family development account matching contributions. Authorizes: (1) designation of earned income tax credit payments for family development account deposit; (2) a commercial building revitalization tax credit; (3) increased first year expensing for renewal community businesses; (4) extension of environmental remediation cost expensing and the work opportunity credit for renewal communities; and (5) similar tax treatment of renewal communities and enterprise zones for specified youth residence requirements. Permits a deduction for contributions to a family development account whether or not a taxpayer itemizes. Makes conforming amendments to provisions respecting: (1) tax on excess contributions and prohibited transactions; (2) trust and annuity information; (3) tax exemption applications; and (4) the commercial revitalization credit. Title VII: Tax Reductions Contingent On Saving Social Security - Prohibits any provision of this Act from taking effect before the first January 1 after the date of enactment of this Act that follows a calendar year for which there is a social security solvency certification, except for specified provisions. States that there is a social security solvency certification for a calendar year if there is a certification that the social security trust funds are in actuarial balance for the 75-year period utilized in the most recent annual report of the Board of Trustees of the Social Security Trust Funds. Provides for the reservation of any social security surpluses for the sole use of the social security system.</summary>
</bill>
