<bill session="105" type="hc" number="299" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress that executive departments and agencies must maintain the division of governmental responsibilities between the national government and the States that was intended by the framers of the Constitution, and must ensure that the principles of federalism established by the framers guide the executive departments and agencies in the formulation and implementation of policies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="1998-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400500" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1998-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="1998-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1998-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1998-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="1998-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1998-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="1998-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1998-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="1998-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1998-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400588" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1998-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="406343" joined="1998-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="1998-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400225" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1998-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1998-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1998-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400353" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409618" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400534" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="410067" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="410084" joined="1998-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400610" joined="1998-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1998-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1998-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1998-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6870"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO01" subcommittee="National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="sc" number="109"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States' rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/1998--Introduced.
Calls for executive agencies, when formulating and implementing policies that have federalism implications, to: (1) strictly adhere to constitutional principles and closely examine the constitutional and statutory authority supporting any Federal action that would limit the policy making direction of the States; (2) take Federal action limiting the policy making discretion of the States only where constitutional authority for the action is clear and certain and the national activity is necessitated by the presence of a problem of national scope; (3) recognize the distinction between problems of national scope and problems that are merely common to the States; (4) recognize that constitutional authority for Federal action is clear and certain only when authority for the action may be found in a specific provision of the Constitution, when there is no provision in the Constitution prohibiting Federal action, and when the action does not encroach upon authority reserved to the States; (5) encourage States to develop their own policies to achieve program objectives and to work with officials in other States; (6) refrain from establishing uniform, national standards for programs and, when possible, defer to the States to establish standards; and (7) consult with officials and organizations representing the States in developing national standards when required. States that: (1) the national Government should grant the States the maximum administration discretion possible with respect to national policies administered by the States; and (2) intrusive Federal oversight of State administration is neither necessary nor desirable. Calls for observation of the following special requirements for preemption of State law: (1) agencies should construe a Federal statute to preempt only when it contains an express preemption provision, when there is some other firm and palpable evidence compelling the conclusion that the Congress intended preemption, or when the exercise of State authority directly conflicts with the exercise of Federal authority under the statute; (2) if a Federal statute does not preempt, such agencies should construe any authorization in the statute for the issuance of regulations as authorizing preemption by rule making only when the statute expressly authorizes issuance of preemptive regulations or when there is some other such evidence compelling the conclusion that the Congress intended to delegate preemption authority; (3) any regulatory preemption should be restricted to the minimum level necessary to achieve the objectives of the statute; (4) an agency that foresees the possibility of a conflict between State law and federally protected interests should consult with State officials and organizations to avoid such a conflict; and (5) an agency that proposes to act through adjudication or rule making should provide all affected States notice and an opportunity for participation in the proceedings.</summary>
</bill>
