<bill session="104" type="h" number="4238" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Compassionate Community Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to enhance tax incentives for charitable contributions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400036"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Economic and Educational Opportunities, Transportation and Infrastructure, Commerce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, and in addition to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Flexible work hours"/>
    <term name="Four-day week"/>
    <term name="Free clinics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in social service"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS Title I: Tax Incentives for Charitable Contributions Title II: Volunteer Enhancement Title III: Common Sense Legal and Regulatory Reforms for Charities Subtitle A: Liability of Certain Tax Exempt Organizations Under CERCLA Subtitle B: Liability of Certain Tax Exempt Organizations Under OSHA Subtitle C: Fair Labor Standards Act Obligations of Certain Tax Exempt Organizations Subtitle D: Limited Damages in Negligence Claims Subtitle E: Volunteer Protection Subtitle F: Charitable Medical Care Subtitle G: Property Access Subtitle H: Volunteer Firefighter and Rescue Squad Worker Protection Compassionate Community Act of 1996 - Title I: Tax Incentives for Charitable Contributions - Amends the Internal Revenue Act Code to establish a charitable credit of up to $100 for an individual and up to $200 for a joint return. Prohibits double benefit charitable deductions and credits. (Sec. 102) Establishes an employer credit for wages paid to qualifying employee volunteers. Title II: Volunteer Enhancement - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to permit employees to receive compensatory time rather than required monetary overtime (at a rate of at least 1.5 hours compensatory time for each hour of overtime). Title III: Common Sense Legal and Regulatory Reforms for Charities - Subtitle A: Liability of Certain Tax Exempt Organizations Under CERCLA - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to limit specified pollutant or hazardous substance-related liability for qualifying tax-exempt organizations. Subtitle B: Liability of Certain Tax Exempt Organizations Under OSHA - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSHA)concerning notification of violation and employer defenses with respect to certain tax-exempt organizations. Subtitle C: Fair Labor Standards Act Obligations of Certain Tax Exempt Organizations - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to authorize tax-exempt employers to establish flexible and compressed schedules. Subtitle D: Limited Damages in Negligence Claims - Limits non-economic damages to $250,000 in a negligence action against a tax-exempt organization. Subtitle E: Volunteer Protection - Provides nonprofit or governmental volunteers with limited protection from tort liability. Sets forth specified State conditions and exceptions to such protection. (Sec. 335) Increases, by one percent, State Social Services Block Grant allotments under title XX of the Social Security Act for specified compliance certifications. Subtitle F: Charitable Medical Care - Provides health care professionals with limited liability for volunteer services. Subtitle G: Property Access - Amends the National Labor Relations Act to state that an employer who provides property access to charitable organizations is not required to provide such access for union-related activities. Subtitle H: Volunteer Firefighter and Rescue Squad Worker Protection - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exclude volunteer fire fighters or rescue squad members from the definition of employee. (Sec. 362) Waives overtime requirements for such volunteers.</summary>
</bill>
