<bill session="106" type="h" number="5322" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Timbisha Shoshone Homeland Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide to the Timbisha Shoshone Tribe a permanent land base within its aboriginal homeland, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400239"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2000-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2000-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2000-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2000--Introduced.
Timbisha Shoshone Homeland Act - Mandates that all U.S. rights and interests to specified California and Nevada lands be held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Timbisha Shoshone Tribe of California and Nevada. Provides development and other limitations with respect to such lands. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to purchase additional lands and appurtenant water rights in trust for the Tribe's use. Recognizes certain special use areas, including the mesquite use area, a buffer area, and the Timbisha Shoshone natural and cultural preservation area.Provides that the trust lands shall constitute the Timbisha Shoshone Reservation.Directs the National Park Service, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Tribe to develop protocols to review planned development in Death Valley National Park (the site of the Tribe's ancestral homeland). Authorizes cooperative agreements for providing training on the interpretation, management, protection, and preservation of the natural and cultural resources of the Tribe's special use areas.</summary>
</bill>
