<bill session="105" type="hr" number="76" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives concerning the human rights situation in the People's Republic of China as it relates to China's position in the international community and encouraging the United States, in conjunction with other members of the United Nations Commission on Human Rights, to work with China to promote the improvement of human rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400604"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E357"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Church and state"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clergy"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Political rights"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Reporters and reporting"/>
    <term name="Tibet"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/1997--Introduced.
Urges: (1) the Congress to explore additional legislative vehicles for explicitly expressing congressional concerns about China's serious human rights situation and to work with the President and the Secretary of State to explore areas of agreement and mutual concern; (2) the President and the Secretary to call on the Government of China to take concrete steps to improve human rights, fully abide by its commitments to maintain basic human and civil rights, an independent judiciary, and an elected legislature in Hong Kong after July 1, 1997, cease efforts to repeal provisions of the Bill of Rights Ordinance and reinstate laws which are not in conformance with the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights; and (3) the President and the Secretary to sponsor and actively seek support among other member governments for a resolution critical of China's human rights practices at the 53d session of the United Nations Commission on Human Rights in Geneva if it is unable to identify substantial and quantifiable progress by China on such matters.</summary>
</bill>
