<bill session="108" type="h" number="5162" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the safe and secure storage of explosive materials by State and local law enforcement agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2004-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2004-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2004--Introduced.
Requires each State to submit to the Attorney General a written report (and subsequent updates) that specifies each location at which a State law enforcement agency stores explosive materials that have been transported in interstate or foreign commerce and the types and amounts of such materials. Directs the Attorney General to prescribe final regulations governing the storage of such materials by such agencies, including public safety and security standards and requirements for video surveillance or an alarm system. Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) make matching grants to State and local law enforcement agencies for complying with such regulations; (2) enter any place where such an agency keeps such explosive materials for inspection and compliance determinations; and (3) reduce by ten percent the funds that an agency would otherwise receive under any Department of Justice grant program if the agency fails to comply.</summary>
</bill>
