<bill session="104" type="h" number="2795" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Trade Act of 1974 and the Tariff Act of 1930 to clarify the definitions of domestic industry and like articles in certain investigations involving perishable agricultural products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1995-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1996-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="1996-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1996-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1996-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400583" joined="1996-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1996-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1996-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="406082" joined="1996-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1995-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1996-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="1996-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="1996-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1996-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1995-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2388"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Tomatoes"/>
    <term name="Vegetable trade"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to revise the definition of "domestic industry" and "like or directly competitive article" with respect to investigations by the International Trade Commission (ITC) to determine whether perishable agricultural products are being imported into the United States in such increased quantities as to be a substantial cause (or threat) of serious injury to the domestic industry producing an article like or directly competitive with such imported products. Authorizes the ITC, in the case of one or more domestic producers who produce a like or directly competitive perishable agricultural product during a particular growing season, to limit the domestic industry to those producers if they sell all or almost all of their production of the article in that growing season and the demand for the article is not supplied, to any substantial degree, by other domestic producers of the article who produce the article in a different growing season. Requires the ITC, with respect to perishable agricultural products, to limit provisional import relief to imported articles that are entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, during the same growing season as the like or directly competitive product. Amends the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act to require the Commissioner of Customs (currently, the ITC), with respect to expediting an investigation concerning provisional import relief, to monitor, until January 1, 2009, imports of fresh or chilled tomatoes and peppers (other than chili peppers) as if proper requests for such monitoring have been made. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture, upon the request of the Commissioner of Customs (currently, the ITC), to provide to the Commissioner information relevant to such monitoring. Requires the Commissioner to make such information available to the public, but in no case more than seven calendar days after the Commissioner receives such information.</summary>
</bill>
