<bill session="106" type="h" number="4501" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gridlock Mitigation and Commuter Flexibility Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Clean Air Act to require States to revise their implementation plans for ozone nonattainment areas to reduce ozone concentrations and fuel consumption associated with automobile commuting by removing State constraints against employers offering flextime to their employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="2000-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="2000-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="2000-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Carbon monoxide"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Flexible work hours"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2000--Introduced.
Gridlock Mitigation and Commuter Flexibility Act of 2000 - Amends the Clean Air Act to require States, in order to reduce weekly employment-related automobile miles traveled by persons employed in moderate carbon monoxide nonattainment areas, to submit revisions to applicable implementation plans that include a provision insuring that no State or local provision of law, regulation, or ordinance has the effect of prohibiting or restricting employers in such areas from offering employees the opportunity to work on flexible weekly schedules. Defines "flexible weekly schedules" as schedules that reduce the number of work days employees are required to travel to and from the workplace during the week without reducing the number of hours of work or modifying employee compensation.</summary>
</bill>
