<bill session="105" type="h" number="4756" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-13T16:37:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-13T16:37:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Year 2000 Preparedness Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Year 2000 Preparedness Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that the United States is prepared to meet the Year 2000 computer problem.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1998-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1998-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1998-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1998-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T12:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Morella moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T12:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10717-10723, H10788-10789" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T12:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T13:10:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Barcia objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T16:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-10-13T16:37:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="526" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 407 - 3 (Roll No. 526).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family enterprises"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Special weeks"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Year 2000 computer problem"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/1998--Passed House amended.
Year 2000 Preparedness Act of 1998 - Directs the President to provide for the acceleration of the development of business continuity plans by Federal agencies to ensure the uninterrupted delivery by those agencies of critical mission-related services. (Sec. 4) Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the President should aggressively promote Year 2000 date change awareness for information technology systems and sensitive infrastructure applications; (2) the President should authorize the Chair of the Year 2000 Conversion Council to take a leadership role in resolving Year 2000 (Y2K) issues of any critical Federal agency system that is in jeopardy of not meeting the January 1, 2000 deadline; (3) the Chair should work toward a national strategy to assure that the critical infrastructures and key sectors of the economy will be prepared for the Year 2000 date change; (4) the Chair is making a significant contribution to Y2K problem awareness by scheduling a National Y2K Action Week for October 19 through 23, 1998; (5) the Small Business Administration (SBA), the Department of Commerce, the Department of Agriculture, and other Federal agencies should undertake maximum efforts to assist American family businesses and farmers in assessing their exposure to the Y2K problem, undertaking necessary remedial steps, and formulating contingency plans; and (6) State and local governments, as well as private sector industry groups and companies, should participate in the effort to prepare the American economy for the year 2000. (Sec. 5) Provides for all Federal agency reports to OMB relating to the Y2K problem to be concurrently transmitted to the Congress, including all agency monthly submissions to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB). (Sec. 6) Directs the Chair to develop guidelines of best practices and standards for remediation and validation with respect to the Y2K problem to provide better direction for government and private sector efforts. (Sec. 7) Requires the Chair to submit to the Congress any national assessment of the Y2K problem conducted through or in conjunction with the Council covering all critical national infrastructures and key sectors of the economy. (Sec. 8) Requires the head of each Federal agency to ensure that all systems and hardware administered by the agency are Year 2000 compliant to ensure that no significant disruption of the agency's operations or data exchange partners occurs. Requires quarterly progress implementation reports to the Congress. (Sec. 9) Directs the National Institute of Standards and Technology, in conjunction with the SBA, to develop a Year 2000 compliance outreach program to assist small and medium-sized businesses with respect to the Y2K problem. (Sec. 10) Directs the Under Secretary of Commerce for Technology to develop a Year 2000 consumer awareness program to assist the public in becoming aware of the implications of the Y2K problem.</summary>
</bill>
