<bill session="105" type="hr" number="91" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:14-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-21T13:04:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-03-21T13:04:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing amounts for the expenses of certain committees of the House of Representatives in the One Hundred Fifth Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-03-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-17T20:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on House Oversight. H. Rept. 105-30. Filed late, pursuant to previous special order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-17T20:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-19T21:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 101 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 91 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. The measure will be considered in the House and the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on House Oversight now printed in the resolution shall be considered as adopted. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-20T18:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 101 failed passage of House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-20T23:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 105 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 91 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-21T11:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 105 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-21T11:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 101. (CR H1273-1279)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1273-1279" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-21T11:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 91 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. The measure will be considered in the House and the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on House Oversight now printed in the resolution shall be considered as adopted. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-21T11:54:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-21T12:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gejdenson moved to recommit with instructions to House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-21T12:34:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-21T12:55:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 176 - 214 (Roll no. 70). (CR H1279)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1279" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1997-03-21T13:04:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 213 - 179 (Roll No. 71).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-21T13:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee staffing"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="House Agriculture"/>
    <term name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <term name="House Budget"/>
    <term name="House Commerce"/>
    <term name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <term name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <term name="House Intelligence"/>
    <term name="House International Relations"/>
    <term name="House Judiciary"/>
    <term name="House National Security"/>
    <term name="House Oversight"/>
    <term name="House Resources"/>
    <term name="House Rules"/>
    <term name="House Science"/>
    <term name="House Small Business"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <term name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>03/21/1997--Passed House amended.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;(There are 2 &lt;a href="/cgi-bin/bdquery/z?d105:HE00091:@@@D&amp;summ1&amp;"&gt;other summaries&lt;/a&gt;).
Makes necessary amounts available for continuing expenses of standing and select committees of the House of Representatives (other than the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight) for the period of April 1, 1997, through May 2, 1997, on the same terms and conditions as amounts were available to such committees for the period of January 3, 1997, through March 31, 1997. Makes a specified amount available for expenses of the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, including the expenses of staff salaries, for the 105th Congress. Sets forth first and second session limitations. Establishes a reserve fund for unanticipated expenses of committees for the 105th Congress to be paid to them pursuant to allocations approved by the Committee on House Oversight. Grants such Committee the authority to make adjustments in the amount made available for the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight if necessary to comply with a presidential sequestration order or to conform to any reduction in appropriations with respect to the other standing and select committees. Provides that any net increase in the aggregate amount of committees expenses for the 105th Congress over the aggregate amount of funds appropriated for such expenses for the 104th Congress shall be offset by reductions in expenses for other legislative branch activities.</summary>
</bill>
