<bill session="104" type="hr" number="303" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-15T11:38:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-05-15T11:38:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1745) to designate certain public lands in the State of Utah as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T14:57:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-404, by Mr. Linder.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T14:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1745 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment, the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Resources now printed in the bill. Before consideration of any other amendment, it shall be in order to consider the amendment printed in the report accompanying this resolution. That amendment shall be debatable for 10 minutes and shall not be subject to further amendment. If that amendment is adopted, the bill, as amended, shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment. During consideration of the bill for amendment, priority in recognition shall be given to Members who...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-12-13T14:57:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="150">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 150.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-05-14T21:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to clause 4(c) of rule XI of the Rules of the House, Mr. Moakley notified the House of his intention to call up H. Res. 303, which had been on the House Calendar more than seven legislative days.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-15T10:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5060-5069" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-15T10:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-15T11:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 221 - 197 (Roll no. 169).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-05-15T11:38:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-05-15T11:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="1745"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the open rule for the consideration of H.R. 1745 (Utah wilderness areas).</summary>
</bill>
