<bill session="106" type="h" number="2361" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Home Health Care Restoration Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal the interim payment system for home health services furnished under the Medicare Program, to eliminate the mandatory 15 percent reduction in payment amounts for such services under the prospective payment system, to continue periodic interim payments for such services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-24">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Hospital personnel"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/1999--Introduced.
Medicare Home Health Care Restoration Act of 1999 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) repeal the interim system of payments for home health services; (2) restore the amount of the pre-Balanced Budget Act of 1997 (BBA '97) per visit payments that may be made under Medicare with respect to services furnished by home health agencies; (3) eliminate the scheduled 15 percent reduction in payment amounts under the prospective payment system (PPS) for home health services; and (4) provide for various specified repeals of freezes and reductions in home health services-related payment updates.Amends BBA '97 to: (1) eliminate the 15 percent contingent reduction under the PPS for home health services under Medicare; and (2) restore periodic interim payments to home health agencies.</summary>
</bill>
