<bill session="104" type="h" number="3116" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the phase-out of existing private sector development enterprise funds for foreign countries and to prohibit the establishment of, or the support for, new private sector development enterprise funds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400611"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Albania"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="CIS countries"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Czech Republic"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Eastern Europe"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Estonia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hungary"/>
    <term name="International Development Cooperation Agency"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Latvia"/>
    <term name="Lithuania"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Poland"/>
    <term name="Romania"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Slovakia"/>
    <term name="Slovenia"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Southern Africa"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/1996--Introduced.
Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds made available to the U.S. Agency for International Development (AID) for assistance to specified private sector development enterprise funds for foreign countries. Prohibits the President from establishing any new private sector development enterprise funds. Prohibits the expenditure of funds appropriated to AID for assistance to any private sector development enterprise fund in which the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (World Bank) (or any other international financial institution of which the United States is a member) participates, or which is financed by that Bank or institution, including: (1) the Russia Small Business Fund; (2) the Regional Venture Fund for the Lower Volga Region; and (3) the Slovenia Development Capital Fund. Directs the President to instruct the U.S. Executive Director of the World Bank and any other international financial institution of which the United States is a member to use the U.S. vote to oppose participation of the World Bank or institution in, or financing by that Bank or institution of, any private sector development enterprise fund named in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
