<bill session="106" type="h" number="1734" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">School Quality Counts Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to improve the quality of education and raise student achievement by strengthening accountability, raising standards for teachers, rewarding success, and providing better information to parents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1999-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1999-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1999-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="1999-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1999-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E888-889"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1422"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary school students"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="High school students"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Paraprofessional school personnel"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Parent-teacher relationships"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: State Plans for Improving Basic Programs Operated by State and Local Educational Agencies Title II: Academic Achievement Awards Program Title III: Conforming Amendments; Effective Date School Quality Counts Act - Title I: State Plans for Improving Basic Programs Operated by State and Local Educational Agencies - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to revise requirements for State plans under ESEA title I (Helping Disadvantaged Students Meet High Standards) part A (Improving Basic Programs Operated by State and Local Educational Agencies). (Sec. 101) Requires such State plans to demonstrate what constitutes adequate yearly progress of the State toward enabling all children in schools receiving part A assistance (part A schools) to meet the State's student performance standards. Revises the manner in which adequate yearly progress is to be defined. Directs the Secretary of Education to collect and review the information from States on the adequate yearly progress of schools and local educational agencies (LEAs) to determine State and local compliance. (Sec. 102) Adds accountability requirements. Requires State plans to assure that all part A schools annually report and disseminate: (1) to each parent or legal guardian of the student, results of all specified assessments used to measure the performance of a student attending the school, including certain information in an understandable format; and (2) to the public, overall student performance data on all such assessments, distributed to local print and broadcast media and posted on an Internet web site. (Sec. 103) Adds teacher quality provisions. Requires such State plans to assure that all part A schools annually report and disseminate: (1) to each parent of the student, information on the qualifications of their child's classroom teachers with regard to the relevant subject areas and grade levels, including certain information in an understandable format; and (2) to the public, such information in an aggregate form for each school, LEA, and the State, distributed to local print and broadcast media and posted on an Internet web site. Requires part A schools to give special parental notification to parents or guardians of any student with a teacher who has not fully met all State requirements to provide instruction at the relevant grade level and in the relevant subject areas. Requires State plans to assure, within two years after enactment of this Act, that all instructional staff who provide services to students, under part A schoolwide programs or targeted assistance schools programs, have demonstrated the subject matter knowledge, teaching knowledge, and teaching skill necessary to teach effectively in the content area or areas in which they provide instruction, according to specified criteria (qualified teacher in every classroom requirement). (Sec. 104) Authorizes LEAs, to meet such ESEA title I part A requirement of a qualified teacher in every classroom, to use funds received under: (1) ESEA title II (Dwight D. Eisenhower Professional Development Program); (2) ESEA title VI (Innovative Education Program Strategies); (3) specified provisions of the Department of Education Appropriations Act, 1999; (4) the Higher Education Act of 1965; or (5) the Goals 2000: Educate America Act. Allows LEAs to use such funds to: (1) recruit fully qualified teachers, including through the use of signing bonuses or other financial incentives; (2) collaborate with programs that recruit, place, and train qualified teachers; or (3) provide the necessary education and training, including paying the costs of college tuition and other student fees, to help current teachers or other school personnel who do not meet these criteria attain the necessary qualifications and licensing requirements. Requires an individual, in order to qualify for such college tuition payments to: (1) be within two years of completing an undergraduate degree; and (2) agree to teach for at least two subsequent years after receiving such degree in a school where, in that academic year, more than one-half of the enrollment may be counted for purposes of concentration grants to LEAs, and its LEA is eligible for ESEA title I assistance. Eliminates certain part A professional development requirements with respect to instructional aides. (Sec. 105) Prohibits the use of any ESEA funds for any professional development services for a teacher that are not directly related to the curriculum and content areas in which the teacher provides instruction. Title II: Academic Achievement Awards Program - Requires each State receiving an ESEA title I grant to establish an Academic Achievement Awards Program to recognize and reward: (1) LEAs and schools that operate schoolwide programs or targeted schools programs and demonstrate outstanding yearly progress for two or more consecutive years; and (2) teachers who provide instruction in such programs. Requires such States to reserve certain funds for such awards programs. Authorizes appropriations to supplement funds for such awards programs. Title III: Conforming Amendments; Effective Date - Sets forth conforming amendments and an effective date.</summary>
</bill>
