<bill session="108" type="h" number="2212" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Maintaining and Ensuring Diversity and Integrity on the Airwaves Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">MEDIA Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Federal Communications Commission to comply with the Administrative Procedures Act and to adhere to the policies and purposes of Communications Act of 1934 favoring diversity of media voices, vigorous economic competition, technological advancement, and promotion of the public interest, convenience, and necessity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2003-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2003-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2003-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2003-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400384" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2003-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2003-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1059"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2003--Introduced.
Maintaining and Ensuring Diversity and Integrity on the Airwaves Act of 2003 or MEDIA Act of 2003 - Amends the Adminsitrative Procedures Act to prohibit a Federal agency from prescribing substantial and extensive revisions to its regulations unless the revised regulations have been published in proposed form to afford interested parties the opportunity to submit data, views, or arguments thereon. Amends the: (1) Communications Act of 1934 to extend the interval for Federal Communication Commission (FCC) review of its regulations from every even-numbered year to every five years beginning with 2008; and (2) Telecommunications Act of 1996 to eliminate biennial FCC review of its rules concerning broadcast ownership. Prohibits the FCC from taking any action to repeal or modify a regulation determined to be no longer necessary in the public interest unless the FCC: (1) has completed its 2003 report to Congress concerning a periodic review of regulations to eliminate telecommunications market entry barriers; (2) has included in such report an analysis of how any change in existing regulations is consistent with national policy and would affect such barriers; and (3) determines that such repeal or modification is consistent with the removal of such barriers as well as prescribed policies. Prohibits license transfers, pending completion of such requirements, with respect to television or radio stations the aggregate value of which exceeds $50 million when the party involved owns, operates, or controls another television or radio broadcast station.</summary>
</bill>
