<bill session="104" type="h" number="3091" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Injunctive Relief Amendments Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Labor Relations Act to allow individuals against whom injunctive relief is sought an opportunity to be heard.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1996-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E362"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities. subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Labor disputes"/>
    <term name="Labor injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/1996--Introduced.
Injunctive Relief Amendments Act of 1996 - Amends the National Labor Relations Act (NLRA) to revise provisions relating to the awarding of preliminary injunctive relief against individuals for alleged unfair labor practices. Allows parties against whom such preliminary injunctive relief is sought an opportunity to review and respond to legal memoranda or documents presented to the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) in support of such relief. Prohibits Federal courts from issuing preliminary injunctive relief unless: (1) there is a reasonable likelihood of success on the merits of the complaint; (2) there is a possibility of irreparable harm if relief is not granted; (3) a balancing of hardships favors injunctive relief; and (4) harm to the public interest stemming from such relief is tolerable in light of the benefits achieved.</summary>
</bill>
