<bill session="106" type="h" number="3652" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mud Dump Permanent Closure and Remediation Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 to direct the Secretary of the Army to prohibit ocean dumping at the Historic Area Remediation Site, located east of Sandy Hook, New Jersey, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2000-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E132"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Bioaccumulation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dredging spoil"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Hydrocarbons"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine biology"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Polychlorinated biphenyls"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2000--Introduced.
Mud Dump Permanent Closure and Remediation Act of 2000 - Amends the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 to prohibit dumping at the Historic Area Remediation Site (the dredged material disposal area located east of Sandy Hook, New Jersey). Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to issue permits authorizing the transportation of dredged materials to such Site solely for purposes of providing for remediation. Bars the Secretary from issuing such permits upon satisfying a goal stated in this Act for reduction of contamination at the Site.Provides that an existing permit shall not be effective if it authorizes dumping in violation of this Act.Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to develop standards for evaluating dredged materials to be used solely for remediation purposes at the Site. Directs the Administrator, in developing such standards, to ensure that the materials used for remediation: (1) contain significantly lower levels of contaminants than exist at the Site; (2) will significantly reduce contamination levels in biota and sediments at the Site; and (3) will reduce the number, extent, and magnitude of undesirable effects on marine life in and around the Site. Requires the goals of such standards to be to reduce the level of contamination at the Site to a level that reflects background ambient contamination levels in the ocean.</summary>
</bill>
