<bill session="106" type="h" number="1851" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hazard Reporting Protection Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to enhance protections for employees reporting workplace hazards to the Occupational Safety and Health Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400306"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1999-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1999-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1999-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1999-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1999-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3831-3833"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Occupational diseases"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/1999--Introduced.
Hazard Reporting Protection Act of 1999 - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to revise and expand protections for employees reporting workplace hazards to the Occupational Safety and Health Administration. Includes reporting any injury, illness or unsafe condition among those employee actions in exercise of their rights under the Act for which employers are prohibited from discharging or otherwise discriminating against them. Prohibits discharging or discriminating against an employee for refusing to perform the employee's duties when the employee has a reasonable apprehension that performing such duties would result in serious injury or serious impairment of health to the employee or other employees. Allows discrimination complaints to be filed by other persons on behalf of employees, or directly by employees. Extends from 30 to 180 days the deadline for filing a complaint after an alleged violation. Requires a preliminary order providing relief to accompany any findings of the Secretary of Labor that there is reasonable cause to believe that a violation has occurred. Authorizes the Secretary to order various types of preliminary and final relief, including correction of violations, reinstatement, compensatory and exemplary damages, and payment of legal costs. Sets forth administrative and judicial review procedures.</summary>
</bill>
