<bill session="105" type="h" number="4842" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To release the reversionary interests retained by the United States in four deeds that conveyed certain lands to the State of Florida so as to permit the State to sell, exchange, or otherwise dispose of the lands, and to provide for the conveyance of certain mineral interests of the United States in the lands to the State of Florida.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400509"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1998-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Forests"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/15/1998--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to release U.S. reversionary interests in four deeds that conveyed certain lands within the Blackwater River and Withlacoochee State Forests in Florida. Requires lands conveyed under the deeds to be used for public purposes. Authorizes the Secretary to convey to the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund of the State of Florida all of the U.S. mineral interests in any real property for which a reversionary interest is released. Provides for any proceeds derived from the sale of these mineral interests to be deposited into the fund established by the Sisk Act and to be available for expenditure, upon appropriation, for the acquisitions of lands and interests in lands in the same State.</summary>
</bill>
