<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="275" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:55-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2996" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2009-06-26T11:25:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400109"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  <description>Amendment allows the abandoned mine land funding to be used for the non-Federal share of the cost of certain environmental restoration projects funded by the Federal Government that repair acid mine drainage from coal abandoned mines; increases funding (by offset) for the Saving America's Treasures Account; and increases the allocation for the Land and Water Conservation Fund Stateside program from $30 million to $40 million, by reducing the allocation for the Department of Interior, Working Capital Fund by $10 million.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in part A of House Report 111-184 to allow the abandoned mine land funding to be used for the non-Federal share of the cost of certain environmental restoration projects funded by the Federal Government that repair acid mine drainage from coal abandoned mines. Would increase funding for the Saving America's Treasures Account, offset by reducing funding from the Construction account of the National Park Service. Would increase the allocation for the Land and Water Conservation Fund Stateside program from $30 million to $40 million, by reducing the allocation for the Department of Interior, Working Capital Fund by $10 million.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25T22:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Dicks.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7410-7411" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7410" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2009-06-26T11:25:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Dicks amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7463-7464" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7463" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
