<bill session="106" type="h" number="3605" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">San Rafael Western Legacy District and National Conservation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">San Rafael Western Legacy District and National Conservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the San Rafael Western Legacy District in the State of Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="2000-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-02-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H259"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-05-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-06T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-647.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-06-06T14:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="357">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 357.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-06T22:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 516 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3605 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Makes in order as an original bill the Committee on resources amendment in the nature of a substitute now printed in the bill as an original bill for the purpsoe of amendment. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. The amendment printed in H.Rept. 106-654 shall be considered as read. The bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T10:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 516 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 516.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3943-3961" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3942-3943" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3605 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Makes in order as an original bill the Committee on resources amendment in the nature of a substitute now printed in the bill as an original bill for the purpsoe of amendment. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. The amendment printed in H. Rept. 106-654 shall be considered as read. The bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Bill Barrett to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 516 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T10:57:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3605. The rule made in order the Committee on Resources amendment in the nature of a substitute, now printed in the bill, as an original bill for the purpose of amendment, which shall be open for amendment at any point.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T11:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Udall of Colorado.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T11:44:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee is debating the substitute amendment offered by Mr. Boehlert.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T12:22:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the substitute amendment offered by Mr. Boehlert by voice vote and announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Udall of Colroado objected to the voice vote. Pursuant to H. Res. 516, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the Boehlert substitute and the underlying Udall of Colorado amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Inslee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T12:55:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the Inslee amendment by voice vote and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Inslee objected to the voice vote. Pursuant to H. Res. 516, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Holt.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T13:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee is debating the substitute amendment offered by Mr. Boehlert.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the substitute amendment offered by Mr. Boehlert by voice vote and announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Holt objected to the voice vote. Pursuant to H. Res. 516, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the Boehlert substitute and the underlying Holt amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T13:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Cook.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T13:34:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEEDINGS - Proceedings will resume on amendments postponed earlier in the following order: (1) Boehlert substitute amendment to the amendment offered by Mr. Udall of Colorado, (2) Udall underlying amendment; (3) amendment offered by Mr. Inslee; (4) Boehlert substitute amendment to the amendment offered by Mr. Holt; and (5) Holt underlying amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3605 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="516"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2048"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Paleontology"/>
    <term name="Recreational vehicles"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trapping"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h742"/>
    <amendment number="h743"/>
    <amendment number="h744"/>
    <amendment number="h745"/>
    <amendment number="h746"/>
    <amendment number="h747"/>
    <amendment number="h748"/>
    <amendment number="h749"/>
    <amendment number="h750"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/6/2000--Reported to House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: San Rafael Western Legacy District Title II: San Rafael National Conservation Area San Rafael Western Legacy District and National Conservation Act - Title I: San Rafael Western Legacy District - Establishes the San Rafael Western Legacy District (SRWLD) in Utah. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, to establish a Legacy Council to furnish advice regarding management, grants, projects, and technical assistance.Authorizes the Secretary to make grants (of up to 50 percent of the total cost of an SRWLD activity) and provide technical assistance to any nonprofit organization or government unit with authority in the SRWLD's boundaries. Authorizes appropriations.Title II: San Rafael National Conservation Area - Establishes the San Rafael National Conservation Area in Utah. Requires the Secretary to develop a comprehensive management plan.Prohibits the use of motorized vehicles in the Conservation Area (except for reasonable access to private or State lands) at all times in areas where roads and trails did not exist as of February 2, 2000. Limits the use of such vehicles to designated roads and trails existing before such date.Requires the United States to acquire any additional water resources needed for purposes of this Act only in accordance with Utah State water law.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
