<bill session="108" type="h" number="2386" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Monument Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Antiquities Act regarding the establishment by the President of certain national monuments and to provide for public participation in the proclamation of national monuments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400376"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400305" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2003-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2003-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional delegations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Natural monuments"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2003--Introduced.
National Monument Fairness Act - Revises Federal law with respect to a presidential proclamation that, during one calendar year, either creates a national monument that is more than 50,000 acres or that adds more than 50,000 acres to an existing national monument. Prohibits the issuance of such a proclamation until 30 days after the President has transmitted the proposed proclamation to the Governor of the State or States in which such acreage is located, soliciting written comment. Makes any such proclamation ineffective two years after its issuance unless Congress has approved it by law. Provides that land subject to a proclamation issued after the enactment of this Act that ceases to be effective shall revert to the land use status it had before the proclamation was issued. Requires the President: (1) to solicit public participation and comment in the development of a monument proclamation; (2) to consult with the Governor and entire congressional delegation of the State or territory in which such lands are located at least 60 days before any national monument proclamation; and (3) before issuing it, to consider any information, including public comments, made available in the development of existing plans and programs for the management of the lands under consideration. Requires any management plan for a national monument developed subsequent to a proclamation made under this Act to comply with the procedural requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</summary>
</bill>
