<bill session="105" type="h" number="1587" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airline Passenger Safety Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to prohibit the transportation of chemical oxygen generators as cargo on any aircraft carrying passengers or cargo in air commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Airline employees"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Oxygen"/>
    <term name="Smoke detectors"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transport aircraft"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/1997--Introduced.
Airline Passenger Safety Act of 1997 - Amends Federal aviation law to prohibit chemical oxygen generators from being transported as cargo on any passenger or cargo aircraft, regardless of whether the generator has been discharged. Sets forth smoke or fire detector system and fire extinguishing system requirements for air cargo compartment transportation of oxidizers and oxidizing materials (other than chemical oxygen generators). Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to modify existing regulations for aircraft airworthiness standards to require that each Class D cargo or baggage compartment be equipped with a separately approved smoke or fire detector and a separately approved built-in fire extinguishing system meeting certain criteria. Requires the Administrator to: (1) evaluate the practices of, and training provided by, all air carriers for accepting passenger baggage and freight shipments and for identifying undeclared or unauthorized hazardous materials; and (2) require all air carriers to revise, as necessary, their practices and training on the basis of such evaluation.</summary>
</bill>
