<bill session="106" type="h" number="2452" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Commerce Elimination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To dismantle the Department of Commerce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400348"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1999-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400590" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400607" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1999-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="1999-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Banking and Financial Services, International Relations, Armed Services, Ways and Means, Government Reform, the Judiciary, Science, and Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, Hazardous Materials and Pipeline Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW08" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, Hazardous Materials and Pipeline Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Ambassadors"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric research"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Chief financial officers"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Earth resources satellites"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational television"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Export-Import Bank of the United States"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade policy"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Geodesy"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="High technology"/>
    <term name="High technology industries"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Job vacancies"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Metric system"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Nonpoint source pollution"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research ships"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Overseas Private Investment Corporation"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Population statistics"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Severance pay"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Statistical services"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology policy"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication policy"/>
    <term name="Television and children"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Textile industry"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade and Development Agency"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in government"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Abolishment of Department of Commerce Title II: Disposition of Programs, Functions, and Agencies of Department of Commerce Title III: Establishment of United States Trade Administration Subtitle A: General Provisions Subtitle B: United States Trade Administration Title IV: Statistical Consolidation Subtitle A: General Provisions Subtitle B: Establishment of the Federal Statistical Service Subtitle C: Transfers of Functions and Offices Subtitle D: Administrative Provisions Subtitle E: Miscellaneous Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions Department of Commerce Elimination Act - Title I: Abolishment of Department of Commerce - Abolishes the Department of Commerce (Department). Transfers all Department functions to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) before the applicable date of abolishment, which is the earlier of: (1) the last day of the six-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act; or (2) September 30, 1999. (Sec. 103) Sets forth requirements for the resolution of all Department functions. Terminates all functions that are transferred to the Director that are not otherwise continued by this Act on the last day of the three-year period beginning on the date of enactment. (Sec. 104) Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) the OMB Director's responsibilities during the resolution and termination of functions; and (2) transfer of Department personnel. (Sec. 106) Provides for the submission of specified reports. (Sec. 107) Requires General Accounting Office (GAO) audits of: (1) persons performing functions or activities pursuant to this Act; and (2) persons providing certain goods or services to, or receiving financial assistance from, persons performing functions or activities pursuant to this Act. (Sec. 109) Sets forth provisions for privatizing transferred functions designated for privatization under Title II of this Act. (Sec. 110) Amends Federal law concerning Government organization and employees to require affected agencies to establish agencywide priority placement programs for Federal employees affected by a reduction in force attributable to this Act. (Sec. 111) Limits the total amount authorized to be appropriated as funding related to the performance of functions transferred to the Director or to OMB from the Department to not exceed: (1) for the first fiscal year that begins after the abolishment date, 75 percent of the total amount of funding appropriated to the Department for FY 1999; and (2) for the second fiscal year that begins after the abolishment date and for each fiscal year thereafter, 65 percent of the total amount appropriated to the Department for FY 1999. Title II: Disposition of Programs, Functions, and Agencies of Department of Commerce - Repeals the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 and transfers all financial obligations owned by the Department under such Act to the Department of the Treasury. Requires an audit by the Comptroller General of all Department grants made under such Act in FY 1999. (Sec. 202) Terminates the Technology Administration and the Office of Technology Policy. Redesignates the National Institute of Standards and Technology as the National Bureau of Standards (NBS). Transfers: (1) the NBS to the National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) reestablished under this Act; (2) all functions relating to the Bureau that were functions of the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) or the Under Secretary of Commerce for Technology to the NBS Director; and (3) all functions of the National Technical Information Service (NTIS) to the OMB Director for privatization. Provides for the reestablishment of NTIS as a wholly owned Government corporation if an arrangement for privatization of the functions of the NTIS has not been made. (Sec. 203) Transfers all functions of the Secretary relating to the Bureau of the Census and the Bureau of Economic Analysis to the Federal Statistical Service established under this Act. (Sec. 204) Terminates assistance to: (1) public telecommunications; (2) educational television programs; and (3) telecommunications demonstrations. Repeals establishment of the National Endowment for Children's Educational Television (thus abolishing it). Transfers: (1) National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) laboratories to the OMB Director for privatization; (2) NTIA functions concerning the research and analysis of the electromagnetic spectrum to the NBS Director; and (3) functions of the NTIA, and of the Secretary and the Assistant Secretary of Communications and Information with respect to NTIA to the Federal Communications Commission. Provides for the transfer of NTIA laboratories to the reestablished NOAA if an arrangement for privatization of the laboratories has not been made. Abolishes the NTIA. (Sec. 205) Terminates specified miscellaneous NOAA research programs. Transfers from the NOAA: (1) aeronautical mapping and charting functions to the Transportation Administrative Services Center at the Department of Transportation; (2) functions relating to mapping, charting, and geodesy authorized under a certain Act to the Army Corps of Engineers; (3) all functions and assets performed by the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information System to the reestablished NOAA; (4) all functions and assets (including global programs) performed by the NOAA that were authorized to be performed by the Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research to the reestablished NOAA; and (5) all functions and assets of the NOAA that are authorized to be performed by the National Weather Service to the reestablished NOAA. Prohibits: (1) funding for the NOAA Corps of commissioned officers after FY 1997; and (2) allowing individuals to serve as such commissioned officers after FY 1997. Provides for the establishment of a priority placement program by NOAA to assist commissioned officers who are separated from the active list because of the termination. Abolishes on September 30, 2002: (1) the Office of the NOAA Administration Corps of Operations or its successor; and (2) the Commissioned Personnel Center. Sets forth service contract provisions with respect to the NOAA Administration Fleet. Directs the Administrator of Oceans and Atmosphere to: (1) use excess capacity of University National Oceanographic Laboratory System vessels; and (2) enter into memoranda of agreement with the operators of such vessels. Transfers certain excess vessels to the National Defense Reserve Fleet. Transfers to the: (1) NOAA all functions authorized to be performed by the National Marine Fisheries Service; (2) reestablished NOAA all functions performed by the National Ocean Service, including the Coastal Ocean Program; and (3) Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency coastal nonpoint pollution functions that are vested in the Secretary under the Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990. (Sec. 206) Reestablishes as an independent agency in the executive branch the NOAA. Provides for administration of NOAA, and all functions and offices transferred to the new NOAA, under the supervision and direction of an Administrator of Oceans and Atmosphere. Transfers to the new NOAA: (1) the functions and offices of NOAA; (2) the NBS along with its functions and offices; and (3) the Office of Space Commerce, along with its functions and offices. Terminates NOAA and certain other agency offices affected by the transfer. (Sec. 207) Terminates: (1) the Minority Business Development Administration; (2) NTIA programs and activities mentioned in section 204 of this Act; (2) the Advanced Technology Program; (3) the Manufacturing Extension Programs; (4) the NIST METRIC Program; and (5) the Economics and Statistics Administration. Title III: Establishment of United States Trade Administration - Subtitle A: General Provisions - Sets forth definitions. Subtitle B: United States Trade Administration - Chapter 1: Establishment - Reestablishes the Trade Administration in the executive branch as an independent establishment to be headed by the Trade Representative who shall retain ambassador rank and represent the United States in all trade negotiations conducted by the Trade Administration. Directs the Trade Representative to serve as the principal adviser to the President on international trade policy, along with certain additional trade related functions, including those under Chapter 3. Chapter 2: Officers - Sets forth provisions related to Trade Administration management positions and related functions, among other things establishing three Deputy U.S. Trade Representatives: (1) the Deputy U.S. Trade Representative for Negotiations (with ambassador rank); (2) the Deputy U.S. Trade Representative to the World Trade Organization (with ambassador rank); and (3) the U.S. Trade Representative for Administration (acts for and exercises the functions of the Trade Representative during the absence, disability, or vacancy of the Trade Representative and exercises all transferred or established Trade Administration functions, except those functions exercised by certain Trade Administration officials). (Sec. 322) Establishes four Assistant Administrators to exercise certain transferred Department functions under the direction of the Deputy Trade Representative for Administration: (1) the Assistant Administrator for Export Administration; (2) the Assistant Administrator for Import Administration; (3) the Assistant Administrator for Trade and Policy Analysis; and (4) the Assistant Administrator for Export Promotion (with ambassador rank). Creates the position of chief financial officer to perform all functions prescribed by the Deputy Trade Representative for Administration under the direction of such Deputy. Chapter 3: Transfers to the Trade Administration - Abolishes the Office of the United States Trade Representative. Transfers to the Trade Administration Federal trade functions, including those of the Department, the Trade and Development Agency, the Export-Import Bank, and the Overseas Private Investment Corporation. Amends the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988 to reestablish the U.S. and Foreign Commercial Service within the Trade Administration (currently, such Service is in the International Trade Administration of the Department) and to revise certain functions of the Trade and Development Program with respect to the U.S. and Foreign Commercial Service. (Sec. 336) Directs the President to: (1) transmit to the Congress a comprehensive plan to consolidate Federal nonagricultural export promotion and financing activities; and (2) transfer those functions to the Trade Administration. (Sec. 337) Transfers: (1) functions of the Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements (CITA) to the Trade Administration; and (2) other functions of CITA related to the assessment of the impact of textile imports on domestic industry to the International Trade Commission. Abolishes CITA. Chapter 4: Administrative Provisions - Sets out Trade Representative related administrative provisions pertaining to personnel and other miscellaneous administrative matters, including those relating to a working capital fund for administrative expenses. Chapter 5: Related Agencies - Amends the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, the National Security Act of 1947, and the Bretton Woods Agreement Act to make miscellaneous and conforming changes to complete the consolidation and streamlining process described above. Chapter 6: Conforming Amendments - Makes miscellaneous technical and conforming amendments to various specified provisions of Federal law, including those relating to executive schedule positions. Chapter 7: Miscellaneous - Limits the total amount appropriated in the performance of all functions vested in the Trade Representative and the Trade Administration to not exceed: (1) for the first fiscal year that begins after the effective date, 75 percent of the total amount appropriated in FY 1999; and (2) for the second fiscal year and each fiscal year thereafter, 65 percent of the total amount appropriated in FY 1999. Title IV: Statistical Consolidation - Subtitle A: General Provisions - Expresses the sense of the Congress with respect to: (1) a more centralized statistical system and the role of the Chief Statistician of OMB; (2) confidentiality; and (3) decennial censuses of population. Subtitle B: Establishment of the Federal Statistical Service - Establishes the Federal Statistical Service as an independent establishment in the executive branch. Sets forth provisions for principal officers, including: (1) an Administrator; (2) a Deputy Administrator; (3) a Director of the Census; (4) a Director of the Bureau of Economic Analysis; and (5) a Director of the Bureau of Labor Statistics. (Sec. 413) Establishes a Federal Council on Statistical Policy to advise the Service, nominate the Administrator, serve as an advisory body to the Chief Statistician on certain confidentiality issues, and establish a unified statistical policy for the Federal Government. Mandates studies by the Council on: (1) whether the functions of the Bureau of the Census relating to decennial censuses of population could be delineated from the other functions of the Bureau; and (2) making the Bureau's field offices part of the field offices of the Bureau of Labor Statistics. Subtitle C: Transfers of Functions and Offices - Transfers to the Service the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor, along with all of its functions and offices. Subtitle D: Administrative Provisions - Sets forth provisions related to the administrative functions of the Administrator. Subtitle E: Miscellaneous - Sets forth miscellaneous provisions with respect to functions or offices of the Service and makes conforming amendments relating to certain officials of the Service. Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions - Sets forth provisions pertaining to officers and employees to whom a function is transferred by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
