<bill session="108" type="hr" number="557" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-17T19:46:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-03-17T19:46:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">War in Iraq Anniversary resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Relating to the liberation of the Iraqi people and the valiant service of the United States Armed Forces and Coalition forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400167" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2004-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-16T19:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 561 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 557 with 4 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Section 2 of the resolution provides that during consideration of H. Res. 557, notwithstanding the operation of the previous question, the Chair may postpone further consideration of the resolution to a time designated by the Speaker. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-17T12:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 561 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-17T14:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 561.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1122-1129, H1130-1133, H1142-1202" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-17T14:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 557 with 4 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Section 2 of the resolution provides that during consideration of H. Res. 557, notwithstanding the operation of the previous question, the Chair may postpone further consideration of the resolution to a time designated by the Speaker. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-17T14:08:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 561, the House proceeded with 4 hours of debate on H. Res. 557.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-17T19:26:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-17T19:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2004-03-17T19:46:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="64" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 327 - 93, 7 Present (Roll no. 64).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1142" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="561"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Constitutions"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2004--Passed House without amendment.
States that the House of Representatives: (1) affirms that the United States and the world have been made safer with the removal of Saddam Hussein and his regime from power in Iraq; (2) commends the Iraqi people for their courage in the face of unspeakable oppression and brutality inflicted on them by Saddam Hussein's regime; (3) commends the Iraqi people on the adoption of Iraq's interim constitution; and (4) commends the members of the U.S. Armed Forces and Coalition forces for liberating Iraq and expresses its gratitude for their valiant service.</summary>
</bill>
