<bill session="105" type="h" number="3164" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-22T11:03:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-04-22T11:03:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hydrographic Services Improvement Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Hydrographic Services Improvement Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Hydrographic Services Improvement Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To describe the hydrographic services functions of the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1998-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1998-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21T13:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-485.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-04-21T13:07:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="279">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 279.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Saxton asked unanimous consent that it be in order on today, or any day thereafter, for the Speaker, as though pursuant to clause 1(b) of rule XXIII, to declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3164), and that consideration of the bill proceed according to the following order:</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>(1) The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 2(1)(6 of rule XI or section 303(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 are waived. (2) General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Resources. (3) After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>(4) In lieu of the amendment recommended by the Committee on Resources now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the Congressional Record and numbered 1 pursuant to clause 6 of rule XXIII. Each section of that amendment shall be considered as read. Points of order against that amendment in the nature of a substitute for failure to comply with clause 5(a) of rule XXI or section 303(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 are waived. (5) During consideration of the bill for amendment, the Charirman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whether the Member offering an amendment has caused it to be printed in the portion of the Congressional Record. Amendments so printed shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>(6) The chairman of the Committee of the Whole may: (a) postpone until a time during further consideration in the Committee of the Whole a request for a recorded vote on any amendment; and (2) reduce to five minutes the minimum time for electronic voting on any postponed question that follows another electronic vote without intervening business, provided that the minimum time for electronic voting on the first in any series of questions shall be 15 minutes. (7) At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the House with such amendments a may have been adopted. Any Member may demand a separate vote in the House on any amendment adopted in the Committee of the Whole to the bill or to the amendment in the nature of a substitute made in order as original text.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>(8) The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and amendments thereto to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or without instructions. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T10:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated by previous order of the House.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2129-2132" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T10:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by previous order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T10:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole on the state of the Union by previous order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T10:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Paul E. Gillmor to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T10:42:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T11:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3164.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T11:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T11:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-04-22T11:03:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T11:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emblems"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Geodetic research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hydrological forecasting"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="Ocean currents"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research ships"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h552"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/22/1998--Passed House amended.
Hydrographic Services Improvement Act of 1998 - Sets forth the responsibilities of the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) regarding hydrographic data, services, and standards and maintenance of a national hydrographic database. Authorizes related procurement, leasing, and contracts. Authorizes a quality assurance program, allowing certification of hydrographic products and use of a related emblem for certified products. Allows a fee for the certification and use. Establishes the Hydrographic Services Account, consisting of those fees. Requires that fees deposited in the Account be credited as offsetting collections to the NOAA Operations, Research, and Facilities account. Prohibits any charge or increase for any hydrographic service except as authorized in this paragraph (or, for increases, by specified provisions of Federal law). Prohibits the design or installation of any new, and requires the cessation of operation of any existing, Physical Oceanographic Real-Time System unless the local sponsor or another Federal agency has agreed to assume operating and maintenance costs. Requires the Administrator to report to the Congress on: (1) a plan to increase private sector contracting for photogrammetric and remote sensing services regarding hydrographic data acquisition and services; (2) implementation of real-time tide and current data systems in U.S. ports; (3) existing safety and efficiency needs in U.S. ports that could be met by increased use of those systems; (4) a plan for expanding those systems; and (5) a plan to ensure that Federal expertise in hydrographic surveying will be maintained after the decommissioning of the three existing NOAA hydrographic survey vessels. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) nautical mapping and charting; (2) conducting hydrographic surveys; (3) geodetic functions; and (4) tide and current measurement. Requires that fund recipients under this Act agree to comply with the Act popularly known as the "Buy American Act." Declares that it is the sense of the Congress that entities receiving assistance under this Act should, in expending the assistance, purchase only American-made equipment and products. Prohibits any person determined to have intentionally affixed on a product a false "Made in America" label from eligibility for any contract or subcontract made with funds under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
