<bill session="106" type="h" number="2876" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Kenneth Starr Corrections Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Rules of Evidence regarding testimonial privileges of parents, children, and members of the Secret Service; to amend title 18 of the United States Code to restrict prosecutorial conduct with respect to sexual activity not unlawful under Federal law, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400245"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Grand jury"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Perjury"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Self-incrimination"/>
    <term name="Sex and law"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/1999--Introduced.
Kenneth Starr Corrections Act of 1999 - Amends the Federal Rules of Evidence to provide that: (1) a witness may not be compelled to testify against, or disclose the content of a confidential communication with, a child or parent of that witness; and (2) a member of the United States Secret Service may not be compelled to testify with respect to any conversation of the President heard by such member while such member is on duty.(Sec. 3) Prohibits the bringing of a criminal proceeding for perjury or false statement against a witness based on a statement made to the grand jury if: (1) such statement is made in response to a question that is asked by the prosecutor or a member of the grand jury and that arises from or has any basis in physical non-testimonial evidence available and then known to the prosecutor; and (2) the prosecutor fails to provide such evidence to the witness before the conclusion of that witness's testimony or to allow the witness, after receiving such evidence, to explain or modify any testimony.Prohibits: (1) a criminal proceeding from being commenced by an officer or employee of the United States against an individual for making a false statement that relates to adultery or to sexual activity that is not unlawful under Federal law in an affidavit filed in a non-criminal proceeding; and (2) an officer or employee of a U.S. agency from authorizing any person to make an audio or video record of a private communication that such officer, employee, or person reasonably expects will relate to adultery or to sexual activity that is not unlawful under Federal law.(Sec. 4) Amends rule 6 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure to prohibit the making of a photographic record of a witness who testifies before a grand jury for the purpose of recording the testimony such witness gives before the grand jury.(Sec. 5) Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit compelling an individual who is a target of an investigation of a violation of Federal law to appear before a grand jury except under the terms of an order that is effective as provided in the code.</summary>
</bill>
