<bill session="107" type="h" number="5621" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Credit Union Services Expansion Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Credit Union Act to expand membership, service, and investment opportunities for credit unions, to expand credit union services within financially underserved communities, to enhance member protections in certain credit union conversions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1841-1842"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank directors"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Bank management"/>
    <term name="Bank mergers"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Chief executive officers"/>
    <term name="Chief financial officers"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development banking"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary school students"/>
    <term name="Executives"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="High school students"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Savings banks"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/2002--Introduced.
Federal Credit Union Services Expansion Act of 2002 - Amends the Federal Credit Union Act (FCUA) to exempt from the numerical limitation on credit union membership: (1) a Federal credit union merger approved by the National Credit Union Administration Board as of August 7, 1998; and (2) student groups, if certain financial education materials are furnished.Instructs the Board to prescribe criteria for continued membership of certain member groups in community charter conversions.Includes electronic fund transfers among the services available to persons in the field of membership (but not members).Raises the ceiling on member business loans.Amends the Small Business Act (SBA) to allow credit union participation in SBA guaranteed loan programs.Amends the FCUA to declare that if a credit union provides debt management and counseling services it may expand its membership in underserved communities that show both: (1) significant unmet needs for affordable short-term credit from depository institutions; and (2) a high concentration of noninsured commercial credit facilities offering high-cost credit and money transfer services.Amends the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994, with respect to business loans to credit union members, to extend the meaning of insured credit union to include a nonprofit organization owned collectively by insured credit unions.Amends the FCUA to prescribe guidelines governing: (1) investments for the credit union's own account; (2) conversion of insured credit unions to mutual savings banks; (3) member participation in credit union decisions to terminate share insurance; and (4) membership and activities of insured state-chartered credit unions.</summary>
</bill>
