<bill session="105" type="h" number="1964" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Communications Privacy and Consumer Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect consumer privacy, empower parents, enhance the telecommunications infrastructure for efficient electronic commerce, and safeguard data security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverage industry"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Encryption"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Internet service providers"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Smoking and youth"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication agreements"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Consumer Privacy and Parental Empowerment Title II: Internet Infrastructure Advancement Communications Privacy and Consumer Empowerment Act - Title I: Consumer Privacy and Parental Empowerment - Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to commence a proceeding to: (1) determine the methods by which consumers may be enabled to have knowledge that consumer information is being collected about them, used without authorization, or sold through their utilization of telecommunications services and to exercise control over, and stop unauthorized use of, personal information; (2) determine whether such authorities can be exercised by the parents of consumers who are children; (3) propose changes in FTC regulations and recommend legislative changes to correct defects in privacy rights and remedies of parents and consumers generally; and (4) determine the methods by which parents may be enabled to block access to content via the Internet or other computer networks that promotes alcoholic or tobacco products and whether alcohol and tobacco companies maintain Internet sites that promote or market products in a manner directed at children. (Sec. 102) Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to commence a proceeding to: (1) examine the impact of interconnected communications networks of technologies on the privacy rights and remedies of consumers of such technologies and determine the methods by which consumers may be enabled to exercise such rights and remedies; (2) determine whether common carriers have taken adequate steps to secure the communications infrastructure against unauthorized interception of communications and personal information; (3) propose changes in regulations to ensure that the effect on consumer privacy rights is considered in the introduction of new telecommunications services and that the protection of such rights and network security is incorporated in the design of, or rules regulating, such services; and (4) propose changes to regulations and recommend legislative changes to correct defects in such rights, remedies, and security. (Sec. 103) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require Internet access providers, at the time of entering into a service agreement with a customer or at any subsequent time upon request, to offer such customer screening software designed to limit access to material that is inappropriate for children. Requires such software to be provided at no charge or for a fee that does not exceed the software's cost to the provider. (Sec. 104) Extends certain regulations that deny equipment authorization (required for marketing) to, and the manufacture, sale, and import of, scanning receivers to scanners capable of: (1) receiving transmissions in frequencies allocated to a commercial mobile service (currently, the domestic cellular radio telecommunications service); or (2) being equipped with decoders that convert digital commercial mobile service (currently, digital cellular) transmissions to analog voice audio. Title II: Internet Infrastructure Advancement - Makes certain duties of local exchange carriers with respect to interconnection, unbundled access, and collocation for telecommunications carriers applicable to requesting information service providers as well. (Sec. 202) Requires the FCC to establish oversight procedures to ensure that the needs of information service providers and their customers and users of the Internet and interactive computer services are considered during coordinated network planning for interconnection of public telecommunications networks. (Sec. 203) Amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to require the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) to examine, and report annually to the Congress and President on, the extent to which network reliability and data security issues impair the conduct of transactions in interstate commerce through the telecommunications networks, the Internet, or other interactive computer systems. Prohibits the Federal Government or State governments from: (1) restricting or regulating the sale in interstate commerce of encryption or other products for improvement of data security; (2) conditioning the issuance of certificates of authentication or authority upon any escrowing or sharing of private encryption keys; or (3) establishing a licensing or other regulatory scheme that requires key escrow as a condition of regulatory approval. Transfers to the NTIA certain functions of the Secretary of Commerce under the Export Administration Act of 1979 with respect to generally available technologies for the improvement of data security.</summary>
</bill>
