<bill session="107" type="hc" number="422" updated="2013-07-14T18:59:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing concern about continuing serious violations of human rights and fundamental freedoms in Kazakhstan, including substantial noncompliance with the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) commitments on human rights and democratization, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2002-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2002-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2002-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2002-10-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-06-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1129-1130"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Kazakhstan"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Opposition (Political science)"/>
    <term name="Political refugees"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Reporters and reporting"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2002--Introduced.
Expresses concern about the efforts by Kazakhstan's President Nazarbaev to remain in power indefinitely and his willingness to manipulate constitutions, elections, and legislative and judicial systems to do so.Urges: (1) the President of the United States and other U.S. officials to make a stronger effort to raise with President Nazarbaev concern about serious human rights violations; and (2) President Nazarbaev to bring Kazakhstan into compliance with Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe commitments on human rights, democracy, and the rule of law by ensuring free and fair elections and allowing all citizens to participate equally in the political process, without intimidation or fear of reprisal.Calls on the Government of Kazakstan to make possible the return of exiled political leaders, most notably former Prime Minister Kazhegelden, as well as other activists and journalists.Expresses support for independent organizations which are qualified to review the Constitution of Kazakhstan and recommend amendments which would protect human rights, democracy, and the rule of law.Calls on President Nazarbaev to establish conditions for independent and opposition media to function without constraint, limitation, or fear of harassment.Urges the Voice of America and Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, Incorporated, to expand broadcasting into Kazakhstan.</summary>
</bill>
