<bill session="106" type="h" number="920" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Firearms Safety and Consumer Protection Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand the powers of the Secretary of the Treasury to regulate the manufacture, distribution, and sale of firearms and ammunition, and to expand the jurisdiction of the Secretary to include firearm products and non-powder firearms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1999-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1999-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="1999-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2000-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2000-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2000-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2000-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2000-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2000-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2000-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2000-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2000-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="1999-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Firearms injuries"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Regulation of Firearm Products Title II: Prohibitions Title III: Enforcement Subtitle A: Civil Enforcement Subtitle B: Criminal Enforcement Title IV: Administrative Provisions Title V: Relationship to Other Law Firearms Safety and Consumer Protection Act of 1999 - Title I: Regulation of Firearm Products - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe such regulations governing the design, manufacture, and performance of, and commerce in "firearm products" (defined as a firearm, firearm part, nonpowder firearm, and ammunition) as are reasonably necessary to reduce or prevent unreasonable risk of injury resulting from the use of such products. Allows any person to petition the Secretary to: (1) issue, amend, or repeal such a regulation; or (2) require the recall, repair, or replacement of, or the issuance of refunds with respect to, a firearm product. Sets deadlines for taking action on petitions. (Sec. 102) Authorizes the Secretary to issue orders: (1) prohibiting the manufacture, sale, or transfer of a firearm product which has been manufactured, imported, transferred, or distributed in violation of a regulation prescribed under this Act; (2) requiring the recall, repair, or replacement of, or refunds for, firearm products; and (3) prohibiting the manufacture, importation, transfer, distribution, or export of a firearm product if the exercise of other authority under this Act would not be sufficient to prevent the product from posing an unreasonable risk of injury to the public. Authorizes the Secretary, in order to ascertain compliance with this Act, to enter and inspect: (1) any place in which firearm products are manufactured, stored, or held, for distribution in commerce; and (2) any conveyance being used to transport a firearm product. Title II: Prohibitions - Sets forth prohibitions on the manufacture or transfer of firearm products for failure by: (1) a manufacturer to test and certify firearm products or to provide notice to the Secretary of new types of firearm products; (2) a manufacturer or dealer in firearms to label firearm products; and (3) an importer, manufacturer, or dealer to fail to maintain, or permit inspection of, records. Prohibits: (1) the importation and exportation of uncertified firearm products; (2) the manufacturer, offer for sale, distribution in commerce, importation, or exportation of a firearm product in violation of this Act; and (3) the manufacture, purchase, or import of a firearm product at a rate that is significantly greater than that at which the person manufactured, purchased, or imported the product during a base period (prescribed by the Secretary) before the applicable regulation is prescribed under this Act. Makes this title inapplicable to specified governmental authorities. Title III: Enforcement - Subtitle A: Civil Enforcement - Directs the Secretary to impose a civil fine upon any person who violates title II. Provides that each violation shall constitute a separate offense with respect to each firearm product involved, subject to specified limitations. Sets the applicable fine amount at $5,000 for the five-year period immediately following this Act's enactment date, and $10,000 thereafter. (Sec. 302) Authorizes the Attorney General, upon request of the Secretary, to bring an action: (1) to restrain any violation of title II in the U.S. district court for any district in which the violation has occurred or in which the defendant is found or transacts business; and (2) in rem for condemnation of a qualified firearm product in the district court for any district in which the Secretary has found and seized for confiscation the product. (Sec. 303) Authorizes: (1) the Secretary to bring an action in district court to restrain a manufacturer or dealer from manufacturing, distributing, transferring, importing, or exporting; and (2) the court, in such an action, to grant such temporary or permanent relief as necessary to protect the public from the risks posed by such product. (Sec. 304) Authorizes: (1) any person aggrieved by a violation of this Act or any interested person to bring an action against such other person in district court for damages; and (2) the court to award to a prevailing plaintiff a reasonable attorney's fee. (Sec. 306) Specifies that: (1) compliance with this Act shall not relieve any person from liability to any person under common law or State statutory law; and (2) the failure of the Secretary to take any action authorized under this Act shall not be admissible in litigation relating to the product under common law or State statutory law. Subtitle B: Criminal Enforcement - Subjects any person who has been notified of a violation of a provision of this Act and who knowingly violates such provision with respect to a firearms product, to a fine and up to two years' imprisonment. Title IV: Administrative Provisions - Directs the Secretary to: (1) maintain a Firearm Injury Information Clearinghouse for information relating to the causes and prevention of death and injury associated with firearms; (2) conduct continuing studies and investigations of firearm-related deaths and injuries and the resulting economic costs and losses; (3) collect and maintain production and sales figures for licensed manufacturers under the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act; (4) conduct research on the safety of firearm products; (5) develop firearm safety testing methods and devices; and (6) make available to the public, at least annually, the results of such activities. (Sec. 402) Sets forth reporting requirements. Title V: Relationship to Other Law - Specifies that: (1) in the event of any conflict between this Act and any provision of the Arms Export Control Act (AECA), the AECA provision shall control; and (2) this Act shall not be construed to preempt State or local law or to prevent a State from enacting any provision of law regulating or prohibiting conduct with respect to a firearm product, except to the extent of inconsistency with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
