<bill session="105" type="h" number="4176" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Cramming bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Digital Jamming Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to protect consumers against 'spamming', 'slamming', and 'cramming', and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1251"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Direct mail advertising"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Mailing lists"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Telephone rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Prevention of Spamming Title II: Prevention of Slamming and Cramming Digital Jamming Act of 1998 - Title I: Prevention of Spamming - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require each electronic mail (e-mail) service provider, under regulations prescribed by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), to inform its subscribers of the opportunity to provide notification of the subscriber's objection to receiving unsolicited commercial e-mail messages (spam messages). Requires such regulations to specify the methods by which each e-mail service subscriber shall be informed by the service provider of: (1) the subscriber's right to give or revoke an objection to receiving spam messages; and (2) the manner in which such right may be exercised. Makes it unlawful for any person to initiate spam messages: (1) unless such a message contains specified information identifying the sender, a means to indicate a desire not to receive such messages, and related information; (2) to any recipients who have previously indicated a desire not to receive such messages; or (3) unless such a message contains Internet routing information that is accurate, valid, and correctly reflects the actual message routing. Prohibits a subscriber from using the provider's e-mail service in violation of that service's published policy prohibiting or restricting the use its service or equipment for the initiation of a spam message. Provides subscriber liability for violations. Title II: Prevention of Slamming and Cramming - Provides that a telecommunications carrier that violates the verification procedures required before recognition of a switch in a subscriber's telephone or toll service provider shall be liable to such subscriber for twice the amount of all charges paid by the subscriber after such violation. Prohibits such a carrier from submitting for billing on telecommunications services bills unauthorized services or products (cramming). Provides carrier liability for violations. Authorizes the attorney general of a State to bring a civil action on behalf of its residents for such violations. Requires a State so acting to previously notify the FCC and provide a copy of its complaint. Directs the National Telecommunications and Information Administration of the Department of Commerce to conduct a study of, and report to specified congressional committees concerning, the feasibility and desirability of establishing third party verification and authentication systems for preventing illegal changes in telephone subscriber carrier selections.</summary>
</bill>
