<bill session="106" type="h" number="4607" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Prescription Drug Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for a prescription drug benefit for Medicare beneficiaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400124"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2000-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2000-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2000-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E951"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug utilization"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Drugstores"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Management information systems"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Medigap"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2000--Introduced.
Medicare Prescription Drug Act of 2000 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to add a new part D (Prescription Drug Benefit for the Aged and Disabled) outlining the following program components: (1) establishment of a voluntary insurance program, administered by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, to provide prescription drug benefits for individuals who are aged or disabled or have end-stage renal disease and who elect to enroll under such program, to be financed from enrollee premium payments together with contributions from Federal appropriations; (2) scope of benefits; (3) payment of benefits and benefit limits; (4) eligibility and enrollment; (5) monthly premium rates; (6) special eligibility, enrollment, and co-payments rules for low-income individuals; (7) creation within the Federal Supplemental Medical Insurance Trust Fund of the Prescription Drug Insurance Account for payments; (8) administration of benefits through benefit managers; (9) authorization for the Employer Incentive Program to encourage employers to provide adequate prescription drug benefits to retired individuals by subsidizing, in part, the sponsor's cost of providing coverage under qualifying plans; and (10) authorization of appropriations to the Account to cover Government contributions.Directs the Secretary to conduct a study on the feasibility and advisability of establishing an annual open enrollment period under the new part D program.Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to: (1) provide for coverage for certain low-income individuals of part D premiums; (2) require State Medicaid plans to provide that in the case of any individual whose eligibility for medical assistance is not limited to Medicare or Medicare drug cost-sharing, and for whom the State elects to pay monthly premiums under part D, the State will purchase all prescription drugs, without regard to whether the benefit limit for such individual has been reached; and (3) require Government payment of Medicare drug cost-sharing for qualified Medicare beneficiaries and for Medicare-eligible individuals with incomes between 100 and 150 percent of the Federal poverty line.Directs the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MEDPAC) to study and report to Congress on: (1) the ability of benefit managers to improve quality and reduce costs and to assume risk; (2) strategies to improve risk assumption by such managers; (3) the likely effect of allowing benefit managers to vary aspects of the benefit packages based on costs, utilization, and access; and (4) the use of the stop-loss provision, including analysis of benefit manager data on beneficiary utilization and the effectiveness of cost constraints once the stop-loss is triggered.</summary>
</bill>
