<bill session="107" type="h" number="2915" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Safety and Cyber Security Enhancement Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, with respect to the interception of communications, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer hackers"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2001--Introduced.
Public Safety and Cyber Security Enhancement Act of 2001 - Amends the Federal criminal code to provide an exception to wiretapping prohibitions for a person acting under color of law to intercept the wire or electronic communications of a "computer trespasser" under specified circumstances. Creates a foreign intelligence exception involving the interception of electronic communications.Permits a Government agency authorized to use a pen register or trap and trace device to use technology reasonably available that restricts the recording or decoding of electronic or other impulses to the dialing, routing, addressing, and signaling information utilized in the processing and transmitting of wire and electronic communications.Directs the court, upon application to it, to enter an ex parte order authorizing the installation and use of a pen register or a trap and trace device: (1) if the court finds that the Government attorney has certified that the information likely to be obtained is relevant to an ongoing criminal investigation (which order shall apply nationwide); or (2) within the jurisdiction of the court if the court finds that the State law enforcement or investigative officer has certified that the information likely to be obtained is relevant.Authorizes any U.S. Attorney or acting U.S. Attorney to have installed and to use a pen register or trap and trace device under specified emergency situations, including situations involving: (1) an immediate threat to national security; and (2) an ongoing attack on a protected computer that constitutes a crime punishable by a term of imprisonment greater than one year.</summary>
</bill>
