<bill session="105" type="h" number="565" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Investment for America Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reinstate a 10-percent domestic investment tax credit, to provide a credit for the purchase of domestic durable goods, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400611"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E143"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/1997--Introduced.
Investment for America Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reinstate a ten percent investment tax credit for domestic property placed in service after December 31, 1992. Defines domestic property as property completed in the United States, at least 60 percent of the basis of which is attributable to value added within the United States. Allows a tax credit for seven percent of the aggregate amount paid for the purchase of domestic durable goods. Limits such credit to $1,000. Permits a tax credit equal to qualified payments made for the purchase of an American automobile. Defines "qualified payments" as State or local sales tax imposed on the purchase of the automobile and interest on the automobile loan. Prohibits a product from bearing a label which suggests that it was made in America unless: (1) the product has been registered with the Department of Commerce; and (2) the Secretary of Commerce has determined that 60 percent of the product was manufactured in, and final assembly took place in, the United States. Requires the registry of American-made products with the Department of Commerce. Prescribes penalties for the fraudulent use of labels.</summary>
</bill>
