<bill session="104" type="h" number="925" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-03T13:33:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-03-03T13:33:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Contract with America bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Regulatory Overhaul bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Takings bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Private Property Protection Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Private Property Protection Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To compensate owners of private property for the effect of certain regulatory restrictions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400574"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-02-23T14:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 104-46.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-02-23T14:30:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="23">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 23.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-02-28T19:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 101 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 925 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. After passage of H.R. 925, it shall be in order to consider in the House H.R. 9. All points of order against the bill and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to amend and on the bill to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-01T21:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated by previous special order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-01T21:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered by previous special order.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2469-2473" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-01T21:06:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole on the state of the Union pursaunt to the previous special order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-01T21:07:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Bud Shuster to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-01T21:08:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-01T21:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 925 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02T10:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 101 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2495-2566" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole resumed general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02T21:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 925 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T10:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2590-2607" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T10:44:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T10:44:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole continued with debate on the Mineta amendment which was pending when the Committee rose on Thursday, March 2, 1995. The amendment seeks to raise the minimum threshold for payment of compensation under the bill from a 10% to 20% loss in property value.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T11:54:00-05:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Canady asked unanimous consent that Mr. Goss be recognized next for the purpose of offering an amendment, that debate on that amendment be limited to not to exceed 10 minutes equally divided and controlled, and that after completion of the Goss amendment, that Messrs. Taylor and Traficant be recognized for the purpose of offering amendments and that debate on each amendment be limited to not to exceed 5 minutes, equally divided and controlled. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T11:56:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement just secured, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Goss amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T12:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 925 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T12:26:00-05:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Canady asked unanimous consent that consideration of the bill, H.R. 925, in the Committee of the Whole be extended for an addtional 10 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T12:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR  H2607" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T12:29:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T13:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 925.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T13:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T13:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-03-03T13:33:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="197" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 277 - 148 (Roll no. 197).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T13:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T13:33:00-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 925.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="101"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="104" type="h" number="9"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="9"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="489"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="790"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1277"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="605"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h247"/>
    <amendment number="h248"/>
    <amendment number="h249"/>
    <amendment number="h250"/>
    <amendment number="h251"/>
    <amendment number="h252"/>
    <amendment number="h253"/>
    <amendment number="h254"/>
    <amendment number="h255"/>
    <amendment number="h256"/>
    <amendment number="h257"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/3/1995--Passed House amended.
Private Property Protection Act of 1995 - Requires the Federal Government to compensate a property owner whose use of that property has been limited by an agency action, pursuant to a specified regulatory law, that diminishes the fair market value of that property by 20 percent or more, for that diminution in value. Requires the Government to buy at fair market value any portion of a property whose value has been diminished by more than 50 percent. Declares that property with respect to which compensation has been paid under this Act shall not thereafter be used contrary to the limitation imposed by the agency action, unless: (1) the action is later rescinded or vitiated; and (2) the property owner refunds the amount of the compensation to the Treasury. Provides that if a use is a nuisance as defined by State law or local zoning ordinance, no compensation shall be made under this Act with respect to a limitation on that use. Prohibits compensation from being made under this Act with respect to: (1) an agency action the primary purpose of which is to prevent an identifiable hazard to public health and safety or damage to specific property other than the property whose use is limited; or (2) an agency action pursuant to the Federal navigational servitude, except as such servitude is applied by U.S. courts to wetlands. Sets forth the procedures by which a property owner may seek compensation under this Act. Subjects any payment under this Act to the availability of appropriations. Requires any agency taking an action limiting private property use to give appropriate notice of rights and compensation procedures to the property owners. Declares that: (1) nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit any right to compensation under the Constitution or other Federal law; and (2) payment of compensation shall not confer on the Federal Government any rights other than the use limitation resulting from the agency action.</summary>
</bill>
