<bill session="108" type="h" number="4586" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-07-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Movie Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Family Movie Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that making limited portions of audio or video content of motion pictures imperceptible by or for the owner or other lawful possessor of an authorized copy of that motion picture for private home viewing, and the use of technology therefor, is not an infringement of copyright or of any right under the Trademark Act of 1946.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2004-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2004-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 11 - 5.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 18 - 9.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 108-670.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-09-08T17:51:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="410">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 410.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2004--Reported to House amended.
Family Movie Act of 2004 - Amends Federal copyright law to create an exemption from copyright infringement for: (1) the act of rendering imperceptible portions of audio or video content in movies by or for the owner or lawful possessor of authorized copies of such movies in the course of private home viewing by means of consumer equipment or services that are operated by an individual in that household, serve only such household, and do not create a fixed copy of the altered version; and (2) the use of technologies allowing such movie content to be rendered imperceptible where the technology does not create a copy of the altered version. Amends the Trademark Act of 1946 to protect from liability for trademark infringement: (1) persons who engage in the above-referenced conduct; and (2) manufacturers, licensees, or licensors of technology that enables content to be rendered imperceptible. Requires such manufacturers, licensees, or licensors to ensure that the technology provides notice that performance of the movie is altered from the director's or copyright holder's intended performance. Establishes civil penalties for manufacturers who fail to provide the requisite notice.</summary>
</bill>
