<bill session="104" type="h" number="3231" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY97, Military Construction</title>
    <title type="popular">Military Construction FY97 Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize certain construction at military installations for fiscal year 1997, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400302" joined="1996-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Air bases"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Architecture"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense burdensharing"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military construction operations"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Naval bases"/>
    <term name="Naval hospitals"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water rates"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title XXI(SIC): Army Title XXII: Navy Title XXIII: Air Force Title XXIV: Defense Agencies Title XXV: North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program Title XXVI: Guard and Reserve Forces Facilities Title XXVII: Expiration and Extension of Authorizations Title XXVIII: General Provisions Subtitle A: Military Construction Program and Military Family Housing Changes Subtitle B: Base Closure and Realignment and Environment Subtitle C: Land Conveyance Subtitle D: Other Matters Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1997 - Title XXI(sic): Army - Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes the Secretary to construct or acquire family housing units, to carry out architectural planning and design activities, and to improve existing military family housing in specified amounts. Authorizes appropriations to the Army for fiscal years after 1996 for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions of the Army. Limits the total cost of construction projects authorized by this title. Title XXII: Navy - Provides, with respect to the Navy, authorizations paralleling those provided for the Army under the previous title. Title XXIII: Air Force - Provides, with respect to the Air Force, authorizations paralleling those provided for the Army. Title XXIV: Defense Agencies - Authorizes the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out architectural planning and design activities and to improve existing military family housing units, in specified amounts. (Sec. 2404) Earmarks funds authorized under this title for the Department of Defense (DOD) Family Housing Improvement Fund. (Sec. 2405) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out specified energy conservation projects. (Sec. 2406) Authorizes appropriations to DOD for fiscal years after 1996 for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions. Limits the total cost of authorized construction projects. Title XXV: North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program - Authorizes the Secretary to make contributions for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program. Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 1996. Title XXVI: Guard and Reserve Forces Facilities - Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 1996 for the Guard and Reserve forces for acquisition, architectural and engineering services, and construction of facilities. (Sec. 2602) Authorizes specified Army National Guard military construction projects and architectural and engineering services and construction design, using prior year appropriations. Title XXVII: Expiration and Extension of Authorizations - Terminates all authorizations contained in the preceding titles of this Act on October 1, 1999, or the date of enactment of an Act authorizing funds for military construction for FY 2000, whichever is later, with exceptions. Extends certain prior-year military construction projects. Title XXVIII: General Provisions - Subtitle A: Military Construction Program and Military Family Housing Changes - Increases: (1) from $300,000 to $350,000 the active and reserve component minor construction threshold for a project the Secretary may carry out using operation and maintenance funds without prior approval from the appropriate congressional committees; and (2) from $400,000 to $1.5 million the reserve component minor construction project threshold beyond which congressional notification and a 21-day waiting period are required. (Sec. 2802) Includes major maintenance and the repair of drives within the definition of an "improvement" for purposes of authorized improvements to military family housing. Subtitle B: Base Closure and Realignment and Environment - Amends the Defense Authorization Amendments and Base Closure and Realignment Act and the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 to authorize the Secretary to contract with local governments for the provision of certain community services at facilities on installations closed pursuant to such laws. (Sec. 2806) Authorizes the Secretary to pay from the Department of Defense Base Closure Account (Part II) up to $50,000 for stipulated environmental damages assessed against Loring Air Force Base, Maine. Subtitle C: Land Conveyance - Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to convey to: (1) Richmond or Madison County, Kentucky, a specified sewage collection, treatment, and disposal system at Bluegrass Army Depot, Kentucky; (2) the Dublin San Ramon Services District, California, a specified water treatment and distribution system at Camp Parks, California; (3) Leavenworth, Kansas, a specified water treatment and distribution system at Fort Leavenworth, Kansas; (4) Pierce County, Washington, a specified sewage collection, treatment, and disposal system at Fort Lewis, Washington; (5) Odenton, Maryland, a specified water treatment and distribution system at Fort Meade, Maryland; (6) Monmouth County, New Jersey, a specified water treatment and distribution system at Fort Monmouth, New Jersey; and (7) Hinesville, Georgia, a specified sewage collection, treatment, and disposal system at the Hunter Army Air Field, Fort Stewart, Georgia. (Sec. 2814) Authorizes the Secretary of the military department concerned to grant an easement for rights-of-way for electric power or communication poles and lines. Subtitle D: Other Matters - Authorizes the Secretary of the Air Force to enter into an agreement with a local electric utility or private company to install, operate, and maintain a new electrical distribution system at Youngstown Air Reserve Station, Ohio. Provides agreement conditions. Provides funds for such system from funds authorized and appropriated for FY 1996.</summary>
</bill>
