<bill session="105" type="h" number="4568" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Retirement Reform Technical Corrections Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical and clarifying amendments to the provisions of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 relating to the reform of certain District of Columbia retirement programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Held by the Subcommittee on Districtof Columbia and Forwarded to Full Committee by Voice Vote Prior to Introduction (Sept 9, 98).</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defined contribution plans"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Municipal employees"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Municipal politics and government"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/1998--Introduced.
District of Columbia Retirement Reform Technical Corrections Act of 1998 - Amends the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, with respect to provisions regarding District of Columbia retirement funds, to include Federal agencies within the definition of "person" under such provisions. Permits the District of Columbia Federal Pension Liability Trust Fund to be used to cover administrative expenses. Authorizes the Trustee of the Trust Fund, with the Secretary of the Treasury's approval, to enter into subcontracts with the District government or any person to provide services to the Trustee in connection with the contract to administer the Trust Fund. Revises provisions regarding reimbursement of the District government for interim administration of retirement benefits. Makes nonjudicial employees of the District of Columbia courts transferred to the Federal Employees' Retirement System eligible for Medicare and Social Security benefits. Requires, for purposes of vesting pursuant to the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, creditable service with the District for employees whose participation in the District Defined Contribution Plan ceases as a result of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 to include: (1) continuous service by nonjudicial employees of the District courts after September 30, 1997; and (2) service performed for a successor employer that provides services previously performed by the District government. Requires this Act to take effect as if included in the enactment of title XI (the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997) of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997.</summary>
</bill>
