<bill session="105" type="h" number="1292" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Voluntary Alcohol Advertising Standards for Children Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to authorize the establishment of a voluntary broadcasting code for alcohol advertising, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1997-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1997-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
    <term name="Television and children"/>
    <term name="Television industry"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/1997--Introduced.
Voluntary Alcohol Advertising Standards for Children Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), on the basis of recommendations from an advisory committee established by the FCC, to prescribe a code of conduct (code) that limits the exposure and appeal to minors of alcoholic beverage advertisements in video programming, taking into consideration the content, frequency, timing, and program placement of such ads as well as the role of public information messages about the risks of alcohol use by minors. Outlines advisory committee requirements. Provides an antitrust exemption, with limitations, for any action or agreement among persons in the television industry undertaken to develop and disseminate such a voluntary code. Requires the FCC to prescribe such code within one year after enactment of this Act, unless the television industry has established a voluntary code which is acceptable to the FCC. Requires the FCC to include in a currently required annual report an assessment of the extent to which a code has been successfully implemented, and complied with, by video programming distributors.</summary>
</bill>
