<bill session="106" type="hr" number="649" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global School Meals and Women and Children Nutrition Resolution of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Urging the President to continue efforts to support programs and activities that provide food to the needy and school-age children in developing countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400538"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2000-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2000-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Ambassadors"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hunger"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Maternal and infant welfare"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/24/2000--Introduced.
Global School Meals and Women and Children Nutrition Resolution of 2000 - Commends Ambassador George McGovern and former Senator Robert Dole for their endorsement and leadership in promoting a worldwide school meals program and for their remarks at the May 2000 National Nutrition Summit at which they called on the U.S. Government to lead the world in providing such meals for the more than 300 million hungry children in developing countries.Urges the President to: (1) continue efforts to support programs and activities that provide food to the needy and school-age children in such countries, including under the Global Food and Education Initiative; (2) ensure that the appropriate offices within the Department of Agriculture and the United States Agency for International Development have an adequate number of personnel to carry out, monitor, and evaluate the Initiative; and (3) continue to lead in organizing a worldwide school meals program and a supplementary feeding program for pregnant and nursing women and their children under the age of five, including by transmitting a request for legislation to authorize and fund such programs for FY 2002 and subsequent fiscal years.</summary>
</bill>
