<bill session="105" type="hr" number="610" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-20T20:29:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-20T20:29:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the people of the Republic of Mozambique are to be commended for their commitment to rebuilding their nation after years of civil war, their willingness to live together harmoniously despite sharp political differences, and their ability to overcome poverty, health crises, and refugee outflows to build a growing economy and a positive future for their country.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400513"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T20:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on International Relations discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T20:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T20:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11689" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-10-20T20:29:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T20:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Mozambique"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/1998--Introduced.
Commends: (1) the achievements of the Mozambican people in overcoming political and economic obstacles to become a model of reconciliation and development; (2) those who have led Mozambique toward political reconciliation and away from armed conflict; and (3) the Mozambican people for continuing to support democracy and democratic institutions. Calls upon: (1) U.S. Government agencies to continue to work with their Mozambican counterparts in forging a close bilateral relationship; (2) the Government of Mozambique to continue to be a model of democracy, economic liberalization, and respect for human rights; and (3) those nations in the world torn by civil strife to look toward the example of Mozambique for the benefits of political reconciliation and peaceful economic development.</summary>
</bill>
