<bill session="104" type="h" number="1004" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Communications Decency Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the public from the misuse of the telecommunications network and telecommunications devices and facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="314"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Telephone rates"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/21/1995--Introduced.
Communications Decency Act of 1995 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit the use of any telecommunications device (currently, only the telephone) by a person not disclosing his or her identity in order to annoy, abuse, threaten, or harass any person who receives such communication. Prohibits the repeated use of a telecommunications device solely for harassment purposes. Prohibits a person from allowing the use of any telecommunications facility (currently, telephone facility) in his or her control for such purposes. Increases: (1) the fine and maximum sentence for such violations; and (2) the fine for the transmission over a cable system of obscene or otherwise unprotected material. (Sec. 4) Amends the Federal criminal code to: (1) increase the fine for broadcasting obscene, indecent, or profane language over the radio; and (2) include digital communications in a prohibition against the interception and disclosure of various forms of communications. (Sec. 6) Prohibits a person making a toll-free telephone call from being assessed a charge for the call by being asked to connect or otherwise transfer to a pay-per-call service. (Sec. 7) Requires a cable operator, in providing video programming unsuitable for children to any subscriber through a cable system, to fully scramble or otherwise block the video and audio portion of each channel carrying such programming to ensure that one not a subscriber to such programming does not receive it. (Sec. 8) Allows a cable operator to refuse to transmit any portion of a public access program or leased access program which contains obscenity, indecency, or nudity.</summary>
</bill>
