<bill session="107" type="h" number="2821" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Defense Space Reorganization Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the organization and management of the Department of Defense with respect to space programs and activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400404"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-08-29">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Air force procurement"/>
    <term name="Astronautics"/>
    <term name="Astronautics and military science"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Military intelligence"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space policy"/>
    <term name="Space warfare"/>
    <term name="Space weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2001--Introduced.
Defense Space Reorganization Act of 2001 - Authorizes the President to establish in the Department of Defense (DOD) the position of Under Secretary of Defense for Space, Intelligence, and Information, to perform duties and exercise powers relating to DOD space, intelligence, and information programs and activities.Requires the President: (1) to notify Congress after establishing such position; or (2) if he declines to establish such position, to report on how he has implemented the recommendations of the report of the Space Commission.Requires the Secretary of the Air Force to be the DOD executive agent for the planning and execution of DOD space-related acquisition programs, projects, and activities.Requires the Secretary of Defense to create a major force program category for space programs for purposes of the future-years defense program.Directs the Comptroller General to carry out an assessment of the implementation of recommendations of the Space Commission applicable to DOD.Prohibits the commander of the Air Force Space Command from serving simultaneously as commander of the U.S. Space Command or as commander of the U.S. element of the North American Air Defense Command..Directs the Secretary of the Air Force to establish and implement policies and procedures to develop a cadre of technically competent officers to develop space doctrine, concepts of space operations, and management of space systems.</summary>
</bill>
