<bill session="108" type="h" number="3993" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Country-of-Origin Labeling Enhancement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946, as recently amended by the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2004, to expedite the implementation of the country of origin labeling requirements of such Act, to impose certain recordkeeping requirements on retailers subject to such Act, to clarify the authority to impose civil penalties under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2004-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2004-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2004-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2004--Introduced.
Country-of-Origin Labeling Enhancement Act of 2004 - Amends the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946, as amended by the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2004, to make country-of-origin notice requirements applicable to retail sales of all covered commodities as of September 30, 2004. (Current law applies such requirements to farm-raised and wild fish as of such date, and other covered commodities as of September 30, 2006.) Requires a retailer to maintain country-of-origin records for at least 180 days. Provides for the future inclusion of national animal identification system information into the certification of origin requirements. Revises civil money penalty provisions for country-of-origin notice violations.</summary>
</bill>
