<bill session="104" type="h" number="1720" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-24T13:51:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-09-24T13:51:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Privatization Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Privatization Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Government-Sponsored Enterprise Privatization Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Library Services and Technology Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Museum and Library Services Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for the cessation of Federal sponsorship of two Government sponsored enterprises, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400267"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-06-08">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Economic and Educational. H. Rept. 104-153.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-06-22T13:25:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="71">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 71.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-09-19">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.1617.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24T13:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McKeon moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10783-10802" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-09-24T13:51:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1617"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Education)"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Airline employees"/>
    <term name="Area studies"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Asbestos"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="College libraries"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="College teachers"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and college"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Credit insurance"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of Indians"/>
    <term name="Education of handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Educational surveys"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary school students"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Graduate students"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Holding companies"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law students"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Leadership"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Librarians"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Migrant education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority students"/>
    <term name="Minority teachers"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Nursing students"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Professional education"/>
    <term name="Public broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radon"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School administrators"/>
    <term name="School violence"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Seasonal labor"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Social sciences"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student employment"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teachers colleges"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women scientists"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/1996--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Reorganization and Privatization Title II: Museums and Libraries Title III: Extension of Programs Title IV: Repeals and Conforming Amendments Government-Sponsored Enterprise Privatization Act of 1996 - Title I: Reorganization and Privatization - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to provide for the reorganization of the Student Loan Marketing Association (Sallie Mae) through the formation of a holding company and the cessation of Federal sponsorship. (Sec. 102) Provides for the privatization and renaming of the College Construction Loan Insurance Association (Connie Lee) and the cessation of Federal sponsorship. (Sec. 103) Revises the definition of proprietary institution of higher education to prohibit the Secretary of Education from considering the financial information of any institution for a fiscal year that began on or before April 30, 1994, in determining whether the institution meets the requirement that it have at least 15 percent of its revenues from sources not derived from HEA student aid funds. Title II: Museums and Libraries - Museum and Library Services Act - Amends the Museum Services Act to revise and rename it as the Museum and Library Services Act (MLSA). (Sec. 201) Establishes within the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities (NFAHA) an Institute of Museum and Library Services (IMLS), consisting of an Office of Museum Services (OMS) and an Office of Library Services (OLS), with a National Museum Services Board in OMS. Provides for an IMLS Director and Deputy Directors for OMS and OLS. Library Services and Technology Act - Provides for Library Services and Technology under MLSA, with an emphasis on library services and technology, access, and literacy programs for underserved communities. Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of Education for grants to States for information access through technology and information empowerment through special services. Directs the Secretary to transfer such funds to the Director to carry out such library services and technology programs. Sets forth basic program requirements for reservations and allotments, payments, 50 percent Federal share, maintenance of effort, and State plans. Sets forth requirements and authorized activities for such library programs of grants to States for: (1) information access through technology; and (2) information empowerment through special services (including special services for children in poverty who are served by libraries). Sets forth administrative provisions for such library grants programs, including State evaluation of assisted activities, State advisory councils, Federal grants for library services for Indian tribes, and a program of national leadership and evaluation activities. Sets forth MLSA provisions for Museum Services. Continues to authorize: (1) grants to museums to increase and improve museum services through specified types of activities; and (2) contracts and cooperative agreements with appropriate entities for projects to strengthen museum services. Continues to limit the Federal share to 50 percent, allowing the Director to use up to 20 percent of funds to make such grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements where the Federal share may be 100 percent. Requires the Director to undertake an assessment of the collaborative possibilities museums can engage in to serve the public more broadly and effectively. Authorizes the Director to make an annual National Award for Museum Service to outstanding museums that have made significant contributions in service to their communities. Includes the Director as a member of the National Museum Services Board (which gives policy advice to the Director with respect to grants, contracts, and other matters). Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 202) Amends the National Commission on Libraries and Information Science Act to make the Commission responsible for advising the IMLS Director on general policies with respect to IMLS duties and powers relating to library services. Directs the Commission to meet jointly with the National Museum Services Board at least once a year to advise on general policy with respect to financial assistance for joint projects of OLS and OMS. Includes the IMLS Director as a nonvoting member of such Commission. Increase the number of such members who must be professional librarians or information specialists. Requires that at least one of the other members be knowledgeable about the library and information service and science needs of the elderly. (Sec. 203) Transfers functions from the Institute of Museum Services (IMS) to the Institute of Museum and Library Services (IMLS). (Sec. 204) Provides that the current IMS Director shall serve as the first IMLS Director. (Sec. 205) Requires the IMLS Director, in appointing OLS employees, to give strong consideration to individuals with experience in administering State-based library programs. (Sec. 206) Directs the Secretary of Education to transfer certain appropriated funds to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, who shall take measures, using such appropriations, to ensure an orderly transition from the activities previously administered by the Director of Library Programs in the Office of Educational Research and Improvement in the Department of Education to the activities administered by the Institute for Museum and Library Services under this title. Title III: Extension of Programs - Amends the National Literacy Act of 1991 to revise and extend provisions for funding related to the National Workforce Literacy Assistance Collaborative and the Functional Literacy and Life Skills Program for State and Local Prisoners. (Sec. 302) Amends the Adult Education Act (AEA) to extend the authorization of appropriations for AEA programs. Provides for family literacy services. Establishes the National Institute for Literacy, under AEA, to be administered under the terms of an interagency group agreement of the Secretaries of Education, of Labor, and of Health and Human Services (the Interagency Group), with daily operations to be carried out by an appointed Institute Director. Directs the Institute to improve the quality and accountability of the adult basic skills and literacy delivery system by making grants and contracts to carrying out specified activities. Authorizes the Institute to award literacy leadership fellowships, as well as paid and unpaid internships. Establishes an Advisory Board to make recommendations to the Institute. Sets forth Institute duties, authorized activities, and biennial reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 303) Amends the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Applied Technology Act to extend its authorization of appropriations. Title IV: Repeals and Conforming Amendments - Repeals the Library Services and Construction Act. (Sec. 401) Repeals specified provisions under the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986, the Technology for Education Act of 1994, the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965, the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act, and other specified Federal law. Repeals various provisions under HEA, including those relating to articulation agreements, access and equity to education through telecommunications, academic libraries and information services, presidential access scholarships, model program community partnerships and counseling grants, database and information line on student financial assistance, technical assistance for teachers and counselors, special child care services for disadvantaged college students, loan forgiveness for teachers and nurses and individuals performing national community service, training in financial aid services, State postsecondary review entity programs, State and local programs for teacher excellence, national teacher academies, Douglas teacher scholarships, the Teacher Corps, class size demonstration grants, middle school teaching demonstration programs, new teaching careers, national mini corps programs, demonstration grants for critical language and area studies, foreign languages and cultures instructional materials development, faculty development grants, early childhood staff training and professional enhancement, intensive summer language institutes, periodicals and other research materials published outside of the United States, academic and library facilities, cooperative education programs, and Eisenhower leadership programs. Repeals: (1) provisions of the Higher Education Amendments of 1986 relating to library resources, a National Academy of Sciences study, and Alaska Native and Native Hawaiian culture and art development; (2) provisions of the Education Amendments of 1974 for the Office of Libraries and Learning Resources; and (3) provisions of the Education Amendments of 1992 relating to American Indian postsecondary economic development scholarships, American Indian teacher training, a national survey of factors associated with participation, a study of environmental hazards in higher education institutions, a national job bank for teacher recruitment, a national clearinghouse for postsecondary education materials, school-based decisionmakers, sexual offenses education, Olympic scholarships, and advanced placement fee payment programs.</summary>
</bill>
