<bill session="105" type="hr" number="257" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-01T11:59:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-10-01T11:59:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 901) to preserve the sovereignty of the United States over public lands and acquired lands owned by the United States, and to preserve State sovereignty and private property rights in non-Federal lands surrounding those public lands and acquired lands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-10-01T11:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-288, by Mr. Hastings (WA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-01T11:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 901 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Resources now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. The amendment made in order by Mr. Miller of California shall be debatable for not to exceed one hour, equally divided and controlled. Upon the adoption of the resolution, H. Res. 243 shall be laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-10-01T11:59:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="102">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 102.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-10-07T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Laid on the table.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8538" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="901"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/1997--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (modified closed) for the consideration of H.R. 901 (Federal land designations). Lays H. Res. 243 on the table in the House.</summary>
</bill>
