<bill session="108" type="h" number="4159" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drug Impaired Driving Research and Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 23, United States Code, to research and prevent drug impaired driving.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400324" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2004-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-02">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="2480"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2004--Introduced.
Drug Impaired Driving Research and Prevention Act - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to develop and provide to the States a model statute relating to drug impaired driving which incorporates certain mandatory and discretionary provisions, including, at a minimum, a provision that the crime of drug impaired driving is committed when a person operates a motor vehicle: (1) while any detectable amount of a controlled substance is present in the person's body; or (2) due to the presence of a controlled substance or a controlled substance in combination with alcohol or an inhalant, or both, the person's mental or physical faculties are affected to a noticeable degree. Specifies discretionary provisions, including: (1) sanctions for refusing to submit to a drug test which are equivalent to sanctions for a positive test result; (2) a graduated system of penalties for repeat offenses; (3) authorization for States to suspend or revoke the license of a driver convicted of driving while under the influence of a controlled substance; and (4) a system of evaluation, counseling, treatment, and supervision for persons convicted of drug impaired driving. Authorizes the Secretary to use certain funds for research and development in drug detection and testing technology. Specifies certain training goals to enhance the State's ability to detect, enforce, and prosecute drug impaired driving laws. Requires the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to advise and coordinate with other Federal agencies on how to address the problem of driving under the influence of an illegal drug, and to conduct research on the prevention, detection, and prosecution of driving under the influence of an illegal drug.</summary>
</bill>
