<bill session="107" type="hc" number="370" updated="2013-07-14T18:59:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress that the United States should promote and support the use of sound science in management decisions made by the International Whaling Commission and remain diligent in their efforts to protect the ability of Native people of the United States, who have been issued quotas by the International Whaling Commission, to continue to legally harvest whales, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-04-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Indian hunting and fishing rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine biology"/>
    <term name="Marine mammal protection"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Whales"/>
    <term name="Whaling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2002--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should: (1) remain diligent in its efforts to protect the ability of Native people of the United States who have been issued quotas by the International Whaling Commission to continue to legally harvest whales; and (2) support prompt completion by the Commission of all outstanding portions of a revised management scheme.Urges the President to instruct the U.S. delegation to the 54th annual meeting of the Commission to support: (1) positions that are based on sound science; and (2) only those resolutions proposing the designation of any new whale sanctuaries that have specific, scientifically defensible goals, that have a long-term research component to monitor progress toward meeting the goals, and that are based on guidelines and criteria developed by the Commission's Scientific Committee.</summary>
</bill>
