<bill session="104" type="h" number="2908" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Domesticated Salmonid Broodstock and Seedstock Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote international trade and interstate commerce in the broodstock and seedstock of domesticated salmonid by authorizing the Secretary of Agriculture to provide diagnostic and certification services to reduce the risk of transmission of diseases associated with domesticated salmonid.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1996-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1996-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1996-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1996-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1996-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="410067" joined="1996-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="410636" joined="1996-02-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-05">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Commerce, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy and Poultry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Received from Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy and Poultry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fish culture"/>
    <term name="Fish inspection"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Test facilities"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/1996--Introduced.
Domesticated Salmonid Broodstock and Seedstock Act of 1996 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, in cooperation with producers of domesticated salmonid seedstock, to establish a comprehensive program with regard to domesticated salmonid broodstock and seedstock to: (1) provide effective and efficient diagnostic and certification services in a manner that fosters the participation of State and private laboratories; (2) establish health criteria; and (3) monitor, evaluate, and facilitate the elimination of unreasonable impediments to the interstate commerce of such stock that is certified under the program. Authorizes the Secretary to use specified authorities to regulate the production, transportation, and exportation of such stock in order to prevent the introduction or dissemination in interstate commerce and international trade of any contagious, infectious, or communicable disease associated with it and to promote its exportation. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish an advisory committee to advise the Secretary regarding the development and implementation of the program; and (2) certify to any person the health status of any domesticated salmonid seedstock intended for export from the United States. Grants the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce sole responsibility for the health of salmonids and the products thereof located in any facility administered by the Departments of the Interior or Commerce.</summary>
</bill>
