<bill session="105" type="h" number="3866" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Water Resources Development Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the conservation and development of water and related resources, to authorize the Secretary to construct various projects for improvements to rivers and harbors of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1998-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1998-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1998-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-05-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E857-858"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="2131"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Beach erosion"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Dredging spoil"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Estuarine ecology"/>
    <term name="Estuarine pollution"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Freshwater ecology"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pacific area"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/1998--Introduced.
Water Resources Development Act of 1998 - Authorizes projects for flood damage reduction, or flood damage reduction and recreation, in California, Louisiana, Minnesota and North Dakota, and Puerto Rico. (Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to undertake a program to perform studies and carry out projects to reduce flood hazards and restore natural functions and values of riverine ecosystems throughout the United States. Outlines cost-sharing requirements. Requires the Secretary to notify the appropriate congressional committees before carrying out a project. Requires independent program review. Provides a per-project limit of $75 million. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1999 through 2004. (Sec. 5) Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 to provide the non-Federal share of the costs of periodic beach nourishment or shore protection projects. (Sec. 6) Amends the Flood Control Act of 1948 to increase to $7 million the maximum amount for small flood control projects. (Sec. 7) Amends the Flood Control Act of 1960 to state that a limitation on funding for the compilation and dissemination of information on floods and flood damage shall not apply to funds voluntarily contributed in order to expand the scope of such services. (Sec. 8) Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1996 to: (1) extend through FY 2000 the Everglades and South Florida ecosystem restoration program; and (2) allow non-profit entities to enter into agreements to pay non-Federal shares of aquatic ecosystem restoration projects. (Sec. 10) Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1992 to allow non-profit entities to enter into agreements to pay non-Federal shares of the costs of projects for beneficial uses of dredged material. (Sec. 11) Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with non-Federal and non-profit entities to facilitate collaborative efforts for environmental protection and restoration, natural resources, conservation, and recreation in connection with the development, operation, and management of water resources projects. (Sec. 12) Amends the Flood Control Act of 1936 to allow contributions by States and political subdivisions to be used for environmental restoration activities. (Sec. 13) Authorizes the Secretary during FY 1999 through 2002 to withhold a specified amount of recreation user fees for backlogged repair and maintenance projects, interpretation, signage, habitat or facility enhancement, resource preservation, annual operation, maintenance, and law enforcement related to public use at recreation sites. (Sec. 14) Directs the Secretary, within a year after enactment of this Act and every five years thereafter, to review the Shoreline Management Program administered by the Army Corps of Engineers (Corps) at Army projects to determine Program costs. (Sec. 15) Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1996 to permit studies undertaken by the Secretary concerning the Pacific region to include flood damage reduction and environmental restoration. (Sec. 16) Establishes the Water Resources Foundation, a nonprofit District of Columbia corporation, to: (1) encourage, accept, and administer gifts of money and property for Corps activities and services in managing natural resources at Army water resources development projects; and (2) undertake and conduct other activities to further the conservation and management of natural, scenic, historic, and recreational resources at such projects. Provides, with respect to the Foundation, for: (1) conflict of interest prohibitions; (2) tax-exempt status; (3) a Board of Directors; (4) corporate powers and obligations; and (5) an authorization of appropriations for FY 1999 through 2001. (Sec. 17) Directs the Secretary to establish and collect fees from applicants for the evaluation of commercial permit applications, the preparation of environmental impact statements in connection with such applications, and the delineation of wetlands for major developments affecting wetlands. Establishes in the Treasury the Army Civil Works Regulatory Program Account for the deposit and expenditure of such fees. (Sec. 18) Authorizes the Secretary to acquire from willing sellers land and property in the vicinity of Pierre, South Dakota, or to floodproof or relocate other property, in order to provide full operational capability for the Missouri River Main Stem dams that are part of the Pick-Sloan Missouri River Basin Program. Requires non- Federal interests to pay 35 percent of such costs. (Sec. 19) Directs the Secretary to finalize a report, together with recommendations, identifying a general implementation strategy and overall plan for environmental restoration and protection along the Lower Missouri River between Gavins Point Dam and the confluence of the Missouri and Mississippi Rivers. (Sec. 20) Authorizes the Secretary to permit the non-Federal sponsor for the project for flood control, Moorefield, West Virginia, to pay without interest the remaining non-Federal project cost over a period to be determined by the Secretary, but not to exceed 30 years.</summary>
</bill>
