<bill session="106" type="h" number="5650" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To declare certain Federal lands in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico as excess, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400615"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military base conversion"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Naval bases"/>
    <term name="Ordnance"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2000--Introduced.
Amends the Floyd D. Spence National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2001 to revise requirements relating to Navy activities on the Island of Vieques, Puerto Rico, to direct the Secretary of the Navy to: (1) report to the General Services Administration (GSA) as excess lands for disposal all lands on the eastern side of the Island, with the exception of all Department of Defense real properties identified as conservation zones, the Live Impact Area, and any other real properties that the Secretary of the Interior identifies as necessary for the management of these areas; and (2) transfer such zones, Area, and any such other properties to such Secretary.Requires DOD to conduct all environmental response actions on such transferred lands, properties, and excess lands.States that neither the Department of the Interior nor GSA shall be liable for environmental contamination, including unexploded ordnance, that is present at the time such properties are transferred or reported as excess, including contamination resulting from DOD activities that is discovered after transfer or subsequent conveyance.Makes the Secretary of Defense exclusively responsible for funding and implementing any necessary response actions (including operation and maintenance) to address environmental contamination resulting from DOD's presence or which is present at the time of any such conveyance, including contamination subsequently discovered, unless such contamination was caused by the Interior Department.</summary>
</bill>
