<bill session="108" type="h" number="5083" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wild Sky Wilderness and Backcountry Wilderness Management Area Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate certain lower-elevation Federal lands in the Skykomish River valley of the State of Washington as wilderness, to designate a portion of such lands for management as a backcountry wilderness management area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="2004-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2004-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2004--Introduced.
Wild Sky Wilderness and Backcountry Wilderness Management Area Act of 2004 - Designates specified Federal lands in the State of Washington (the State) as: (1) the Wild Sky Wilderness (the Wilderness); and (2) the Skykomish Backcountry Wilderness Management Area (the Area). Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to manage the Wilderness in accordance with the Wilderness Act and this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to use helicopter access to construct and maintain a joint U.S. Forest Service and Snohomish County repeater site, in compliance with a Forest Service-approved communications site plan, to improve communication for safety, health, and emergency services. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop a management plan for the Area (but prohibits the Secretary from permitting commercial timber harvest in the Area); (2) establish a trail plain for specified National Forest System lands to develop a system of hiking and equestrian trails in the Wilderness and the Area, and trails adjacent to the Wilderness or the Area; and (3) carry out a land exchange with the Chelan County Public Utility District in the State, subject to specified requirements.</summary>
</bill>
