<bill session="108" type="h" number="4734" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to include a definition of initial reservation and consultation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400203"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1281"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2004--Introduced.
Amends the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to define initial reservation (geographical area) and consultation (with State, local, and tribal governments within 50 miles of land proposed to be taken into trust for a gaming facility). Revises consultation requirements for an exception to gaming restrictions on certain land. Specifies that the State or local governments or nearby Indians tribes with which the Secretary of the Interior is required to consult on a proposed gaming establishment must have jurisdiction over land located within 50 miles of the land proposed to be taken into trust for the establishment. Declares as a favorable determination alternative to the currently required best interest of the Indian tribe and its members, with no detriment to the surrounding community, that the gaming establishment would not have a negative economic impact on businesses, governments, or Indian tribes within a 50 mile radius of the land proposed to be taken into trust.</summary>
</bill>
