<bill session="104" type="hr" number="284" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-30T11:02:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-11-30T11:02:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1788) to reform the statutes relating to Amtrak, to authorize appropriations for Amtrak, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408976"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29T16:35:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-370, by Mr. Quillen.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29T16:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1788 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. All points of order against consideration of the bill shall be waived. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in part 1 of the report accompanying this resolution. All points of order against the modified amendment shall be waived. Before the consideration of any other amendment, it shall be in order to consider the amendment printed in part 2 of the report accompanying this resolution, which shall be debatable for 10 minutes and may amend portions of the bill not yet...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-11-29T16:36:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="140">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 140.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-11-30T10:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13813-13916" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-30T10:48:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-30T11:02:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-11-30T11:02:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-11-30T11:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="1788"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/29/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the open rule for the consideration of H.R. 1788 (Amtrak revisions and authorization).</summary>
</bill>
