<bill session="106" type="h" number="3558" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Pipelines Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to improve pipeline safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2000-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="2000-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2000-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2000-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2000-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-01-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H69-70"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, Hazardous Materials and Pipeline Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H612-613"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4172"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW08" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, Hazardous Materials and Pipeline Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2004"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2004"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution control"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pipeline safety"/>
    <term name="Pipeline siting"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2000--Introduced.
Safe Pipelines Act of 2000 - Amends Federal pipeline safety law (the Act) to revise Federal minimum safety standards for gas and hazardous liquid pipeline facilities to require pipeline operators to be: (1) tested for qualification to perform enumerated activities related to the installation, testing, and maintenance of a pipeline; and (2) certified as qualified by the Secretary of Transportation to perform such activities.(Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to require an operator of a pipeline facility that: (1) has an instrumented internal inspection device (smart pig) to test the pipeline once every five years for corrosion and anomalies and make test results available to the public; and (2) is not covered by a certain certification under a State pipeline safety program or by a State pipeline safety agreement to test the pipeline hydrostatically once every five years to redetermine its maximum allowable operating pressure of the pipeline and make test results available to the public. Authorizes the Secretary, upon the request of an operator of a non-high-risk pipeline, to approve an alternative method of testing the pipeline, including inspection by smart pig, for structural weaknesses instead of hydrostatic testing if the Secretary first provides notification in the Federal Register and to interested State and local governments and other persons of the proposed approval and provides for public comment. Directs the Secretary to establish a list of high-risk pipelines (that have had a specified number of leaks over a certain period of time).(Sec. 4) Requires pipeline operators to report to the Secretary hazardous liquid spills of more than 40 gallons and ruptures to pipelines.(Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to make available on the Internet maps of the location of all pipeline facilities subject to the Act.(Sec. 7) Directs the Governor of each State desiring to administer its own pipeline safety standards for interstate pipelines to submit to the Secretary a complete description of its proposed program. Prohibits a State program from containing standards that are less stringent than those established by Federal law.(Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary to study and report to Congress on the effectiveness of: (1) external leak detection systems (including hydrocarbon sensor cables) for the purpose of improving pipeline leak detection; and (2) double-walled pipelines for the purpose of preventing ruptures and leaks.(Sec. 9) Directs the Secretary to complete cost-benefit analyses of all recommendations made by the National Transportation Safety Board to the Secretary that the Board classifies as being "open".(Sec. 10) Directs the Secretary to study and report to Congress on the optimal minimum burial depth of underground pipelines for the purpose of preventing the release of hazardous materials in the air.</summary>
</bill>
