<bill session="104" type="h" number="3476" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">College Campus Alcohol Abuse Prevention and Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide incentives to colleges and universities to develop, implement, and improve alcohol abuse prevention and education programs on their campuses, to strengthen sanctions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1996-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1996-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1996-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Alcohol"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverage industry"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="College and school journalism"/>
    <term name="College sports"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Newspapers"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="School discipline"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="School violence"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Student activities"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Students' rights"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/1996--Introduced.
College Campus Alcohol Abuse Prevention and Education Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to revise drug and alcohol abuse prevention program certification requirements (which must be met in order for a higher education institution (institution) to receive any Federal financial assistance) to require such programs to limit alcoholic beverage advertisements in the institution's newspapers and other publications to price and product identification. Prohibits: (1) distribution of any promotional material that encourages the consumption of alcoholic beverages on campus; (2) distribution of free alcoholic beverages for promotional purposes on campus; and (3) sponsorship or public support of any on-campus athletic, musical, cultural, or social program, event, or competition by any alcoholic beverage company or by any group of such companies. Requires that identification, referral, or treatment of students and employees under such programs not jeopardize their matriculation status or employment. Requires specified items under such programs to be developed and adopted with student and employee participation. Directs the Secretary of Education to waive certain sanctions relating to such programs for up to one year in the case of any institution in the process of developing and implementing a required plan. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to institutions or consortia of them, and contracts with such institutions and other organizations, for programs of prevention, and education (including treatment-referral) to reduce and eliminate the illegal use of drugs and alcohol and associated violence. Allows such contracts also to be used for a higher education center for alcohol and drug abuse prevention which will provide training, technical assistance, evaluation, dissemination, and associated services and assistance to the higher education community and institutions of higher education. Make a conforming repeal to the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Directs the Secretary to make ten National Recognition Awards annually to institutions that have developed and implemented effective alcohol and drug abuse prevention and education programs. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
