<bill session="106" type="h" number="2880" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Conservation Tax Incentives Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax incentives for land sales for conservation purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="2000-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1999-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1999-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2000-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="1999-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2000-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection groups"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/1999--Introduced.
Conservation Tax Incentives Act of 1999 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income 50 percent of any gain from the sale of land or an interest in land or water (determined without regard to any improvements) to an eligible entity if: (1) such land or interest in land or water was owned by the taxpayer or a member of the taxpayer's family at all times during the three-year period ending on the date of the sale; and (2) it is being acquired by an eligible entity which provides the taxpayer, at the time of acquisition, a written letter of intent which states that the purchaser's intent is that the acquisition will serve one or more of specified conservation purposes.Includes as "land or an interest in land or water" stock in any corporation, if the fair market value of the corporation's land or interests in land or water equals or exceeds 90 percent of the fair market value of all of its assets at all times during the three-year period ending on the date of the sale.Deems a purchaser an eligible entity if it is: (1) any Federal, State, or local governmental agency; or (2) any tax-exempt charitable organization that is organized and at all times operated principally for one or more specified conservation purposes, and meets certain other requirements.</summary>
</bill>
