<bill session="105" type="h" number="1194" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Facilities Clean Water Compliance Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act relating to Federal facilities pollution control.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1997-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1997-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="1997-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1997-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1997-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative responsibility"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Liability for water pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/1997--Introduced.
Federal Facilities Clean Water Compliance Act of 1997 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require each Federal department, agency, and instrumentality to be subject to and comply with all Federal, State, and local requirements with respect to the control and abatement of water pollution and management in the same manner and extent as any person is subject to such requirements, including the payment of reasonable service charges. Waives immunity of the United States with respect to any such requirements. Absolves Federal employees of personal liability for civil penalties under water pollution control laws for acts or omissions within the scope of official duties. Makes Federal employees subject to criminal sanctions under Federal or State water pollution laws, but prohibits applying criminal sanctions to Federal agencies. Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of the Army, and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to pursue enforcement actions under this Act. Allows States to use funds collected from the Federal Government under this Act only for projects designed to improve or protect the environment or to defray the costs of environmental protection or enforcement. Includes Federal agencies within the definition of "person" for purposes of such Act.</summary>
</bill>
