<bill session="105" type="h" number="342" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:31-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the comparable treatment of Federal employees and Members of Congress and the President during a period in which there is a Federal Government shutdown.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1997-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1997-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400329" joined="1997-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on House Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Civil Service"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Debt limit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Presidential compensation"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>01/07/1997--Introduced.
Requires that the basic pay of Members of Congress be treated in the same manner as the basic pay of the most adversely affected Federal employees who are not compensated for any period in which: (1) there is more than a 24-hour lapse in appropriations for any Federal agency or department as a result of a failure to enact a regular appropriations bill or continuing resolution; or (2) the Federal Government is unable to make payments or meet obligations because the public debt limit has been reached. Requires the same treatment for the President's basic pay. Directs the Secretary of the Senate and the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives to promulgate any regulations needed to implement this Act in a manner consistent with the U.S. Constitution.</summary>
</bill>
