<bill session="105" type="h" number="4431" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HIV Partner Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XXVI of the Public Health Service Act to provide for State programs of partner notification with respect to individuals with HIV disease.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1998-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="HIV-positive persons"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Intravenous drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/1998--Introduced.
HIV Partner Protection Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit a grant to a State under provisions relating to human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) care grants unless the State: (1) carries out a program of notification of sex or needle sharing partners of individuals with HIV disease that the partners may have been exposed; (2) requires HIV testing entities to confidentially report positive test results, including the individual's name, to the State; (3) does not inform partners of the infected individual's identity; (4) meets certain counseling, testing, and referral requirements; (5) there is no criminal or civil penalty or civil liability for an infected individual if the individual chooses not to identify their partners or for an individual who makes a good faith error in submitting reports or making disclosures; and (6) the failure of the State to notify partners is not a basis for civil liability of any health entity who reported to the State the identity of the infected individual. Prohibits such a grant unless a State prohibits insurers from taking any action against an individual solely on the basis that the individual has been tested for HIV disease. Authorizes grants to States to assist with the costs of carrying out the program. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
