<bill session="106" type="h" number="5514" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Seafood Safety and Mercury Screening Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a tolerance for the presence of methyl mercury in seafood, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/2000--Introduced.
Seafood Safety and Mercury Screening Act of 2000 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a tolerance for methyl mercury in seafood, which shall be based on a scientific analysis of the health risks attributable to such substance. Deems unsafe any seafood containing methyl mercury over the tolerance limits.Requires the Secretary to: (1) ensure that such tolerance is safe and to modify or revoke any tolerance found to be unsafe; and (2) ensure that there is a reasonable certainty that no harm will result to pregnant women, infants, and children from aggregate exposure to methyl mercury.Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a system for the ongoing collection and analysis of seafood samples to determine the extent of tolerance compliance; (2) design and implement a national public education program regarding the presence of methyl mercury in seafood; (3) work with States and other appropriate entities to develop national and regional methyl mercury advisories; (4) consider, when determining such tolerance, certain findings of the National Academy of Sciences regarding the Environmental Protection Agency's recommended level for methyl mercury; and (5) report to Congress on progress made in establishing the tolerance.</summary>
</bill>
