<bill session="108" type="h" number="3785" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-12-23">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-12-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the exchange of certain land in Everglades National Park.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400108"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400167" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400212" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2004-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-06-01T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-516.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-06-01T16:13:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="296">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 296.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hayworth moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5935-5936" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3785.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-07-19T15:00:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5935" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-07-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="653">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 653.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2004-12-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12020" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2004-12-08">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2004-12-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-12-16">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-12-23">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2004-12-23" type="public" number="108-483">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-483.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="2046"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="2046"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="2046"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Everglades"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Freshwater resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/23/2004--Public Law.
Amends the Everglades National Park Protection and Expansion Act of 1989 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to acquire from one or more willing sellers not more than ten acres of land located outside the boundary of Everglades National Park and adjacent to or near the East Everglades area of the Park for the development of administrative, housing, maintenance, or other Park purposes. Requires such land, on acquisition, to be administered as part of the Park in accordance with the laws (including regulations) applicable to the Park. Directs the Administrator of General Services to convey to Miami-Dade County, Florida, fee title to approximately 595.28 acres of land designated as Site Alpha that is declared by the Department of the Navy to be excess land in exchange for conveyance by the County to the Secretary of fee title to two parcels of land owned by the County totaling approximately 152.93 acres that are designated as Tract 605-01 and Tract 605-03. Directs the Secretary, after the completion of such exchange, to convey to the South Florida Water Management District fee title to approximately 1,054 acres of land located in the Rocky Glades area of the Park in exchange for fee title to approximately 1,054 acres of District land located in the Southern Glades Wildlife and Environmental Area. Requires that the land conveyed to the District be used by the District for the purposes of the C-111 project, including restoration of the Everglades natural system. (The C-111 Spreader Canal project modifies the existing water management system to restore historic freshwater flows to areas of the Everglades National Park and to maintain existing flood protection for surrounding areas.) Amends Federal law relating to the Big Cypress National Preserve and the Big Cypress National Preserve Addition to: (1) provide for the reduction in the amount of payment or reimbursement by the Secretary of total costs to the State of Florida of acquiring lands within Big Cypress National Preserve Addition by an amount equal to 20 percent of the amount of the total cost incurred by the Secretary in acquiring lands in the Addition other than from the State; and (2) remove the requirement for reducing the aggregate cost to the United States of acquiring lands within the Addition by an amount equal to 20 percent of the amount of the total cost incurred by the Secretary in acquiring lands in the Addition other than from the State.</summary>
</bill>
