<bill session="105" type="hr" number="457" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-09T18:09:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-06-09T18:09:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill (H.R. 2709) to impose certain sanctions on foreign persons who transfer items contributing to Iran's efforts to acquire, develop, or produce ballistic missiles.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-06-04T23:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-566, by Mr. Goss.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-06-04T23:22:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="202">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 202.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-06-04T23:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of Senate amendments to H.R. 2709 with 1 hour of general debate. Provides for a single motion offered by the Chairman of the Commitee on International Relations or his designee to concur in each of the Senate amendments. Provides that the Senate amendments and the motion shall be considered as read. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to final adoption without intervening motion or demand for division of the question.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-09T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4283-4285" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-09T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-09T18:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-06-09T18:09:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-06-09T18:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="2709"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/1998--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of the Senate amendment to H.R. 2709 (sanctions on foreign persons who contribute to Iran's efforts to acquire, develop, or produce ballistic missiles).</summary>
</bill>
