<bill session="104" type="h" number="2470" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-10-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Second Amendment Reaffirmation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restore the Second Amendment rights of all Americans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410396"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1996-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1995-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1996-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="1996-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="1996-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403864" joined="1995-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404367" joined="1995-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="405258" joined="1996-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1995-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="1996-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1995-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1996-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1995-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Government Reform and Oversight, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-11">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-11">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Assault weapons"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/1995--Introduced.
Second Amendment Reaffirmation Act of 1995 - Repeals: (1) the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act; and (2) the Assault Weapon Manufacturing Strict Liability Act of 1990 (D.C. Act 8-289). Amends the Firearms Owners' Protection Act (the Act) to: (1) provide that, where discontinuance of a firearms or ammunition business is to be absolute, the records required to be kept shall be delivered within 30 days after such discontinuance to another Federal firearms licensee; and (2) make provisions regarding the award of attorney's fees to the prevailing party, including when the court finds that the action was without foundation or initiated in bad faith, applicable to certain actions and proceedings under Internal Revenue Code (IRC) provisions concerning excise taxes for machine guns, destructive devices, and certain other firearms, including a proceeding before an administrative law judge. Authorizes: (1) any person aggrieved by the violation of a civil or constitutional right in connection with the lawful possession or use of a firearm by the U.S. Government, any official or employee thereof, or the government of any State or subdivision or official or employee thereof to bring an action for actual and punitive damages in the Federal district court in which such person resides or transacts business; and (2) the court to award a prevailing plaintiff, other than the Government, reasonable attorneys' fees and costs. Bars: (1) the application of any legal provision or any State or local statute enacted to regulate the level of any pollutant from being applied to the sale, transportation, possession, importation, or use of any firearm or ammunition; and (2) any officer or employee of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms (BATF) from undertaking any investigation of a single individual, organization, or business which will reasonably require expenditures in excess of $4,000, or any investigation in consultation or cooperation with the Internal Revenue Service, without prior written approval by the Deputy Secretary of the Treasury. Sets penalties for violations. Prohibits any U.S. officer, agent, or employee from listing, recording, copying, or computerizing the names of firearm owners (other than those required to be maintained under the IRC), transferring information concerning the identities of firearms owners to a facility owned, managed, or controlled by the United States or any State or political subdivision thereof, or participating in the establishment of any system of registration of firearms, firearms owners, or firearms transactions or dispositions. Requires that any such list, record, copy, computerization, facility, or system that would have violated this Act had it been created or expanded following the effective date of this Act be destroyed. Creates a cause of action for persons aggrieved by the violation of any civil or constitutional right in connection with a violation of the Act by the Government for actual and punitive damages, including the award of reasonable attorney's fees and costs to a prevailing plaintiff other than the Federal, a State, or local government.</summary>
</bill>
