<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="961" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:52-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2202" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="1996-03-19T20:54:00-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <offered datetime="1996-03-19"/>
  <description>Amendment makes certain technical and conforming changes; clarifies that any new forward deployment of border patrol officers will not affect current border checkpoints; sets up a pilot program for using closed military bases as possible holding areas for illegal aliens; provides that city and county governments can qualify for reimbursement from the Federal Government for incarceration of illegal aliens; and increases the number of Federal prosecutors dealing with immigration-related crimes such as the smuggling of illegal aliens or previously deported aliens into the United States.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment, printed as amendment No. 1 in House Rept. 104-483, to make several technical and conforming changes to the bill, requiring border identification cards with biometric identifiers to be issued to aliens who frequently enter the U.S.; directing the INS to consult with authorities regarding the possibility of using closed military bases for housing illegal immigrants awaiting deportation; authorizing local police to arrest, detain, or deport any illegal immigrant in their locality in order to assist the Attorney General; provide that new attorneys hired by the AG be assigned to prosecute immigration related crimes; changes the date for hiring new federal prosecutors from fy 1995 to fy 1996;allows for the immediate release and deportation for nonviolent illegal immigrants; restricts aliens from being deported to a country where they would face possible persecution; allowing family sponsors of alien parents to obtain a performance bond in lieu of health insurance; deleting provisions in the bill to allot 50,000 visas for the spouses of children of lawful permanent resident aliens; clarifying that all aliens may have access to public health immunizations, including treatment for symptoms of communicable diseases, regardless of their cause; deleting the Earned Income Tax Credit provisions which would prohibit individuals without tax i.entification numbers from participating in the program; allowing family-sponsored aliens to receive certain forms of public assistance without violating terms of sponsorship.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-03-19T20:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Smith (TX).</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1996-03-19T20:54:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Smith (TX) amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
