<bill session="106" type="h" number="4755" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Preservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a permanent fund to ensure the continued maintenance and rehabilitation of the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400318"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2000-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Ground Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW10" subcommittee="Ground Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Car pools"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2000--Introduced.
Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Preservation Act - Requires the Secretary of Transportation to be solely responsible for the maintenance, rehabilitation, and expansion of the existing Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge over the Potomac River between Virginia and Maryland until all conditions under this Act have been met for the construction of a replacement for the bridge. Provides that terms of the agreement of April 19, 1985, between the Secretary, Virginia, Maryland, and the District of Columbia, related to the assignment of responsibility for the operation and maintenance of the bridge, shall remain in effect.Designates certain contract and associated obligational authorities for the bridge as the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Preservation Fund which shall be maintained within the Department of Transportation. Requires that such Fund be available to the Secretary for the maintenance, rehabilitation, and expansion of the bridge for keeping it in a condition sufficient to facilitate interstate traffic in an efficient and safe manner. Provides for amounts in the Fund only to be available for those portions of the bridge that are owned by the Federal Government. Sets forth a rule for the replenishment of the Fund.Requires the Secretary to prepare and transmit to Congress an annual report on the bridge's condition.Directs the Secretary, Virginia, Maryland, and the District of Columbia to develop a transportation plan for the Capital Beltway corridor (Interstate Route 495) served by the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge project. Requires that the plan establish what level of high occupancy vehicle lanes and transit service should be provided in the corridor and how such service should be accommodated on a replacement bridge. Permits the cost of developing the plan to be paid from the Fund.Requires the balance in the Fund to be available for the construction of a replacement bridge upon certification to Congress by the Secretary that all of the following conditions have been met: (1) the transportation plan has been completed and approved by the Secretary, the Governors of Virginia and Maryland, and the mayor of the District of Columbia; (2) title to the existing bridge has been transferred from the Federal Government to Virginia, Maryland, or both; and (3) Virginia and Maryland have developed a finance plan to pay for all costs of the replacement bridge project in excess of the current Federal payment and have signed an agreement with the Secretary to pay for all cost overruns to the plan (requires the plan to give priority to the use of such Federal payment for the bridge component). Allows the Secretary, in developing a replacement bridge and its approaches, upon petition by the States of Virginia and Maryland, to waive any Federal highways requirement (with exceptions) that the States have determined to cause unreasonable increases in the cost of the project.Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the $900 million Federal payment to replace the bridge is the final Federal contribution for that project; (2) any of the Federal payment remaining after completion of the replacement bridge shall be available to pay for costs associated with construction of approaches to it; and (3) all project costs not associated with the bridge component are the responsibility of the Commonwealth of Virginia and the State of Maryland.</summary>
</bill>
