<bill session="105" type="h" number="4725" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Autism Statistics, Surveillance, Research, and Epidemology Act of 1998 (ASSURE)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide surveillance and research to better understand the prevalence and pattern of autism and other pervasive developmental disabilities so that effective treatment and prevention strategies can be implemented.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1942-1943"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Autism"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/1998--Introduced.
Autism Statistics, Surveillance, Research, and Epidemiology Act of 1998 (ASSURE) - Authorizes grants and contracts for the collection, analysis, and reporting of data on autism and pervasive developmental disabilities. Mandates establishment of three to five regional centers of excellence in autism and pervasive developmental disabilities epidemiology to collect and analyze information, to be established and operated through grants or cooperative agreements. Requires that the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention serve as the coordinating agency for autism and pervasive developmental disabilities surveillance through the establishment of a clearinghouse for data generated from the monitoring programs created by this Act. Mandates establishment of an Advisory Committee for Autism and Pervasive Developmental Disabilities Epidemiology Research. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
