<bill session="106" type="h" number="4860" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">North Korea Nonproliferation Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for reports to Congress about proliferation by North Korea of weapons of mass destruction and missiles to deliver such weapons, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400225" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2000-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1267-1268"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms control negotiations"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Artificial satellites"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cruise missiles"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Launch vehicles"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear exports"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2000--Introduced.
North Korea Nonproliferation Act of 2000 - Directs the President to report on: (1) compliance by North Korea with its September 12, 1999, commitment to suspend launches of long-range missiles as well as with any international agreement limiting testing, deployment, or transfer to other countries of missiles or missile technology; and (2) transfer of specified nuclear goods, services, or technology to outside destinations.Authorizes the President to reinstate any or all of specified restrictions on commerce with North Korea any time a proliferation report indicates credible information that North Korea transferred nuclear goods, services, or technology to an outside destination. Requires a detailed justification to Congress in any such instance where the President decides not to reinstate restrictions.Requires a minimum two-year reinstatement (unless waived for national security reasons) of such restrictions if there is credible information that North Korea took an action inconsistent with: (1) compliance with the September 12, 1999, commitment to suspend launches of long-range missiles, or with any international agreement limiting testing, deployment, or transfer to other countries of missiles or missile technology; or (2) transferred any of specified nuclear goods, services, or technology to any country whose government has repeatedly supported acts of international terrorism, or has tested any long-range missile incorporating goods or technology knowingly transferred to such government by North Korea.Declares that reinstatement requirements shall not apply if the President reports to the relevant congressional committees that there is substantial doubt that North Korea knowingly took such an action.Encourages the President to seek to negotiate a binding international agreement with North Korea that satisfies U.S. concerns regarding the transfer by North Korea to other countries of missiles and missile technology. Authorizes the President, if North Korea enters into such an agreement, to: (1) waive specified sanctions under the Arms Export Control Act and the Export Administration Act of 1979; and (2) use certain funds to support the commercial launch in the United States or other countries of satellites for North Korea (other than a launch by North Korea or by certain other entities).</summary>
</bill>
