<bill session="107" type="h" number="4913" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Nuclear Security Initiative Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage and facilitate the security of nuclear materials and facilities worldwide.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400396"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-06-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1006"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="2470"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fissionable materials"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Plutonium"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sabotage"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2002--Introduced.
Global Nuclear Security Initiative Act of 2002 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Energy should develop a comprehensive program of activities to encourage all countries with nuclear materials to adhere to, or adopt standards equivalent to, the International Atomic Energy Agency standard on the Physical Protection of Nuclear Material and Nuclear Facilities relating to the security of stockpiles of highly enriched uranium and plutonium. Directs the Secretary to require the Office of International Materials Protection, Control, and Accounting of the Department of Energy to conduct a study of the feasibility and advisability of developing a program to secure radiological materials outside the United States that pose a threat to U.S. national security. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on: (1) such study's results; and (2) results of a study by the Secretary of the feasibility and advisability of various actions to reduce the risks associated with terrorist attacks on nuclear power plants outside the United States.Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should encourage amendment of the Convention on the Physical Protection of Nuclear Materials to make it: (1) apply to both domestic and international use and transport of nuclear materials; (2) incorporate fundamental practices for the physical protection of such materials; and (3) address protection against sabotage involving nuclear materials.</summary>
</bill>
