<bill session="107" type="h" number="3743" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">No More Terror in New York Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for restrictions on travel by diplomatic representatives of the Palestine Liberation Organization while in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="2002-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Offices"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations delegations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2002--Introduced.
No More Terror in New York Act of 2002 - Urges the: (1) Secretary of State to designate the Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO), appropriate PLO constituent groups, and appropriate arms of the Palestinian Authority as a foreign terrorist organization; (2) President to direct the U.S. Representative to the United Nations (UN) to ensure termination of the PLO's permanent observer status; and (3) United Nations General Assembly to revoke such status and any status under which the PLO is able to maintain an office in New York City.Restricts the travel of any alien admitted to the United States with diplomatic status as a representative of the PLO to within a 25-mile radius of the UN Headquarters Building. Requires prior approval of a written request for any other travel in the United States.Requires biannual reports from the Secretary of State to specified congressional committees on the PLO's involvement with acts of terror and terrorist groups, as well as on PLO representatives' travel outside the restricted areas.</summary>
</bill>
