<bill session="105" type="h" number="1803" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Career Preparation Education Reform Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assist States and secondary and postsecondary schools to develop, implement, and improve career preparation education so that every student has an opportunity to acquire academic and technical knowledge and skills needed for postsecondary education, further learning, and a wide range of opportunities in high-skill, high-wage careers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1997-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="993"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Career education"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational surveys"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="School-to-work transition"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in education"/>
    <term name="Sexual harassment of women"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Amendments to the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Applied Technology Education Act Title II: Effective Dates; Transition Title III: Amendments to Other Acts Career Preparation Education Reform Act of 1997 - Title I: Amendments to the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Applied Technology Education Act - Amends the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Applied Technology Education Act to: (1) rename it the Carl D. Perkins Career Preparation Education Act (the Act); (2) revise it; and (3) extend the authorization of appropriations through FY 2002. (Sec. 101) Provides that, under the Act, career preparation education programs, services, and activities are those that: (1) support the development, implementation, or improvement of State School-to-Work systems, as set forth in title I of the School-to-Work Opportunities Act of 1994; or (2) otherwise prepare students for employment and further learning in technical fields. Replaces the current title I, Vocational Education Assistance to the States, with a new title I, Preparing Students for Careers. Sets forth a new title I, part A, Career Preparation Education. Directs the Secretary of Education to make grants to States (which will make subgrants to localities) for career preparation, programs, services, and activities. Sets forth requirements for such career preparation education programs and priorities, State leadership activities, State plans, local activities, local applications, performance goals and indicators, evaluation, improvement, and accountability, allotments, and within-State allocation and distribution of funds. Revises, under a new title I part B, program elements for Tech-Prep Education (currently under title III part E). Revises requirements for State grants for tech-prep education programs, eliminating discretionary Federal grants for such programs. Sets forth requirements for State leadership activities and plans, local activities and consortia applications, program evaluation, and allotment and distribution of funds. Replaces the current title II, Basic Grants for Vocational Education, with a new title II, National Support for State and Local Reforms (which revises some of the current title IV, National Programs). Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) make awards for excellence to States; (2) carry on certain national research, development, dissemination, evaluation, capacity-building, and technical assistance activities; (3) support professional development activities for educators; and (4) establish one of more national centers in the areas of applied research and development and of dissemination and training. Directs the Secretary to carry out certain activities related to: (1) national assessment; and (2) data systems. Continues the National Occupational Information Coordinating Committee. Provides for reservation of funds for career preparation education for Indians and Native Hawaiians. Replaces the current title III, Special Programs, with a title III, General Provisions (currently title V). (Eliminates all such special programs, except Tech-Prep Education which is transferred to title I, part B.) Title II: Effective Dates; Transition - Sets forth effective date and transition provisions. Title III: Amendments to Other Acts - Amends the following Acts with respect to references to the Act and to the School-to-Work Opportunities Act of 1994: the Job Training Partnership Act, the School-to-Work Opportunities Act of 1994, the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, the Goals 2000: Educate America Act, the Higher Education Act of 1965, the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, the Displaced Homemakers Self-Sufficiency Assistance Act, the Wagner-Peyser Act, the Equity in Educational Land-Grant States Act of 1994, the Nontraditional Employment for Women Act, and the Training Technology Transfer Act of 1988.</summary>
</bill>
