<bill session="105" type="h" number="1189" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Health Improvement Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Social Security Act and the Public Health Service Act with respect to the health of residents of rural areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400568" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1997-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400037" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="1997-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400079" joined="1997-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1997-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1997-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400517" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="1997-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400190" joined="1997-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400202" joined="1997-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="1997-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1997-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="1997-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1997-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="410084" joined="1997-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400410" joined="1997-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1997-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="1997-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Community hospitals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospital personnel"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Long-term care facilities"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Midwives"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Rural hospitals"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Equalization of Medicare Reimbursement Rates to Health Maintenance Organizations and Competitive Medical Plans Title II: Expansion of Grant Authority to Include Technical Assistance for Rural Health Networks Title III: Medicare Rural Primary Care Hospital Program Title IV: Incentives for Health Professionals to Practice in Rural Areas Subtitle A: National Health Service Corps Subtitle B: Primary Care Services Furnished in Shortage Areas Title V: Classification as Rural Referral Centers; Geographic Reclassification for Disproportionate Share Payment Adjustment Title VI: Medicare Payment Methodologies Title VII: Antitrust Title VIII: Financing Rural Health Improvement Act of 1997 - Expresses the sense of the Congress that this Act reflects the dedication of the late U.S. Representative Bill Emerson to ensuring health care access for all rural Americans. Title I: Equalization of Medicare Reimbursement Rates to Health Maintenance Organizations and Competitive Medical Plans - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to revise provisions for payments to health maintenance organizations (HMOs) and competitive medical plans (CMPs) for the stated purpose of equalizing Medicare reimbursement rates to HMOs and CMPs. (Sec. 102) Expresses the sense of the Congress that HMOs or CMPs in rural areas receiving additional payments as a result of this title should allocate those payments to provide increased health care services to Medicare beneficiaries or to pay for health care service infrastructure needs. Title II: Expansion of Grant Authority to Include Technical Assistance for Rural Health Networks - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to provide technical assistance, directly or through grants or contracts, for the planning, development, and operation of any program or service carried out pursuant to a rural health network under that Act. Title III: Medicare Rural Primary Care Hospital Program - Replaces the Essential Access Community Hospital Program (EACH) under Medicare with the Medicare Rural Primary Care Hospital Program while continuing payment to designated EACHs, rural primary care hospitals, and certain other medical assistance facilities operated as limited service rural hospitals under a specified demonstration program. Permits agreements between rural primary care hospitals and the Secretary for the use of up to 25 beds for extended care services. Bases payment for inpatient and outpatient rural primary care hospital services on the reasonable costs of the hospital in providing such services. Lengthens from 72 to 96 hours the maximum period of permitted inpatient stay at a rural primary care hospital. Title IV: Incentives for Health Professionals to Practice in Rural Areas - Subtitle A: National Health Service Corps - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude qualified National Health Service Corps scholarship payments and loan repayments from gross income. (Sec. 402) Requires the HHS Secretary to report to the Congress on the study being conducted on the criteria for designation of health professional shortage areas and medically underserved areas under the Public Health Service Act. (Sec. 403) Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary to give special priority to applications by community rural health networks for the assignment of Corps personnel for providing health services in or to a health professional shortage area. Subtitle B: Primary Care Services Furnished in Shortage Areas - Amends SSA title XVIII to provide for an increase in the amount of additional Medicare payments for primary care services (currently, physicians' services) furnished in rural shortage areas, and for services that are furnished by a physician assistant, nurse practitioner, or nurse midwife that would be physicians' services if furnished by a physician. Extends such payment for former shortage areas. Requires carriers to report on services provided. Title V: Classification of Rural Referral Centers; Geographic Reclassification for Disproportionate Share Payment Adjustment - Amends SSA title XVIII to prohibit denial of a rural referral center's request for reclassification on the basis of comparability of wages. Provides for the continuing treatment of previously designated rural referral centers. (Sec. 502) Permits Medicare hospital geographic reclassification for purposes of disproportionate share payment adjustments. Title VI: Medicare Payment Methodologies - Directs the HHS Secretary to implement a methodology based on a specified proposal for making payments under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) for telemedicine services. Title VII: Antitrust - Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) physician and hospital networks in rural areas are working to develop alternative means of providing accessible, affordable, and quality health care services to Americans living and working in rural areas; and (2) the Federal Trade Commission, in conjunction with the Justice Department, should, when implementing antitrust guidelines with respect to physician and hospital networks in rural areas, give special consideration to and provide appropriate relief for such networks. Title VIII: Financing - Extends certain Medicare secondary payer requirements with respect to end stage renal disease.</summary>
</bill>
