<bill session="104" type="h" number="681" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securities Private Enforcement Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 in order to reform private enforcement of the federal securities laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1995-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1995-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="1995-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1995-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1995-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1995-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/1995--Introduced.
Securities Private Enforcement Reform Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to declare that a defendant may be liable jointly and severally for damages in an implied private action only if the trier of fact specifically determines that the defendant knowingly engaged in securities fraud. Sets forth a liability allocation scheme to determine the percentage of responsibility among the plaintiff, the defendants, and any other alleged contributors to the harm alleged if the trier of fact finds that a defendant did not engage in knowing securities fraud. Prescribes guidelines for the award of reasonable attorney's fees and related expenses incurred by the prevailing party in any implied private action. Declares that in any implied right of action that is certified as a plaintiff class action: (1) the share of any settlement or final judgment awarded to the representative plaintiff shall be calculated in the same manner as the share awarded to all other members of the plaintiff class; (2) the plaintiff class may not be represented by any attorney who owns or has a beneficial interest in the securities that are the subject of the litigation, or any attorney affiliated with him or her, or any attorney who is obligated to pay remuneration to a third party for assistance in obtaining the representation of any party to the action; and (3) funds disgorged as a result of Securities and Exchange Commission action shall not be distributed as payment for attorney's fees or expenses incurred by private parties seeking distribution of the disgorged funds.</summary>
</bill>
