<bill session="106" type="h" number="820" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-27">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Coast Guard Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Coast Guard, FY2000 and 2001 Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coast Guard Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Coast Guard Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Coast Guard Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2000 and 2001 for the Coast Guard, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1999-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="1999-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1999-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-03-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-03-11T20:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 106-51.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-03-11T20:42:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="31">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 31.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-03-16T15:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 113 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 820 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five minute rule and to consider as an original bill the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill. The Chairman of the Committee may postpone votes and to reduce voting time to five minutes on a postponed question if the vote follows a fifteen minute vote. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. Members who have preprinted their amendments in the Congressional Record will be given priority to offer their amendments. At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment, the Committee shall rise and repo...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T10:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 113 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T13:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 113.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1370-1382" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1376-1377" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T13:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 820 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five minute rule and to consider as an original bill the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill. The Chairman of the Committee may postpone votes and to reduce voting time to five minutes on a postponed question if the vote follows a fifteen minute vote. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. Members who have preprinted their amendments in the Congressional Record will be given priority to offer their amendments. At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment, the Committee shall rise and repo...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T13:38:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 113 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T13:38:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Paul E. Gillmor to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T13:39:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 820.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T14:25:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. LoBiondo by voice vote and announced that the ayes had prevailed. Subsequently Mr. Shuster demanded a recorded vote. The Chair announced that further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T15:10:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 820.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T15:11:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T15:11:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-03-17T15:29:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="55" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 424 - 7 (Roll no. 55).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T15:29:00-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 820.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17T15:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7757" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 1089 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-07-27" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 1089 with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees McCain, Stevens, Snowe, Hollings and Kerry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04T13:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilchrest asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04T13:01:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8766" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04T13:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Shuster, Young (AK), Gilchrest, DeFazio, and Baird.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04T13:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-11">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="113"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="949"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="1047"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="920"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="920"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="106" type="s" number="1089"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1089"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="106" type="s" number="1089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Coastwise shipping"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Flight training"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human engineering"/>
    <term name="Ice breaking operations"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Liability for water pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lighthouses and lightships"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Military aircraft"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military helicopters"/>
    <term name="Military leave"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military posture"/>
    <term name="Military promotions"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Military vehicles"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Morale"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Offshore structures"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution of the sea"/>
    <term name="Patrol aircraft"/>
    <term name="Patrol ships"/>
    <term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
    <term name="Private legislation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Service academies"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil remediation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Tugboats"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in rivers, lakes, etc."/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h28"/>
    <amendment number="h29"/>
    <amendment number="h30"/>
    <amendment number="h31"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/27/2000--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Authorization Title II: Personnel Management Title III: Marine Safety Title IV: Renewal of Advisory Groups Title V: Miscellaneous Title VI: Jones Act Waivers Title VII: Certain Alaskan Cruise Ship Operations Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2000 - Title I: Authorization - Authorizes appropriations for the Coast Guard for fiscal year (FY) 2000 for: (1) operation and maintenance; (2) acquisition, construction, rebuilding, and improvement of aids to navigation, shore and offshore facilities, vessels, and aircraft (requiring that a specified amount be available for the construction and acquisition of a replacement vessel for the Cutter MACKINAW); (3) research, development, testing, and evaluation; (4) retired pay, payments under the Retired Serviceman's Family Protection and Survivor Benefit Plans, and payments for medical care of retired personnel and their dependents; (5) environmental compliance and restoration at Coast Guard facilities; and (6) alteration or removal of bridges constituting obstructions to navigation. Authorizes appropriations for the Coast Guard for FY 2002, requiring that a specified amount be available for construction or acquisition of a replacement vessel for the Cutter MACKINAW.(Sec. 102) Authorizes, for FY 2000, the Coast Guard end-of-year strength for active duty personnel and its average military training student loads.(Sec. 103) Authorizes appropriations, for FY 2001-2002, to the Department of Transportation, in addition to funds authorized for the Coast Guard for operation of the LORAN-C system, for capital expenses related to LORAN-C navigation infrastructure. Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to transfer funds from the Federal Aviation Administration and other agencies of the department to reimburse the Coast Guard for related expenses.(Sec. 104) Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation, notwithstanding any other provision of law, to accept, by direct transfer without cost, for use by the Coast Guard primarily for expanded drug interdiction activities required to meet national supply reduction goals, up to seven PC-170 patrol craft from the Department of Defense if it offers to transfer such craft. Authorizes appropriations to the Coast Guard for the conversion, operation, and maintenance of, personnel to operate and support, and shoreside infrastructure requirements for, up to seven patrol craft.(Sec. 105) Authorizes the Coast Guard to operate and maintain a Caribbean Support Tender (or similar vessel) to provide technical assistance, including law enforcement training, for foreign coast guards, navies, and other maritime services.Title II: Personnel Management - Limits the director of the Coast Guard band to the rank of captain (currently, commander).(Sec. 202) Adds the Secretary of Transportation (when the Coast Guard is not operating under the Department of the Navy) to the required members of the Board of Governors of the United Service Organizations, Inc. (USO).(Sec. 203) Authorizes compensatory absence from duty for military Coast Guard personnel serving at isolated duty stations (currently, at isolated aids to navigation) in certain circumstances.(Sec. 204) Allows a promotion selection board to recommend officers of particular merit for placement at the top of the list of selectees and requires, if approved by the President, placement of those officers (in seniority order) at the top of the list.(Sec. 205) Authorizes the Coast Guard Commandant to establish a Coast Guard Academy Board of Trustees to provide advice to the Commandant and the Academy's Superintendent on the Academy's operation and programs. Makes the Federal Advisory Committee Act inapplicable to the Board.(Sec. 206) Authorizes special pay rates for officers in the Coast Guard or Coast Guard Reserve designated as physician assistants.(Sec. 207) Authorizes the Commandant to suspend payment of retired pay of a service member or former member while the member willfully remains outside the United States to avoid criminal prosecution or civil liability.(Sec. 208) Extends the Coast Guard's authority to enter into transactions under provisions relating to Coast Guard housing.Title III: Marine Safety - Amends the Vessel Bridge-to-Bridge Radiotelephone Act to revise requirements regarding the waters on which vessels, dredges, and floating plants must carry a radiotelephone.(Sec. 302) Prohibits the Coast Guard from planning or implementing decommissioning of WYTL-class harbor tugs unless it has procured sufficient replacement assets to remediate any icebreaking services degradation caused by the decommissioning.(Sec. 303) Ends a requirement of annual reports regarding all transfers to and expenditures from the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund.(Sec. 304) Allows the Coast Guard to borrow a limited amount from the Fund when the limit of $50 million in unappropriated funds is inadequate to deal with a discharge or threatened discharge. Mandates repayment to the Fund when, and to the extent that, removal costs are recovered from responsible parties.(Sec. 305) Amends Federal law relating to vessels and seamen to: (1) authorize, in certain circumstances, issuance of interim merchant mariner's documents valid for a period not over 120 days; and (2) exempt, with regard to those employed as entertainment personnel with no duties, including emergency duties, related to navigation or safety of the vessel, crew, cargo, or passengers, a passenger vessel that is not engaged in a foreign voyage from a requirement that a vessel employee have a merchant mariner's document.(Sec. 306) Increases the civil fine limit for negligent vessel operation or interfering with safe vessel operation.(Sec. 307) Amends Federal law (popularly known as the "Death on the High Seas Act") to make that Act inapplicable to the death of certain individuals on vessels on the high seas 12 nautical miles or closer to the shore of any State, the District of Columbia, or U.S. Territories or dependencies. Allows nonpecuniary but prohibits punitive damages in the case of deaths on the high seas more than 12 nautical miles from shore.Title IV: Renewal of Advisory Groups - Renames the Commercial Fishing Industry Vessel Advisory Committee as the Commercial Fishing Industry Vessel Safety Advisory Committee and modifies Committee requirements to involve the Commandant of the Coast Guard. Extends the Committee's termination date.(Sec. 402) Involves the Commandant and extends the termination date by amending: (1) the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 1991 regarding the Houston-Galveston Navigation Safety Advisory Committee and the Lower Mississippi River Waterway Advisory Committee; (2) Federal law relating to vessels and seamen regarding the Great Lakes Pilotage Advisory Committee; (3) the Inland Navigational Rules Act of 1980 regarding the Navigation Safety Advisory Council; and (4) Federal law relating to navigation and navigable waters regarding the Towing Safety Advisory Committee.Title V: Miscellaneous - Requires the Commandant to report to a specified congressional committee on actions the Coast Guard has taken to implement the recommendations in a specified National Transportation Safety Board report.(Sec. 502) Authorizes conveyance, without consideration: (1) to the Gulf of Maine Aquarium Development Corporation of the Naval Reserve Pier property (exclusive of floating docks) in Portland, Maine; and (2) to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) of the Coast Guard Station Scituate. Exempts both transfers from requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966, and the Steward B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act. Imposes other requirements. Authorizes the Coast Guard to lease and improve land for relocating the Scituate Station.(Sec. 504) Requires the Coast Guard to: (1) study existing local harbor safety coordinating committees in the United States regarding cooperation with interested groups, organizational models, technological assistance, and recurring resources; and (2) test the feasibility of expanding the harbor safety committee concept to small and medium-sized ports not generally served by such a committee by establishing one or more prototype committees. Makes the Federal Advisory Committee Act inapplicable to harbor safety committees established under any provision of law.(Sec. 505) Amends the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 1998 to extend one of the termination dates of provisions requiring the enforcement of the United States Coast Guard 1997 Enforcement Policy for Cargo Residues on the Great Lakes (regulating incidental discharges from vessels of residues of dry bulk cargo into Great Lakes waters under U.S. jurisdiction).(Sec. 506) Requires the conveyance authorized by Coast Guard Authorization Act of 1998 of Point Retreat Light Station, Alaska, to the Alaska Lighthouse Association, within three months after enactment of this Act, notwithstanding any other provision of law other than specified provisions of that Act.(Sec. 507) Authorizes the transfer of limited funds to the Traverse City Area Public School District for demolition and removal of the structure commonly known as "Building 402" at former Coast Guard property located in Traverse City, Michigan, and associated site work.(Sec. 508) Authorizes conveyance to Lake County, California, without consideration, of a described property involving a portion of the Coast Guard Loran Station Middletown reported to the General Services Administration as excess property.Title VI: Jones Act Waivers - Authorizes, notwithstanding specified Federal laws, issuance of a certificate of documentation with a coastwise endorsement for eight named vessels.Title VII: Certain Alaskan Cruise Ship Operations - Regulates the discharge of untreated sewage, treated sewage, and graywater by a cruise vessel operating in Alexander Archipelago waters, Alaska. Makes knowing violation a class D felony. Imposes a civil monetary fine for violations and makes violating vessels liable in rem.</summary>
</bill>
