<bill session="106" type="h" number="3659" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Response Employees Disease Protection Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a study and for demonstration projects regarding cases of hepatitis C among firefighters, paramedics, and emergency medical technicians who are employees or volunteers of units of local government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2000-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="2000-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2000-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="2000-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="2000-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hepatitis"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liver diseases"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in government"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2000--Introduced.
Emergency Response Employees Disease Protection Act of 2000 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to study and report to Congress on: (1) an estimate of the prevalence of hepatitis C among designated emergency response employees in the United States; and (2) the likely means through which such employees become infected with such disease in the course of performing their duties. Defines "designated emergency response employees" as firefighters, paramedics, and emergency medical technicians who are employees or volunteers of units of local government.Directs the Secretary to make grants to qualifying local governments for purposes of carrying out demonstration projects that: (1) train such employees in minimizing the risk of infection of hepatitis C in performing their duties; and (2) test such employees for infection with, and treat them for, the disease. Defines "qualifying local government" as a local government whose population of designated emergency response employees has a prevalence of hepatitis C that is not less than 200 percent of the national average for the prevalence of such disease in such populations. Conditions such grants on the local government maintaining confidentiality of information regarding testing or treatment. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on evaluations of such projects and provide recommendations for administrative or legislative initiatives regarding project activities.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
