<bill session="105" type="h" number="3293" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Women's Higher Education Opportunity Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Child Care Access Means Parents in School Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve the access of women to higher education opportunities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="1998-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1998-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1998-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1998-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1998-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1998-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1998-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="1998-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1998-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1998-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E246"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="College and school journalism"/>
    <term name="College sports"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Community and college"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Graduate students"/>
    <term name="Hate crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority students"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School discipline"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="School violence"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in education"/>
    <term name="Social sciences"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stalking"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women athletes"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/1998--Introduced.
Women's Higher Education Opportunity Act of 1998 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) with respect to the access of women to higher education opportunities. (Sec. 2) Provides that the following shall remain in effect during FY 1999 through 2004: (1) part-time student eligibility for Pell grants; and (2) the exclusion of HEA student aid from eligibility determinations for other programs. (Sec. 3) Increases the dependent care allowance for Pell Grant recipients. (Sec. 4) Child Care Access Means Parents in School Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to assist institutions of higher education in providing campus-based child care services to low-income students. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 5) Requires: (1) each institution of higher education to provide the Secretary with information regarding men's and women's athletic programs; and (2) the Secretary to prepare a report based on such information, which shall be made available on the Internet. Requires the Secretary to establish a toll-free telephone service to provide the public with information regarding such reports and respond to inquiries about title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 and athletic opportunities for girls and women. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to institutions of higher education to combat violent crimes against women on campuses. Requires the Secretary to provide for a national baseline study and report on university campus procedures in cases of reports of sexual assault. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 7) Revises and renames HEA title IX as the National Graduate Fellowship Program (currently, Graduate Programs). Authorizes the Secretary to carry out such national graduate fellowship program either directly or by contract with a nongovernmental organization which demonstrates the capacity to administer such programs. Sets forth fellowship conditions for recipients and for institutional applications. Requires award of fellowships: (1) in areas of national need; (2) in the humanities, social sciences, and arts; and (3) for scholars from underrepresented groups. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 8) Revises campus security policy reporting and crime statistics disclosure requirements. Includes other campus officials (as well as campus security or law enforcement, or local law enforcement) among those officials that must report, for statistical disclosure purposes, if specified types of criminal offenses are reported to them. Specifies additions to the list of such offenses. Makes annual submission of campus crime statistics mandatory for all institutions participating in any student aid program under HEA title IV (participating institutions). (Currently such submissions are only required upon the request of the Secretary.) Directs the Secretary to report each set of such statistics, clearly identifying each institution and campus, not only to specified congressional committees but also to each participating institution and to the public via printed and electronic means. Requires each official charged with compiling such statistics to certify their accuracy and to disseminate certain statistics and information without identifying the victims or the accused. Requires any participating institution which maintains a police or security department to make a monthly report of specified crime information for public inspection. (Sec. 9) Amends the General Education Provisions Act to exclude allegations of criminal activities from the education records subject to family access. (Sec.10) Requires, under HEA student aid program agreements, that the campus security policies and crime statistics disclosed be comprehensive and accurate. (Sec. 11) Directs the Attorney General and the Secretary to report annually to specified congressional committees on model programs for improving campus safety and complying with specified HEA requirements, including an identification of programs at institutions of varying sizes and purposes. Requires the provision of such report to each participating institution and the public through Internet, print, and other means.</summary>
</bill>
