<bill session="107" type="h" number="2764" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Colorado River Quantification Settlement Facilitation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To address certain matters related to Colorado River water management and the Salton Sea by providing funding for habitat enhancement projects at the Salton Sea, authorization and direction to the Secretary of the Interior regarding Federal environmental compliance, and funding for off-stream water management reservoirs and associated facilities near the All American Canal.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="2001-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2001-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2001-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2002-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2001-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2001-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="2002-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2001-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1531"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-08-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation districts"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Water allocation (Policy)"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water supply engineering"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2001--Introduced.
Colorado River Quantification Settlement Facilitation Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, in order to satisfy the requirements of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 for whatever actions relating to the Salton Sea may be required as a result of the Quantification Settlement Agreement (the agreement among the Imperial Irrigation District, the Metropolitan Water District of Southern California, the Coachella Valley Water District, and the State of California) water transfers, to provide for the construction of the Habitat Enhancement Projects benefitting species using the Salton Sea area, including projects that provide facilities for hunting, fishing, bird watching, boating, and camping.Requires the Secretary to approve the Habitat Conservation Plan and to issue related incidental take permits and all other approvals required so as to provide for compliance with such Act for covered activities within the Plan area.Directs the Secretary to exercise existing authority to operate and maintain the Colorado River front work and levee system to provide for the construction of off-stream water management reservoirs and associated facilities near the All-American Canal. Requires the reservoirs to be constructed on lands owned by the Imperial Irrigation District. Requires the Secretary to enter into an operating agreement with such District to arrange for operation of such reservoirs to provide for regulating river flows, furthering water conservation and hydropower generation, preventing the loss of Lake Mead storage, and facilitating any arrangements with Mexico in addressing its Colorado River water supply management needs.Provides for the termination of this Act, including such permits and approvals, after December 31, 2002, unless the Agreement is in effect on or before such date and remains in effect.</summary>
</bill>
