<bill session="104" type="h" number="2116" updated="2012-11-01T22:44:31-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Voter Opportunity To Inform Congress Effectively on a Flat Tax and a Cap on Tax Increases Act of 1995 (National VOICE on a Flat Tax and Cap on Tax Increases Act of 1995)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a national advisory referendum on a flat income tax rate, and requiring a national vote to raise taxes at the general election of 1996.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400182"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7687)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7687"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H8166-8169)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8166-8169"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Flat-rate tax"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>07/26/1995--Introduced.
National Voter Opportunity To Inform Congress Effectively on a Flat Tax and a Cap on Tax Increases Act of 1995 (National VOICE on a Flat Tax and Cap on Tax Increases Act of 1995) - Establishes a national advisory nonbinding referendum to provide for placing on the 1996 general election ballot or, if there is no general election in a particular district, placing on a ballot the following questions: (1) Should Congress adopt a simple flat tax rate on income?; and (2) Should Congress approve a constitutional amendment to require a majority vote of the American people to raise taxes? Authorizes that $5 million be reimbursed to the States from the franking accounts of the House of Representatives and the Senate for the costs of conducting the nonbinding referendum in proportions equal to the total amount appropriated for franking in each House.</summary>
</bill>
