<bill session="107" type="h" number="4141" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-01T18:27:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-01T18:27:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Red Rock Canyon National Conservation Area Protection and Enhancement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Red Rock Canyon National Conservation Area Protection and Enhancement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the acquisition by exchange of lands for inclusion in the Red Rock Canyon National Conservation Area, Clark County, Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2002-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2002-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-25">
      <text>Executive Comment Received from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-705.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-10-01T18:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="436">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 436.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6872-6874" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4141.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-10-01T18:27:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6872-6873" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2002--Passed House amended.
Red Rock Canyon National Conservation Area Protection and Enhancement Act of 2002 - (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of the Interior, if the Howard Hughes Corporation offers to convey to the United States certain high-ground lands (at the eastern edge of the Red Rock Canyon National Conservation Area), to accept such offer and convey: (1) specified Federal lands to the Corporation; and (2) specified other Federal lands to Clark County, Nevada.Directs the Secretary to require, as conditions of such conveyance, that: (1) the Corporation be responsible for removal of and remediation related to any hazardous materials that are present on the property conveyed to the United States; (2) the Corporation provide a metes and bounds survey of the common boundary between the parcels of land to be conveyed that is acceptable to the Corporation, Clark County, and the Secretary; and (3) the lands transferred to the County must be used only as a public park or as part of a public regional trail system.(Sec. 5) Requires the Secretary to administer certain flood control detention basin lands and lands acquired under this Act as part of the Conservation Area and in accordance with the Red Rock Canyon National Conservation Area Establishment Act of 1990, the Southern Nevada Public Lands Management Act of 1998, and all other applicable laws.(Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to complete a review of the Complete Self-Contained Appraisal Red Rock Exchange, Las Vegas, Nevada. Requires the difference in appraisal values to be reimbursed to the Secretary by the Corporation. Withdraws from operation of the public land and mining laws those Federal lands acquired by the United States under this Act and those Federal lands already owned by the United States but included within the Conservation Area's boundaries pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
