<bill session="104" type="h" number="1283" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gang Prevention and Youth Recreation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to cities to establish teen resource and education centers to provide education, employment, recreation, social, and cultural awareness assistance to at-risk youth.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities. for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to cities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Gardening"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/1995--Introduced.
Gang Prevention and Youth Recreation Act of 1995 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to not more than ten selected cities to assist them to establish and operate teen resource and education centers to provide education, employment, recreation, social, and cultural awareness assistance to at-risk youth. Authorizes the Secretary to make such grants to a city if it applies and agrees to operate at least two such centers. Requires such centers to offer for at-risk youth: (1) educational assistance, including information on institutions of higher education, assistance with financial aid and scholarship applications, and preparatory courses for high school equivalency and college entrance examinations; (2) employment and skills training assistance, including hiring teen peer counselors to provide basic job skills training, job referral services, and job banks; (3) recreational opportunities, such as sports teams, neighborhood gardening and food distribution, creative activities and arts, and reading programs; (4) social skills development, including hiring adult counselors and providing support groups for counseling on social and personal issues; and (5) cultural awareness programs, such as classes in the history and culture of various cultural groups and productions of plays, stories, and artwork reflecting the cultural heritage of such youth. Requires such centers to provide financial assistance to college graduates who work full-time at the center to assist them to repay part of their student loan debt. Sets forth grant selection, allocation, and reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
