<bill session="107" type="h" number="2351" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Threat Reduction Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the policy of the United States for reducing the number of nuclear warheads in the United States and Russian arsenals, for reducing the number of nuclear weapons of those two nations that are on high alert, and for expanding and accelerating programs to prevent diversion and proliferation of Russian nuclear weapons, fissile materials, and nuclear expertise.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2001-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2001-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms control negotiations"/>
    <term name="Arms control verification"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Bomber aircraft"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Crisis management"/>
    <term name="Debt agreements"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fissionable materials"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intercontinental ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Missile warheads"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear submarines"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Scientists in government"/>
    <term name="Strategic forces"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2001--Introduced.
Nuclear Threat Reduction Act of 2001 - Repeals a provision of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998 which provides funding limits for retirement or dismantlement of the B52H bomber, Trident submarines, and Minuteman III and Peacekeeper intercontinental ballistic missiles. Declares it to be U.S. policy to: (1) reduce the number of nuclear warheads and delivery systems of the United States and Russia, through bilateral agreements, to the lowest possible number consistent with national security, requiring any warhead removed to be kept safe and secure, accounted for, and eventually destroyed or eliminated in a verifiable manner; (2) pursue with Russia formal arrangements to remove as many nuclear weapons of the two nations as feasible from immediate, launch-ready status, concentrating on those weapons earmarked for downloading, dismantlement, or elimination under the START II Treaty; and (3) work cooperatively with Russia to prevent the diversion from Russia of nuclear weapons, materials, and expertise.Requires the President to submit to Congress a plan for nonproliferation programs with Russia, as well as a related study.</summary>
</bill>
