<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="124" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:55-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2187" sequence="3"/>
  <status datetime="2009-05-13T14:54:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="412318"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  <description>Amendment adds a new section requiring the Secretary of Education to establish an Advisory Council to the Secretary on green, high-performing schools. Such a Council would consult with the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality, the Commerce Secretary, Energy Secretary, Health and Human Services Secretary, Labor Secretary, EPA Administrator, and the GSA Administrator.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 3 printed in House Report 111-106 to add a new section 314 requiring the Secretary of Education to establish an Advisory Council to the Secretary on green, high-performing schools. The Council advises the Secretary on the impact of green, high-performing schools on teaching and learning, health energy costs and environmental impact; works with the Secretary to recommend Federal policies to increase the number of green, high-performing schools; provides technical assistance to states; and identifies Federal policies that are barriers to helping states make schools green and high-performing. The Council consults with the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality, the Commerce Secretary, Energy Secretary, Health and Human Services Secretary, Labor Secretary, EPA Administrator, and the GSA Administrator.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13T13:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Ms. Titus.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5511-5512, H5521" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5511" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2009-05-13T14:54:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="249">
      <text>On agreeing to the Titus amendment (A003) Agreed to by recorded vote: 270 - 160 (Roll no. 249).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
