<bill session="104" type="h" number="146" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Crimes Against the Elderly Penalty Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To impose mandatory sentences for violent felonies committed against individuals of age sixty-five or over, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-07">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.2974.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2974"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Crimes against the elderly"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Pleas (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Crimes Against the Elderly Penalty Act - Amends the Federal criminal code to impose mandatory minimum sentences for committing violent felonies against individuals aged 65 or over. Prohibits suspended, probationary, and concurrent sentences. Prohibits any plea bargaining agreements that would result in the defendant's serving less than the minimum sentence. Provides that an appeal by the United States shall lie to a court of appeals from an otherwise final decision, judgment, or order of a district court sentencing a defendant on the ground that such sentence is less severe than that required under such provisions. Amends rule 32 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure to: (1) provide that neither the defendant nor the court may waive a presentence investigation and report unless there is in the record information sufficient for the court to determine whether a mandatory sentence must be imposed pursuant to such provisions; and (2) require that the presentence report include information relating to whether any victim had attained age 65 on the date that the offense was committed.</summary>
</bill>
