<bill session="105" type="hr" number="306" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-05T22:08:00-05:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-11-05T22:08:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving a requirement of clause 4(b) of rule XI with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-11-05T22:07:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-384, by Mr. Linder.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-05T22:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of. The provisions of clause 4(b) of rule XI (requiring a two-thirds vote to consider a rule on the same day it is reported from the Rules Committee) against resolutions reported from the Rules Committee before Nov. 10, 1997, providing for consideration of a bill or joint resolution making appropriations for the fiscal year ending Sept. 30, 1998, any amendment thereto, any conference report thereon, or any amendment reported in disagreement from a conference thereon are waived; the Speaker may entertain motions to suspend the rules at any time before Nov. 10,</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-11-05T22:08:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="129">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 129.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-11-10T01:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 311, H. Res. 306 is laid on the table.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10575-10577" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hr" number="311"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hr" number="311"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House Rules"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/1997--Introduced.
Waives provisions of rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives that require a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to resolutions reported by such Committee before November 10, 1997, to provide for the consideration or disposition of a bill or joint resolution (including any amendment, conference report, or any amendment from conference in disagreement thereon) that: (1) makes general appropriations for FY 1998; or (2) includes provisions making continuing appropriations for FY 1998. Makes it in order at any time before November 10, 1997, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules, provided that the object of any such motion is announced from the House floor at least one hour before the motion is offered.</summary>
</bill>
