<bill session="108" type="hr" number="580" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-30T16:04:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-03-30T16:04:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 3966) to amend title 10, United States Code, and the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to improve the ability of the Department of Defense to establish and maintain Senior Reserve Officer Training Corps units at institutions of higher education, to improve the ability of students to participate in Senior ROTC programs, and to ensure that institutions of higher education provide military recruiters entry to campuses and access to students that is at least equal in quality and scope to that provided to any other employer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-29T19:00:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 108-451, by Mrs. Myrick.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-29T19:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3966 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-03-29T19:00:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="162">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 162.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30T14:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30T14:53:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 580.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30T16:04:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 223 - 202 (Roll no. 98).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2004-03-30T16:04:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30T16:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="h" number="3966"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2004--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 3966 (ROTC and Military Recruiter Equal Access to Campus Act of 2004).</summary>
</bill>
