<bill session="107" type="h" number="4759" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Governors Island National Monument Ratification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ratify the Governors Island National Monument and the boundaries thereof, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400289"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2002-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Docks"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/2002--Introduced.
Governors Island National Monument Ratification Act - Ratifies the establishment of the Governors Island National Monument. Declares that the Monument shall not be subject to sale. Directs the Administrator of General Services to transfer to the Secretary of the Interior administrative jurisdiction over and management of the Monument.States that the boundary of the Monument shall include Building 140, its land, and Dock 102. Requires the Monument to be administered by the Secretary in accordance with this Act and with the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System.Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) consult and enter into cooperative agreements with the Administrator or any management entity to provide for the preservation, development, interpretation, use of, and access to the Monument; and (2) provide, subject to an agreement with the Administrator or any management entity, interpretive services and signage in the Governors Island National Historic Landmark District.Directs the Secretary to prepare a complete management plan for the Monument by January 19, 2004, with specified reservations of rights of access and use.</summary>
</bill>
