<bill session="107" type="h" number="5509" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Cruise Tourism Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit the transportation of passengers between United States ports by certain foreign-flag vessels and to encourage United States-flag vessels to participate in such transportation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2002-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="2002-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="2002-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2002-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Coastwise shipping"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flags of convenience"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine insurance"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Smoke detectors"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2002--Introduced.
United States Cruise Tourism Act of 2002 - Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to approve the transportation of passengers on foreign-flag cruise vessels not otherwise qualified to engage in the coastwise trade between ports in the United States, directly or by way of a foreign port, except with respect to coastwise trade served by a U.S.-flag cruise vessel. Requires termination of any such foreign-flag cruise vessel passenger service within three years after a U.S.-flag cruise vessel commences such service between the same ports.Requires the owner or charterer of a qualified foreign-flag cruise vessel to have any vessel repairs performed in the United States, unless the vessel requires repairs or service while at a distant foreign port. Directs the Secretary to terminate the coastwise trade privileges of the owner or charterer of a foreign-flag cruise vessel if such repairs have not been made in the United States. Provides for a waiver of such requirements in emergencies.</summary>
</bill>
