<bill session="104" type="hj" number="46" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to provide for a balanced budget for the United States Government and for greater accountability in the enactment of tax legislation and to allow an item veto of appropriation bills.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-24">
      <text>For Further Action See H.J.Res.1.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hj" number="1"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Item veto"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Requires the Congress and the President, prior to each fiscal year, to agree on an estimate of total receipts for that fiscal year by enactment of a law devoted solely to that subject. Prohibits outlays for that year from exceeding this amount unless the Congress, by a two-thirds roll call vote of each House, authorizes a specific excess of outlays over receipts. Requires a two-thirds roll call vote of each House to increase the public debt. Directs the President to submit a balanced budget to the Congress. Requires a two-thirds roll call vote of the total membership of each House before any bill to increase revenue may become law. Waives these provisions when a declaration of war is in effect. Grants the President the authority to disapprove any appropriation or provision and approve any other appropriation or provision in the same appropriation bill.</summary>
</bill>
