<bill session="106" type="hr" number="534" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-17T19:27:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-07-17T19:27:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the recent nuclear weapons security failures at Los Alamos National Laboratory demonstrate that security policy and security procedures within the National Nuclear Security Administration remain inadequate, that the individuals responsible for such policy and procedures must be held accountable for their performance, and that immediate action must be taken to correct security deficiencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400610"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400609" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="2000-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported Without Recommendation by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-12T20:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Armed Services. H. Rept. 106-730.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-12T20:42:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="255">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 255.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-17T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Spence moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-17T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H6072-6077</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-17T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 534.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-17T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-17T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-17T19:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2000-07-17T19:27:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="401" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 391 - 5, 2 Present (Roll no. 401).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6072-6073" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2000--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House that: (1) certain security failures at Los Alamos National Laboratory demonstrate continued inadequacy of nuclear weapons security policy and procedures within the National Nuclear Security Administration and its facilities; (2) individuals responsible for the implementation, oversight, and management of nuclear weapons security policy and procedures within the Administration and its facilities must be held accountable for their performance; and (3) the Administrator for Nuclear Security must take immediate action to improve safeguard procedures for classified nuclear weapons information and correct all identified nuclear weapons security deficiencies within the Administration.</summary>
</bill>
