<bill session="106" type="h" number="3807" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stable Oil Supply Home Heating Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to ensure that petroleum importers, refiners, and wholesalers accumulate minimally adequate supplies of home heating oil to meet reasonably foreseeable needs in the northeastern States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400600"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400613" joined="2000-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Antitrust actions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Northeastern States"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Petroleum storage"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2000--Introduced.
Stable Oil Supply Home Heating Act - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to mandate that voluntary plans for home heating oil reserve be submitted to the Secretary of Energy by importers, refiners, and wholesalers holding oil inventories for sale to markets in the Northeast in order to ensure stability in energy fuel markets and to protect consumers from dramatic price swings. Prescribes implementation and certification guidelines, including an antitrust defense for actions taken in compliance with this Act. Exempts certain small-sized importers and refiners.Directs the Secretary to: (1) issue an order requiring the establishment of a private home heating oil reserve for the Northeast if a certified plan has not been implemented within a specified time frame for an importer, refiner, or wholesaler that stores heating oil for sale in the Northeast; (2) periodically monitor supply levels to ensure that home heating oil inventories in the Northeast are adequate to supply customer needs during the present or following winter season so as to obviate sudden price increases caused by inadequate inventories; (3) require an importer, refiner, or wholesaler to increase its inventory if the Secretary determines that inventories are insufficient; and (4) establish civil penalties and cooperate with State energy authorities in carrying out this Act.Instructs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to take action to enable importers, refiners, or wholesalers to sell their remaining excess inventories at the end of each winter season.</summary>
</bill>
