<bill session="108" type="h" number="2734" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Aviation Administration Research and Development Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Federal Aviation Administration Research and Development Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for the civil aviation research and development projects and activities of the Federal Aviation Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400137"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2003-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2003-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2003-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-07-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T01:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Boehlert asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Science, Space and Technology have until 4:00 p.m. on Aug. 29 to file a report on H.R. 2734. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08T20:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 108-405, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure for a period ending not later than Dec. 8, 2003 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(q), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08T20:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-12-08T20:07:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="231">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 231.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2115"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Avionics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication satellites"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Flight training"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="High technology"/>
    <term name="Human engineering"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Navigation (Aeronautics)"/>
    <term name="Navigation satellites"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="New products"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication systems"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2003--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Federal Aviation Administration Research and Development Reauthorization Act - (Sec. 2) Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 through 2006 for Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) Research and Development programs, projects and activities. (Sec. 3) Requires the FAA and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to establish a Joint Program Office (JPO) to conduct long-term research and development for a Next Generation Air Traffic Management system capable of tripling capacity by 2025. (Sec. 4) Amends Federal transportation law to require future FAA budgets to identify all research and development activities that would be classified as basic research, applied research, or development under the guidelines established by the Office of Management and Budget Circular A-11, regardless of the budget category in which they appear in the budget request. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish an airport cooperative research grant program to identify problems shared by airport operating agencies that can be solved through applied research, and to fund research addressing those problems. Requires the Secretary to appoint an independent governing board for the program from candidates proposed by national associations representing airport executives, public airport operating agencies, State aviation officials, and the scheduled airlines. (Sec. 6) Directs FAA to conduct research to: (1) promote development of analytical tools to improve existing certification methods (for new aircraft, engines, and aircraft systems); and (2) reduce overall certification costs for new products. (Sec. 7) Establishes a program to fund research on the impact of new technologies and procedures, particularly those related to aircraft flight deck and air traffic management functions, on training requirements for pilots and air traffic controllers. (Sec. 8) Directs the FAA Administrator to establish a rotorcraft initiative with the objective of developing and demonstrating technologies, within ten years, to enable specified performance enhancements over state-of-the-art rotorcraft, including: (1) an 80 percent reduction in noise levels on take and on approach and landing; (2) a factor of 10 reduction in vibration; (3) a 30 percent reduction in empty weight; (4) a predicted accident rate to that of fixed-wing aircraft in commercial service; and (5) the capability of operating in instrument meteorological conditions. Requires the FAA Administrator, in cooperation with NASA, to provide an implementation plan to specified congressional committees. Authorizes FAA to contribute up to $5 million for the operation of a center for rotorcraft technology. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 through 2008. (Sec. 9) Directs the FAA Administrator to study and report to Congress on whether commercial airline pilots between the ages of 60 and 64, who fly for foreign commercial air carriers, pose a significant safety risk to U.S. passengers and airspace.</summary>
</bill>
