<bill session="104" type="h" number="2830" updated="2012-11-01T22:44:51-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campaign Finance Reform, Fairness, and Citizens Involvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to provide for a House of Representatives election limitation on contributions from persons other than in-State individual residents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1995-12-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Commerce, and Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Postal Service"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSIF" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" name="House Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural societies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Horticulture"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>12/22/1995--Introduced.
Campaign Finance Reform, Fairness, and Citizens Involvement Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to prohibit: (1) a candidate for Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress, for a reporting period for an election, from accepting contributions from persons other than in-State individual residents in excess of 50 percent of the total of contributions accepted; and (2) any person from acting as an intermediary or conduit for any contribution from another in the form of a check or other negotiable instrument that is made payable to a candidate for Federal office or a campaign committee of such candidate. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an individual to take a tax credit for up to $100 ($200 for a joint return) of Federal campaign contributions, subject to verification procedures. Limits the exemption from taxation on labor, agricultural, or horticultural organizations to such organizations which do not participate or intervene in any political campaign on behalf of, or in opposition to, any candidate for public office. Sets forth or revises provisions regarding: (1) denial of a tax exemption by reason of expenditures to influence legislation; (2) a prohibition on treatment as a civic league or organization not organized for profit because of substantial lobbying or political activities; (3) taxation of excess expenditures to influence legislation; (4) taxation of political expenditures generally; (5) termination assessments for flagrant political expenditures; (6) actions to enjoin flagrant political expenditures; and (7) declaratory judgments relating to status as exempt labor, agricultural, or horticultural organizations. Amends FECA to prohibit an eligible House of Representatives candidate, with respect to an election, from: (1) making expenditures totaling more than $500,000; and (2) using more than $25,000 from such candidate's personal funds. Provides that if any opponent of an eligible House candidate uses more than $50,000 from personal funds with respect to an election, specified limits shall be inapplicable to contributions to the eligible House candidate by individuals who are residents of the State in which the congressional district involved is located. Specifies that any payment by the national or State committee of a political party or by a corporation or labor organization for a mixed political activity: (1) shall be subject to limitation and reporting under FECA as if such payment were an expenditure; and (2) may be paid only from an account that is subject to the FECA requirements. Repeals the building fund exception to the definition of the term "contribution." Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to revise provisions regarding broadcast media rates to provide that charges made for the use of any broadcasting station by a legally qualified candidate for public office in connection with such person's nomination campaign shall not exceed, during the 30 days preceding the date of a primary or primary runoff election and the 60 days preceding the date of a general or special election in which such person is a candidate, the lowest charge of the station for the same amount of time for the same period on the same date. Specifies that, in the case of an eligible House candidate, the charges for the use of a broadcasting station during such 30- and 60-day periods shall not exceed 50 percent of such lowest charge. Prohibits a licensee from preempting the use, during any such period, of a broadcasting station by an eligible House candidate who has purchased and paid for such use, with an exception for circumstances beyond the station's control. Allows the Federal Communications Commission to revoke any station license or construction permit for willful or repeated failure to allow reasonable access to, or to permit purchase of reasonable amounts of time for the use of, a broadcasting station by a legally qualified candidate for Federal elective office on behalf of his or her candidacy under the same terms, conditions, and business practices as apply to its most favored advertiser. Amends Federal law to include the principal campaign committee of an eligible House candidate within the term "qualified political committee" (thus making such committee eligible for reduced postage rates).</summary>
</bill>
