<bill session="105" type="h" number="1558" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hansen's Disease Program Amendments of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the relocation of the Gillis W. Long Hansen's Disease Center, to provide for the transfer to the State of Louisiana of the current site of such Center, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400012"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="406863" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1997-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Bacterial diseases"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leprosy"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Long-term care facilities"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/1997--Introduced.
Hansen's Disease Program Amendments of 1997 - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for the relocation of the Gillis W. Long Hansen's Disease Center near Carville, Louisiana, and to transfer to Louisiana the real property and improvements constituting the Center. Provides transfer conditions, including the requirement that the property and improvements be used for the next 30-year period exclusively for promoting public health or education. Provides employee pay and retirement considerations for Federal employees of the Center who become State employees at the transferred property. Requires the Center's relocation site to be in the Baton Rouge area and to continue to use the same name. Provides care and treatment options of patients at the relocated Center. Amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit the Secretary from providing long-term care at the relocated Center for patients suffering from Hansen's disease (a form of leprosy) or its complications. Directs the Center to conduct training in the diagnosis and management of the disease and to conduct and promote the coordination of research, investigations, demonstrations, and studies relating to the causes, diagnosis, treatment, control, and prevention of that disease as well as other mycobacterial diseases and complications related to such disease. Authorizes the Secretary to establish sites for the treatment of persons with Hansen's disease, requiring each site to provide for appropriate outpatient care and treatment.</summary>
</bill>
