<bill session="104" type="h" number="2414" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Youth Smoking Prevention Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Federal authority to regulate tobacco and other tobacco products containing nicotine.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404996" joined="1995-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="409400" joined="1995-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="411314" joined="1995-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Billboards"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community service (Punishment)"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emblems"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to alcoholism programs"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Playgrounds"/>
    <term name="Postal crimes"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Schools"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
    <term name="Smoking and youth"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
    <term name="Toys"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Vending machines"/>
    <term name="Video games"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1995--Introduced.
Youth Smoking Prevention Act of 1995 - Declares that the Secretary of Health and Human Services does not have any authority under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, the Federal Cigarette Labeling and Advertising Act, or the Comprehensive Smokeless Tobacco Health Education Act of 1986 to regulate the manufacture, labeling, sale, distribution, and advertising and promotion of tobacco and other tobacco products containing nicotine. Establishes the Federal authority to regulate the sale, distribution, and advertising and promotion of tobacco and tobacco products containing nicotine as a condition to the receipt by State of the Federal preventive health and health services block grant. Amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit or reduce the amount of block grants for the prevention and treatment of substance abuse based on whether a State has a law prohibiting: (1) sale of tobacco or tobacco products to individuals under the age of 18; (2) purchase of those materials by such individuals; (3) use of false identification for the purchase of those materials; (4) sale of individual cigarettes and packages of fewer than 20 cigarettes; (5) operation of a vending machine dispensing such materials unless specified requirements are met; (6) use of unsupervised self-service displays; (7) distribution of free samples to such individuals; and (8) distribution through the mail to such individuals. Sets forth general requirements regarding the sale of such materials and related notice by the owner to the employees of a retail establishment. Prohibits engaging in the retail sale of cigarettes without a license issued by the State. Sets forth State responsibilities. Regulates billboard advertising. Prohibits the placement of a tobacco manufacturer's brand name or logo on any item marketed specifically to minors, including toys and video games. Allows use of amounts available under such block grants to enforce the laws described in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
