<bill session="104" type="h" number="256" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-28T15:11:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-03-28T15:11:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fort Carson-Pinon Canyon Military Lands Withdrawal Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To withdraw and reserve certain public lands and minerals within the State of Colorado for military uses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on National Security, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-17">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, Army.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Installations.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-01-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 42 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-02-03">
      <text>Subcommittee on Military Installations and Facilities Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 104-28, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-14T19:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on National Security. H. Rept. 104-28, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-02-14T19:12:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="15">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T15:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hefley moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T15:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3828-3831" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T15:04:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-03-28T15:11:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T15:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSAS04" subcommittee="Military Installations and Facilities" name="House National Security"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Forests and Public Land Management" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military maneuvers"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trapping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Fort Carson-Pinon Canyon Military Lands Withdrawal Act - Withdraws from appropriation under public land, mining, mineral, geothermal leasing, and mineral materials disposal laws, and reserves for military use by the Army, specified lands at the Fort Carson Military Reservation and Pinon Canyon Maneuver Site (both in Colorado). Requires the Secretary of the Army to manage such lands for military purposes covered by this Act and to authorize their use by other U.S. military agencies. Directs the Secretary, with the concurrence of the Secretary of the Interior, to develop a management plan for such reserved and withdrawn lands. Terminates such land withdrawals and reservations 15 years after enactment of this Act. Requires the Secretary of the Army to: (1) decontaminate relinquished lands (but authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to refuse to accept lands if such decontamination is not practicable or economically feasible, if the lands cannot be decontaminated sufficiently to allow them to be opened to the operation of the public land laws, or if insufficient funds are appropriated for the purpose of decontaminating the lands); (2) if the Secretary of the Interior declines to accept jurisdiction of lands proposed for relinquishment under such provision or determines that some of the lands withdrawn by this Act are contaminated to an extent that prevents opening the contaminated lands to operation of the public land laws, warn the public of risks of entry, conduct only decontamination activities on such lands after the expiration of the withdrawal, and make a status report to the Secretary of the Interior and to the Congress; and (3) maintain a program of decontamination of the lands withdrawn by this Act at least at the level of effort carried out during FY 1992, subject to specified limitations. Directs that the United States be held harmless and not liable for any injuries or damages to persons or property suffered in the course of any mining, mineral activity, or geothermal leasing activity conducted on lands comprising the Fort Carson Reservation or Pinon Canyon Maneuver Site, including liabilities to non-Federal entities under specified provisions of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 or the Solid Waste Disposal Act. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
