<bill session="106" type="h" number="5496" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide for maintenace and repair of buildings and properties located on lands in the National Wildlife Refuge System by lessees of such facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400385"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/18/2000--Introduced.
Amends the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to include in any agreement, lease, permit, or contract that authorizes a person to use land or water in the National Wildlife Refuge System to provide accommodations, facilities, or services to visitors provisions that: (1) authorize the person to maintain or repair any improvement on or in such land or water; and (2) treat costs incurred by the person for such maintenance or repair as consideration otherwise required to be paid to the United States for such use.Requires amounts received by the United States as fees or other payments required under any such agreement, lease, permit, or contract to be available to the Secretary for expenditure to increase the quality of the visitor experience and enhance the protection of resources. Allows such amounts to be used only for the area, site, or project concerned for: (1) backlogged repair and maintenance projects; (2) interpretation, signage, habitat, or facility enhancement; (3) resource preservation; or (4) annual operation, maintenance, and law enforcement relating to public use.</summary>
</bill>
