<bill session="108" type="h" number="186" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sewage Sludge in Food Production Consumer Notification Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and the egg, meat, and poultry inspection laws to ensure that consumers receive notification regarding food products produced from crops, livestock, or poultry raised on land on which sewage sludge was applied.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400366"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2003-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2003-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock and Horticulture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Livestock and Horticulture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Fertilizers"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Natural foods"/>
    <term name="Organic farming"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Sewage sludge"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/2003--Introduced.
Sewage Sludge in Food Production Consumer Notification Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to classify a food as adulterated if it was produced, or contains any ingredient that was produced, on land on which sewage sludge was applied. Permits the following exceptions: (1) if the application of sewage sludge ended more than one year before the production of the food commenced; (2) if a labeling requirement is met; or (3) in the case of a food that is generally offered for sale without labeling, if an informative sign is posted near the product.Amends the Egg Products Inspection Act, the Federal Meat Inspection Act, and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to classify specified foods under those Acts as adulterated if sewage sludge was involved in specified ways in their production. Allows exceptions for each food similar to those to be permitted under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to modify the prohibition under a specified Federal regulation on the use of sewage sludge in organic food production under the National Organic Program of the Department of Agriculture.</summary>
</bill>
