<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="1367" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:56-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="3820" sequence="2"/>
  <status datetime="1996-07-25T16:06:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="404013"/>
  <offered datetime="1996-07-25"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute consisted of the text of H.R. 3505, as modified, and sought to provide a voluntary spending limit of $600,000 for the 2-year election cycle; index the limit for future inflation; limit the contributions of large individual donors to $200,000 in an election cycle and limit a candidate to spending not more than $50,000 of their own money, including loans.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute to estalish a voluntary limitation on campaign spending of $600,000,000 in each election cycle (with exceptions made for special elections, a contested primary, and run-off elections.) Candidates who adhere to the voluntary limits would receive discount rates for broadcasting time and postal rates. The amendment would place a limit on PAC contributions to $8,000 from any individual PAC in each election cycle, and limit PACs to $5000 per election. Candidates would be limited to an aggregate of $200,000 from all PACs per election cycle, except in special circumstances. Individual donors would be limited to $200,000 to any single candidate in an election cycle, and candidates would be limited to spending no more than $50,000 of their own money. "Bundling" and "soft money" contributions would be eliminated, except for non-affiliated, independent PACs that do not engage in lobbying activities.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Fazio.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1996-07-25T16:06:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="363">
      <text>On agreeing to the Fazio amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 177 - 243 (Roll no. 363).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
