<bill session="106" type="h" number="3010" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Restraint Safety Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to ensure that individuals enjoy the right to be free from restraint, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1999-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1999-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2000-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="1999-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400508" joined="1999-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2000-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1999-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Corporal punishment"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Elder abuse"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hospices (Terminal care)"/>
    <term name="Hospital patients"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mentally disabled"/>
    <term name="Mortality"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Psychotropic drugs"/>
    <term name="Rights of institutionalized persons"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/1999--Introduced.
Restraint Safety Act of 1999 - Amends part D (Miscellaneous) of title XVIII (Medicare) and of title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to specify Medicare and Medicaid program beneficiaries' rights to freedom from restraint and other abuse while in a psychiatric hospital or other care facility or treatment center. Requires a service provider to report sentinel events (when a program beneficiary under psychiatric care dies unexpectedly or suffers serious injury unrelated to his or her illness or underlying condition) to the appropriate agencies or entities with oversight authority.Allows the imposition of restraints only for the following: (1) to ensure the physical safety of the individual or others in the provider's care or custody; and (2) upon the written order of a physician specifying the duration and circumstances of restraint use (except in emergency circumstances specified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services until such an order could reasonably be obtained).Requires the service provider to investigate the sentinel event reported and the appropriate agencies or entities to review and approve the provider's root cause analysis before reporting on the matter to the Secretary for use in the Sentinel Events Database.Directs the Secretary to establish such Database for use on the Internet, with appropriate privacy safeguards for individuals whose treatment is the subject of a report under this Act.Requires additional reporting in certain cases, including to the following: (1) the Secretary about a provider identified as having a pattern of poor performance; and (2) the State Attorney General or the appropriate State law enforcement agency in sentinel events involving death. Mandates sanctions for failure to report.Bars disclosure or discovery of a root cause analysis in a civil action.</summary>
</bill>
