<bill session="113" type="h" number="1960" updated="2013-07-17T16:03:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-14T13:08:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-14T13:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2014 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2014 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2013-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Tactical Air and Land Forces.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Seapower and Projection Forces.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence, Emerging Threats &amp; Capabilities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 59 - 2.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Armed Services. H. Rept. 113-102.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-07T19:41:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="71">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 71.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11T17:05:00-04:00">
      <text>FILING AUTHORITY - Mr. Wilson (SC) asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to file a supplemental report on the bill H.R. 1960. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Armed Services, H. Rept. 113-102, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11T19:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 256 Reported to House. Resolution provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 1960. Resolution also provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 1256 under a closed rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 256.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3333-3341" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Resolution provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 1960. Resolution also provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 1256 under a closed rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 256 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steve Womack to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1960.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1960 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T03:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 260 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1960. Motion to recommit with or without instructions allowed. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution makes in order only those further amendments printed in part B of this report and amendments en bloc described in Section 3 of this resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T14:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 260 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. McKeon asked unanimous consent that during further consideration of H.R. 1960 pursuant to H. Res. 260, amendments 18, 19, and 20 printed in Part B of House Report 113-108 may be considered out of sequence. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3382-3553" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3382-3519" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1960. Motion to recommit with or without instructions allowed. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution makes in order only those further amendments printed in part B of this report and amendments en bloc described in Section 3 of this resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 260 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lee Terry to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McKeon Part B amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer Part B amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T14:54:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Blumenauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lummis Part B amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T15:07:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lummis amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T15:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pearce Part B amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Coffman (CO) Part B amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Coffman amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Coffman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc amendments #1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T15:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Turner Part B amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rigell Part B amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rigell amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rigell demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McGovern amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McGovern amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Goodlatte amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T16:32:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Goodlatte amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T16:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Radel amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc amendments #2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T18:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McKeon moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1960 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. McKeon asked unanimous consent that during further consideration of H.R. 1960 pursuant to H.Res. 260, amendments 14 and 23 printed in part B of House Report 113-108 may be considered out of sequence. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T18:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3553-3589" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T18:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T18:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Denham amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Turner (OH) amendment No. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T18:33:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Turner (OH) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Larsen (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T18:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc amendments #3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Holt amendment No. 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T19:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Holt amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Holt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T19:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCollum amendment No. 25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T19:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McCollum amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T19:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nolan amendment No. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T19:31:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nolan amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Nolan demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T19:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry (TX) en bloc amendments #4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Larsen (WA) amendment No. 33.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T19:54:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Larsen (WA) amendment No. 33, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Larsen (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T19:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gibson amendment No. 36.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T20:05:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gibson amendment No. 36, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gibson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T20:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Coffman (CO) amendment No. 37.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T20:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Coffman (CO) amendment No. 37, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Coffman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T20:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc amendments #5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T20:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc amendments #6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc amendments #7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T20:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McKeon moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13T20:38:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T09:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3594-3636" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T09:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T09:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walorksi amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T09:23:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Walorski amendment No. 19, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith(WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T09:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment No. 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T09:49:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment No. 20, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T09:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T10:01:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis amendment No. 14, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T10:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T10:14:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis amendment No. 23, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T10:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Van Hollen amendment No. 39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T10:31:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Van Hollen amendment No. 39, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Van Hollen demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T10:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walz amendment No. 53.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T10:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc amendments #8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T10:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 123.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T11:08:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 123, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Blumenauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T11:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeLauro amendment No. 137.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T11:15:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeLauro amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. DeLauro demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T12:39:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1960.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T12:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3633" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T12:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T12:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Duckworth moved to recommit with instructions to Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3633-3635" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3633-3634" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T12:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duckworth motion to recommit with instructions to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to require that for any sexual assault or sex-related offense, the commander refers the charges to the staff judge advocate. If the victim chooses not to pursue the case through the commander, the victim can seek to refer the charges to the Office of the Chief Prosecutor of the armed force of which the accused is a member. Finally, the motion would require any armed force which does not currently have a Chief Prosecutor to appoint one.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T12:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3634" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T12:55:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 194 - 225, 1 Present (Roll no. 243).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3635" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2013-06-14T13:08:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="244" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 315 - 108 (Roll no. 244).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T13:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T13:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1960.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="126">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 126.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS25" subcommittee="Tactical Air and Land Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS28" subcommittee="Seapower and Projection Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS26" subcommittee="Intelligence, Emerging Threats &amp; Capabilities" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS29" subcommittee="Strategic Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="256"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="256"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="hr" number="256"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="260"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1672"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2303"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2344"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1034"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1169"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1197"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Bahrain"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Kuwait"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Romania"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h141"/>
    <amendment number="h142"/>
    <amendment number="h143"/>
    <amendment number="h144"/>
    <amendment number="h145"/>
    <amendment number="h146"/>
    <amendment number="h147"/>
    <amendment number="h148"/>
    <amendment number="h149"/>
    <amendment number="h150"/>
    <amendment number="h151"/>
    <amendment number="h152"/>
    <amendment number="h153"/>
    <amendment number="h154"/>
    <amendment number="h155"/>
    <amendment number="h156"/>
    <amendment number="h157"/>
    <amendment number="h158"/>
    <amendment number="h159"/>
    <amendment number="h160"/>
    <amendment number="h161"/>
    <amendment number="h162"/>
    <amendment number="h163"/>
    <amendment number="h164"/>
    <amendment number="h165"/>
    <amendment number="h166"/>
    <amendment number="h167"/>
    <amendment number="h168"/>
    <amendment number="h169"/>
    <amendment number="h170"/>
    <amendment number="h171"/>
    <amendment number="h172"/>
    <amendment number="h173"/>
    <amendment number="h174"/>
    <amendment number="h175"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/14/2013--Introduced.
National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 - Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Defense (DOD) for FY2014. Authorizes appropriations to DOD for: (1) procurement, including aircraft, missiles, weapons and tracked combat vehicles, ammunition, shipbuilding and conversion, and other procurement; (2) research, development, test, and evaluation; (3) operation and maintenance; (4) active and reserve military personnel; (5) Working Capital Funds; (6) the National Defense Sealift Fund; (7) the Joint Urgent Operational Needs Fund; (8) chemical agents and munitions destruction; (9) drug interdiction and counter-drug activities; (10) the Defense Inspector General; (11) the Defense Health Program; (12) the Armed Forces Retirement Home; (13) chemical demilitarization; (14) the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program; (15) Guard and reserve forces facilities; and (16) base closure and realignment activities. Sets forth provisions or requirements concerning: (1) military personnel policy, including education and training; (2) military pay and allowances; (3) military health care, including TRICARE cost-sharing; (4) acquisition policy and management; (5) DOD organization and management; (6) financial matters; (7) civilian personnel matters; (8) matters relating to foreign nations; (9) military construction; (10) real property and facilities administration; and (11) military land withdrawals. Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2014 for military construction for the Armed Forces and defense agencies.</summary>
</bill>
