<bill session="108" type="h" number="3179" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Anti-Terrorism Intelligence Tools Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen anti-terrorism investigative tools and promote information sharing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="2003-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Official secrets"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2003--Introduced.
Anti-Terrorism Intelligence Tools Improvement Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal criminal code to provide for imprisonment for not more than one year for knowingly violating nondisclosure provisions under the Fair Credit Reporting Act, the Right to Financial Privacy Act, or the National Security Act of 1947, and for imprisonment for not more than five years if the violation is committed with the intent to obstruct an investigation or judicial proceeding. Authorizes the Attorney General, in the case of a refusal to comply with a request for records, a report, or other information made to any person under those Acts, to invoke the aid of any U.S. court with jurisdiction to compel compliance. Amends the Classified Information Procedures Act to require (current law allows) the court to permit the United States to request authorization to delete specified items of classified information from documents to be made available to the defendant through discovery, to substitute a summary of the information for such classified documents, or to substitute a statement admitting relevant facts that the classified information would tend to prove. Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to: (1) include individuals who engage in international terrorism or activities in preparation therefor as agents of foreign powers; and (2) make an exception to specified notification procedures in cases involving surveillance in civil proceedings or other civil matters under the immigration laws.</summary>
</bill>
