<bill session="106" type="hr" number="228" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the peace process in Colombia and calling on the government and all other parties to the current conflict in Colombia to take steps to advance the peace process so as to end the ongoing violence which continues to pose a serious threat to democracy, human rights, and economic and social stability in that nation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1999-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alternative crops"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Cocaine"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Guerrilla warfare"/>
    <term name="Hijacking"/>
    <term name="Hostages"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Missionaries"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/1999--Introduced.
Commends: (1) the Colombian people for their continued demonstration of support for the democratic process as well as for an end to internal conflict; (2) President Andres Pastrana for his commitment to seek an end to the guerilla insurgency and paramilitary violence in Colombia and for his efforts to begin a peace process; and (3) the Colombian Government and military leadership for their initial steps toward removing from the armed forces officers found to be linked to illegal and unacceptable activities of paramilitaries. Condemns the violations of human rights, including murder and kidnappings, that continue in Colombia, particularly the murder by the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) guerrillas of three U.S. citizens, the disappearance of three U.S. missionaries of the New Tribes Mission in territory controlled by FARC, and the recent mass kidnappings and hijackings by the National Liberation Army (ELN) which resulted in two U.S. citizens being taken hostage. Urges: (1) the leaders of FARC and ELN, and the leaders of the paramilitary groups, to end the violence, agree to suspend all kidnappings, release all hostages, renounce their relationships with the narcotics trade, and negotiate a meaningful peace accord with the Government of Colombia; and (2) the Colombian Government to rapidly implement a program to help protect threatened human rights workers. Encourages FARC and the Government of Colombia to agree to the establishment of an international observer group that would monitor the "despeje" zone and report on illegal narcotics activities and human rights abuses in that zone. Urges FARC to demonstrate its renunciation of the narcotics trade by eradicating coca cultivation in 10,000 hectares of that zone and by cooperating with the Government of Colombia in converting those hectares to the cultivation of legal crops. Welcomes the agreement between FARC and the Government of Colombia to create a commission to investigate and provide a final report on the fate of the three U.S. missionaries. Calls upon the international community to play a more active role in helping to resolve the internal conflict in Colombia by encouraging all sides to participate in the peace process. Declares that the House of Representatives reaffirms U.S. support for the peace process, commits the United States to assist the Government of Colombia in finding a peaceful resolution to the internal conflict, continues to support U.S. assistance to help strengthen political stability and economic growth, and continues to cooperate with all segments of Colombian society who demonstrate a clear and unequivocal commitment to combating the drug trade within Colombia.</summary>
</bill>
