<bill session="104" type="h" number="1262" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Water Enforcement and Compliance Improvement Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to improve the enforcement and compliance programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1995-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1995-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1995-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1995-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1995-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="1995-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1995-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="406082" joined="1995-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1995-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1995-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1995-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1995-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1995-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1995-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1995-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1995-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1995-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1995-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1995-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1995-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1995-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1995-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fish inspection"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Nonpoint source pollution"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Shellfish fisheries"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/1995--Introduced.
Clean Water Enforcement and Compliance Improvement Amendments Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require any person subject to the requirements of such Act (currently, owners or operators of point sources) to maintain records, make reports, and allow access to information to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) with respect to carrying out such Act. Directs States to post signs containing information concerning water quality and environmental and health effects at each major point of public access to a body of navigable water that does not meet an applicable water quality standard or that is subject to a fishing ban or consumption restriction due to fish or shellfish contamination. Requires permits issued for discharges to navigable waters (except those issued to municipalities for discharges composed entirely of stormwater) to ensure compliance with public information requirements concerning the discharge and location of discharges of pollutants by the permittee. Provides for the issuance of compliance orders and the imposition of civil, criminal, or administrative penalties for violations of requirements of pretreatment programs. Repeals a provision that treats a single operational upset that leads to simultaneous violations of more than one pollution parameter as a single violation. Raises the ceiling on the amount of administrative penalties allowed to be assessed for violations. Removes provisions that permit State enforcement actions to serve as a bar to Federal enforcement actions. Directs the EPA Administrator to: (1) conduct inspections of facilities operated by significant noncompliers at which violations occurred; and (2) report annually to the Congress and to State Governors on persons classified as significant noncompliers. Requires State pollutant discharge permit programs to include specified inspection, monitoring, and reporting requirements. Prohibits the issuance of permits to significant noncompliers until conditions giving rise to violations have been corrected. Authorizes the Administrator to renew expired State discharge permits under certain conditions. Authorizes citizen suits for past violations of effluent standards or limitations. Establishes the Clean Water Trust Fund. Requires the Administrator to use Fund moneys to carry out inspections and enforcement activities. Makes specified provisions of this Act applicable to cases pending on this Act's enactment date.</summary>
</bill>
