<bill session="105" type="h" number="4252" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to revise the interim payment system for home health care furnished to Medicare beneficiaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="1998-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1998-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="1998-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1998-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1998-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/1998--Introduced.
Amends part D (Miscellaneous Provisions) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 (BBA '97), to revise reasonable cost requirements for the interim system of limited payments for services provided by home health agencies, especially with regard to per beneficiary cost limits and efficiency standards. Amends BBA '97 with regard to the establishment of a prospective payment system (PPS) for such services to provide that if the Secretary of Health and Human Services does not establish such PPS for specified applicable cost reporting periods, the Secretary shall, for such periods, apply applicable limits under Medicare's reasonable cost requirements as they would otherwise be in effect. Repeals the current requirement that, during such a period, existing limits be reduced by 15 percent.</summary>
</bill>
