<bill session="104" type="h" number="3334" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require broadcasters to participate in drug and substance abuse information and education efforts as a part of their public service obligations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1996-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1996-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="411997" joined="1996-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E648"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/1996--Introduced.
Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission, in its review of any application for renewal of a commercial or noncommercial television broadcast license, to consider the extent to which the licensee has participated in efforts to educate and inform the public as to the dangers of drug and substance abuse and appropriate methods for obtaining treatment. Prohibits the Commission from finding that a renewal is consistent with the public interest, convenience, and necessity unless the applicant demonstrates that: (1) the station has broadcast public service announcements concerning drug and substance abuse and treatment during each hour of its broadcasting day; and (2) the duration of such announcements equals not less than five percent of the duration of commercial advertisements during that hour. Requires the Commission to include in its annual reports to the Congress an analysis of broadcasters' progress in meeting the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
