<bill session="108" type="h" number="3297" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-10-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Counterfeit Drug Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish recall authority regarding drugs, to increase criminal penalties for the sale or trade of prescription drugs knowingly caused to be adulterated or misbranded, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2004-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Product counterfeiting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/15/2003--Introduced.
Counterfeit Drug Enforcement Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, upon a finding of reasonable probability that a drug intended for human use would cause serious health consequences or death, to issue an order requiring the appropriate person (including the manufacturers, importers, distributors, or retailers of the drug) to: (1) cease distribution of the drug; (2) notify health professionals of the order and instruct such professionals to cease administering or prescribing the drug; and (3) amend the order to include a recall if necessary. Provides a criminal fine and/or imprisonment for a person who knowingly caused a prescription drug to be adulterated or misbranded and sells or trades the drug, or who purchased or traded for the drug knowing or having reason to know that the drug was knowingly adulterated or misbranded. Provides additional funding for Food and Drug Administration (FDA) inspections and investigations. Modifies provisions pertaining to criminal penalties for committing certain prohibited acts involving food, drugs, devices, or cosmetics to: (1) make a violation punishable by a fine in accordance with Federal criminal law, imprisonment for not more than one year, or both; (2) make a second violation, or a violation committed with intent to defraud or mislead, punishable by a fine in accordance with Federal criminal law, imprisonment for not more than three years, or both; and (3) make a violation of provisions pertaining to prescription drug marketing punishable by a fine in accordance with Federal criminal law, imprisonment for not more than ten years, or both.</summary>
</bill>
