<bill session="104" type="h" number="3434" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Revolving Door Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 207 of title 18, United States Code, to further restrict Federal officers and employees from representing or advising foreign entities after leaving Government service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1996-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1996-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1996-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1996-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1996-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Ex-presidents"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential ethics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/1996--Introduced.
Revolving Door Act of 1996 - Modifies Federal criminal code provisions restricting the activities of former officers, employees, and elected officials of the executive and legislative branches relating to foreign entities. Replaces a ban for one year after leaving office on representing, aiding, or advising a foreign entity before an officer or employee of any U.S. department or agency with intent to influence a decision of such officer in carrying out official duties with: (1) a ten-year restriction on the President, certain senior executive branch personnel, and Members of Congress and officers and employees of the legislative branch knowingly acting as an agent or attorney for, or otherwise representing or advising for compensation (representing), a foreign government or political party if the representation relates directly to a matter in which the United States is a party or has a direct and substantial interest; and (2) a five-year restriction on representing specified foreign persons or organizations if the representation relates directly to a matter in which the United States is a party or has a direct and substantial interest. Imposes penalties upon: (1) former executive branch officers who, within one year after termination of Federal service or employment, knowingly make, with intent to influence, any communication to or appearance before a Member or legislative branch officer or employee on behalf of any person other than the United States or the District of Columbia; and (2) former Members and former employees of the House of Representatives or Senate whose salaries exceeded 120 percent of the minimum rate of basic pay for GS-15 of the General Schedule who, within one year after termination of service, knowingly make such a communication to or appearance before any executive branch officer. Bars such an officer, employee, or Member who is convicted of a felony from making any communication to or appearance before any employee of the House or Senate or any executive branch officer for compensation. Amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act to: (1) exempt from registration requirements specified agents or entities engaged in lobbying activities that have registered under the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995; and (2) add a civil penalty of up to $50,000 for each violation (with respect to false statements and willful omissions) knowingly committed.</summary>
</bill>
