<bill session="105" type="h" number="1488" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Financial Institution Reform and Authorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize United States participation in various international financial institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1997-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="404634" joined="1997-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1997-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held by the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy Prior to Referral.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy to Full Committee (amended) by Voice Vote Prior to Referral.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Special drawing rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/1997--Introduced.
International Financial Institution Reform and Authorization Act of 1997 - Amends the International Development Association Act to authorize appropriations, without fiscal year limitation, for the U.S. contribution to the 11th replenishment of the resources of the International Development Association. Amends the Asian Development Bank Act to authorize the U.S. Governor of the Asian Development Bank to contribute on behalf of the United States a specified amount to the Asian Development Fund. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development Act to authorize the U.S. Governor of the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development to subscribe on behalf of the United States to specified additional shares of the Bank's capital stock. Authorizes appropriations without fiscal year limitation. Amends the Inter-American Development Bank Act to authorize appropriations, without fiscal year limitation, for the U.S. capital subscription to the eighth general increase in the authorized capital stock of the Inter-American Development Bank. Amends the Bretton Woods Agreements Act to authorize the U.S. Governor of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to contribute on behalf of the United States a specified amount to the Interest Subsidy Account of the successor to the Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility of the IMF. Authorizes appropriations without fiscal year limitation. Increases: (1) the amount of loans (equivalent to Special Drawing Rights) the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to make to the IMF; and (2) the authorization of appropriations for such loans.</summary>
</bill>
