<bill session="107" type="hj" number="65" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-09-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Continuing Appropriation FY2002 (First)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 2002, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400439"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T17:34:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. Young of Florida asked unanimous consent that it be in order at any time to consider in the House H.J. Res. 65; that the joint resolution be considered as read when called up; that debate shall continue for not to exceed 1 hour, equally divided and controlled; and that the previous question be consdidered as ordered without intervening motion except one motion to recommit. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T17:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated by previous order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by previous order of the House.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5959-5961" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.J. Res. 65.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T17:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T17:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the joint resolution, the Chair put the question on adoption of H.J. Res. 65 and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Obey objected to the voice vote based upon the absence of a quorum and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the joint resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T18:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5962-5963" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-09-24T18:44:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="350" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 392 - 0 (Roll no. 350).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5959-5960" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2001-09-25" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9780" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-09-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2001-09-25">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2001-09-27">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2001-09-28">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2001-09-28" type="public" number="107-44">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 107-44.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Export-Import Bank of the United States"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Management information systems"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2001--Passed House without amendment.
Makes continuing appropriations for FY 2002.Appropriates amounts for continuing, at the current rate of operations, projects or activities which were conducted in FY 2001 and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority would be available in: (1) the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002; (2) the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002; (3) the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2002; (4) the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2002; (5) the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002; (6) the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2002; (7) the Military Construction Appropriations Act, 2002; (8) the Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002; (9) the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2002; and (10) the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002.Appropriates amounts for continuing, at the current rate of operations, projects or activities which were conducted in FY 2001 and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority was made available under: (1) the Department of Defense Appropriations Act of 2001; (2) the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001; and (3) the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2001.(Sec. 107) Provides funding under this resolution until enactment into law of any covered appropriation or the applicable appropriations Act (without any provision for the covered appropriation) or October 16, 2001, whichever occurs first.(Sec. 113) Continues, until October 16, 2001, certain activities authorized by: (1) the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968; (2) title V (multi-family assisted housing) of the Departments of Veteran Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998; (3) the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (including financing the export of nonlethal defense articles and services whose primary end-use is civilian); (4) the Trade Act of 1974 (adjustment assistance to workers for relief from injury from competition); and (5) the Government Management Reform Act of 1994 (Franchise Fund pilot programs).(Sec. 118) Permits the Library of Congress to temporarily transfer funds to a revolving fund to continue FEDLINK and Federal research program operations at the same rate applicable during FY 2001.(Sec.119) Conditions the availability of $100 million earmarked for international organizations and conferences, and contributions to international organizations, upon certification by the Secretary of State that the United Nations (UN) has taken no action in calendar year 2001 prior to the enactment of this Act to increase funding for any UN program without identifying an offsetting decrease and cause the UN to exceed its 2000-2001 budget.(Sec.120) Requires that fees, charges, and assessments collected under the Investor and Capital Markets Fee Relief Act or other legislation amending specified sections of the Securities Act of 1933 or the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 enacted into law during the period covered by this joint resolution, fees, charges, and assessments collected under be offset against appropriations to the Securities and Exchange Commission.(Sec. 121) Continues the collection and use of maintenance fees authorized by the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act through October 16, 2001. Continues the prohibition against collecting other fees through such date.(Sec. 122) Excludes funds made available under the 2001 Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Recovery from and Response to Terrorist Attacks on the United States from the terms and conditions of this joint resolution.</summary>
</bill>
