<bill session="107" type="hc" number="405" updated="2013-07-14T18:59:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-21T14:28:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-05-21T14:28:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Commemorating the independence of East Timor and expressing the sense of Congress that the President should establish diplomatic relations with East Timor.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">Commemorating the independence of East Timor and commending the President for promptly establishing diplomatic relations with East Timor.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2002-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2002-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400508" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2002-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2002-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2002-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2002-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2739-2745" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 405.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T13:26:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2748" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-05-21T14:28:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="178" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 405 - 1 (Roll no. 178).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2739-2740" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="sc" number="109"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="East Timor"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Refugee children"/>
    <term name="Refugee resettlement"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations economic assistance"/>
    <term name="War crime trials"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in public life"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2002--Passed House amended.
Congratulates and honors the courageous people of East Timor and their leaders. Welcomes East Timor into the community of nations as a sovereign state. Supports the efforts of United Nations and international organizations to support reconstruction and development in East Timor, and of UN and international peacekeeping forces to safeguard East Timor's security, including continuing periodic visits by U.S. military forces.Expresses continued concern over deplorable humanitarian conditions and an environment of intimidation among the East Timorese refugees living in West Timor.Supports prompt, safe, voluntary repatriation and reintegration of East Timorese refugees, in particular those still held in militia-controlled refugee camps in West Timor, especially reunification of East Timorese children separated from their parents through coercion or force.Expresses a commitment to maintaining appropriate restrictions and prohibitions in law on military assistance, training relations, and technical support to the Indonesian Armed Forces.Acknowledges that a United Nations International Commission of Inquiry found in January 2000 that justice is "fundamental for the future social and political stability of East Timor," and remains deeply concerned about the lack of justice in the region.Commends the President for immediately extending to East Timor diplomatic relations afforded to other sovereign nations, including the establishment of an embassy in East Timor.Urges the President and the Secretary of State to: (1) maintain a level of U.S. assistance for East Timor; (2) work to fund in a generous and responsible way East Timor's financing gap in its recurrent and development budgets, coordinating with other donors; (3) focus bilateral assistance for East Timor on the areas of employment creation, job training, rural reconstruction, microenterprise, environmental protection, health care, education, refugee resettlement, reconciliation and conflict resolution, and strengthening the role of women in society; (4) strongly urge the Indonesian Government to step up efforts to disarm and disband all militia, hold them accountable to the rule of law, ensure stability along the border, and promptly reunite East Timorese children separated from their parents through coercion or force; and (5) review thoroughly information from the East Timorese Commission for Reception, Truth, and Reconciliation, and use all diplomatic resources at their disposal to ensure that those officials responsible for crimes against humanity and war crimes against the East Timorese people are held accountable, and that the Indonesian Government fully cooperates with the East Timorese judicial system.</summary>
</bill>
