<bill session="104" type="h" number="3308" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-05T13:55:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-09-05T13:55:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Armed Forces Protection Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">United States Armed Forces Protection Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to limit the placement of United States forces under United Nations operational or tactical control, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406922"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400127" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400547" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="405560" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="406343" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400610" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="410887" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1996-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on National Security, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-05-01">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 47 - 1.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on National Security. H. Rept. 104-642, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on International Relations Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 27, 1996.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on International Relations discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-06-27T16:51:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="321">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 321.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-04T19:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 517 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3308. Measure will be read by section. A specified amendment is in order. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in the report accompanying this resolution, to be considered in the order and manner specified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 517 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 517.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10053-10074" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3308. Measure will be read by section. A specified amendment is in order. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in the report accompanying this resolution, to be considered in the order and manner specified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:53:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 517 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jim Kolbe to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:53:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T12:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 517, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Spence amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T12:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 517, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Bartlett amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T13:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 517, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Schroeder amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T13:32:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T13:33:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T13:33:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-09-05T13:55:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="405" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 299 - 109 (Roll no. 405).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="517"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Croatia"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emblems"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="Macedonia"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1381"/>
    <amendment number="h1382"/>
    <amendment number="h1383"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/5/1996--Passed House amended.
United States Armed Forces Protection Act of 1996 - States certain congressional findings and policy concerning the placement of U.S. armed forces under United Nations (UN) operational or tactical control. Prohibits Department of Defense funds from being obligated or expended for activities of any element of the armed forces that is placed under UN operational or tactical control, unless: (1) the President, at least 15 days before UN control is to become effective (or not later than 48 hours afterwards in an emergency), certifies to the Congress that such action is in the national security interests; or (2) such placement is specifically authorized by law or is part of a North Atlantic Treaty Organization operation. Specifies information to be submitted with the President's certification, including: (1) information on the national security interests to be advanced; (2) the mission, size, and composition of the U.S. forces involved; (3) the command and control relationship of the U.S. forces with the UN command structure and with the U.S. unified command for the region; (4) the exit strategy for, and withdrawal authority of, U.S. forces; and (5) the anticipated monthly incremental cost of U.S. participation and the percentage that such cost represents of the total anticipated monthly incremental costs of all nations expected to participate in the operation. Provides that this Act shall not apply to activities of the armed forces carried out as part of specified ongoing activities of the UN Preventive Deployment Force in Macedonia or the UN Transitional Administration for Eastern Slavonia, Baranja, and Western Sirmium in Croatia. Requires that members of the armed forces be informed of their unit's mission and their chain of command in any operation to which their unit is assigned. Prohibits U.S. military personnel from being required to wear UN insignia except when such insignia is specifically authorized by law with respect to a particular UN operation.</summary>
</bill>
