<bill session="105" type="h" number="1705" updated="2012-11-01T22:48:10-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campaigns in the Sunshine Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require political parties to submit reports to the Federal Election Commission on expenditures of any funds used to influence an election for Federal office and to require reports to the Commission on any independent expenditures which mention a political party or a candidate for election for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400506"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400568" joined="1997-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1997-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="1997-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400329" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1997-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1997-09-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1044)</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1044"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>05/22/1997--Introduced.
Campaigns in the Sunshine Act of 1997 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to make applicable reporting requirements under FECA to any amount (soft money) expended by a political party for the purpose of influencing an election for Federal office. Requires that, in addition to any reports required to be filed by a principal campaign committee in accordance with FECA requirements, any person who first makes independent expenditures with respect to an election in an aggregate amount or value in excess of $1,000 after the deadline for filing a pre-election report shall file a report containing the information described under FECA at the time the person makes independent expenditures in such aggregate amount or value. Defines the term "independent expenditure" for the purposes of the reports requirement. Redefines the requirement for every person (other than a political committee) to report any independent expenditure aggregating $1,000 or more during a specified period before any election to require that the report include the identification of each person who made a contribution to the person filing such report which was in excess of $200 and was made for the purpose of furthering an independent expenditure.</summary>
</bill>
