<bill session="106" type="h" number="1833" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Customs Service Authorization bill</title>
    <title type="popular">FY2000-2001 Customs Service Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Trade Agency Authorizations, Drug Free Borders, and Prevention of On-Line Child Pornography Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Trade Agency Authorizations, Drug Free Borders, and Prevention of On-Line Child Pornography Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Trade Agency Authorizations, Drug Free Borders, and Prevention of On-Line Child Pornography Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Customs Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Customs Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2000 and 2001 for the United States Customs Service for drug interdiction and other operations, for the Office of the United States Trade Representative, for the United States International Trade Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An Act to authorize appropriations for the United States Customs Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400085"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 9 - 6.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-05-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 36 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T19:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 106-161.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-05-24T19:22:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="89">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 89.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crane moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3521-3529" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1833.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T11:42:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-05-25T13:21:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="149" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 410 - 2 (Roll no. 149).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Finance"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Reported to Senate by Senator Roth with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-07-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="218">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 218.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1999-08-05" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10524-10527" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>By Senator Roth from Committee on Finance filed written report. Report No. 106-156.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13526-13528"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Balloons"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Cameras"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf States"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Night work"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Police corruption"/>
    <term name="Police dogs"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Shift systems"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="U.S. International Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Undercover operations"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban crime"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="X-rays"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/1999--Reported to Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Authorization of Appropriations for United States Customs Service for Enhanced Inspection; Trade Facilitation, and Drug Interdiction Title II: Customs Management Title III: Marking Violations Customs Authorization Act of 1999 - Title I: Authorization of Appropriations for United States Customs Service for Enhanced Inspection, Trade Facilitation, and Drug Interdiction - Amends the Customs Procedural Reform and Simplification Act of 1978 to authorize appropriations for FY 2000 and 2001 for the United States Customs Service for: (1) noncommercial and commercial operations; and (2) the air and marine interdiction program. Requires the Commissioner of Customs to submit to specified congressional committees an estimated budget for each fiscal year.(Sec. 101) Establishes within the U.S. Customs Service an Automation Modernization Working Capital Fund to implement a program for modernizing the Customs Service computer systems. Authorizes appropriations. Directs: (1) the Commissioner of Customs to report annually to specified congressional committees regarding the progress made in modernizing the Customs Service computer systems; and (2) the Comptroller General to audit such report and provide the results to the Commissioner and specified congressional committees.(Sec. 102) Earmarks amounts for: (1) the acquisition and deployment of narcotics detection equipment (including maintenance and support of such equipment, training of personnel, and new technologies, and for internal management improvements and textile transshipment enforcement) along the United States-Mexico border, the United States-Canada border, and Florida and Gulf Coast seaports; (2) additional inspectors, canine enforcement officers, special agents, and enhanced investigative resources during peak hours along such borders (including the Bahamas); (3) air and marine drug interdiction operation and maintenance; and (4) agent rotation and elimination of background investigation backlog.(Sec. 106) Requires the Commissioner of Customs, as part of the annual program activity performance plan set forth in the Customs Service budget, to evaluate the benefits with respect to such border activities.(Sec. 107) Directs the President to submit a plan for funding the acquisition and operation by the Customs Service of tethered aerostat radar systems currently operated by the Department of the Air Force and scheduled for replacement in FY 2001. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 108) Directs the Commissioner of Customs to report to specified congressional committees on the intelligence- and information-gathering capabilities and needs of the Customs Service, including recommendations for improving the agency's capabilities.(Sec. 109) Authorizes appropriations for FY 2000 to carry out a program to prevent child pornography-child sexual exploitation established by the Child Cyber-Smuggling Center of the Customs Service. Earmarks a specified amount to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children for the operation of the child pornography cyber tipline of the Center and for increased public awareness of the tipline.Title II: Customs Management - Provides for the appointment of the Commissioner of Customs to a five year term. Requires the Commissioner to have demonstrated ability in management. Changes the basic pay rate of the Commissioner from level IV to level III of the Executive Schedule.(Sec. 202) Directs the Commissioner of Customs to report to specified congressional committees with respect to: (1) the establishment, within the Office of Internal Affairs, of a program of internal compliance designed to enhance the performance of the mission of the Customs Service, including implementation of the Customs Modernization Act; (2) the review of current best practices in internal compliance programs among government agencies and private sector organizations; (3) the Commissioner's recommendations for modifying existing personnel rules to permit more effective management of Customs resources (personnel flexibility) and for improving the ability of the Customs Service to fulfill its mission; (4) the implementation of the personnel allocation model under development in the Customs Service; and (5) Customs Service requirements for counterdrug detection and monitoring of the arrival zones along the southern tier and northern U.S. border.Title III: Marking Violations - Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to revise the civil penalties for violations of country of origin marking requirements with respect to imported articles and containers to make a violator liable for not more than $10,000 for each violation (currently, $100,000 for first violation and $250,000 for second and subsequent violations).</summary>
</bill>
