<bill session="105" type="hc" number="315" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-23T18:12:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-09-23T18:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress condemning the atrocities by Serbian police and military forces against Albanians in Kosova and urging that blocked assets of the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (Serbia and Montenegro) under control of the United States and other governments be used to compensate the Albanians in Kosova for losses suffered through Serbian police and military action.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1998-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1998-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1998-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1593"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-09-10">
      <text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8493-8495, H8506-8507" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T18:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-09-23T18:12:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="456" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 410 - 0, 1 Present (Roll No. 456).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T18:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Albanians"/>
    <term name="Alien property"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International claims"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Montenegro"/>
    <term name="Police brutality"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Serbia"/>
    <term name="Yugoslavia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/1998--Passed House amended.
Condemns the loss of life and the destruction of property in Kosova that is the consequence of the brutal actions of the Serbian police and military forces against the ethnic Albanian population of the province. Expresses the belief of the Congress that the Government of Serbia is primarily responsible and should bear the principal burden of providing compensation for the loss of life and for the costs of rebuilding areas which its forces have devastated. Urges: (1) the President and officials he designates to work with the Congress to draft legislation and regulations which will permit the claims of ethnic Albanians from Kosova who have suffered as a consequence of the actions of Serbian police and military forces in Kosova to be considered, without prejudice to the claims of U.S. nationals, when claims settlement negotiations involving the assets of the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (Serbia and Montenegro), which the United States has blocked or asserted control over, take place; (2) that in drafting such legislation and implementing regulations, special consideration be given to the circumstances of the Government of the Republic of Montenegro and to persons located in Montenegro; and (3) the President and the Secretary of State to urge all other countries to follow a policy which permits ethnic Albanians who have suffered as a consequence of the actions of Serbian police and military forces in Kosova to make claims against the assets of the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia which are in the control of the respective country.</summary>
</bill>
