<bill session="107" type="hr" number="185" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Supporting the implementation of the Good Friday Agreement as the framework for the peaceful settlement of the conflict in Northern Ireland.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2001-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA14" subcommittee="Europe" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Northern Ireland"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2001--Introduced.
Congratulates the people of Northern Ireland for demonstrating their continued support for the peace process, the Good Friday Agreement, and political parties and candidates who support the Agreement.Expresses support for the Prime Minister of the United Kingdom (UK), the Irish Taoiseach, and the leaders of the Northern Ireland political parties who created the opportunity for a negotiated peace. Urges them to implement agreements they endorsed.Encourages: (1) all Agreement signatories to remain supportive of the peace process; (2) the Government of the UK to review concerns expressed about the inadequacies of implementation of the reforms in the report of the Independent Commission on Policing (Patten report) and to submit changes which will assist the process; and (3) the parties which have not appointed members to the policing board to do so.Commends the reported thousands of citizens of Ireland and Northern Ireland who believe in the necessity of police reform and who submitted applications to join the new police service. Stresses the importance of decommissioning weapons held by paramilitary organizations. Calls on all sides to support the functioning of the North/South Ministerial Council.Urges the UK Government to reconsider its use of plastic bullets.Reaffirms the bonds of friendship and cooperation that exist between the United States and the Governments of the UK and the Republic of Ireland and U.S. support for the Agreement and for political parties seeking a strong and lasting peace in Northern Ireland.</summary>
</bill>
