<bill session="104" type="h" number="2186" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ohio &amp; Erie Canal National Heritage Corridor Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Ohio &amp; Erie Canal Corridor National Heritage Corridor in the State of Ohio.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400334"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="403015" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="405560" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400590" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1995-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="410407" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1995-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.4236.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="4236"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1190"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/1995--Introduced.
Ohio &amp; Erie Canal National Heritage Corridor Act of 1995 - Establishes the Ohio &amp; Erie Canal National Heritage Corridor in Ohio. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to establish the Ohio &amp; Erie Canal National Heritage Corridor Advisory Commission to assist Federal, State, and local authorities and the private sector in the preparation and implementation of an integrated Corridor Management Plan (Plan) for the conservation, funding, management, and development of the Corridor. Requires the Commission to submit a recommendation to the Secretary for designation of a management entity for the Corridor. Directs such entity to develop and submit the Plan to the Commission for review. Directs the Commission, after endorsing the plan, to submit it to the Secretary for approval. Requires the entity: (1) in developing and implementing the Plan, to consider the interests of diverse units of government, businesses, private property owners, and nonprofit groups; (2) to conduct public meetings at least quarterly regarding Plan implementation; and (3) to submit annual reports to the Secretary. Directs the Commission to annually review the management entity's proposed expenditures of Federal funds for consistency with the purposes of this Act and the Plan. Sets forth provisions concerning the management entity's: (1) eligibility requirements of legal ability to receive and disburse Federal funds; (2) authorization to receive Federal funding to carry out this Act; (3) disqualification to receive such funds if the Plan is not submitted within the prescribed time; (4) authority to use the funds for purposes of preparing and implementing the Plan; (5) eligibility for financial assistance over three years for operating costs and six years for development costs; and (6) prohibition against using such funds to acquire real property. Continues the designation of the Corridor unless the Secretary: (1) determines that its use, condition, or development is incompatible with the purposes of this Act or that the management entity has not made reasonable and appropriate progress in preparing or implementing the Plan; and (2) notifies the Congress that the Corridor designation should be withdrawn. Authorizes the Secretary, on request of the management entity, to provide technical assistance to units of government, nonprofit organizations, and other persons regarding the Plan and its implementation. Prohibits the Secretary from requiring recipients of such assistance to enact or modify land use restrictions. Authorizes the Superintendent of the Cuyahoga Valley National Recreation Area, on request, to provide to public and private organizations within the Corridor such operational assistance as appropriate to support the implementation of the Plan. Provides that nothing in this Act: (1) modifies any authority of Federal, State, or local governments to regulate any use of land; (2) grants powers of zoning or land use control to the Commission or management entity; (3) affects or authorizes the Commission to interfere with the rights of persons with respect to private property or any local zoning ordinance or land use plan of Ohio or a political subdivision; or (4) diminishes Ohio's authority to manage fish and wildlife. Limits the Federal contribution to the management entity to not more than: (1) 50 percent of the total cost of the entity's annual operating costs attributed to preparation and implementation of the Plan; and (2) 30 percent of the total cost of the entity's annual development costs attributable to the implementation of such Plan. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
