<bill session="104" type="h" number="3860" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Care Consolidation and Investment Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To consolidate and expand Federal child care services to promote self sufficiency and support working families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1996-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1996-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1996-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1996-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="404298" joined="1996-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1996-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1996-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1996-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-07-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1315"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Dual-career families"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/1996--Introduced.
Child Care Consolidation and Investment Act of 1996 - Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to authorize appropriations for FY 1997 through 2001 for child care services for eligible children through the awarding of grants to States. Requires (currently, authorizes) child care and development block grants for States. Decreases from 25 to 20 percent the amount of funds to be reserved by States per fiscal year for activities to improve the quality of child care and to provide before- and after-school and early childhood development services. Directs States to reserve at least 50 percent of grant amounts for child care activities to support low-income working families. Requires State plans to assure that the availability of child care will be coordinated with AFDC requirements and to ensure that the parent of a dependent child is not required to undertake an education, job training or search, or employment requirement unless child care assistance is available. Sets forth a matching requirement for States with respect to amounts that exceed amounts received in FY 1995. Increases from 20 to 50 percent the minimum percentage of reserved amounts States must use to carry out specified activities to improve the quality of child care. Directs the Secretary to establish a child care quality improvement incentive initiative to make funds available to States that demonstrate progress in the implementation of: (1) innovative teacher training programs; or (2) enhanced child care quality standards and licensing and monitoring procedures. Decreases from 75 to 50 percent the minimum percentage of reserved amounts States must use to carry out early child development and before- and after-school services. Requires amounts allotted to States under this Act to include the base amount such States received under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 and under AFDC provisions repealed under this Act. Amends part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) (AFDC) of title IV of the Social Security Act to repeal the AFDC, Job Opportunities and Basic Skills (JOBS) Training program, and transitional child care programs, as well as the at-risk child care program. Repeals the Child Development Assistance Associate Scholarship Assistance Act of 1985, and the authority for State dependent care grants under the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981.</summary>
</bill>
