<bill session="107" type="h" number="5712" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 23, United States Code, to improve roadway safety for motor vehicles, bicycles, and pedestrians and workers in proximity to vehicle traffic.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400542"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-11-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2005-2006"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bicycles"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic signs and signals"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the aged"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/13/2002--Introduced.
Amends Federal highway provisions to include within the definition of "safety improvement project" a project that installs or maintains fluorescent, yellow-green signs at pedestrian or bicycle crossings or school zones.Authorizes the payment from apportioned funds for the entire cost of construction projects involving the maintenance of protective devices at railway-highway crossings. Makes specified sums available for each fiscal year for that purpose.Provides for biennial (currently, annual) reports by each State to the Secretary of Transportation on progress being made to implement the railway-highway crossings program.Requires each State to identify roadway safety improvement needs for hazardous locations, sections, and elements which may constitute a danger to motorists, bicyclists, and pedestrians. Authorizes the Secretary to approve as a project under the hazard elimination program any safety improvement project that reduces the likelihood of crashes involving road departures, intersections, pedestrians, bicycles, older drivers, or construction work zones. Makes funds available for: (1) police assistance for traffic and speed management in construction work zones; or (2) compilation and analysis of data.Directs the Secretary to: (1) transmit to specified congressional committees biennial reports on the results of the hazard elimination program; and (2) issue regulations to decrease the likelihood of worker injury and maintain the free flow of vehicular traffic by requiring workers whose duties place them on or in close proximity to a Federal-aid highway to wear high visibility garments. Authorizes such regulations to require other worker-safety measures.</summary>
</bill>
