<bill session="108" type="hr" number="344" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Syria, Lebanon and Iran should be held accountable for the well-being of abducted Israeli civilian Elchanan Tannenbaum, provide the International Committee of the Red Cross access to Elchanan Tannenbaum, and take all necessary measures to secure the release of Elchanan Tannenbaum.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2003-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2003-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2003-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hostages"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2003--Introduced.
Declares the sense of the House of Representatives that the Governments of Syria, Lebanon, and Iran shall be held responsible for the well-being of Elchanan Tannenbaum, who is being held hostage in Lebanon by the terrorist organization Hizballah. Declares the sense of the House of Representatives that the Governments of Syria, Lebanon, and Iran shall immediately and unconditionally: (1) provide a complete medical accounting of Elchanan Tannenbaum's present state of health to the International Committee of the Red Cross; (3) take all necessary measures to provide the International Committee of the Red Cross with ongoing access to Elchanan Tannenbaum; and (4) take all necessary measures to secure the release of Elchanan Tannenbaum from captivity.</summary>
</bill>
