<bill session="104" type="h" number="808" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for jurisdiction, apprehension, and detention of certain civilians accompanying the Armed Forces outside the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="1995-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House National Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Courts-martial and courts of inquiry"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/1995--Introduced.
Provides that persons serving with, employed by, or accompanying the armed forces outside the United States who engage in conduct which would constitute a criminal offense within the maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States shall be guilty of a like offense against the United States and shall be subject to prosecution and punishment under the Federal criminal code. Exempts such persons who are not nationals of the United States and who were appointed to their positions in the country in which the conduct occurred. Prohibits prosecution for such an offense if a foreign government has prosecuted such person for the conduct, except as may be authorized by specified Federal officials in certain instances. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to designate a person serving in a law enforcement position in a criminal investigative agency of the Department of Defense to apprehend and detain outside the United States any person reasonably believed to have engaged in such an offense. Provides for release of such person to civilian law enforcement authorities of the United States for judicial proceedings. Authorizes such law enforcement designee to deliver to the appropriate authorities of a foreign country an individual alleged to have engaged in such an offense if: (1) the appropriate authorities of such country request such delivery for trial; and (2) such delivery is authorized by a treaty or an agreement to which the United States is a party. Retains any concurrent jurisdiction of military tribunals with respect to offenses of such persons which may be tried by court- martial or otherwise.</summary>
</bill>
