<bill session="104" type="h" number="2127" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-04T01:12:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-08-04T01:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY96, Labor, HHS, Education</title>
    <title type="popular">Education Department FY96 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Health and Human Services FY96 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Labor Department FY96 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of Education Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of Health and Human Services Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of Labor Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Education Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Health and Human Services Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Labor Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and related agencies, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400604"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor - Health and Human Services, and Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings Prior to Referral (Jan 24, 95).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-07-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-07-27T23:09:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against the bill, and against its consideration were reserved.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-27T23:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-209, by Mr. Porter.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-07-27T23:20:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="108">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 108.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01T21:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 208 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2127 with 2 hours and 30 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. The rule, as amended, permits an additional period of 90 minutes of debate prior to consideration of each of the first 3 titles of the bill. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments. The first amendment printed in the report accompanying this resolution shall be considered as pending. The reading of the bill for further amendment shall not proceed until disposition of the amendments printed in part one of the report. Each amendment printed in part 1 shall be debatable for 10 minutes and shall not be subject to further amendment accept as specified. After disposition of the part 1 amendments the bill shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment. It shall be in ...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T11:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Porter asked unanimous consent that, during the consideration of the bill H.R. 2127 pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, the Chairman of the Committee of the Whole may postpone until a time during further consideration in the Committee a request for a recorded vote on any amendment, and that the Chairman may reduce to not less than five minutes the time for voting by electronic device on any postponed question that immediately follows another vote by electronic device without intervening business, provided that the time for voting on the first in any series of questions shall not be less than 15 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T11:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Porter asked unanimous consent that during consideration of H.R. 2127 the following amendments listed may amend portions of the bill not yet read for amendment if offered by the Member designated: the amendment by Mr. Obey No. 36; and amendments en bloc by Ms. Pelosi No. 60, 61, and 62. The time for debate on each amendment and any amendments thereto shall be limited to 40 minutes; the amendment by Mr. Obey No. 36; by Mr. Stokes No. 70, by Ms. Lowey No. 30, by Mr. Kolbe to strike section 509 of the bill; by Mr. Skaggs No. 64; by Mr. Sabo or Mr. Obey proposing to amend title VI of the bill; and by Mr. Solomon No. 116. Except as otherwise specified in H. Res. 208, the time for debate on each other amendment shall be limited to 20 minutes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T11:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Porter further asked unanimous consent that after a motion that the Committee rise has been rejected on a day, the Chairman may only entertain a second motion that day if offered by the Chairman of the Committee on Appropriations or the Majority Leader or their designee. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T12:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 208 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 208.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8194-8268" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 208 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Robert S. Walker to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T12:38:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with two and one-half hours of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Porter amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T15:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Porter amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T15:40:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, as amended, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 90 minutes of additional General Debate on Title I (Department of Labor) provisions of the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Stokes amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Obey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the Obey amendment and announced that by voice vote, the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Bonilla objected to the vote based upon the absence of a quorum. Pursuant to the earlier unanimous consent agreement, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Pelosi amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the Pelosi amendment and announced that by voice vote, the noes had prevailed. Mr. Obey objected to the vote based upon the absence of a quorum. Pursuant to the earlier unanimous consent agreement, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T19:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Crapo amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the Crapo amendment and announced that by voice vote, the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Crapo objected to the vote based upon the absence of a quorum. Pursuant to the earlier unanimous consent agreement, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T20:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Greenwood amendment and the Livingston substitute amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T21:33:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the Livingston substitute amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Livingston requested a recorded vote and, pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, further proceedings were postponed on the Livingston substitute and the underlying Greenwood amendment. The Chair then announced the pending business to be the further consideration of amendments on which recorded votes were previously requested, in the order in which the requests had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T22:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Porter moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T22:24:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02T22:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2127 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T10:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8315-8359, H8363-8417, H8417-8421" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T10:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T10:29:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 90 minutes of debate on title II of the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T12:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with twenty minutes of debate on the Moran amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 90 minutes of debate on title III of the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Goodling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Hastert amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Lowey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Cunningham amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T16:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Hoekstra amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the amendment and announced that by voice vote, the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hoekstra requested a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Kolbe amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Kolbe amendment and announced that by voice vote, the noes had prevailed. Mr. Kolbe requested a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Ganske amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Ganske amendment and announced that by voice vote, the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ganske requested a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Blute amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Blute amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Blute requested a recorded vote and, pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T19:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Skaggs amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T21:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Saxton amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T21:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Solomon amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T22:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Gordon amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T22:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Sanders amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T23:21:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Sanders amendment and announced that by voice vote, the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sanders subsequently requested a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 208, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T23:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Emerson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T23:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Menendez amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T23:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Johnson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T23:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kleczka amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03T23:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement of August 2, 1995, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Ewing amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-04T00:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2127.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-04T00:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-04T00:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-04T00:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-04T00:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit the bill back to the Committee on Appropriations with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-04T00:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-04T00:54:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 188 - 238 (Roll no. 625).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 8/3/1995 H8420" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-08-04T01:12:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="626" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 208 (Roll no. 626).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-08-04T01:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2127.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-04T01:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-13">
      <text>Subcommittee on Labor, HHS, and Education. Approved for full committee consideration with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-09-15">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-09-15">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported to Senate by Senator Specter with amendments. With written report No. 104-145.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-09-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="189">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 189.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-09-28">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14438-14456" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-28">
      <text>Pursuant to the order of September 27, 1995, 60 votes required on the motion to proceed to the consideration of this bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-28">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 54-46. Record Vote No: 471.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14448" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-28">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 54-46. Record Vote No: 472.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14455-14456" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-15">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S18713"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-15">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S18713" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-16">
      <text>Motion to proceed considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S18781-18784" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAP07" subcommittee="Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education" name="House Appropriations"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP07" subcommittee="Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="208"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Abandonment of family"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative responsibility"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Alternative medicine"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces Retirement Home"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arthritis"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Bilingual education"/>
    <term name="Birth control"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Black lung"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Boarder babies"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Busing (School integration)"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cancer research"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Childbirth"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining unit"/>
    <term name="College libraries"/>
    <term name="College sports"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Consumer price indexes"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Deaf"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Dentistry"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Diseases"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Employee-management relations in government"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Eye diseases"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service"/>
    <term name="Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to adult education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to handicapped services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Hearing disorders"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeless children"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Human embryology"/>
    <term name="Human engineering"/>
    <term name="Human genetics"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Impacted area programs"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical libraries"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Meditation"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="National Commission on Libraries and Information Science"/>
    <term name="National Council on Disability"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board"/>
    <term name="National Mediation Board"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Nervous system diseases"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Old age assistance"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace research"/>
    <term name="Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Pension trust guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Physician Payment Review Commission"/>
    <term name="Political activities"/>
    <term name="Prayer in the public schools"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Prospective Payment Assessment Commission"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Public service employment"/>
    <term name="Railroad Retirement Board"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Refugee policy"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of the mentally handicapped"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of the physically handicapped"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Replacement workers"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Runaway children"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School-to-work transition"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soldiers' homes"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Truck drivers"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h711"/>
    <amendment number="h712"/>
    <amendment number="h713"/>
    <amendment number="h714"/>
    <amendment number="h715"/>
    <amendment number="h716"/>
    <amendment number="h717"/>
    <amendment number="h718"/>
    <amendment number="h720"/>
    <amendment number="h721"/>
    <amendment number="h722"/>
    <amendment number="h723"/>
    <amendment number="h724"/>
    <amendment number="h725"/>
    <amendment number="h726"/>
    <amendment number="h727"/>
    <amendment number="h728"/>
    <amendment number="h729"/>
    <amendment number="h730"/>
    <amendment number="h731"/>
    <amendment number="h732"/>
    <amendment number="h733"/>
    <amendment number="h734"/>
    <amendment number="h735"/>
    <amendment number="h736"/>
    <amendment number="h737"/>
    <amendment number="h738"/>
    <amendment number="h739"/>
    <amendment number="h740"/>
    <amendment number="s2809"/>
    <amendment number="s2810"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/15/1995--Reported to Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of Labor Title II: Department of Health and Human Services Title III: Department of Education Title IV: Related Agencies Title V: General Provisions Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996 - Title I: Department of Labor - Department of Labor Appropriations Act, 1996 - Makes appropriations for FY 1996 for agencies within the Department of Labor. Rescinds unobligated advances to the Employment Security Administration account of the Unemployment Trust Fund. Title II: Department of Health and Human Services - Department of Health and Human Services Appropriations Act, 1996 - Makes appropriations for FY 1996 for agencies within the Department of Health and Human Services. Rescinds appropriations made to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for immunization activities. Rescinds existing and makes new appropriations for low income home energy assistance, designating certain of the new appropriations as emergency requirements under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 and making those funds available only on a formal Presidential budget request that designates the request as an emergency requirement under that Act. Provides limitations on the use of appropriated funds. (Sec. 207) Requires a transfer of funds for the security protection of the Secretary of Health and Human Services. (Sec. 210) Cancels a specified amount of budgetary resources available to the Department of Health and Human Services under the heading "National Institutes of Health" for administrative expenses. Title III: Department of Education - Department of Education Appropriations Act, 1996 - Makes appropriations for FY 1996 for agencies and programs within the Department of Education. Sets forth general provisions relating to the use of appropriated funds. (Sec. 301) Prohibits appropriated funds from being used to transport teachers or students in order to: (1) overcome racial imbalance in any school or school system; or (2) carry out a racial desegregation plan. (Sec. 303) Prohibits the use of funds to prevent the implementation of programs of voluntary prayer and meditation in the public schools. Title IV: Related Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY 1996 for the following agencies or programs: (1) Armed Forces Retirement Home; (2) Corporation for National and Community Service; (3) Corporation for Public Broadcasting; (4) Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service; (5) Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission; (6) National Commission on Libraries and Information Science; (7) National Council on Disability; (8) National Education Goals Panel; (9) National Labor Relations Board; (10) National Mediation Board; (11) Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission; (12) Physician Payment Review Commission; (13) Prospective Payment Assessment Commission; (14) Social Security Administration; (15) Railroad Retirement Board; and (16) United States Institute of Peace. Title V: General Provisions - Sets forth provisions on the use of the appropriated funds. (Sec. 505) Prohibits the use of funds to carry out any program of distributing sterile needles for the hypodermic injection of any illegal drug unless the Surgeon General determines that such programs are effective in preventing the spread of HIV and do not encourage the use of illegal drugs. (Sec. 506) Expresses the sense of the Congress that, to the greatest extent practicable, all equipment and products purchased under this Act should be American-made. (Sec. 507) Imposes a disclosure requirement on grantees receiving Federal funds. (Sec. 508) Prohibits the use of funds to perform abortions except to save the life of the mother or where the pregnancy is the result of rape or incest. (Sec. 514) Sets forth limitations on the use of appropriated funds. (Sec. 520) Imposes limitations on the use of funds for cash performance awards.</summary>
</bill>
