<bill session="105" type="h" number="2095" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">China Human Rights and Democracy Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for certain activities regarding the promotion of respect for human rights, the development of democratic government and the development of the rule of law within the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400604"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1997-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400334" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400520" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="410136" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400610" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="1997-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Birth control"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conventional weapons"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Espionage"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Federal incorporation"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International propaganda"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military technology"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nonviolence"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Passive resistance"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific exchanges"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/1997--Introduced.
China Human Rights and Democracy Act of 1997 - Authorizes appropriations for International Broadcasting Activities only for broadcasting to China. Earmarks funds for: (1) capital expenditures for the purchase and construction of transmission facilities; and (2) Radio Free Asia. (Sec. 2) Expresses the sense of the Congress that U.S. international broadcasting through Radio Free Asia and Voice of America should be increased to provide continuous 24-hour broadcasting in multiple languages and dialects, including Mandarin, Cantonese, Tibetan, and Uighur. (Sec. 3) Authorizes appropriations to the National Endowment for Democracy, and directs the Secretary of State to use funds available in the East Asia-Pacific Regional Democracy Fund, to promote democracy, civil society, and the development of the rule of law in China. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to report annually to specified congressional committees on human rights in China, including religious persecution, the development of democratic institutions, and the rule of law. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a Prisoner Information Registry for China; and (2) assign not less than six foreign service officers to the U.S. Embassy and consular offices in China to monitor and report on human rights matters in China. (Sec. 5) Requires specified reports to the Congress on Chinese intelligence activities against U.S. interests and on commercial enterprises affiliated with the Chinese military. (Sec. 6) Expresses the sense of the Congress that U.S. nationals conducting industrial cooperation projects in China should adhere to certain principles. Declares that such nationals should: (1) suspend the use of any merchandise that they have reason to believe was produced by convict or forced labor, and refuse to use forced labor in their projects; (2) seek to ensure that political or religious views, sex, ethnic or national background, or association with dissidents will not prohibit hiring, lead to harassment, demotion, or dismissal of an individual employed in the industrial cooperation project; (3) ensure that methods of production used in the projects do not pose unnecessary danger to workers and the surrounding neighborhoods and environment; (4) strive to establish a private business enterprise when involved in an industrial cooperation project with China or other state entity; (5) discourage any military presence on the premises of projects which involve dual-use technologies; (6) promote freedom of association and assembly among the U.S. national's employees; (7) provide the Department of State with information relevant to its efforts to collect information on prisoners for purposes of the Prisoner Information Registry; (8) discourage or prevent compulsory political indoctrination programs from taking place on project premises; (9) promote freedom of expression of all kinds; and (10) prevent harassment of workers who decide freely the number and spacing of their children, and prohibit compulsory population control activities on the premises of the project. Directs the Secretary to forward a copy of these principles to the member nations of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, and encourage them to promote similar principles. Directs each U.S. national conducting an industrial cooperation project in China to register with the Secretary and indicate whether they agree to implement such principles. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to give preference to U.S. nationals that have adopted such principles when selecting participants for trade missions in China. (Sec. 7) Requires the promotion of cultural, educational, scientific, agricultural, military, legal, political, and artistic exchanges between the United States and China. Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the Speaker of the House and the Majority Leader of the Senate should establish a legislative exchange program with China; and (2) a federally chartered not-for-profit organization should be established to fund exchanges between the United States and China through private donations. (Sec. 8) Prohibits the Secretary from issuing any visa to, and the Attorney General from admitting to the United States, any Chinese national that has been materially involved in: (1) the commission of human rights violations; or (2) the proliferation of conventional or nuclear weapons technology, or other sensitive or dual-use technologies, in contravention of U.S. interests. Provides for waiver of such requirements in the U.S. national interest. (Sec. 9) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Congress, the President, and the Secretary should work with the governments of other countries to establish a Commission on Security and Cooperation in Asia which would be modeled after the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe.</summary>
</bill>
