<bill session="104" type="h" number="590" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, relating to air carrier safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/1995--Introduced.
Amends Federal law to apply certain minimum safety standards uniformly to all air carrier operations, regardless of the seating or payload capacity of the aircraft involved. Authorizes the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to prescribe alternative safety standards for the operation of aircraft of a type: (1) approved for transportation of no more than nine passengers (exclusive of flight crew); (2) approved for transportation of no more than 30 passengers (exclusive of flight crew), if such aircraft is not used for scheduled air transportation; and (3) designed for transportation of no more than 19 passengers (exclusive of flight crew) for which application for design approval was made before February 17, 1987. States that alternative standards of the third kind may be prescribed only for specific areas found necessary because the aircraft's approved design makes compliance with one or more of the uniform standards impossible.</summary>
</bill>
