<bill session="107" type="h" number="5468" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians Land Exchange Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a Federal land exchange for the environmental, educational, and cultural benefit of the American public and the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400398"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400066" joined="2002-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2002-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2002-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian gambling operations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Scenic byways"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2002--Introduced.
Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians Land Exchange Act of 2002 - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to exchange the Ravensford tract, currently in the Great Smoky Mountains National Park, for the Yellow Face tract adjacent to the Waterrock Knob Visitor Center on the Blue Ridge Parkway.Requires the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians (Eastern Band) to deed specified parcels of land to the United States. Requires the deeds for specified lands be held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Eastern Band as part of the Cherokee Indian Reservation.Requires the Secretary to file a legal description of the areas held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Eastern Band.Requires the Director of the National Park Service and the Eastern Band to: (1) enter into government-to-government consultations and develop protocols to review planned construction on the Ravensford tract; and (2) develop mutually agreed upon standards for size, impact, and design of construction consistent with the Eastern Band's need to develop educational facilities and support infrastructure.Authorizes the Director to enter into cooperative agreements with the Eastern Band for the purpose of providing training, management, protection, and preservation of the natural and cultural resources on the Ravensford tract.Requires the Secretary to give first preference of employment for service in the Great Smoky Mountains National Park to qualified members of the Eastern Band.</summary>
</bill>
