<bill session="105" type="h" number="3718" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-19T21:10:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-05-19T21:10:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit the jurisdiction of the Federal courts with respect to prison release orders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400104"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T13:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Coble moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3404-3407, H3461-3462" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Scott objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T21:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-05-19T21:10:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="163" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 352 - 53 (Roll No. 163).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19T21:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Prison overcrowding"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/1998--Introduced.
Amends the Federal judicial code to deny jurisdiction to a Federal court, in a civil action regarding prison conditions, to enter or carry out any order that would result in the release from, or non-admission to, a prison of any person subject to incarceration, detention, or admission because of a felony conviction or a violation of the terms or conditions of parole, probation, pretrial release, or a diversionary program on the basis of prison conditions. Terminates any consent decree that was entered into before this Act's enactment date, that is in effect on the day before such date, and that provides for remedies relating to prison conditions.</summary>
</bill>
