<bill session="104" type="h" number="260" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-19T11:57:00-04:00">PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-09-19T11:57:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Park System Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Park System Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the development of a plan and a management review of the National Park System and to reform the process by which areas are considered for addition to the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1995-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="403864" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1995-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1995-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E46-47"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held. Hearings Printed: H. Hrg. 104-1.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Received from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-05-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 34 - 8.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-06-07T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 104-133.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-06-07T13:12:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="60">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 60.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-09-18T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-18T16:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9083-9097" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-18T16:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-18T17:13:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed until Sept. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-19T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9151" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="1995-09-19T11:57:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="667" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays (2/3 required): 180 - 231 (Roll No. 667).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/1995--Reported to House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: National Park System Plan Title II: New Area Establishment National Park System Reform Act of 1995 - Title I: National Park System Plan - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service (NPS), to prepare and submit to the House Committee on Resources and the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources a National Park System Plan to guide the direction of the System into the next century. Provides that the Plan shall be deemed approved unless the Congress enacts a joint resolution modifying or rejecting it within 180 days. Directs the Secretary to publish in the Federal Register and transmit to the Committees, within 45 days after transmittal of the Plan, the proposed and final criteria to be used by the Department of the Interior in reviewing existing System units. Provides that such criteria shall be the final criteria to be used unless disapproved by a joint resolution of the Congress enacted within 30 legislative days after its receipt. Allows the Secretary to amend such criteria but prohibits the amendments from becoming effective until they have been published in the Federal Register, opened to public comment for at least 30 days, and transmitted to such Committees in final form. Requires the Secretary to: (1) review the existing System to determine whether any units do not conform to the Plan and, if so, to determine whether there are more appropriate alternatives for managing them; and (2) develop a report that contains a list of units where National Park Service management should be modified or terminated (which may not include any area Congress has designated as a national park). Establishes a National Park System Review Commission: (1) to review such report or to develop it if the Secretary fails to develop and transmit it; and (2) within two years after its establishment, to transmit to the Committees a report recommending System units where NPS management should be terminated or modified. Provides that nothing in this Act shall be construed as modifying or terminating any System unit without a subsequent Act of the Congress. Prohibits this limitation from limiting any existing authority of the Secretary. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Secretary to report on the procedures that have been instituted to report to the U.S. Attorney or other appropriate law enforcement officials any intimidation, threats, or acts of violence against Service employees related to their duties. Title II: New Area Establishment - Removes certain reporting requirements concerning additional areas for the National Park System. Directs the Secretary to submit to the Committees an annual list of areas recommended for study for potential inclusion in the System. Bars the initiation of any study of the potential of an area for inclusion in the System after this Act's enactment, except by specific authorization by an Act of the Congress. Requires studies to be completed within three fiscal years of the enactment date of legislation providing for a study. Specifies factors to be considered in such studies and requires such studies to be completed in compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a single office to prepare all new area studies and to implement other functions of this title; and (2) submit with the annual budget submission a list of areas which have been studied previously which contain primarily historical resources and areas which contain primarily natural resources in numerical order of priority for addition to the System.</summary>
</bill>
