<bill session="107" type="h" number="2225" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Election Law Integrity Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit certain election-related activities by foreign nationals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400150"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Decision making in public administration"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Political conventions"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Primaries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2001--Introduced.
Federal Election Law Integrity Act of 2001 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to revise the ban on direct or indirect contributions by a foreign national in connection with any election to a political office, or any primary election, convention, or caucus held to select candidates for such an office. Specifies donations as well as contributions under such ban. Extends the ban to cover contributions or donations (or the promise of them) to any political committee, or any organization or account created or controlled by any U.S. political party or candidate.Makes it unlawful for any person to solicit, accept, or receive any such contribution or donation.Prohibits any person organized under or created by Federal or State law from making any contribution to any candidate for political office, or to any political committee or any organization or account created or controlled by any U.S. political party, unless such contribution or donation is derived solely from funds generated from such person's own business activities in the United States.Prohibits any foreign national from directing, dictating, controlling, or directly or indirectly participating in the decisionmaking process of any person organized under or created by Federal or State law with regard to: (1) any decisionmaking concerning the administration of a political committee; (2) the making of any contributions or expenditures to or on behalf of any candidate for political office; or (3) the making of any contributions, donations, or expenditures to or on behalf of any political committee, or any organization or account created or controlled by any United States political party.</summary>
</bill>
