<bill session="105" type="h" number="1213" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Perkins County Rural Water System Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the construction of the Perkins County Rural Water System and authorize the appropriation of Federal dollars to assist the Perkins County Rural Water System, Inc., a nonprofit corporation, in the planning and construction of the water supply system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-01">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Plumbing"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water rates"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water supply engineering"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/1997--Introduced.
Perkins County Rural Water System Act of 1997 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to make grants for the planning and construction of the Perkins County Rural Water System, Inc. Prohibits the obligation of System construction funds until: (1) Federal environmental compliance requirements have been met; (2) a final System engineering report has been prepared and submitted to the Congress for at least a 90-day period; and (3) a water conservation program has been developed and implemented. Requires the water conservation program to be designed to ensure that System water users will use the best practicable technology and management techniques to conserve water use. Requires the mitigation of fish and wildlife losses during System construction and operation. Directs the Western Area Power Administration to make available, from power produced under the Pick-Sloan Missouri River Basin Program, the capacity and energy required to meet the pumping and incidental operational requirements of the System from May 1 to October 31 of each year. Provides power use conditions. States that this Act does not limit: (1) the authorization for water projects in North and South Dakota under any law; or (2) current water rights. Provides the Federal share (75 percent) of System costs. Authorizes the Secretary to allow the Bureau of Reclamation to provide construction oversight to a specified service area within the System, limiting oversight costs. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
