<bill session="106" type="h" number="4835" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-11-01">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the exchange of land between the Secretary of the Interior and the Director of Central Intelligence at the George Washington Memorial Parkway in McLean, Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-895, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8153-8154" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4835.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-09-26T18:45:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8153" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T18:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10838" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-10-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-24">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-11-01">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-11-01" type="public" number="106-412">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-412.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="3000"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Limited access highways"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2000--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior and the Director of Central Intelligence to exchange specified land within the boundary of the George Washington Memorial Parkway for specified land under the jurisdiction of the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) adjacent to the boundary of the Parkway.Requires the Director to allow access to the property transferred from the National Park Service (NPS) and conveyed by the Secretary to the CIA to the public, to personnel of the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) Turner-Fairbank Highway Research Center as provided for in the FHWA's report of excess, dated May 20, 1971, and to other Federal employees and visitors whose admission to the Research Center is authorized by such Center.Allows the CIA to have the right to close off such transferred property to all persons except the U.S. Park Police, other necessary NPS personnel, and personnel of the Research Center to protect CIA personnel, facilities, or property.Requires the Director to ensure compliance by the CIA with the deed restrictions for the transferred land.Requires compliance by the NPS and the CIA with the terms and conditions of the Interagency Agreement between the NPS and the CIA regarding the exchange and management of the lands discussed in that Agreement.Requires that the land conveyed: (1) to the Secretary be included within the boundary of the Parkway and be administered by the NPS as part of the Parkway; and (2) to the CIA be administered as part of its headquarters building compound.</summary>
</bill>
