<bill session="104" type="h" number="1457" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Social Security Act to provide tax benefits with respect to long-term care insurance contracts that satisfy certain requirements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1995-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1995-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1995-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E846-848"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Accident insurance"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Brain diseases"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Critically ill"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
    <term name="Mentally ill"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Tax Treatment of Long-Term Care Insurance and Services Title II: Federal Standards for Private Long-Term Care Insurance Contracts Title I: Tax Treatment of Long-Term Care Insurance and Services - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for the treatment of qualified long-term care insurance or plans as accident and health insurance or plans. Revises the computation of reserves for purposes of determining insurance company income. Prohibits provision of long-term care insurance under cafeteria plans. Includes in an employee's gross income employer-provided coverage for long-term care services to the extent such coverage is provided by a flexible spending arrangement. Makes inapplicable, with respect to coverage under a long-term care insurance contract, the excise tax imposed on group health plans for failure to provide continuation coverage. Makes amounts paid to relatives for long-term care services (unless they are licensed professionals with respect to such services) ineligible for the income tax deduction for medical expenses. (Sec. 103) Includes amounts paid for qualified long-term care services as medical expenses deductible from gross income. (Sec. 104) Provides for nonrecognition of gain on the exchange of a life insurance contract or an endowment or annuity contract for a long-term care insurance contract. (Sec. 105) Excludes from gross income certain amounts withdrawn from individual retirement accounts and certain employer cash or deferred arrangements to pay long-term care premiums. (Sec. 106) Excludes from gross income long-term care benefits received by terminally ill individuals. Excludes such benefits received by chronically ill individuals above a certain amount. (Sec. 107) Requires returns to be made by persons who pay long-term care benefits and statements to be supplied to persons with respect to whom information is provided. Title II: Federal Standards for Private Long-Term Care Insurance Contracts - Amends the Social Security Act to add a new title XXI, establishing Federal standards for long-term care insurance contracts. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to review and approve State programs that certify compliance with these standards. Requires the Secretary to promulgate regulations, in consultation with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC) to standardize long-term care insurance contracts and facilitate the provision of consumer information regarding public and private long-term care coverage. Requires insurers to use in contracts uniform terminology, definitions, and formats and to furnish an outline of coverage for each contract that includes at a minimum: (1) a description of benefits and exclusions; (2) conditions for cancellation; (3) a premium statement; and (4) a cost-value comparison. Prohibits contracts from imposing certain conditions on benefits. Prohibits certain limits on benefits for home care, community-based, or nursing facility services. Requires a contract to provide for treatment of mental impairments (including Alzheimer's disease) and HIV infection or AIDS that is not different from the treatment of any other medical condition for purposes of determining thresholds or amounts of benefits. Requires the Secretary, in consultation with NAIC, to promulgate regulations regarding: (1) inflation adjustments of benefits; (2) nonforfeiture benefits; and (3) procedures for renewal, replacement, conversion, and cancellation of contracts.</summary>
</bill>
