<bill session="106" type="h" number="2390" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Smart Classrooms Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to create small, manageable, accountable classrooms with qualified teachers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400520" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1999-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="1999-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-30">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-30">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Bilingual education"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Class size"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to territories"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leadership"/>
    <term name="Learning"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority teachers"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Parent-teacher relationships"/>
    <term name="Pension portability"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="School administrators"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School principals"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State aid to education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teachers colleges"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="World Wide Web"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/1999--Introduced.
Smart Classrooms Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to revise and rename title II as Smart Classrooms (replacing the current title II Dwight D. Eisenhower Professional Development Program).(Sec. 2) Sets forth a new title II part A Qualified Teachers in Every Classroom program of grants to improve the quality of teaching and learning.Authorizes appropriations for State and Local Activities and National Activities for the Improvement of Teaching and School Leadership.Directs the Secretary of Education to make State and Local Activities grants to States according to certain hold-harmless provisions and allotment formulas.Requires States to distribute such grant funds as follows: (1) 92 percent for subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) according to specified formulas, with 20 percent of that LEA subgrant total amount reserved for competitive subgrants; (2) at least two percent for competitive subgrants to eligible partnerships; and (3) up to six percent for authorized State activities.Sets forth requirements for LEA applications for formula subgrants and for competitive subgrants.Requires LEAs to use all funds from such subgrants, up to a specified amount, for professional development activities in mathematics and science, in an amount at least equal to that under the current Eisenhower Program (unless given a State waiver). Allows LEA use of such funds for interdisciplinary activities that focus on more than one core academic subject if those activities focus predominantly on improving instruction in mathematics or science. Requires that any use of such funds for professional development, when it is in areas other than mathematics or science, be in core academic subjects.Requires LEAs receiving subgrants to: (1) report annually to SEAs on activities funded by subgrants; and (2) provide parents information regarding the professional qualifications of students' classroom teachers.Sets forth requirements for SEA technical assistance to LEAs, corrective actions, and limitations on use of funds.Sets forth certain national activities for the improvement of teaching and school leadership. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out such activities through grants to, and contracts and agreements with, various entities. Includes among such activities support for: (1) the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards; (2) recruitment and retention of fully qualified teachers and principals in high-poverty LEAs and low-performing LEAs; and (3) improvement of teaching and school leadership in the Nation's schools.Authorizes the Secretary to reserve a specified amount to make competitive grants for professional development for principals as leaders of school reform to eligible partnerships of institutions of higher education (IHEs), LEAS, and other entities.Authorizes the Secretary to reserve a specified amount to make competitive grants for school technology centers to eligible partnerships of IHEs, technology-deficient LEAS, technology-proficient LEAs, and other entities.Authorizes the Secretary to make a grant or contract to continue the Eisenhower National Clearinghouse for Mathematics and Science Education.Directs the Secretary to gather and disseminate information related to comprehensive, research-based professional development.Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to establish or expand elementary and secondary school counseling programs.Provides for a program for transition of career-changing professionals to teaching and for the Troops-to-Teachers Program. Authorizes the Secretary to use specified funds for a program to recruit qualified math and science teachers for high-need school systems, following the model of the Troops-to-Teachers teacher placement program. Authorizes program grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to higher education institutions and public and private nonprofit entities. Authorizes continuation of the Troops-to-Teachers Program under specified conditions. Authorizes appropriations.Establishes a class-size reduction program to help States and LEAs recruit, train, and hire 100,000 additional teachers over a seven-year period in order to: (1) reduce class sizes nationally, in grades one through three, to an average of 18 students per classroom; and (2) improve teaching in the early grades so that all students can learn to read independently and well by the end of the third grade. Authorizes appropriations.Redesignates as part D the Professional Development Demonstration Project (currently part C).Extends the authorization of appropriations for the National Writing Project (NWP).Provides for sabbatical leave for professional development. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to SEAs and LEAs to pay one-half of amount of the salary that otherwise would be earned by an eligible teacher who completes a course of study during a sabbatical term. Authorizes appropriations.Prescribes program performance indicators.(Sec. 3) Extends the authorization of appropriations for the Reading Excellence Act (REA) program under ESEA.</summary>
</bill>
