<bill session="105" type="h" number="3330" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit discrimination and preferential treatment on the basis of race, sex, color, national origin, or ethnicity in connection with admission to an institution of higher education participating in any program authorized under the Higher Education Act of 1965.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409228"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Affirmative action programs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in education"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Ethnic groups"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in education"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/1998--Introduced.
Anti-Discrimination in College Admissions Act of 1998 - Prohibits discrimination and preferential treatment on the basis of race, sex, color, national origin, or ethnicity in connection with admission to an institution of higher education participating in any program authorized under the Higher Education Act of 1965. Declares that such prohibition does not prohibit or limit any effort by an institution of higher education to encourage and recruit qualified women and minorities to seek admission to such institution if such recruitment or encouragement does not involve granting preferential treatment, in selecting any person for admission, that is based in whole or in part on race, sex, color, ethnicity, or national origin.</summary>
</bill>
