<bill session="104" type="h" number="836" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Metropolitan Washington Airports Act Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Metropolitan Washington Airports Act of 1986 to provide for reorganization of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority and for local review of proposed actions of the Airports Authority affecting aircraft noise.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E279-280"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-09">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Aviation Prior to Referral.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-01">
      <text>See H.R.1036.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1036"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="362"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="362"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation policy"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan politics and government"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/1995--Introduced.
Metropolitan Washington Airports Act Amendments of 1995 - Amends the Metropolitan Washington Airports Act of 1986 to revise congressional findings with respect to the two federally owned airports in the Washington metropolitan area to declare a perceived declining limited need for a Federal role in the management of these airports and increasing need for local planning and management on a metropolitan statistical area basis. (Sec. 3) Revises the composition of the Board of Directors for the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority. Repeals the mandate for and authority of a Board of Review of the Airports Authority, thus abolishing it. Prohibits any proposed action of the Board of Directors which could result in a change in the impact of aircraft noise in the vicinity of a Metropolitan Washington Airport unless, at least 60 days before the action is to take effect, it: (1) notifies the Committee on Noise Abatement at National and Dulles Airports of the Washington Council of Governments of the action to allow them an opportunity to review, and submit comments on, such action; and (2) submits to such committee a response to any committee comment with respect to such action. (Sec. 4) Requires persons appointed as members of the Board upon the enactment of this Act to continue to serve until their original terms expire. Provides for the appointment of persons to fill vacancies on the Board.</summary>
</bill>
