<bill session="105" type="h" number="4576" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 106 of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act and subpart 1 of part B of title IV of the Social Security Act to require States receiving funds under such provisions to have in effect a State law providing for a criminal penalty on an individual who fails to report having knowledge of another individual's commission of a crime of violence or a sex crime against a person under the age of 18.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/1998--Introduced.
Amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act and title IV (Temporary Assistance to Needy Families) (TANF) of the Social Security Act to require States receiving funds under such Acts to have in effect a State law providing for a criminal penalty on an individual who, having knowledge of another individual's commission of a crime of violence or a sex crime against a person under age 18, fails to report such crime to an appropriate State authority.</summary>
</bill>
