<bill session="104" type="h" number="3005" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-10-11">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securities Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Capital Markets Deregulation and Liberalization Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Investment Company Act Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Securities Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Capital Markets Deregulation and Liberalization Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Investment Company Act Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Securities Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Capital Markets Deregulation and Liberalization Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Investment Company Act Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Securities and Exchange Commission Authorization Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Securities Investment Promotion Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Investment Advisers Supervision Coordination Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Investment Company Amendments Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">National Securities Markets Improvement Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Capital Markets Efficiency Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Investment Advisers Supervision Coordination Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Investment Company Act Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Securities and Exchange Commission Authorization Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal securities laws in order to promote efficiency and capital formation in the financial markets, and to amend the Investment Company Act of 1940 to promote more efficient management of mutual funds, protect investors, and provide more effective and less burdensome regulation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404068"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-07">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 25 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-05-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-17T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Commerce. H. Rept. 104-622.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-06-17T14:30:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="310">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 310.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18T14:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bliley moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18T14:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6436-6449" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18T14:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-19T11:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6528" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-06-19T11:56:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="249" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays (2/3 required): 407 - 8, 1 Present  (Roll No. 249).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-06-19T11:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7212-7216" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 1815.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1996-06-27" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 1815 with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment asks for a conference, appoints conferees D'Amato; Gramm; Bennett; Sarbanes; Dodd.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7216" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T18:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bliley asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8330" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Bliley, Fields (TX), Oxley, Tauzin, Schaefer, Deal, Frisa, White, Dingell, Markey, Boucher, Gordon, Furse, and Klink.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-24T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 104-864 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12037-12047" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bliley moved to suspend the rules and agree to the conference report, H. Rept. 104-864.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28T20:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28T20:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28T20:35:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the conference report Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12047-12051" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-30">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:SENATE" datetime="1996-10-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12093-12095" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1996-10-01">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1996-10-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-10-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-10-11">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-10-11" type="public" number="104-290">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-290.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="104" type="s" number="1815"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1815"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="104" type="s" number="1815"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Automation"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Capital formation"/>
    <term name="Churches"/>
    <term name="Clergy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Corporate management"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign news"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Investment advisers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Margins (Security trading)"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Press"/>
    <term name="Press conferences"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Program trading (Securities)"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Reporters and reporting"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Stock exchanges"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stockholders' voting"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Swaps (Finance)"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Tender offers"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1996--Conference report filed in House.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Capital Markets Title II: Investment Company Act Amendments Title III: Investment Advisers Supervision Coordination Act Title IV: Securities and Exchange Commission Authorization Title V: Reducing the Cost of Saving and Investment National Securities Markets Improvement Act of 1996 - Title I: Capital Markets - Capital Markets Efficiency Act of 1996 - Amends the Securities Act of 1933 to preempt State regulation of "covered securities," including: (1) nationally traded securities and investment company securities subject to Federal registration requirements; (2) securities transactions with certain "qualified purchasers"; (3) securities offered or sold to qualified purchasers; and (4) certain securities whose offer or sale is exempt from registration and report-filing requirements. (Sec. 102) Retains State investigation and enforcement authority with respect to: (1) securities fraud or deceit; and (2) certain notice filings and fee requirements. Allows continued State collection of filing and registration fees as in effect before enactment of this Act, until State law or regulation adopted after enactment of this Act provides otherwise. Provides a three-year period after enactment of this Act during which a State securities commission may require the registration of securities whose issuer refuses to pay such fees. Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to study and report to the Congress on the extent to which uniformity of State regulatory requirements for securities has been achieved for non-covered securities. (Sec. 103) Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to preempt State law with respect to capital, margin, recordkeeping, bonding, and reporting requirements. (Sec. 104) Exempts certain national securities exchange members, brokers, and dealers from Federal margin requirements. Repeals the borrowing and lending restrictions imposed upon members, brokers, and dealers of a national securities exchange. (Sec. 105) Amends the Securities Act of 1933 and the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to grant the SEC general exemptive authority regarding registration requirements (but not authority to exempt persons, securities, transactions, or classes of these, from government securities or government securities broker, dealer, and associated person requirements, rules, and regulations). (Sec. 106) Amends specified securities laws to direct the SEC to consider whether an action will promote efficiency, competition, and capital formation whenever it is required to consider the impact of an action upon investor protection pursuant to a rulemaking function. (Sec. 107) Prescribes guidelines for the SEC to examine and report to the Congress on proposals for the privatization of the EDGAR system. (Sec. 108) Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to mandate that the SEC and certain self-regulatory organizations ("examining authorities") coordinate their examination functions according to prescribed guidelines in order to eliminate duplication in the examination process. Prescribes general requirements for confidentiality of information as well as appropriate disclosure to the Congress or a Federal agency, or in compliance with a Federal court order. (Sec. 109) Directs the SEC to adopt rules under the Securities Act of 1933 concerning the registration status of foreign press conferences and foreign press releases by persons engaged in securities transactions. Title II: Investment Company Act Amendments - Investment Company Act Amendments of 1996 - Amends the Investment Company Act of 1940 to exempt from certain acquisition prohibitions the securities of a registered open-end investment company (or a registered unit investment trust) acquired by another such company belonging to the same group of investment companies if specified circumstances apply. (Sec. 203) Revises requirements for the amendment of registration statements under the Securities Act of 1933 relating to securities issued by face-amount certificate companies, open-end management companies, or unit investment trusts. Repeals provisions for an increase in the number of securities specified in a registration, and deems any such registration to be for an indefinite number of securities. Prescribes formulae for the determination of registration fees, including interest due on late payments. (Sec. 204) Directs the SEC to permit the use of a prospectus containing substantive information not included in the prospectus specified in the Securities Act, but which shall be deemed permitted under such Act. (Sec. 205) Prescribes guidelines for the sale of variable insurance contracts. (Sec. 206) Repeals the requirement that a registered investment company file quarterly or semi-annual reports with the SEC. Requires the SEC to take specified steps to avoid unnecessary reporting and minimize the compliance burdens upon registered investment companies and their affiliated persons when exercising its authority to require the filing of information on a basis more frequently than semi-annually, and in the maintenance and preservation of requisite records. (Sec. 207) Revises the guidelines for: (1) the maintenance and preservation of investment company records for the SEC; and (2) annual reports to the SEC and shareholders. (Sec. 208) Revises the strictures on deceptive or misleading investment company names to declare unlawful the adoption of a name which is materially deceptive or misleading (the current standard is "deceptive or misleading"). Repeals the SEC's authority to bring an action in a U.S. district court for injunctive relief against a violator of such prohibition. (Sec. 209) Modifies the guidelines that exempt investment companies from the Act, adding market intermediaries (or "swap dealers") to the exempt list. Instructs the SEC to prescribe rules: (1) implementing such modified guidelines; and (2) permitting ownership by knowledgeable employees of an issuer of the securities without loss of the issuer's statutory exception from treatment as an investment company. (Sec. 210) Authorizes the SEC to provide exemptions from certain investment advisory performance fee contract restrictions to the extent that an exemption relates to a contract with any person that the SEC determines does not need the statutory protections. Title III: Investment Advisers Supervision Coordination Act - Investment Advisers Supervision Coordination Act - Authorizes additional appropriations to the SEC for FY 1997 and 1998 to enforce the Investment Advisers Act of 1940. (Sec. 303) Amends the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to exempt from SEC registration requirements investment advisers subject to a State securities regulator, unless they: (1) manage at least $25 million in assets; and (2) serve as advisers to certain federally registered investment companies. Exempts from State regulation advisers subject to SEC regulation, or excepted from the SEC definition of investment adviser. Permits States, in such cases, to: (1) require the filing of documents for notice purposes; and (2) investigate fraud or deceit and bring enforcement actions. (Sec. 304) Prohibits the enforcement of any State law or regulation that sets recordkeeping or capital and bond requirements in addition to those of the State in which an adviser maintains its principal place of business and is in compliance with applicable requirements. Exempts from State registration, licensing, or qualification requirements certain investment advisers who: (1) do not have a place of business located within the State; and (2) have had fewer than six clients who are residents of that State during the preceding 12-month period. (Sec. 305) Directs the SEC to restrict the activities of investment advisers convicted of certain felonies (including convictions of a substantially equivalent crime by a foreign court). (Sec. 306) Directs the SEC to: (1) provide for the establishment and maintenance of a readily accessible telephonic or other electronic process to receive inquiries regarding disciplinary actions and proceedings involving investment advisers; and (2) promptly respond to such inquiries. (Sec. 307) Declares that nothing in this title prohibits a State securities commission (or similar agency) from requiring the filing of any documents filed with the SEC pursuant to securities laws solely for notice purposes, together with consent to service of process and any required fee. Allows continued State collection of filing and registration fees as in effect before enactment of this Act, until State law or regulation adopted after enactment of this Act provides otherwise. Provides a three-year period after enactment of this Act during which a State securities commission may require the registration of securities whose issuer refuses to pay such fees. Title IV: Securities and Exchange Commission Authorization - Securities and Exchange Commission Authorization Act of 1996 - Authorizes additional appropriations for the SEC for FY 1997. (Sec. 404) Amends the Securities Act of 1933 to require the SEC to collect securities registration fees that are designed to recover the costs to the Government of the securities registration process, and related costs, including enforcement activities, policy and rulemaking activities, administration, legal services, and international regulatory activities. States that the registration fee shall be the sum of a general revenue fee and an offsetting collection fee. Sets the general revenue fee at $200 for each $1 million of the maximum aggregate price at which the securities in question are sold (reduced to $67 per $1 million beginning FY 2007). Schedules the offsetting collection rate for each $1 million of the maximum aggregate sales price of the securities in question in declining specified levels from $95 in FY 1998 to $5 in FY 2005 and zero in each succeeding fiscal year. Declares: (1) that no offsetting collection fees shall be collected for any fiscal year except to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts; and (2) that such fees collected during any fiscal year shall be deposited and credited as offsetting collections in accordance with appropriations Acts. States that, if on the first day of a fiscal year a regular appropriation to the SEC has not been enacted, the SEC shall continue to collect offsetting collections fees at the preceding fiscal year rate, until such regular appropriation is enacted. Requires that such rates be applied pro rata to amounts and balances under $1 million. (Sec. 405) Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to revise annual transaction fees that national securities exchanges must pay the SEC. Requires the SEC to collect transaction fees designed to recover the costs to the Government of the supervision and regulation of securities markets and securities professionals, and related costs. Requires every national securities exchange to pay the SEC an annual exchange-traded securities fee at a rate of one three-hundredth of one percent (reduced in FY 2007 to one eight-hundredth of the aggregate dollar amount of sales of securities (other than bonds, debentures, and other evidences of indebtedness) transacted on such exchange. Eliminates specific reference to registered brokers and dealers. Requires every national securities association to pay the SEC an annual off-exchange-trade fee at a rate of one three-hundredth of one percent of the aggregate dollar amount of sales (reduced in FY 2007 to one eight-hundredth of one percent) transacted by or through any member of such association otherwise than on a national securities exchange of securities registered on such an exchange (other than bonds, debentures, and other evidences of indebtedness). Requires every national securities association to pay the SEC an annual fee for off-exchange-trades of last-sale-reported securities at one three-hundredth of one percent of the aggregate dollar amount of sales transacted by or through any member of such association otherwise than on a national securities exchange of securities (other than bonds, debentures, and other evidences of indebtedness), subject to prompt last sale reporting under SEC rules or the rules of a registered national securities association. Declares that no offsetting collection fees shall be collected for any fiscal year except to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts. States that any such fees collected during any fiscal year, except in excess of certain levels, shall be deposited and credited as offsetting collections to the account providing appropriations to the SEC. States that, if on the first day of a fiscal year a regular appropriation to the SEC has not been enacted, the SEC shall continue to collect fees for off-exchange-trades of last-sale-reported securities (as offsetting collections) at the preceding fiscal year rate, until such regular appropriation is enacted. Sets forth annual due dates for all fees. Requires annual publication of fee rates in the Federal Register. (Sec. 406) Authorizes the SEC to specify the time that fee payments shall be determined and paid relative to the filing with the SEC of any statement or document. (Sec. 407) Declares the sense of the Congress that in order to maintain the competitiveness of U.S. securities markets relative to foreign markets, no fee should be assessed on transactions involving portfolios of equity securities taking place at times of day characterized by low volume and during non-traditional trading hours. Title V: Reducing the Cost of Saving and Investment - Exempts from the purview of the Investment Company Act of 1940 specified companies not engaged in the business of issuing redeemable securities, but whose financial or managerial assistance operations are subject to State regulation, if their activities are limited to the promotion of economic, business, or industrial development through the provision of such assistance to certain enterprises. (Sec. 502) Increases from $100,000 to $10 million the maximum size of closed-end investment companies exempt from the purview of the Act. (Sec. 503) Redefines: (1) "eligible portfolio company" to include maximum total assets of $4 million, and maximum capital and surplus of $2 million; and (2) "business development company" to provide that it need not make available significant managerial assistance to specified companies. (Sec. 505) Revises guidelines governing business development companies, including: (1) acquisitions of assets; (2) capital structure; and (3) filing of written statements. (Sec. 508) Amends the Investment Company Act of 1940 to exempt certain church employee pension plans from its definition of investment company (thus removing such plans from its purview). Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to mandate disclosure to church plan participants that: (1) such plans are not subject to Federal or State regulatory oversight; and (2) plan participants and beneficiaries will therefore not be afforded the protections concomitant with such oversight. (Sec. 509) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the SEC should present a status report to the Congress regarding: (1) the development of international accounting standards; and (2) the outlook for completion of such standards for offerings and listings by foreign corporations in U.S. markets. (Sec. 510) Directs the SEC to study and report to the Congress on: (1) the impact of technological advances and on-line information systems upon securities markets operations (including steps taken by the SEC to facilitate electronic delivery of prospectuses to investors); (2) shareholder proposals and access to proxy statements; (3) the impact of "preferencing" upon investors and the national market system; and (4) the impact of disparate State licensing requirements on associated persons of registered brokers or dealers and methods for States to attain uniformity in such requirements.</summary>
</bill>
