<bill session="106" type="h" number="3619" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bryan's Law</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to notify parents concerning missing person reports about their children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Missing children"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2000--Introduced.
Bryan's Law - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require institutions of higher education, if they participate in any program under title IV (Student Assistance) of ESEA, to notify parents concerning missing person reports about their children.Requires each such institution, after its campus police or security authority receives a report that a resident student younger than age 21 is missing, to make a preliminary investigation and if such authority cannot verify that the student is safe within 24 hours of receiving the report: (1) notify the student's parents, or if appropriate, any other individual listed as an emergency contact person for the student in its records, and the local police agency; and (2) cooperate with the local police agency regarding the investigation.Authorizes the Secretary of Education to waive such requirements upon the request of a State that has enacted a law with similar requirements.Declares that nothing in this Act may be construed to: (1) create a cause of action against any institution of higher education or its employees for any civil liability; or (2) establish any standard of care.</summary>
</bill>
