<bill session="107" type="h" number="5498" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To convey to the Board of Trustees of the California State University the balance of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration property known as the Tiburon Laboratory, located in Tiburon, California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2002-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01">
      <text>Rereferred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Re-Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Estuarine ecology"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="School boards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2002--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Commerce to convey to the Board of Trustees of the California State University all right, title, and interest of the United States in the balance of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration property known as the Tiburon Laboratory, located in Tiburon, California.Permits the property conveyed only to be used for certain purposes, including to enhance estaurine scientific research and estuary activities within San Francisco Bay.Retains for the United States a certain building and related holdings on the grounds of Tiburon Laboratory, as well as other rights, including rights-of-way to access the retained property.Permits the Secretary and the Board to enter into negotiations to substitute another building of equal value for the Secretary to retain. Assigns certain of the costs for repair, removal, or moving of facilities and equipment under this Act to the Board and certain costs to the Secretary.Directs the Board to remediate or pay the cost of remediating all hazardous or toxic substance contamination found on the property to be conveyed. Requires the Secretary to remediate all hazardous or toxic substance contamination occurring as a direct result of work on the facilities and equipment retained by the Secretary.Specifies conditions for the Secretary to follow if occupancy on the retained property is terminated.</summary>
</bill>
