<bill session="105" type="h" number="4709" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Beneficiary Notification Rights Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require a health insurance issuer to notify all participants and beneficiaries if a group health plan fails to pay premiums necessary to maintain coverage, and provide a conversion option for such participants and beneficiaries if the plan is terminated.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400509"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="1998-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1998-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1998-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400439" joined="1998-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1998--Introduced.
Beneficiary Notification Rights Act of 1998 - Amends the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Internal Revenue Code to require a health insurance issuer intending to terminate coverage or allow a policy to lapse because a group health plan failed to pay premiums necessary to maintain coverage, to: (1) notify all participants and beneficiaries of such situation; and (2) if such plan is terminated, provide all participants and beneficiaries with the option of enrollment under a conversion health plan.</summary>
</bill>
