<bill session="106" type="h" number="4734" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Deployment Health Research Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a National Center for Military Deployment Health Research to provide an independent means for the conduct and coordination of research into issues relating to the deployment of members of the Armed Forces overseas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2000-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2000-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to nursing education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: National Center for Military Deployment Health Research Title II: Centers for Research on Post-Deployment Illnesses in Department of Veterans Affairs Military Deployment Health Research Act of 2000 - Title I: National Center for Military Deployment Health Research - Establishes the National Center for Military Deployment Health Research to coordinate and conduct private and public research on deployment-related health issues of members of the armed forces, veterans, and their families. Requires the Center to report to the Military and Veterans Health Coordinating Board, established by prior presidential directive. Requires the Research Working Group of such Board to be disestablished, and their functions assumed by the Center. Establishes a Center Governing Board. Requires the Center's research activities to include Federal research programs as well as Center-initiated research. Requires an annual Center activities report from the Governing Board to Congress.Title II: Centers for Research on Post-Deployment Illnesses in Department of Veterans Affairs - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish and operate centers for research, education, and clinical activities related to post-deployment illnesses, designating such centers as National Centers for Military Post-Deployment Illness Research. Defines a "post-deployment illness" as one having an association or relation to a military mission, including a peacekeeping mission. Allows the designation of no more than 25 centers, and requires geographical diversity of such centers. Requires the Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs to establish a peer review panel to assess the scientific and clinical merit of proposals submitted for center designation.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
