<bill session="105" type="h" number="4742" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Aviation Consumer Right To Know Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve consumers' access to airline industry information, to promote competition in the aviation industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1998-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1998-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1975"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airline employees"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airline rates"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
    <term name="Travel agents"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/1998--Introduced.
Aviation Consumer Right To Know Act of 1998 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to begin implementation of the requirements contained in the notice of proposed rulemaking of the Department of Transportation, dated August 10, 1994, regarding the disclosure of code-sharing arrangements and long-term wet leases. Requires the Secretary to modify such requirements to ensure that written notice of a code-sharing arrangement or long-term wet lease is provided on ticket stock and any accompanying itinerary. Directs the Secretary to conduct a rulemaking proceeding to require: (1) a ticket agent for air transportation to disclose verbally to a prospective air ticket buyer the commissions paid to the ticket agent by all air carriers serving the markets of interest to the prospective consumer; (2) each air carrier to keep records and publish statistics concerning the possibility of redeeming frequent flyer benefits offered by the air carrier for air transportation between any of its city-pair markets; and (3) each air carrier to publish on the Internet, and update every 24 hours, the available fares for air transportation it offers on each flight scheduled for departure.</summary>
</bill>
