<bill session="106" type="h" number="155" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Municipal Biological Monitoring Use Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide for the use of biological monitoring and whole effluent toxicity tests in connection with publicly owned treatment works, municipal separate storm sewer systems, and municipal combined sewer overflows, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="1999-01-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E54-55"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic animals"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
Municipal Biological Monitoring Use Act - Amends provisions of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act relating to a State's adoption of water quality standards to require criteria for biological monitoring or whole effluent toxicity to employ an aquatic species that is indigenous to the type of waters, a species that is representative of such species, or other appropriate species to indicate the toxicity of the effluent in the specific receiving waters, taking into account the natural biological variability of the species. Provides that, with respect to publicly owned treatment works, municipal separate storm sewer systems, and municipal combined sewer overflows (public sewer facilities), nothing in such Act shall be construed to authorize the use of water quality standards or permit effluent limitations which result in a finding of a violation upon failure of whole effluent toxicity or biological monitoring tests. States that where the permitting authority determines that the discharge from a public sewer facility has reasonable potential to cause or contribute to an in-stream excursion above a criterion for whole effluent toxicity, the permit may contain terms, conditions, or limitations requiring further toxicity analysis and evaluation. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to follow the above criteria when the Administrator determines that it is necessary to include biological monitoring, whole effluent toxicity testing, or assessment methods as a permit term, condition, or limitation issued to a public sewer facility. States that the failure of a biological monitoring or whole effluent toxicity test at a public sewer facility shall not result in a finding of a violation under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
