<bill session="105" type="h" number="735" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Essential Health Facilities Investment Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a program of assistance for essential community providers of health care services, to establish a program to update and maintain the infrastructure requirements of safety net hospitals, and to require States to develop plans for the allocation and review of expenditures for the capital-related costs of health care services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1997-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1997-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1997-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1997-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-02-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E241-243"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Community hospitals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Rural hospitals"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Essential Access Community Hospital Program Title II: Capital Financing Assistance for Safety Net Providers Subtitle A: Amendments of Internal Revenue Code of 1986 Subtitle B: Capital Financing Assistance for Safety Net Providers Title III: Capital Allocation Plans Essential Health Facilities Investment Act of 1997 - Title I: Essential Access Community Hospital Program - Amends part A (Hospital Insurance) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to: (1) revise the Essential Access Community Hospital Program (EACH), extending EACH to all States and authorizing increased appropriations for EACH grants; and (2) establish a program of assistance (PA) for activities related to the formation of State and local community health networks. (Sec. 103) Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to report on EACH and PA effectiveness in increasing medically underserved population health care. Title II: Capital Financing Assistance for Safety Net Providers - Subtitle A: Amendments of Internal Revenue Code of 1986 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to impose a tax on the hospital gross receipts of any person for the taxable year. Subtitle B: Capital Financing Assistance for Safety Net Providers - Amends SSA to establish a program to provide capital financing assistance in the form of loan guarantees, interest rate subsidies, matching loans, and direct grants to eligible hospitals and facilities. Creates in the Treasury the related Capital Financing Trust Fund. (Sec. 212) Provides for adjustment of Medicare hospital payments to take into account any capital financing assistance received by the hospital. (Sec. 213) Amends the IRC to grant tax-exempt status to State and local bonds guaranteed by the Fund. Title III: Capital Allocation Plans - Amends SSA title XVIII to mandate that each State establish a plan for Federal approval of capital expenditures for certain non-rural health care services in the State in order to receive Medicare reimbursement for capital-related expenses.</summary>
</bill>
