<amendment session="105" chamber="h" number="91" updated="2013-07-17T07:51:34-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2" sequence="28"/>
  <status datetime="1997-05-14T15:06:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="406277"/>
  <offered datetime="1997-05-14"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to combine public housing programs into two grant programs; require annual management plans from housing authorities; increase HUD's ability to take action against troubled housing authorities; target housing assistance with 40 percent of units for families with incomes less than 30 percent of median income and 90 percent of units for families with incomes less than 60 percent of median income; target 75 percent of tenant-based rental assistance to families with incomes less than 30 percent of median income; establish minimum rents of between zero and 25 dollars; and require housing authorities to encourage tenants to volunteer in their community.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute, printed as amendment No. 10 in the Congressional Record of April 29, 1997 to reduce the minimum rents allowed to be charged by Public Housing Authorities from between $25-$50 per month to $0-$25 per month. Public Housing authorities would be required to reserve 40% of units for families with incomes below 30% of themedian income of the area, and make 90% of units available to families withincomes at or below 60% of the local median income and 10% of the availableunits would be reserved for families with incomes at or below 80% of the local median income. The amendment would require housing authorities to target 75% of its Section 8 tenant-based rental assistance to families withincomes at or below 30% of the local median income and authorizes the creation of a board HUD to determine improved methods of evaluating the performance of PHAs. The amendment would merge Section 8 certificate housing assistance and voucher programs into one tenant-based program. Drug elimination programs for public housing facilities would be funded on the basis of demonstrated need.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-05-14T13:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A028) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Kennedy (MA).</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1997-05-14T15:06:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="126">
      <text>On agreeing to the Kennedy (MA) amendment (A028) Failed by recorded vote: 163 - 261 (Roll no. 126).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
