<amendment session="105" chamber="h" number="207" updated="2013-07-17T07:51:36-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2014" sequence="2"/>
  <status datetime="1997-06-26T17:09:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <offered datetime="1997-06-26"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to increase HOPE scholarship credits; extend an income tax exclusion for employer provided educational assistance; authorize interest free bonds and loans for schools with students from poor families; provide tax credits for children of families who earn less than $60,000 per year; provide capital gains exclusions for the sale of a principal residence; allow a deductible capital gain loss when selling a residence; provide a special rate for the sale of farms, business assets, and real estate; create an additional exemption for estates that include a family owned business; extend expiring provisions of various tax credits; expand empowerment zones and enterprise zones; provide various tax credits and incentives including the deduction of remediation costs incurred with toxic waste cleanup and a welfare to work credit.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute, printed as amendment No. 2 in the Congressional record of June 24, 1997. The amendment would target 71% of the tax cuts to families earning less than $100,000 and limit the $500 child credit to families earning less that $75,000. The amendment would provide $1,500 HOPE scholarships for the first two year of post-secondary education and provide a credit of 20% of tuition costs after the first two years. Capitol gains and estate taxes would be reduced for small businesses and family farms, and homeowners would be allowed to exclude up to $500,000 of capital gains on the sale of a home.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-06-26T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Rangel.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1997-06-26T17:09:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="243">
      <text>On agreeing to the Rangel amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 197 - 235 (Roll no. 243).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
