<bill session="104" type="h" number="3032" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fiscal Year 1996 Disaster Recovery Flexibility Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assist State and local governments in recovering from recent disasters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1996-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1996-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407400" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1996-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="1996-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services. for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/1996--Introduced.
Fiscal Year 1996 Disaster Recovery Flexibility Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to waive, or specify alternative requirements for, any provision of any statute or regulation that the Secretary administers in connection with the obligation by the Secretary or the use by any recipient of any funds or loan guarantees appropriated or made available to HUD for FY 1996, but only upon a finding that: (1) such waiver is required to facilitate the obligation or use of such funds or guarantees for activities in an area for which the President has declared a major disaster under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act; and (2) such waiver would not be inconsistent with the overall purposes of the statute or regulation. Limits the application of any such waiver only to funds or guarantees used for activities in such a disaster area. Prohibits the Secretary from waiving or specifying alternative requirements under this Act for any statutory or regulatory requirements relating to fair housing or nondiscrimination, the environment, or labor standards.</summary>
</bill>
