<bill session="104" type="hr" number="427" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-09T20:22:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-05-09T20:22:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3322) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 1997 for civilian science activities of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411214"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-05-07T22:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-565, by Ms. Greene (UT).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-07T22:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3322 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 2(l)(2) of rule XI and clause 5(a) of rule XXI shall be waived. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments. Before consideration of any other amendment, it shall be in order to consider the Walker amendment printed in the report accompanying this resolution, debatable for 10 minutes and not subject to further amendment. If that amendment is adopted, the bill, as amended, shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-05-07T22:18:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="219">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 219.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T20:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4764-4766" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T20:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T20:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-05-09T20:22:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09T20:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="3322"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/1996--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 3322 (Federal civilian science activities authorization).</summary>
</bill>
