<bill session="104" type="h" number="675" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securities Litigation Equity Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to provide certain safeguards to ensure that the interests of investors are well protected under the implied private action provisions of the Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407772"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1995-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E184"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Professional ethics"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/1995--Introduced.
Securities Litigation Equity Act of 1995 - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (the Act) to prohibit brokers, dealers, or associated persons from soliciting or accepting referral fees from an attorney for obtaining the representation of a customer in any implied private action. (Sec. 2) Prohibits, unless otherwise ordered by the court, the use of funds disgorged solely as the result of any administrative or court action brought by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to pay legal expenses incurred by private parties seeking distribution of such funds. Modifies the guidelines for class action litigation, including: (1) recovery by named plaintiffs in the same manner as all other members of the class; (2) court determination of conflicts of interest on the part of counsel with a beneficial interest in the securities that are the subject of the litigation; (3) restrictions on settlements under seal; (4) restrictions on payment of attorney's fees from settlement funds; (5) disclosure of settlement terms to class members; and (6) special verdicts. (Sec. 3) Establishes a statute of limitations period for implied private rights of action. (Sec. 4) Provides for a court-appointed guardian ad litem or class action steering committee to oversee counsel and settlement offers for the plaintiff class. (Sec. 5) Delineates the requirements for securities fraud actions. (Sec. 6) Modifies the allocation of damages scheme to distinguish between primary degrees of responsibility and the application of proportionate liability. (Sec.7) Directs the SEC to re-examine the regulatory and judicial framework with respect to predictive statements ("forward-looking statements") concerning the future economic performance of an issuer of securities. Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to prescribe litigation procedures with respect to safe harbors for forward-looking statements. (Sec. 8) Modifies requirements for audits conducted by an independent public accountant of an issuer's financial statements to include procedures to: (1) detect illegal acts; (2) identify related party transactions material to financial statements; and (3) evaluate an issuer's ability to continue as a going concern. Sets forth notification and reporting guidelines for a public accountant who detects illegal activities during the course of an audit. Limits such auditor's liability for complying with such guidelines. Establishes civil penalties for an auditor's noncompliance with this Act. (Sec. 9) Amends the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations statute to exclude from its purview a civil action if the racketeering activity in question involves fraud in the sale of securities.</summary>
</bill>
