<bill session="106" type="h" number="2950" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oregon Land Exchange Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Northeast Oregon Assembled Land Exchange Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Triangle Land Exchange Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the exchange of certain land in the State of Oregon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400419"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-04">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Departments of Agriculture and the Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="h" number="1950"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1629"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Bureau of Land Management Title II: Forest Service Title III: Equitable Exchange Oregon Land Exchange Act of 1999 - Title I: Bureau of Land Management - Northeast Oregon Assembled Land Exchange Act of 1999 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to convey to certain identified private landowners all U.S. rights and interests in specified lands within the Central Oregon and Baker Resource areas in Oregon in exchange for the conveyance by such landowners of certain other parcels of land within such resource areas. Title II: Forest Service - Triangle Land Exchange Act of 1999 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to certain identified private landowners all U.S. rights and interests in specified lands within the Malheur National Forest, Oregon, in exchange for the conveyance by such landowners of certain other parcels of land within or adjacent to the Malheur, Wallowa-Whitman, and Umatilla National Forests in Oregon. Title III: Equitable Exchange - Provides for exchange valuation, appraisals, and equalization of value received with respect to such land exchanges. Provides for administration and management, by the BLM or Forest Service, as appropriate, of lands received by the United States.</summary>
</bill>
