<bill session="107" type="h" number="4733" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Indian Child Welfare Act Amendments of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical amendments to the Indian Child Welfare Act of 1978.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="2002-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E790"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Adoptive parents"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grandparents"/>
    <term name="Guardian and ward"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Indian courts"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to the poor"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2002--Introduced.
Indian Child Welfare Act Amendments of 2002 - Amends the Indian Child Welfare Act of 1978 concerning: (1) jurisdiction over child custody and child adoption proceedings, including transfers and special rules for Indian tribes in Alaska; (2) transfer of jurisdiction to tribal court, excluding cases where there is no subject matter jurisdiction or a transfer would cause undue hardship; (3) intervention in state court proceedings, including the intervention rights of the extended family; (4) full faith and credit, including tribal court judgments; (5) pending court proceedings, including notice requirements and a prohibition against prebirth involuntary custody proceedings; (6) voluntary termination of parental rights, including an explanation of placement options and treating certain Indian custodians as parents; (7) withdrawal of consent before a final decree, as specified; (8) notice to Indian tribes of the voluntary termination of parental rights or voluntary placement of a child; (9) content of notice based on a good faith investigation; (10) intervention by an Indian tribe upon filing a notice of intent or a written objection; (11) written notice to parents of a terminated or changed adoptive placement or a commenced proceeding to adopt; (12) invalidation of child custody proceedings, including the right to petition of a member of the child's extended family previously rejected as a placement; (13) notice to extended family members; (14) expanded release of information concerning the tribal affiliation of biological parents; (15) resumption of jurisdiction over child custody proceedings by Indian tribes, as specified; (16) agreements between States and Indian tribes as they affect jurisdiction; (17) criminal sanctions for fraudulent representation during Indian child adoption proceedings; (18) visitation as an enforceable right; (18) promulgating regulations governing compliance reviews; and (19) the application of these requirements to children of State-recognized tribes.</summary>
</bill>
