<bill session="106" type="h" number="445" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Debit Card Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Electronic Fund Tranfer Act to safeguard consumers in connection with the utilization of certain debit cards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400553"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1999-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1999-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Checking accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debit cards"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/1999--Introduced.
Consumer Debit Card Protection Act - Amends the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to mandate that any check card issued by a financial institution to a consumer shall bear the legend "Check Card" in prominent typeface and in a conspicuous place on the face of such card. Prescribes guidelines governing consumer liability for unauthorized electronic fund transfers where the relevant cards do not necessitate a unique identifier. Conditions such liability upon timely notification to the consumer of liability for such transfers and of the advisability of prompt reporting of any loss, theft, or unauthorized use of a card code or other means of access. Permits distribution to consumers of electronic fund transfer cards without unique identifiers only if certain validation requirements are met. Mandates that any financial institution which issues consumer check cards maintain a 24-hour notification system which includes a toll-free telephone number at which personnel are continuously accessible to accept reports of theft, loss, or unauthorized use. Precludes consumer liability for fees for insufficient funds due to an unauthorized electronic fund transfer executed by the use of a card lacking a protective device to serve as a unique identifier of the rightful consumer. Requires prompt re-crediting of the consumer's account for any fee imposed before receipt of the consumer's notice of an unauthorized electronic fund transfer.</summary>
</bill>
