<bill session="106" type="h" number="5459" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Corps of Engineers Benefit-Cost Improvement Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Army to recommend a water resources development and conservation project for authorization by Congress only if the project has projected benefits that are at least 1.5 times as great as the project's estimated total cost, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400607"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2000-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2000-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2000-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/2000--Introduced.
Corps of Engineers Benefit-Cost Improvement Act of 2000 - Direct the Secretary of the Army to: (1) recommend for authorization by Congress a water resources development and conservation project that is subject to a benefit-cost analysis only if the project's projected benefits are at least 1.5 times its estimated total cost; and (2) review the projected benefits and cost of currently authorized projects for which less than 33 percent of the total cost has been expended; and(3) transmit to Congress a list of each such currently authorized project that has projected benefits that are less than 1.5 times its estimated cost. Terminates authorization of a project included on the list three years after the transmittal of the list unless it is reauthorized.</summary>
</bill>
