<bill session="108" type="hr" number="564" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Relating to the liberation of the Iraqi people and the valiant service of the United States Armed Forces and Coalition forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400314"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="2004-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Children's rights"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Constitutions"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Guerrilla warfare"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International employees"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military intelligence"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military vehicles"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Wounds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2004--Introduced.
States that the House of Representatives: (1) acknowledges the belief that the United States and the world have been made safer with the removal of Saddam Hussein and his regime from power in Iraq, and the belief that a final judgment on the value of activities in Iraq cannot be made until Iraq is stable and secure; (2) commends the Iraqi people for their courage in the face of unspeakable oppression and brutality inflicted on them by Saddam Hussein's regime; (3) commends the Iraqi people on the adoption of Iraq's interim constitution; (4) commends the members of the U.S. Armed Forces and Coalition forces for liberating Iraq and expresses its gratitude for their valiant service; (5) expresses deep sorrow and regret for the deaths of more than 550 and the wounding of more than 3,500 U.S. armed forces members in Iraq and extends support to their families; and (6) expresses sorrow and regret for the deaths in Iraq of U.S. civilians, U.N. personnel, unknown numbers of Iraqi civilians, and other noncombatants. States that the House of Representatives urges the President to: (1) take all steps necessary to ensure that U.S. armed forces members in Iraq receive the best force protection equipment available, including protective body armor and extra-armored wheeled vehicle; (2) ensure that U.S. armed forces members who suffer wounds or other injuries, or who incur illness while serving in Iraq receive high-quality health care to treat the short-term and long-term consequences of such wounds, injuries, and illnesses; (3) recognize the key contributions made by members of the reserve components of the armed forces, and their families, in Operation Iraqi Freedom, and, in consultation with Congress, to address the civilian-military pay disparity that exists for many Reserve and Guard personnel when ordered to active duty; (4) acknowledge that there were serious deficiencies in U.S. pre-war intelligence on Iraq, particularly in light of the failure to find any evidence of significant weapons of mass destruction stockpiles, and to take steps to improve intelligence so that United States troops are better protected and future United States national security strategies are better informed; (5) request sufficient funding to fully support U.S. military operations in Iraq and the surrounding region in order to ensure the safety and well-being of U.S. troops deployed to Iraq and the surrounding region; (6) obtain international participation in the securing, reconstruction, and political development of Iraq, including the protection of women's and children's rights; and (7) take steps to correct the failure of the United States Government to plan adequately for the post-war occupation of Iraq, including the failure to integrate internal United States Government studies and outside expert opinions that predicted the onset of guerrilla activity and described how to promote effective reconstruction, democratization, and civil society development activities, and the failure to apply those studies and opinions today in order to improve current U.S. reconstruction efforts in Iraq.</summary>
</bill>
