<bill session="106" type="h" number="4180" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Library of Congress Financial Management Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Librarian of Congress to establish certain programs and activities of the Library of Congress as programs to be administered through a revolving fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400189"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-04-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1822-1823"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2491"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bibliography"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Librarians"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/5/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Library of Congress Revolving Fund Title II: Cataloging Products and Services Title III: Library of Congress Trust Fund Board Title IV: Effective Date Library of Congress Financial Management Act of 2000 - Title I: Library of Congress Revolving Fund - Authorizes the Librarian of Congress to: (1) establish specified Revolving Fund service activities, including certain library, sales, and special event services as well as the preparation of research reports, translations, analytical studies, and related services for Federal Government or District of Columbia government entities; and (2) establish Revolving Fund service units, which may be partially or fully sustained through the Library of Congress Revolving Fund established under this Act.(Sec. 102) Specifies the Fund service activities that may be conducted by Fund Service units.(Sec. 103) Establishes the Library of Congress Revolving Fund, to be made available to the Librarian without fiscal year limitation, to carry out Fund service activities. Limits the obligations for such activities for any fiscal year to the total amounts specified in appropriations Acts for such fiscal year.Allows the Librarian to temporarily transfer to the Fund other Funds appropriated to the Library, except that the Fund shall reimburse the appropriate accounts of the Library for amounts so transferred before the period of availability of the Library appropriation expires.(Sec. 104) Authorizes the Librarian to make products and services provided as Revolving Fund service activities available for purchase at rates adequate to recover related costs.Requires participants in Revolving Fund service activities to pay for such products and services by advance of funds: (1) if the Librarian determines that amounts in the Revolving Fund are otherwise insufficient to cover the costs of providing such products and services; or (2) upon agreement between participants and the Librarian.Authorizes the Librarian, in the operation of Fund activities, to enter into: (1) contracts for the lease and acquisition of goods and services for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in the next fiscal year, pursuant to the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act; and (2) multi-year contracts for the acquisition of property and services, pursuant to such Act.(Sec. 105) Repeals provisions of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1998 establishing the Cooperative Acquisitions Program Revolving Fund for financing a Library program to acquire foreign publications and research materials on behalf of participating institutions on a cost-recovery basis.(Sec. 106) Prohibits the construction of this title to affect the terms and conditions of employment of any Library of Congress employee who carries out any activities designated as a Revolving Fund service activity or who is assigned to a Revolving Fund service unit.Title II: Cataloging Products and Services - Authorizes the Librarian of Congress to make cataloging products and services, created by the Library, available for purchase at prices that reflect as closely as practicable the cost of distribution over a reasonable period.(Sec. 202) Repeals Federal law provisions that authorize the Librarian of Congress to sell copies of card indexes and other publications to institutions or individuals.Title III: Library of Congress Trust Fund Board - Revises the composition of the Library of Congress Trust Fund Board to include the vice chair of the Joint Committee on the Library. Decreases the Board's quorum from nine to seven members for the transaction of business. Provides for a temporary extension of Board members' terms.Title IV: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
