<bill congress="106" type="hr" number="3206" updated="2012-10-31T13:24:17-05:00">
  <status datetime="1999-11-03">REFERRED</status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security Solvency Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide prospectively for personalized retirement security through personal retirement savings accounts to allow for more control by individuals over their Social Security retirement income, to amend such title and the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to protect Social Security surpluses, and to provide other reforms relating to benefits under such title II.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor state="MI" title="Rep" thomas_id="1080" district="7" name="Smith, Nick"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor name="Campbell, Tom" district="15" title="Rep" state="CA" sponsored_at="1999-11-03" thomas_id="170"/>
    <cosponsor name="Kolbe, Jim" district="5" title="Rep" state="AZ" sponsored_at="1999-11-03" thomas_id="645"/>
    <cosponsor name="Porter, John Edward" district="10" title="Rep" state="IL" sponsored_at="1999-11-03" thomas_id="923"/>
    <cosponsor name="Sanford, Marshall (Mark)" district="1" title="Rep" state="SC" sponsored_at="1999-11-03" thomas_id="1012"/>
    <cosponsor name="Shadegg, John B." district="4" title="Rep" state="AZ" sponsored_at="1999-11-03" thomas_id="1043"/>
    <cosponsor name="Stenholm, Charles W." district="17" title="Rep" state="TX" sponsored_at="1999-11-03" thomas_id="1110"/>
    <cosponsor name="Toomey, Patrick J." district="15" title="Rep" state="PA" sponsored_at="1999-11-03" thomas_id="1594"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <referral datetime="1999-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned"/>
    </referral>
    <referral datetime="1999-11-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </referral>
    <referral datetime="1999-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </referral>
    <referral datetime="1999-11-03">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
      <committee name="House Budget"/>
    </referral>
    <action datetime="2000-06-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5088-5089"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Retirement age"/>
    <term name="Retirement income"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security beneficiaries"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Widowers"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary date="1999-11-03" status="Introduced">TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Individual Retirement Security Program Title II: Social Security Surplus Protection Title III: Social Security Benefit Reforms Social Security Solvency Act of 1999 - Title I: Individual Retirement Security Program - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to create a new Individual Retirement Security Program (Program) in which a covered individual and spouse, upon the attainment of a minimum deposit balance of $2,500 in the Interim Investment Fund (IIF) established by this Act in the Treasury and governed by the Board (Board) of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, may designate one or more personal retirement savings accounts to which the Secretary of the Treasury shall make deposits from the IIF with respect to the individual according to prescribed formulae.(Sec. 101) Directs the Commissioner of Social Security to conduct a public education effort regarding the Program.Mandates that the Board divide the IIF into three accounts for investment in common stock and corporate bonds according to prescribed guidelines.Requires the Secretary to deposit into the IIF, from amounts otherwise available in the general fund of the Treasury, a total amount equal, in the aggregate, to 100 percent of the redirected social security taxes for such calendar year of each covered individual for such calendar year.(Sec. 102) Requires a reduction in Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance appropriations, according to a certain formula.Directs the Board of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund to publish in the Federal Register each year the reallocation percentage (calculated according to a specified formula) for amounts otherwise appropriated to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund from Federal Insurance Contributions Act taxes imposed with regard to wages and self-support income for the fiscal year beginning on October 1 of each calendar year.(Sec. 103) Provides for adjustments to primary OASDI insurance amounts of such covered individuals with designated accounts in the IIF.(Sec. 104) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax deduction in the case of an electing personal retirement savings account participant in an amount equal to 50 percent (up to $2,000) of the amount the individual contributed during the taxable year to a personal retirement savings account maintained for the individual's benefit, regardless of whether or not the taxpayer itemizes other deductions.Excludes from gross income any amount deposited in a personal retirement savings account. Includes distributions in gross income as if they were social security benefits.Allows an excise tax on excess contributions to a personal retirement savings account.Title II: Social Security Surplus Protection - Amends SSA title II to provide for transfers of budget surpluses to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund for FY 2001 through 2009.(Sec. 202) Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) to mandate the sequestration of the estimated net surplus in the social security trust funds for the budget year, less the transfers made above to reduce the public debt and to provide for associated reports regarding such sequestration.Title III: Social Security Benefit Reforms - Amends SSA title II to provide for: (1) a gradual increase in retirement age and early retirement age; (2) adjustments to bend points in determining primary insurance amounts; (3) information relating to benefit limitations in social security account statements; (4) coverage of newly hired State and local employees; (5) an increase in widow's and widower's insurance benefits; (6) elimination of the limitation on the amount of outside income (earnings test) which a beneficiary may earn without incurring a reduction in benefits for individuals who have attained retirement age; (7) acceleration of increase in delayed retirement credit; and (8) authorization for reimbursement of Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund for certain costs of disability insurance benefits.(Sec. 309) Directs the Commissioner of Social Security to study and report to the Congress on the most appropriate and feasible means of providing for elections under which individuals may opt for exclusion from OASDI coverage.</summary>
</bill>
