<bill session="104" type="h" number="668" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-10T15:15:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-02-10T15:15:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Anti-Crime bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Contract with America bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Criminal Alien Deportation Improvements Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Criminal Alien Deportation Improvements Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Criminal Alien Deportation Improvements Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To control crime by further streamlining deportation of criminal aliens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1995-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1995-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1995-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 8.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06T21:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 104-22.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-02-06T21:28:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="9">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 9.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-02-09T18:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 69 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 668 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment contained in section 2 of this resolution. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 69 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 69.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1588-1597" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 668 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment contained in section 2 of this resolution. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:14:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 69 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:14:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable David Dreier to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:14:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McCollum asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on each amendment to the bill, and every amendment thereto, be limited to not to exceed 20 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:32:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Cunningham amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:34:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Moran amenndment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:38:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Horn amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:43:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Cunningham amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:49:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Foley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:51:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 668.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:51:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T14:52:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-02-10T15:15:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="118" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 380 - 20 (Roll no. 118).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T15:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10T15:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 668.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-18">
      <text>For Further Action See S.735.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="69"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="735"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administration of criminal justice"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Automobile theft"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Perjury"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Receiving stolen goods"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h138"/>
    <amendment number="h139"/>
    <amendment number="h140"/>
    <amendment number="h141"/>
    <amendment number="h142"/>
    <amendment number="h143"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>2/10/1995--Passed House amended.
Criminal Alien Deportation Improvements Act of 1995 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (Act), as amended by the Immigration and Nationality Technical Corrections Act of 1994, to expand the definition of "aggravated felony." (Sec. 3) Subjects a conditional permanent resident alien convicted of an aggravated felony to expedited deportation. (Sec. 4) Revises the seven-year residency defense against a deportation or exclusion order to permit deportation or exclusion of a permanent resident alien who has been sentenced (currently imprisoned) to five or more years for an aggravated felony. (Sec. 5) Limits collateral attacks on deportation orders. (Sec. 6) Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to: (1) rename the criminal alien tracking center as the criminal alien identification system; (2) specify that the system shall be used to identify and locate deportable aliens who have committed aggravated felonies; and (3) transfer the system from the Attorney General to the Commissioner of the Immigration and Naturalization Service. (Sec. 7) Amends Federal criminal law to: (1) bring certain alien smuggling-related crimes under the purview of the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations (RICO) provisions; and (2) authorize wiretaps for alien smuggling investigations. (Sec. 9) Amends the Act to expand the criteria for deportation for crimes of moral turpitude. (Sec. 10) Makes local governments eligible for specified alien incarceration reimbursement assistance under the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994. (Sec. 11) Amends the Act to permit the use of electronic and telephonic media in deportation hearings. (Sec. 13) Directs the Secretary of State and the Attorney General to report on the effectiveness of the Prisoners Transfer Treaty with Mexico. (Sec. 14) Directs the Attorney General to designate a Department of Justice office which shall provide States and local entities with technical and prosecutorial assistance with respect to aliens who flee prosecution for crimes committed in the United States. (Sec. 15) States that the Congress advises the President to negotiate bilateral prisoner transfer treaties. Requires annual presidential certification that a treaty is effectively returning illegal aliens incarcerated in the United States to finish their prison term in their home country. (Sec. 16) Directs the Attorney General and the Commissioner to develop an interior (home country) repatriation program. (Sec. 17) Amends the Act to authorize deportation of nonviolent offenders prior to Federal or State sentence completion.</summary>
</bill>
