<bill session="104" type="h" number="200" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lender and Fiduciary Fairness in Liability Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400414"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400500" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1995-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400079" joined="1995-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400225" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1995-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400603" joined="1995-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400520" joined="1995-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="409400" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400398" joined="1995-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="1995-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1995-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E31"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Lender and Fiduciary Fairness in Liability Act of 1995 - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to exclude from the definition of "owner or operator" (thus, protecting from individual liability) fiduciaries who hold legal title to, are the mortgagees or secured parties with respect to, control, or manage any facility or vessel at which a hazardous substance release occurred for purposes of administering an estate or trust of which such vessel or facility is a part. Provides that the liability of a fiduciary that is liable under other CERCLA provisions for releases in connection with property held in a fiduciary capacity may not exceed the assets held in such capacity that are available to indemnify the fiduciary. Provides for potential liability of fiduciaries in cases of negligence or intentional misconduct. Lists additional conditions under which fiduciaries are exempted from liability. Limits CERCLA liability of lenders in connection with property acquired through foreclosure, subject to a security interest, held by a lessor pursuant to an extension of credit, or subject to financial control pursuant to an extension of credit to the actual benefit conferred on such lenders by a removal, remedial, or response action undertaken by another party. Defines the "actual benefit" as the net gain realized by the lender due to such action. Provides for potential liability for response actions of lenders that caused or contributed to releases. Creates a rebuttable presumption that a defendant who has acquired real property has made all appropriate inquiry into previous ownership and uses of the property if he establishes that, within 180 days prior to the time of acquisition, he conducted an environmental site assessment (an assessment of the property and surrounding areas to determine the presence of contamination and which provides for review of specified records and inspections). Provides that no presumption shall arise: (1) unless the defendant has maintained a compilation of the information reviewed in the course of the assessment; or (2) if the assessment discloses contamination on the property to be acquired, unless the defendant has taken reasonable steps to confirm the absence of such contamination. Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to exclude fiduciaries and certain security interest holders from the definitions of "operator," "generator," and "transporter."</summary>
</bill>
