<bill session="107" type="h" number="5217" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Affordable Drugs Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to grant waivers permitting individuals to import prescription drugs from Canada, to amend such Act with respect to the sale of prescription drugs through the Internet, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2002-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400026" joined="2002-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2002-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="2002-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2002--Introduced.
Affordable Drugs Access Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require a waiver of prohibitions which would then permit an individual to import a prescription drug from Canada. Stipulates that the drug be: (1) imported in final form in limited quantities for personal use from a registered Canadian pharmacy; (2) approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services; and (3) accompanied by a valid prescription.Requires the Secretary to study the authenticity and quality of drugs imported into the United States from other countries for personal use. Authorizes the Secretary, based on whether study results indicate the presence or absence of a significant threat to public health, to: (1) condition the entry of drugs; (2) terminate the waiver; and/or (3) extend the waiver to other countries.Amends the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to reduce the aggregate number of dosage units of a controlled substance a U.S. resident may import into the United States without a prescription.Regulates the Internet sale of prescription drugs. Requires Internet sites used for purposes of sales of a prescription drug to include a page (and links thereto) providing the identities of the seller and the persons serving as pharmacists or medical consultants and the States in which the seller and such persons are authorized to dispense drugs or provide consultations.Permits State enforcement of Internet prescription drug sale requirements, but retains the right of the Secretary to intervene.</summary>
</bill>
