<bill session="106" type="h" number="4572" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To eliminate the regional system of organizing the National Forest System and to replace the regional offices of the Forest Service with State offices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400534"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2000--Introduced.
Declares that, by one year after enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall no longer administer the National Forest System using the organizational structure of Forest Service regions. Directs the Secretary, by that time, to eliminate the ten existing regional offices of the Forest Service and replace them with State offices.Directs the Secretary to establish a State office of the Forest Service in each State containing any portion of the National Forest System. Authorizes establishment of a Forest Service office to serve more than one State, or consolidate separate offices previously established, if: (1) the total acreage of System lands in a particular State does not justify a separate Forest Service office for that State; and (2) the System lands in that State can be readily managed through a Forest Service office in another State.Authorizes the Secretary to establish up to six technical support centers, which must be at the same location as a State office.</summary>
</bill>
