<bill session="104" type="h" number="1905" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-13">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY96, Energy and Water Development</title>
    <title type="popular">Energy FY96 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Water Development FY96 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for energy and water development for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408092"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Water Development.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-13">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-13">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-06-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20T20:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-149, by Mr. Myers.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-06-20T20:57:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="69">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 69.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22T16:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 171 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1905 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Points of order against specific provisions of the bill shall be waived. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments. Before consideration of any other amendment it shall be in order to consider the amendment printed in the report accompanying this resolution. The amendment shall be debatable for 10 minutes and shall not be subject to further amendment. After the disposition of the amendment, the provisions of the bill as then perfected shall be considered as original text. Priority in offering amendments may be given to those amendments printed in the Congressional Record prior to consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 171 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 171.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6772-6815" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1905 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Points of order against specific provisions of the bill shall be waived. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments. Before consideration of any other amendment it shall be in order to consider the amendment printed in the report accompanying this resolution. The amendment shall be debatable for 10 minutes and shall not be subject to further amendment. After the disposition of the amendment, the provisions of the bill as then perfected shall be considered as original text. Priority in offering amendments may be given to those amendments printed in the Congressional Record prior to consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 171 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Michael G. Oxley to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Shuster raised a point of order against the content of the measure. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee proceeded with up to 10 minutes of debate on the Shuster en bloc amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. DeFazio asked unanimous consent to return to Title II of the bill. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeFazio amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Myers asked unanimous consent that debate on the Obey amendment and all amendments thereto be limited to 30 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T20:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Myers moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T20:24:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11T20:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1905 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6838-6883" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 171 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T10:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Myers asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the amendment, and all amendments thereto be limited to not to exceed 40 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T10:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Obey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T11:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Myers asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Klug amendment, and all amendments thereto, be limited to not to exceed 40 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Klug amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T12:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Myers asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Ward amendment and all amendments thereto, be limited to not to exceed 12 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T12:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 12 minutes of debate on the Ward amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Myers asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Klug amendment and all amendments thereto, be limited to not to exceed 15 minutes, with 10 minutes of the time allocated to Mr. Klug, and 5 minutes allocated to Mr. Bevill. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T15:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of additional debate on the Klug amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Myers asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Klug amendment and all amendments thereto, be limited to not to exceed 60 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 60 minutes of debate on the Klug amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Markey appealed the ruling of the Chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T18:10:00-04:00">
      <text>On sustaining the ruling of the Chair. Agreed to by recorded vote: 255 - 167 (Roll no. 493).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1905.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T18:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-07-12T18:46:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="494" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 400 - 27 (Roll no. 494).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12T18:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-25">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Water Development. Approved for full committee consideration with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-07-27">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-07-27">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported to Senate by Senator Domenici with amendments. With written report No. 104-120.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-07-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="156">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 156.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-07-31">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10918-10922, S10926-10929" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11068-11099, S11101-11105" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2053 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Reid.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2053 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2054 proposed by Senator Jeffords.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2054 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2055 proposed by Senator Bumpers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2055 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 62-38. Record Vote No: 347.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2056 proposed by Senator Abraham.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2056 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2057 proposed by Senator Dorgan.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2057 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 83-14. Record Vote No: 348.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2058 proposed by Senator Grams.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Motion to table SP 2058 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 60-38. Record Vote No: 349.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2059 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Bingaman.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2059 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2060 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Lautenberg.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2060 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2061 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Daschle.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2061 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2062 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Baucus.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2062 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2063 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Byrd.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2063 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2064 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Feingold.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2064 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2065 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Boxer.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2065 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2066 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Hutchison.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2066 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2067 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Grams.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2067 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2068 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Warner.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2068 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2069 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Brown.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2069 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2070 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Brown.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2070 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2071 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Craig.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2071 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2072 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Pressler.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2072 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2073 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Dole.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2073 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2074 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Hatfield.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2074 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2075 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Pressler.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2075 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2076 proposed by Senator Wellstone.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Amendment SP 2076 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1995-08-01" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendments asks for a conference, appoints conferees Domenici; Hatfield; Cochran; Gorton; McConnell; Bennett; Burns; Johnston; Byrd; Hollings; Reid; Kerrey; Murray.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11105" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Myers asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8664" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Bevill motion to instruct conferees on the part of the House that, with regard to resolving differences with the Senate regarding projects and programs of the U.S. Corps of Engineers, the managers should select projects and programs within the scope of the conference without regard to the proposal of the Administration to reduce the role of the Corps of Engineers in flood control, shore protection, and navigation projects.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8664" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Myers, Rogers, Knollenberg, Riggs, Frelinghuysen, Bunn, Livingston, Bevill, Fazio, Chapman, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-24">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-26T18:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 104-293 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10913-10974" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-30T18:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 248 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 1905. Upon adoption of this resolution, all points of order against the confernece report accompanying the bill and against its consideration shall be waived. The waiver apply to clause 2 of rule XX, relating to legislation and unauthorized items on a general appropriations bill, specifically amendment Nos. 7, 13, and 14. The waiver shall also apply to clause 3 of rule XXVII, to protect provisions which exceed the scope of differences between the House and Senate, specifically amendment Nos. 1, 12 and 37.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31T13:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 248 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31T13:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Myers brought up conference report H. Rept. 104-293 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 248.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31T13:17:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31T14:02:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31T14:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="1995-10-31T14:21:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="748" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 402 - 24 (Roll no. 748).</text>
      <reference ref="CR  H11513" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1995-10-31" how="roll" result="pass" roll="558" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 89-6. Record Vote No: 558.</text>
      <reference ref="CR  S16398" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1995-11-07">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1995-11-13">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1995-11-13" type="public" number="104-46">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-46.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAP10" subcommittee="Energy and Water Development" name="House Appropriations"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP10" subcommittee="Energy and Water Development" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="171"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="248"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appalachia"/>
    <term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Beach erosion"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Columbia River development"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Delaware River Basin Commission"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Dismissal wage"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Fissionable materials"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Helium"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin"/>
    <term name="Interstate commissions"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Item veto"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Line item veto"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fusion"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution of rivers, harbors, etc."/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Plutonium"/>
    <term name="Polychlorinated biphenyls"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Potomac Basin development"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive waste disposal in the ground"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Rain and rainfall"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley Authority"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley development"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Unfunded mandates"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water allocation (Policy)"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water supply engineering"/>
    <term name="Waterfronts"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h503"/>
    <amendment number="h504"/>
    <amendment number="h505"/>
    <amendment number="h506"/>
    <amendment number="h507"/>
    <amendment number="h508"/>
    <amendment number="h509"/>
    <amendment number="h510"/>
    <amendment number="h511"/>
    <amendment number="h512"/>
    <amendment number="h513"/>
    <amendment number="h514"/>
    <amendment number="h515"/>
    <amendment number="h516"/>
    <amendment number="h517"/>
    <amendment number="h518"/>
    <amendment number="h519"/>
    <amendment number="h520"/>
    <amendment number="h521"/>
    <amendment number="h522"/>
    <amendment number="h523"/>
    <amendment number="s2019"/>
    <amendment number="s2020"/>
    <amendment number="s2021"/>
    <amendment number="s2022"/>
    <amendment number="s2023"/>
    <amendment number="s2024"/>
    <amendment number="s2027"/>
    <amendment number="s2028"/>
    <amendment number="s2053"/>
    <amendment number="s2054"/>
    <amendment number="s2055"/>
    <amendment number="s2056"/>
    <amendment number="s2057"/>
    <amendment number="s2058"/>
    <amendment number="s2059"/>
    <amendment number="s2060"/>
    <amendment number="s2061"/>
    <amendment number="s2062"/>
    <amendment number="s2063"/>
    <amendment number="s2064"/>
    <amendment number="s2065"/>
    <amendment number="s2066"/>
    <amendment number="s2067"/>
    <amendment number="s2068"/>
    <amendment number="s2069"/>
    <amendment number="s2070"/>
    <amendment number="s2071"/>
    <amendment number="s2072"/>
    <amendment number="s2073"/>
    <amendment number="s2074"/>
    <amendment number="s2075"/>
    <amendment number="s2076"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/26/1995--Conference report filed in House.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of Defense-Civil Title II: Department of the Interior Title III: Department of Energy Title IV: Independent Agencies Title V: General Provisions Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1996 - Title I: Department of Defense-Civil - Makes appropriations for FY 1996 for: (1) authorized civil functions of the Department of the Army relating to rivers and harbors, flood control, beach erosion, and related purposes; (2) expenses necessary for the collection and study of information related to such purposes; (3) the prosecution of authorized water development and related projects (provided that the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall transfer specified funds to the Secretary of the Interior for operation and maintenance at specified Columbia River Fishing Access Sites to be constructed by the Department of the Army); (4) certain flood control projects on the Mississippi River and its related tributaries; (5) water development projects operation and maintenance (provided that the Secretary of the Army shall maintain a specified minimum conservation pool level at Wister Lake, Oklahoma); (6) regulatory programs; (7) flood control and coastal emergencies; (8) oil spill research; and (9) general expenses. (Sec. 101) Directs the Secretary of the Army to advertise for competitive bid specified cubic yards of the hopper dredge volume accomplished with Government-owned dredges in FY 1992. Authorizes the Secretary to use the dredge fleet of the Corps of Engineers to undertake projects when industry does not perform as required by contract or when the bids are more than 25 percent in excess of a fair and reasonable cost estimate. Prohibits the use of any funds available to the Army Corps of Engineers to study, design, or undertake improvement or major repair of the Federal vessel McFARLAND (except for normal maintenance and repair to maintain its operational condition). Prohibits the Secretary from significantly altering operating schedules of the remaining Federal hopper dredges if any of the four Corps of Engineers hopper dredges is removed from normal service for repair or rehabilitation, and such repair prevents the dredge from accomplishing its volume of work regularly carried out in each of the past three years. (Sec. 102) Amends a specified Act relating to the project for navigation, Manistique Harbor, Schoolcraft County, Michigan, to permit installation of a sand and stone cap over sediments affected by polychlorinated biphenyls in accordance with an administrative order of the Environmental Protection Agency. States that such project shall continue to be maintained as a harbor of refuge. (Sec. 103) Prohibits the use of any funds available to the Army Corps of Engineers for a movement to the Southeast Federal Center, except funds used to process required Department of the Army permits. (Sec. 104) Modifies a flood control project authorized for Petersburg, West Virginia, to authorize the Secretary of the Army to construct the project at a specified cost. (Sec. 105) Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to: (1) accept from a non-Federal sponsor certain additional lands contiguous to the Cooper Lake and Channels Project, Texas; and (2) redesignate certain mitigation land to recreation purposes. States that the cost of all work undertaken pursuant to this section shall be borne by the donating sponsor. (Sec. 106) Authorizes the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to undertake a specified Indianapolis, Indiana, project, to include certain riverfront alterations described in a specified master plan with specified estimated Federal and non-Federal costs. (Sec. 107) Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1992 to: (1) authorize increased appropriations for South Central Pennsylvania Environmental Restoration Infrastructure and Resource Protection Development Pilot Program providing environmental assistance to non-Federal interests in south central Pennsylvania; (2) increase the number of counties that compose "south central Pennsylvania"; and (3) revise the cost-sharing guidelines governing such program. (Sec. 108) Directs the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to proceed with engineering, design, and construction of flood control projects and improvements to rainfall drainage systems in Jefferson, Orleans, and St. Tammany Parishes in Louisiana. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 109) Instructs the Secretary of the Army to convey specified Federal lands to the City of Prestonburg, Kentucky, for public use recreational purposes and to further the regional economic development, subject to certain conditions. Title II: Department of the Interior - Makes FY 1996 appropriations for: (1) carrying out the Central Utah Project Completion Act; (2) the Bureau of Reclamation; (3) general investigations of proposed Federal reclamation projects (4) project construction and rehabilitation; (5) project operation and maintenance; (6) Bureau of Reclamation Loan Program Account; (7) the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund; and (8) general administrative expenses and special funds. Title III: Department of Energy - Makes appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for FY 1996 for: (1) energy supply, research, and development activities (2) uranium supply and enrichment activities; (3) Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund; (4) general DOE science and research activities; (5) the Nuclear Waste Disposal Fund; (6) atomic energy defense weapons activities; (7) defense environmental restoration and waste management; (8) other DOE defense activities (9) defense nuclear waste disposal (subject to the condition that specified sums shall be available for obligation and expenditure only for an interim storage facility and only upon enactment of specific statutory authority); (10) DOE administrative expenses; (11) Office of the Inspector General; (12) operation, maintenance, construction, rehabilitation, and funding expenses of the various geographical power administrations of DOE (including operation, maintenance, and emergency costs for the hydroelectric facilities at the Falcon and Amistad Dams); and (13) salaries and expenses of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission. Title IV: Independent Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY 1996 for: (1) the Appalachian Regional Commission; (2) the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board; (3) the Delaware River Basin Commission; (4) the Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin; (5) the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC); (6) the NRC Office of the Inspector General; (7) the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board; (8) the Susquehanna River Basin Commission; and (9) the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA). Sets a deadline by which TVA must submit a preliminary plan to the Congress securing funding for the environmental research center from sources other than direct appropriations to TVA. Title V: General Provisions - Amends the Fiscal Year 1991 Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act to repeal the prohibition against the use of appropriated funds to: (1) change the employment levels determined necessary by the Administrators of the Federal Power Marketing Administrations; or (2) change the employment levels of other Department of Energy programs to compensate for the employment levels of the Federal Power Marketing Administrations. (Sec. 502) Extends until five years after enactment of the Western Water Policy Review Act of 1992 the due date for the President's report regarding Federal activities in the 19 Western States which directly or indirectly affect the allocation and use of water resources. (Sec. 503) Provides that a member of the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board whose term has expired may continue to serve until a successor has taken office. (Sec. 504) Amends specified Federal law to extend to October 1, 1996, the authorization of appropriations for the Trinity River Restoration Program of the Central Valley Project, California. (Sec. 505) Declares the sense of the Congress that all equipment and products bought with funds under this Act should be American-made. Requires each Federal agency to give notice of this policy to any entity to whom it provides financial assistance or contracts. (Sec. 506) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this Act to revise the Missouri River Master Water Control Manual when it is made known to the appropriate Federal authority to which the funds are made available that such revision provides for an increase in the springtime water release program during the spring heavy rainfall and snow melt period in States that have rivers draining into the Missouri River below the Gavins Point Dam. (Sec. 507) Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to proceed without delay with facilities construction pursuant to the final Biological Opinion for the Animas-La Plata project, Colorado and New Mexico, dated October 25, 1991, in order to ensure timely implementation of the Colorado Ute Indian Water Rights Settlement Act of 1988. (Sec. 508) Authorizes the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration to dispose of excess Federal electric power: (1) outside the Pacific Northwest, if certain conditions are met; and (2) in any region without specified statutory prohibition on resale. Requires the Northwest Power and Conservation Planning Council to report to the Congress on the most appropriate governance structure for more effective regional control over conservation efforts affecting anadromous and resident fish and wildlife within the Federal Columbia River Power System. Authorizes the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works, acting through the North Pacific Division of the Corps of Engineers, to place orders for goods and services related to facilities for electric power generation and fish and wildlife mitigation associated with the Federal Columbia River Power System with and through the Administrator using the available authorities. Declares that in spite of certain statutory rates, the cost benefits of eligible utilities' total purchase and exchange sales shall be $145 million for FY 1997, and the net benefits paid to each eligible electric utility shall be $145 million multiplied by the percentage of the total of such net benefits paid by the Administrator to such utility for FY 1995. Authorizes the Administrator to offer employees voluntary separation incentives not to exceed $25,000. Provides that recipients who accept Federal employment within five years after separation must repay the entire amount to the Bonneville Power Administration. (Sec. 509) Amends the Magnetic Fusion Energy Engineering Act to repeal the mandate for establishment of a technical panel on magnetic fusion of the Energy Research Advisory Board to review the conduct of the national magnetic fusion energy program. (Sec. 510) Mandates specified water levels at dams at International Falls and Kettle Falls, Minnesota, in Rainy Lake and Namakan Lake, respectively. Confers enforcement authority for such water levels upon the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</summary>
</bill>
