<bill session="108" type="h" number="2709" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Election Administration Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to replace the Federal Election Commission with the Federal Election Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2003-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2003-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2003-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1388"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Election fraud"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2003--Introduced.
Federal Election Administration Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to create a new independent establishment, the Federal Election Administration (FEA), replacing the Federal Election Commission (FEC), with enhanced authority to enforce Federal campaign finance laws, while leaving reporting and disclosure provisions largely the same. Gives the FEA exclusive jurisdiction with respect to the civil enforcement of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, the Presidential Election Campaign Fund Act, and the Presidential Primary Matching Payment Account Act. Requires under this new system for the Administration to be composed of three members, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, one of whom shall serve as the Chair of the Administration, while the two other members are prohibited from being affiliated with the same political party. Requires the Chair to be appointed for a term of ten years, while the two other members shall be appointed for a term of six years, with one of the initial members appointed for a term of three years. Imposes on members a general one-term limitation. Bars present and former FEC members and others from the regulated community as well as individuals employed in certain executive branch positions from serving as FEA members. Requires enforcement proceedings for violations of campaign finance laws to be conducted before administrative law judges. Allows any final determination made by an administrative law judge to be appealed to the FEA for final agency action, subject to judicial review. Includes under the enhanced authority of the FEA to enforce Federal campaign laws the authority to impose civil penalties, issue cease-and-desist orders, and to report apparent violations to the appropriate law enforcement authorities. Allows the FEA to conduct audits and field examinations of campaign committees. Directs the Comptroller General to conduct: (1) an examination of the enforcement of Federal campaign finance laws by the Attorney General for a report to the Attorney General and Congress; and (2) an ongoing study on the level of funding that constitutes an adequate level of resources for the FEA to competently execute its responsibilities, for reports to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and Congress.</summary>
</bill>
