<bill session="106" type="h" number="4208" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Recruiting, Retention, and Reservist Promotion Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expedite the implementation of the per diem allowance for members of the Armed Forces subjected to lengthy or numerous deployments, to extend the allowance to the Coast Guard, and to reevaluate the eligibility criteria for the allowance, to require a study on the need for a tax credit for businesses that employ members of the National Guard and Reserve, and to require a study on the expansion of the Junior ROTC and similar military programs for young people.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400157"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6475-6476"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="High school students"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Morale"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax incentives"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2000--Introduced.
Recruiting, Retention, and Reservist Promotion Act of 2000 - Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000 to require an authorized per diem allowance for members who are deployed 251 days or more out of the preceding 365 days to take effect on the first day of the month after enactment of this Act (currently, October 1, 2001.) Makes eligible for such allowance members of the Coast Guard when not operating as a service of the Navy.Directs the Secretary of Defense to study and report to Congress on the extent to which such allowance is being paid to regular and reserve personnel, its effect on morale and retention rates, and the feasibility of establishing a reduced eligibility threshold for members of National Guard and reserve units serving on active duty of more than 30 days. Authorizes the Secretary, after such study, to reduce the threshold below 251 days (requiring congressional notification of any such change).Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress on the possibility of tax credits or small business loan incentives for businesses that employ National Guard and reserve personnel.Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the feasibility and desirability of expanding the Junior Reserve Officers' Training Corps of each military department, the Civil Air Patrol, the Naval Sea Cadet Corps, and the Young Marines.</summary>
</bill>
