<bill session="105" type="h" number="2417" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-09-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fight Hospital Fraud in Medicare Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Social Security Act to fight fraud by hospitals under the Medicare Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/5/1997--Introduced.
Fight Hospital Fraud in Medicare Act of 1997 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to devise plans for random investigations of hospitals for potential violations of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA). Directs the Administrator of the Health Care Financing Administration to establish a program to educate hospitals on compliance with Medicare regulations. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to the Congress on the extent to which fines, settlements, and overpayments under the Medicare program are associated with for-profit hospitals. Amends SSA title XVIII to authorize the Secretary to impose fees for hospital agreements, except in the case of for-profit hospitals, with respect to which the Secretary is required to impose such fees. Requires that collected fees be credited to a special fund in the Treasury to remain available until expended for specified purposes. Outlines similar provisions for fees for issuance of standard health care identifiers.</summary>
</bill>
