<bill session="108" type="h" number="4068" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State and Local Government Election Administration Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to postpone the deadline by which a State is required to meet the election administration requirements of the Act until the total amount appropriated to the State for requirements payments under the Act is equal to or greater than the costs incurred by the State in meeting such requirements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Federal mandates"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2004--Introduced.
State and Local Government Election Administration Act of 2004 - Amends the the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to postpone the deadline by which a State is required to meet the election administration requirements of the Act until the total amount appropriated to the State for requirements payments under the Act is equal to or greater than the costs incurred by the State in meeting such requirements. Declares that no State (or local government) shall be required to meet any of such election administration requirements until the later of: (1) the first day of the first calendar year which begins after the aggregate amount appropriated to the State for requirements payments for all fiscal years is equal to or greater than the costs incurred by the State in meeting such requirements; or (2) the applicable date otherwise provided.</summary>
</bill>
