<bill session="104" type="h" number="2353" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-02-13">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to extend certain expiring authorities of the Department of Veterans Affairs relating to delivery of health and medical care, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An Act to amend title 38, United States Code, to extend the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out certain programs and activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300151"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="1995-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404142" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407838" joined="1995-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1995-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1995-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-09-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-10-12T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 104-275.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-10-12T17:08:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="144">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 144.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-10-17T16:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Stump moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-17T16:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10113-10116, H10118" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-17T16:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-17T16:27:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-17T17:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-10-17T17:44:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="716" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays (2/3 required): 403 - 0 (Roll No. 716).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-10-17T17:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05">
      <text>Senate Committee on Veterans discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 991 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1996-01-05" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 991 with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S108" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-01-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-25T19:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Stump asked unanimous consent that the House agree with amendments to the Senate amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-25T19:56:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House agree with amendments to the Senate amendments Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H901-903" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-25T19:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-26">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at the desk: House amendments to Senate amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-01-30" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendments to Senate amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR  S566" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1996-01-30">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1996-01-31">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-02-13">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-02-13" type="public" number="104-110">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-110.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1536"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1565"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2219"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2322"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="104" type="s" number="991"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="991"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="104" type="s" number="991"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Anesthetics"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flags"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Gulf War syndrome"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mentally ill"/>
    <term name="Missing in action"/>
    <term name="Mortgage interest rates"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Occupational therapy"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf War"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/1996--House agreed to Senate amendment with amendment.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Extensions of Authority Title II: Other Provisions Title I: Extensions of Authority - Extends through December 31, 1996, the authority of the Department of Veterans Affairs to: (1) provide priority hospital care and medical services to Persian Gulf veterans exposed to toxic substances or environmental hazards during such service; (2) provide outpatient services to such veterans; and (3) guarantee the payment of principal and interest on certificates or other securities evidencing an interest in a pool of Department-guaranteed mortgage loans made in connection with the sale of properties represented by such loans. Extends through December 31, 1997, Department authority to: (1) contract with community-based treatment facilities for the care of eligible veterans suffering from alcohol or drug dependence or abuse disabilities; (2) provide a pilot program for furnishing veterans with noninstitutional alternatives to nursing home care; (3) enter into agreements with nonprofit organizations and State and local governments to assist homeless veterans and their families to obtain shelter; (4) provide a health professionals scholarship program; (5) enter into enhanced use leases of Department real property; and (6) use data on local compensation rates for determining the pay rates of certified registered nurse anesthetists. Repeals a Federal provision authorizing: (1) the veteran and the mortgagee to negotiate the interest rate on a Department-guaranteed loan; and (2) a lender on such a loan to appraise the property which is the basis for the loan. Amends the Veterans' Benefits and Services Act of 1988 to extend through December 31, 1997, the authority to use community-based residential care for the treatment of homeless chronically mentally ill veterans and other veterans. Extends through such date the Department's compensated work therapy and therapeutic transitional housing program. Amends the Homeless Veterans Comprehensive Service Programs Act of 1992 to extend through September 30, 1997, the authority for a pilot program (and grants made under the program) to expand and improve Department benefits and services to homeless veterans. Amends the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act to extend through December 31, 1997, the authority for homeless veterans' reintegration projects. Ratifies any actions taken by the Secretary before the enactment of this Act during any periods of expired authority for programs and projects amended by this Act. Title II: Other Provisions - Requires, within an annual fiscal report from the Secretary to the Congress, the inclusion of a discussion of Department housing and small business loans made to veterans. Repeals superseded reporting requirements under the Veterans Home Loan Program Amendments of 1992. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress: (1) on the advantages and disadvantages of consolidating into one program the alcohol and drug abuse program, the program to provide community-based residential care to homeless chronically mentally ill veterans, and the demonstration program of compensated work therapy and therapeutic transitional housing; (2) the results of a study evaluating the operation of the health professionals scholarship program; and (3) evaluating the operation of the Department's real property enhanced use lease program. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into contracts for the provision of utilities to the Audie L. Murphy Memorial Hospital in San Antonio, Texas. Outlines contract requirements, including a contract term limit of no more than 35 years. Allows such contracts only to the extent provided for in advance in appropriations Acts.</summary>
</bill>
