<bill session="108" type="h" number="2933" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-07-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Critical Habitat Reform Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Critical Habitat Reform Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to reform the process for designating critical habitat under that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400026" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400066" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2004-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2004-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2003-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400302" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400303" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2004-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="2004-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2004-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400336" joined="2004-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2004-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2003-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 14.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T19:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-786.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-11-19T19:46:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="480">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 480.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local budgets"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State budgets"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2004--Reported to House amended.
Critical Habitat Reform Act of 2004 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (ESA) to require the relevant Secretary (the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce), to the maximum extent practicable, prudent, and determinable, to issue a final regulation designating critical habitat of endangered or threatened species within one year after final approval of a recovery plan for the species or three years after publication of the final regulation implementing the endangered or threatened species determination, whichever is earlier. Requires the Secretary to reconsider any determination that designation of critical habitat of a species is not practicable or determinable during the next five-year review of endangered or threatened species or at the time of final approval of a recovery plan for the species. Authorizes the Secretary to revise any designation of critical habitat. Prohibits any designation of an area as critical habitat from applying with respect to actions authorized by: (1) a permit under ESA provisions authorizing the otherwise prohibited taking of listed species in certain circumstances where a habitat conservation plan has been submitted; (2) a written statement issued by the Secretary pursuant to a Federal agency consultation process; or (3) a land conservation or species management program of a State, Federal agency, federally recognized Indian tribe within the contiguous 48 States, or the Metlakatla Indian Community that the Secretary determines provides habitat protection substantially equivalent to the protection that would be provided by species designation. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary, in determining whether an area is critical habit, to seek and consider information from State and local governments in the vicinity of the area, including local resource data and maps. Specifies factors for consideration regarding the economic impact of critical habitat designation, including changes in revenues and costs associated with preparing reports, surveys, and analyses. Requires the Secretary, in making such a designation, to first consider all areas known to be within the geographical area occupied by the species as determined by field survey data. (Sec. 4) Modifies the contents of the required notice of proposed designation of critical habit to include any municipality having administrative jurisdiction over the area in which the species is believed to occur. Requires the Secretary, with respect to a regulation to designate or revise a designation of critical habitat, to: (1) publish and maintain, on a publicly accessible Internet page of the relevant Department (Interior or Commerce), maps, coordinates, and field survey data of the area; and (2) include in such notice a reference to the Internet page. (Sec. 5) Redefines "critical habitat" to mean those specific areas: (1) within the geographical area determined by field survey data to be occupied by the species at the time of critical habitat designation, on which are found those physical and biological features necessary to avoid jeopardizing the continued existence of (currently, essential to the conservation of) the species and which may require special management considerations or protections; and (2) areas not within such geographical area but essential for the survival of the species.</summary>
</bill>
