<bill session="104" type="h" number="3841" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27T18:28:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-09-27T18:28:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Omnibus Civil Service Reform Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Thrift Savings Investment Funds Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Thrift Savings Plan Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Omnibus Civil Service Reform Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Thrift Savings Investment Funds Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Thrift Savings Plan Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Omnibus Civil Service Reform Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the civil service laws of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1996-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1996-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1190"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-07-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 104-831.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-09-24T18:43:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="455">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 455.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11340-11352, H11355-11356" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="1996-09-26T19:19:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="444" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 224 - 201 (Roll no. 444).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica asked unanimous consent to consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11547-11565" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-09-27T18:28:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27T18:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Administrative responsibility"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Civil service system"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employee-management relations in government"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government employees' life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Magistrates"/>
    <term name="Marriage"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Municipal officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Personal loans"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Relocation of employees"/>
    <term name="Retirement age"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Seniority in employment"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Supervisors"/>
    <term name="Support of dependents"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1392"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Demonstration Projects Title II: Performance Management Enhancement Title III: Enhancement of Thrift Savings Plan and Certain Other Benefits Title IV: Reorganization Flexibility Title V: Soft-Landing Provisions Title VI: Miscellaneous Omnibus Civil Service Reform Act of 1996 - Title I: Demonstration Projects - Amends Federal law provisions concerning government organization to modify certain provisions concerning demonstration projects, including: (1) revising the authority of agencies concerning such projects; and (2) increasing the number of projects which may be in effect at any one time. Title II: Performance Management Enhancement - Prohibits an appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board with respect to a denial of a periodic step-increase. Changes standards for performance ratings concerning such increases, including those affecting the Library of Congress. (Sec. 202) Modifies the performance appraisal system requirements to limit an employee to a single opportunity to demonstrate acceptable performance. (Sec. 203) Amends provisions respecting cash awards honoring invention or superior accomplishment, including: (1) eliminating any reference to the District of Columbia; and (2) permitting such awards to a group. (Sec. 204) Eliminates the authority of an arbitrator, in a negotiated grievance, to order an agency to take specified disciplinary actions. (Sec. 205) Directs OPM to collect information on training programs within the Government and to submit a report to the Congress on an annual basis. Permits OPM to: (1) collect information on training programs utilized outside the Government and; (2) on request, make such information available. Title III: Enhancement of Thrift Savings Plan and Certain Other Benefits - Provides for loans for furloughed employees under the Thrift Savings Plan. (Sec. 302) Requires that Federal life insurance benefits which would otherwise be paid under the specified order of preference be paid to another person, if there is a domestic relations court order in effect. (Sec. 303) Continues unreduced additional optional life insurance for certain employees in accordance with the employee's written election at the time eligibility to continue insurance during retirement or receipt of compensation arises. Title IV: Reorganization Flexibility - Revises provisions under which the head of an Executive agency or military department (currently, military only), until September 30, 2001, (currently, September 30, 1996) may: (1) separate any employee volunteering to separate (except for an employee with critical skills) whether or not such employee is subject to separation due to a reduction in force; and (2) retain an employee, for each such employee voluntarily separated, in a similar position who would otherwise be separated due to a reduction in force. (Sec. 402) Authorizes nonreimbursable details within Executive agencies and military departments before a reduction in force. Title V: Soft-Landing Provisions - Permits an involuntarily separated employee to make payments which will continue his or her Federal life insurance coverage for up to 18 months following the separation. (Sec. 502) Makes provisions for the continued eligibility of involuntarily separated Federal employees for health insurance. (Sec. 503) Authorizes the establishment of a program to provide job placement and counseling services to current and former employees. (Sec. 504) Authorizes non-Federal employment incentive payments for education and retraining. Sets forth: (1) definitions; and (2) a limitation on the total amount paid to any individual relating to educational assistance. Title VI: Miscellaneous - Authorizes the use of appropriated funds to reimburse qualified Federal employees for up to 50 percent of the costs of a limited amount of professional liability insurance. (Sec. 602) Requires a contractor to offer the right of first refusal of employment to the former Federal employee whose position was abolished because of the conversion of his or her duties to contract. (Sec. 603) Revises provisions regarding the debarment of any health care provider found to have engaged in fraudulent practices, including requiring (currently, permitting) debarment for certain fraudulent practices. (Sec. 604) Amends the FEGLI Living Benefits Act to provide for the continuation of health benefits coverage for individuals enrolled in a plan administered by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System before the plan's termination on January 1, 1997. (Sec. 605) Amends the Omnibus Consolidated Rescissions and Appropriations Act of 1996 to direct the United States Enrichment Corporation to pay to the Thrift Savings Fund required employee and agency contributions for those employees who elect to retain their coverage under the Civil Service Retirement System or the Federal Employees' Retirement System. (Sec. 606) Makes amendments relating to the health benefits program for Federal employees which: (1) modify the definition of a carrier; (2) specify that the Government-wide service benefit plan need not be underwritten by participating affiliates licensed in each State; and (3) revise preemption provisions. (Sec. 607) Sets and maintains the rate of basic pay for certain positions formerly classified at GS-18 of the General Schedule at the rate equal to the highest rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service. (Sec. 608) Amends Federal law to repeal the requirement that the Civil Service Commission keep minutes of its proceedings. (Sec. 609) Extends to employees of the Federal Bureau of Investigation certain procedural and appeal rights with respect to certain adverse personnel actions.</summary>
</bill>
