<bill session="106" type="h" number="4508" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Excellence in Economic Education Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend programs and activities under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="2000-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400578" joined="2000-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="2000-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2000-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2000-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic theory"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Personal budgets"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student activities"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2000--Introduced.
Excellence in Economic Education Act of 2000 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to establish a program for excellence in economic education under title X (Programs of National Significance).(Sec. 1) Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award a grant to the National Council on Economic Education (the grantee), a nonprofit educational organization.Requires the grantee to reserve certain amounts for States that do not have designated recipients.Requires the grantee to use one-quarter of the grant amount (after such reservation) to: (1) strengthen and expand the grantee's nationwide network on economic education; (2) support and promote training of teachers who teach a grade from kindergarten through grade 12 regarding economics; (3) support research on effective teaching practices and the development of assessment instruments to document student performance; (4) develop and disseminate appropriate materials to foster economic literacy; and (5) coordinate activities assisted under this Act with activities assisted under of ESEA title II (Dwight D. Eisenhower Professional Development Program).Requires the grantee to award grants to State economic education councils, or in the case of a State that does not have a State economic education council, a center for economic education (a recipient). Requires that such a grant pay for the Federal share of the cost of enabling the recipient to work in partnership with one or more specified educational entities for one or more of the following purposes: (1) collaboratively establishing and conducting teacher training programs that use effective and innovative approaches to the teaching of economics; (2) providing resources to school districts that want to incorporate economics into the curricula of their schools; (3) evaluating the impact of economic education on students; (4) conducting economic education research; (5) creating and conducting school-based student activities to promote consumer, economic, and personal finance education, such as saving, investing, and entrepreneurial education, and to encourage awareness and student achievement in economics; (6) establishing interstate and international student and teacher exchanges to promote economic literacy; and (7) encouraging replication of best practices to encourage economic literacy.Sets forth requirements for recipients in carrying out teacher training programs under this Act.Encourages the grantee and recipients, in carrying out assisted activities under this Act, to: (1) include interactions with the local business community to the fullest extent possible, to reinforce the connection between economic education and economic development; and (2) work with private businesses to obtain matching contributions for Federal funds and assist recipients in working toward self-sufficiency.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
