<bill session="104" type="h" number="2051" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care Accessibility Expansion Act of 1993</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to restore the deduction for the health insurance costs of self-employed individuals, to provide incentives for certain medical practitioners to practice in rural areas, to provide for the creation of medical savings accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400012"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Catastrophic health insurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Osteopathy and osteopaths"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/1995--Introduced.
Health Care Accessibility Expansion Act of 1993 (sic) - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase the allowable deduction for health insurance costs of self-employed individuals from 25 percent to 100 percent; and (2) make the deduction permanent. Allows a tax credit for a medical practitioner who commences a medical practice in a rural area. Allows such credit for the year such commencement occurs and the four succeeding taxable years. Limits such credit to $5,000. Requires the taxpayer to practice medicine in the rural area for at least nine months in a taxable year. Allows a deduction on medical education loan interest of a physician which accrues while the physician is living in and providing medical care to residents of a rural area. Allows individuals a tax deduction for contributions made to a medical care savings account established for the benefit of an eligible individual. Defines an eligible individual as: (1) one who is not covered by an employer-provided group health plan; or (2) one who is covered by such a plan which is a qualified catastrophic coverage health plan and is not covered by any other health plan. Exempts such accounts from taxation. Allows such deduction in arriving at adjusted gross income. Establishes an excise tax for excess contributions to medical care savings accounts and makes such accounts subject to the tax on prohibited transactions. Allows the transfer of unused amounts in flexible spending accounts of cafeteria plans to medical savings accounts. Establishes a program under which eligible participants in medical savings accounts may obtain health insurance vouchers to make payments for qualified medical expenses. Allows a tax credit for the amount of such vouchers. Declares that it shall not be considered a violation of antitrust laws for hospitals to jointly undertake the purchasing, contracting for, or sharing of high technology equipment and services. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require demonstration projects to assist hospitals in acquiring and sharing such equipment and services. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1993 through 1996 for such projects.</summary>
</bill>
