<bill session="104" type="h" number="1904" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural America Health Care Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for various programs relating to improving the health of rural populations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411677"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1995-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1299"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulances"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Midwives"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Regional medical programs"/>
    <term name="Rural hospitals"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Provisions Relating to Public Health Service Act Title II: Provisions Relating to Medicare Title III: Tax Incentives for Health Services Providers Rural America Health Care Improvement Act - Title I: Provisions Relating to Public Health Service Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1996 through FY 1998. Requires allocations from such amounts in order to ensure that 20 percent of the participants in the Scholarship and Loan Repayment Program are being educated as specified nonphysician health professionals. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to public and nonprofit private entities for carrying out projects to develop health plans to provide services exclusively in rural and frontier areas. Sets forth requirements for those requesting grant assistance. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to public and nonprofit private hospitals in medically underserved rural communities for the purpose of carrying out projects to develop or increase the capacity of the hospitals and facilities to provide primary health services. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes appropriations for training of rural health professionals other than physicians. Title II: Provisions Relating to Medicare - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to increase the amount of payment to primary care service providers in underserved areas. Title III: Tax Incentives for Health Services Providers - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for certain primary health services providers in health professional shortage areas who have not received a National Health Service Corps scholarship or loan.</summary>
</bill>
