<bill session="106" type="h" number="4908" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Notice of Electronic Monitoring Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for the disclosure of electronic monitoring of employee communications and computer usage in the workplace.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="2000-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2898"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2000--Introduced.
Notice of Electronic Monitoring Act - Declares that an employer who intentionally, by any electronic means, monitors any wire, oral, or electronic communication of an employee, or otherwise monitors an employee's computer usage, without first having provided the employee specified notice, shall be liable to the employee for relief. Provides an exception where the employer has reasonable grounds to believe that an employee is engaged in conduct that violates the legal rights of, or involves significant harm to, the employer or another person.Requires an employer: (1) after first providing notice of such electronic monitoring, to provide annual notice to all employees who are subject to such monitoring; and (2) before implementing a material change in such an electronic monitoring practice, to provide notice to all employees who are subject to such monitoring as a result of the change.Allows any person aggrieved by any act in violation of this Act to bring an action in a U.S. district court. Sets limits on monetary damages awarded.</summary>
</bill>
