<bill session="104" type="h" number="3781" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to update its report on hate speech, especially as it relates to hate speech on the Internet, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Antisemitism"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Hate speech"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Prejudice"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Racism"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/1996--Introduced.
Amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to require the National Telecommunications Information Administration (NTIA), with the assistance of the Federal Communications Commission, the Department of Justice, and the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, to report to specified congressional committees on: (1) the use of the Internet and other interactive communications media for the dissemination of propaganda advocating hatred on the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, or sex; (2) the extent to which such propaganda is accessible to minors and the extent to which software or other measures are available to protect minors from such propaganda; and (3) any recommendations that such agencies deem appropriate.</summary>
</bill>
