<bill session="112" type="h" number="6582" updated="2013-07-14T19:20:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Energy Manufacturing Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">American Energy Manufacturing Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">American Energy Manufacturing Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">American Energy Manufacturing Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To allow for innovations and alternative technologies that meet or exceed desired energy efficiency goals, and to make technical corrections to existing Federal energy efficiency laws to allow American manufacturers to remain competitive.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2012-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2012-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2012-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2012-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2012-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2012-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2012-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2012-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2012-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2012-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2012-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2012-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2012-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-04T12:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Whitfield moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-04T12:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6599-6606" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-04T12:32:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6582.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-04T13:04:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-04T13:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6607" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-12-04T14:11:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="614" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 398 - 2, 1 Present (Roll no. 614).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6599-6602" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-12-04T14:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2012-12-06" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7688" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-12-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2012-12-12">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2012-12-18">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2012-12-18" type="public" number="112-210">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-210.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="482"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4850"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="156"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government investigations"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/2/2012--Introduced.
American Energy Manufacturing Technical Corrections Act - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to exempt a walk-in cooler or walk-in freezer component manufactured on or after January 1, 2009, from the requirement that it contain wall, ceiling, and door insulation of at least R-25 for coolers and R-32 for freezers, if the manufacturer has demonstrated to the Secretary of Energy (DOE) that such component reduces energy consumption at least as much as if such requirement were to apply. Requires the Secretary to publish a rule that establishes a uniform efficiency descriptor and accompanying test methods for covered water heaters (water heaters, storage water heaters, instantaneous water heaters, and unfired water storage tanks). Declares that the purpose of such rule is to replace with a uniform efficiency descriptor: (1) the energy factor descriptor for water heaters established under such Act; and (2) the thermal efficiency and standby loss descriptors for storage water heaters, instantaneous water heaters, and unfired water storage tanks established under such rule. Requires the efficiency standard for covered water heaters to be denominated according to the efficiency descriptor established by such rule. Requires the Secretary to develop a mathematical conversion factor for converting the measurement of efficiency for such heaters from the test procedures in effect on this Act's enactment to the new energy descriptor established under this Act. Considers a covered water heater to be in compliance with such rule and with any revised labeling requirements established by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to implement such rule if the covered water heater: (1) was manufactured prior to the effective date of the rule, and (2) complied with the efficiency standards and labeling requirements in effect prior to the rule. Establishes energy efficiency standards for: (1) daily energy consumption of service over the counter, self-contained, medium temperature commercial refrigerators; and (2) through-the-wall central air conditioners, through-the-wall central air conditioning heat pumps, and small duct, high velocity systems. Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide notice on whether energy efficiency standards for specified commercial heating and cooling equipment will be amended every six years, (2) evaluate each class of such equipment, (3) provide notice of a decision to grant or deny a petition to amend energy conservation standards, and (4) publish a rule that contains new or amended energy conservation standards every three years.</summary>
</bill>
