<bill session="104" type="h" number="2934" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Taxpayer Savings Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To eliminate certain Federal programs and subsidies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401547"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy and Poultry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Resource Conservation, Research and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Risk Management and Specialty Crops.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy and Poultry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG25" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG26" subcommittee="Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG27" subcommittee="Resource Conservation, Research and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG24" subcommittee="Risk Management and Specialty Crops" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Acreage allotments"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alcohol tax"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy tax credits"/>
    <term name="Export subsidies"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Farm production quotas"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Marketing orders"/>
    <term name="Methanol"/>
    <term name="Peanuts"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Sugar and sugar trade"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/1996--Introduced.
Taxpayer Savings Act of 1996 - Amends Federal law to repeal or eliminate the following: (1) the commercial export market promotion program and the export enhancement program, both established and operated by the Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) under the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978; (2) certain animal damage control activities under the Rural Development, Agriculture, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1986; and (3) the tax credit under the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) for the use and production of ethanol as a fuel and other incentives (including reduced tax rates) for the use and production of ethanol (requiring fuel alcohol to be taxed in the same manner as other motor fuels). Imposes a floor stocks tax rate of 18.4 cents a gallon on fuel alcohol held on the date of enactment of this Act. Outlines liability for such tax and the method and time of payment. Prohibits the imposition of such tax: (1) on fuel alcohol held in the tank of a motor vehicle or motorboat; and (2) when the aggregate amount of fuel held by a person (including certain corporations) does not exceed 2,000 gallons. Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 to terminate the agricultural price support and production adjustment programs for sugar beets and sugarcane. Terminates the acreage allotments and marketing quotas for such products under the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938. Prohibits the Secretary of Agriculture from making price supports available for crops of sugar beets or sugarcane by using CCC funds or under any other law. Requires the Secretary to settle outstanding loans. Terminates the peanut marketing quota and peanut price support programs under the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 and the Agricultural Act of 1949. Prohibits the Secretary from making future price supports for peanut crops. Requires the Secretary to settle outstanding loans.</summary>
</bill>
