<bill session="107" type="h" number="5713" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax Technical Corrections Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make technical corrections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2002-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-11-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="3153"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Options (Contract)"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/13/2002--Introduced.
Tax Technical Corrections Act of 2002 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to make technical corrections to the Job Creation and Worker Assistance Act of 2002 concerning: (1) the special depreciation allowance for certain property acquired after September 10, 2001 and before September 11, 2004; (2) the application of the temporary suspension of the 90 percent alternative minimum taxable income limit on certain carrybacks of net operating losses; (3) certain tax benefits for areas of New York City which sustained damage from the terrorist acts of September 11, 2001; (4) the interest rate range for certain additional funding requirements under the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA); and (5) a technical correction to the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001.Makes technical corrections to the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 concerning: (1) modifications to educational individual retirement accounts (IRAs); (2) an increase in benefit and contribution limits for defined benefit plans; and (3) a waiver of tax for nondeductible contributions to domestic and similar workers.Makes technical corrections to the Victims of Terrorism Tax Relief Act of 2001 concerning the disclosure of tax information in terrorism and national security investigations.Makes technical corrections to the Community Renewal Tax Relief Act of 2000 concerning the tax treatment of securities futures contracts.Makes technical corrects to the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997 concerning constructive sales treatment for appreciated financial positions and the extension and modification of taxes funding the Airport and Airway Trust Fund.Redefines valid taxpayer identification number for the earned income credit.</summary>
</bill>
