<bill session="108" type="h" number="3751" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-21T14:46:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-06-21T14:46:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require that the Office of Personnel Management study and present options under which dental and vision benefits could be made available to Federal employees and retirees and other appropriate classes of individuals.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To require that the Office of Personnel Management study current practices under which dental, vision, and hearing benefits are made available to Federal employees, annuitants, and other classes of individuals, and to require that the Office also present options and recommendations relating to how additional dental, vision, and hearing benefits could be made so available.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2004-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service and Agency Organization.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-04-01">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17T20:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 108-552.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-06-17T20:10:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="320">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 320.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-06-21T14:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Miller (MI) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-21T14:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4599-4600" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-21T14:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3751.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-06-21T14:46:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4599" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-06-21T14:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-21T14:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO18" subcommittee="Civil Service and Agency Organization" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Eye care"/>
    <term name="Eye diseases"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hearing aids"/>
    <term name="Hearing disorders"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2004--Passed House amended.
Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to submit to Congress a report describing and evaluating options whereby additional dental, vision (including glaucoma screening), and hearing benefits could be made available to Federal employees and annuitants, their relatives, and other appropriate classes of individuals. Requires that such report include: (1) a description of the dental, vision, and hearing benefits currently available under the Federal Employees Health Benefits (FEHB) program; (2) a description of the supplemental dental, vision, and hearing plans currently offered by carriers participating in the FEHB program; (3) a description of specific dental, vision, and hearing benefits that could be offered in addition to those specified above; (4) a description of the specific classes of the individuals to whom those additional benefits should be made available; (5) a description and assessment of the various contracting arrangements by which the Government could make those additional benefits available; (6) the estimated cost of those additional benefits; (7) a description of how those additional benefits could be made available through FEHB, one or more plans outside of FEHB, FEHB in combination with one or more of such plans, and any other dental, vision, and hearing coverage delivery method; (8) an analysis of the advantages and disadvantages associated with the alternatives described in clause seven; (9) a recommendation from OPM as to its preferred method(s) for providing those additional benefits; and (10) any proposed legislation or other measures the Office considers necessary in order to implement any of the foregoing.</summary>
</bill>
