<bill session="105" type="h" number="3842" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Surplus Property Improvement Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that certain Federal property shall be made available to States for State use before being made available to other entities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400316"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on National Security, Small Business, International Relations, and Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Basic Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Basic Research" name="House Science"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="h" number="4010"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="1621"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientific instruments and apparatus"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/1998--Introduced.
Federal Surplus Property Improvement Act of 1998 - Requires that nonlethal excess supplies of the Department of Defense be made available to a State or a local government upon request before such supplies are made available for humanitarian relief purposes. Permits the President to make such supplies available for humanitarian purposes before they are made available to a State or local government in response to a natural disaster emergency. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, with respect to the transfer of property for environmental protection in foreign countries, to prohibit such transfers unless the Administrator of General Services (GSA Administrator) determines that there are no Federal or State use requirements for the property under any other provision of law. Amends the Small Business Act to: (1) repeal the requirement permitting the transfer of U.S.-owned technology or surplus property to participants in the small business and capital ownership development program on a priority basis; and (2) subject to the oversight of the GSA Administrator, in consultation with State agencies responsible for surplus property distribution, the transfer of such technology or surplus property to program participants. Repeals the authority of the Secretary of Energy to transfer surplus equipment to an educational institution with which it has a partnership agreement. Requires the Administrator of General Services to report to the Congress on the effectiveness of surplus personal property donation and disposal programs (except for any program that grants access to personal property by local communities affected by the closure of a military base), along with recommendations for consolidating such programs under a single Federal authority.</summary>
</bill>
