<bill session="104" type="h" number="3159" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-10-11">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Transportation Safety Board Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Intermodal Safe Container Transportation Amendments Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">National Transportation Safety Board Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Intermodal Safe Container Transportation Amendments Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">National Transportation Safety Board Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 1997, 1998, and 1999 for the National Transportation Safety Board, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1996-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1996-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1996-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="407817" joined="1996-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1996-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="1996-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-05-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-17T20:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 104-682.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-07-17T20:09:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="353">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 353.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-22T13:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Duncan moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-22T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8049-8052" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-22T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-22T13:38:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-22T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8074-8075" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-07-22T19:13:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="337" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays (2/3 required): 400 - 0 (Roll No. 337).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-07-22T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-07-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="508">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 508.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10898" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 1831 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1996-09-18" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 1831 with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Shuster moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-09-26T17:00:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11330-11334" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Con. Res. 221, enrollment corrections have been made.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1996-10-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-10-11">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-10-11" type="public" number="104-291">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-291.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hc" number="221"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hc" number="221"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="4040"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="1831"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="104" type="s" number="1831"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1831"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="104" type="s" number="1831"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Business intelligence"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Containerization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="National Transportation Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/1996--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: NTSB Amendments Title II: Intermodal Transportation Title I: NTSB Amendments - National Transportation Safety Board Amendments of 1996 - Amends Federal transportation law to prohibit the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) and any agency receiving information from it from disclosing: (1) records or information relating to its participation in foreign aircraft accident investigations, except in certain circumstances; or (2) voluntarily provided safety-related information unrelated to the exercise of the NTSB's accident or incident investigation authority, if disclosure would inhibit the voluntary provision of that type of information. (Sec. 104) Authorizes the NTSB to conduct training of its employees in subjects necessary for the proper performance of accident investigations. (Sec. 105) Authorizes appropriations to the Board through FY 1999. Title II: Intermodal Transportation - Intermodal Safe Container Transportation Amendments Act of 1996 - Amends Federal transportation law to revise the prior notification requirements for intermodal freight transportation. Requires a person who tenders to a first carrier that is a motor carrier (currently, any carrier) a container or trailer with a gross cargo weight of more than 29,000 pounds (currently, 10,000 pounds, including packing material and pallets) for intermodal transportation to give prior notification of the cargo weight and a reasonable description of its contents to the motor carrier. (Sec. 204) Allows such notification to be made by telephone, and allows the required certification of container or trailer contents to be electronic. Sets forth administrative and civil penalties for persons who inaccurately transfer certification information. (Sec. 205) Allows a motor carrier to presume that the gross cargo weight of a container or trailer is under 29,001 pounds if it receives no certification before or when a loaded intermodal container or trailer is tendered to it. Declares that a copy of a certification is not required to accompany the intermodal container or trailer. Requires a motor carrier that knows that the gross cargo weight of an intermodal container or trailer violates State vehicle weight laws to give notice to the operator of a leased vehicle that transports such items. Requires the motor carrier to reimburse the operator of the leased vehicle that is fined because of a violation of a State's gross vehicle weight laws. (Sec. 206) Adds to the circumstances giving certain persons a lien against the contents of the container or trailer as a result of a violation of a State's gross vehicle weight laws. Includes among such circumstances: (1) failure of the party required to provide certification of gross cargo weight to the first carrier to provide it; (2) failure of the party required to forward such certification to forward it; or (3) error in the transfer of information on the certification to another document.</summary>
</bill>
