<bill session="104" type="h" number="1748" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax Fairness for Farmers, Ranchers, and Small Businesses Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for farmers and closely held businesses a one-time exclusion of gain from certain sales or exchanges, for self-employed individuals a 100 percent deduction of health insurance costs, and for farmers a carryover of unused standard deductions and personal exemptions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="1995-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="411677" joined="1995-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-06-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1163"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Expatriation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family enterprises"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/1995--Introduced.
Tax Fairness for Farmers, Ranchers, and Small Businesses Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit a limited, one-time exclusion from gross income of up to $500,000 ($250,000 in a separate return of a married individual) of the gain from a single sale or exchange to a qualified buyer of qualified property. Defines "qualified property" as property that has been used by a seller over 55 years of age, or a family member, in farming or in a closely held business throughout the ten year period ending on the sale or exchange date. Defines "qualified buyer" as a buyer who is a lineal descendant of the seller, or a beginning farmer or rancher. Requires the seller to pay recapture taxes if within ten years after the sale or exchange the property is no longer used for the same farming or business purpose, unless the buyer is bankrupt or the initial income exclusion failed to reduce the seller's net tax. Increases from 30 percent to 100 percent the deduction for health insurance costs of self-employed individuals. Allows the carryover of unused personal exemptions and standard deductions for an individual whose income for the previous three years is at least 50 percent derived from engaging in continuous and substantial farming. Eliminates the possession tax credit granted income from sources within one of the U.S. territorial possessions. Alters the tax liability of a U.S. citizen who relinquishes his or her citizenship by considering certain property held at the time of relinquishment as sold at fair market value in order to tax any gain on that property. Requires that this additional taxed income: (1) be offset by a $600,000 exclusion from gross income; and (2) not include the value of U.S. real property (other than stock of a U.S. real property holding corporation), or any interest in certain specified domestic or (up to $500,000) foreign retirement and pension plans.</summary>
</bill>
