<bill session="105" type="hr" number="559" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-10T15:24:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-10T15:24:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Condemning the terror, vengeance, and human rights abuses against the civilian population of Sierra Leone.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400119"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1998-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1998-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1998-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T15:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T15:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10433-10434" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T15:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-10-10T15:24:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children's rights"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Compulsory military service"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Guinea"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Liberia"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military regimes"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Sierra Leone"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations economic assistance"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/1998--Passed House amended.
Urges the President and the Secretary of State to: (1) give high priority to solving the conflict in Sierra Leone and to bring stability to West Africa in general; (2) strictly enforce the United Nations (UN) arms embargo on the Armed Forces Revolutionary Council and Revolutionary United Front rebel forces; (2) work with Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) nations to ensure there are sufficient African forces and arms provided to ECOMOG (ECOWAS's military peacekeeping arm); and (3) support the UN High Commission for Refugees appeal for aid to the Sierra Leone refugees in Guinea, Liberia, and other countries. Urges the State Department and the UN to give the needed logistical support to ECOMOG and the Government of Sierra Leone to bring the conflict to a rapid conclusion. Condemns the use of children as combatants in the conflict. Urges the establishment of a secure humanitarian corridor to strategic areas in the north and east of Sierra Leone for the safe delivery of food and medicines by the Government of Sierra Leone and humanitarian agencies. Urges the President and the State Department to: (1) support the UN agencies and nongovernmental organizations working in Sierra Leone to bring humanitarian relief and peace to the country; and (2) support the Government of Sierra Leone in its demobilization, disarmament, and reconstruction plan for the country. Encourages and supports Olara Otunu, UN Special Representative of the Secretary General for Children and Armed Conflict, to continue in his efforts to work in Sierra Leone in the establishment of programs designed to rehabilitate child combatants.</summary>
</bill>
