<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="336" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:18-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2475" sequence="2"/>
  <status datetime="2005-06-21">offered</status>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-06-21"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the director of National Intelligence to provide written notice to Congress explaining the failure of the executive branch to implement the National Counterterrorism Center, as provided by law, by the deadlines imposed, including the failure by the President to nominate an individual to serve as Director of the National Counterterrorism Center.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment printed in part B of House Report 109-141 to require the President, if the National Counterterrorism Center (NCTC) is not fully operational by June 17, 2005, to provide Congress written justification as to why the Center is not fully operational. Justification would be required to be updated every thirty days until the NCTC is fully implemented and operational.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T15:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mrs. Maloney.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4852-4854" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4852" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T15:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Maloney amendment (A002) modified by unanimous consent. Modification changes the reporting requirements of the amendment by investing the responsibility for reporting in the Director of National Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T15:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A002) and on the bill pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T15:56:00-04:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the Maloney amendment (A002) as modified Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4853-4854" label="text of amendment as modified"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
