<bill session="106" type="h" number="4924" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-25T15:20:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-07-25T15:20:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Truth in Regulating Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a 3-year pilot project for the General Accounting Office to report to Congress on economically significant rules of Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="2000-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400410" joined="2000-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ryan (WI) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H6851-6855" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 4924.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-07-25T15:20:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H6851" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="4744"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2000--Introduced.
Truth in Regulating Act of 2000 - Provides that when a Federal agency (except an independent regulatory agency) publishes an economically significant rule, a chairman or ranking member of a committee of jurisdiction of either House of Congress may request the Comptroller General to review such rule. Defines "economically significant rule" to mean any proposed or final rule, including an interim or direct final rule, that may have an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more or adversely affect in a material way the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or State, local, or tribal governments or communities, or for which an agency has prepared an initial or final regulatory flexibility analysis. Requires the Comptroller General to submit a report on each rule reviewed, including an independent evaluation of an agency's analysis of the costs and benefits, and alternative approaches in the notice of proposed rulemaking and in the rulemaking record, as well as of any regulatory impact analysis, federalism assessment, or other analysis or assessment prepared by the agency or required for the rule, and the results of the evaluation and the implication of those results. Grants the Comptroller General discretion to develop procedures for determining the priority and number of requests for review.Authorizes appropriations for FY 2001 through 2003.Provides for the pilot project established under this Act to continue for a three-year period, if specified appropriations are provided. Requires the Comptroller General to report to Congress on such project's effectiveness and on whether it should be authorized permanently.</summary>
</bill>
