<bill session="105" type="h" number="1278" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY98-99, NOAA</title>
    <title type="popular">NOAA FY98-99 Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Authorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Authorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Oceanographic and Atmospheric Research Authorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for the activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for fiscal years 1998 and 1999, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400057"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1997-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1997-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1997-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1997-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-10">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-10">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-11">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-04-21T15:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Science, Space and Technology have until 6:00 p.m. on April 22 to file a report on H.R. 1278. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-22T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 105-66, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-22T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Resources Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 20, 1997.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-06-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-06-20T12:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-66, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-06-20T12:10:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="80">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 80.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric research"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Automation"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Capital budgets"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer programming"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Earth resources satellites"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood forecasting"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Geodesy"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Meteorological research"/>
    <term name="Meteorological satellites"/>
    <term name="Meteorology"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Ocean currents"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research ships"/>
    <term name="Oceanography"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development contracts"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Supercomputers"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Weather"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
    <term name="Year 2000 computer problem"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/1997--Reported to House amended, Part II.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Atmospheric, Weather, and Satellite Programs Title II: Oceanography and Marine Research Title III: Program Support and Other Accounts Title IV: Streamlining of Operations Title V: Miscellaneous Oceanographic and Atmospheric Research Authorization Act of 1997 - Title I: Atmospheric, Weather, and Satellite Programs - Authorizes appropriations for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) for: (1) National Weather Service (NWS) operations and research and public warning and forecast; (2) the Advanced Weather Interactive Processing System (AWIPS); (3) construction, repair, and modification regarding new and existing weather forecast offices; (4) restructuring of the National Meteorological Center into the National Centers for Environmental Prediction; (5) NEXRAD Weather Service Office maintenance. Amends the Weather Service Modernization Act to modify: (1) requirements regarding the restructuring of NWS field offices; and (2) the duties of the Modernization Transition Committee. Sets a termination date for the Committee. Encourages the NWS to form a working group with the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) regarding NWS operational use of FAA weather radar data. Requires that Department of Defense NEXRADs that provide primary detection coverage over a portion of their ranges function as fully committed, reliable elements (and be considered as integral parts) of the National Weather Radar Network. (Sec. 102) Authorizes appropriations for NOAA for: (1) climate and air quality research; (2) atmospheric research; (3) modifications to the Boulder Laboratory in Boulder, Colorado; (4) satellite observing systems; and (5) environmental data and information services. Title II: Oceanography and Marine Research - Authorizes appropriations for NOAA for: (1) the Coastal Ocean Program; (2) data acquisition activities of the Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research; (3) ocean remote sensing; (4) marine prediction research; (5) Arctic research; (6) the National Undersea Research Program; and (7) ocean services. Authorizes NOAA to participate in the National Oceanic Partnership Program established by the National Oceanic Partnership Act. Title III: Program Support and Other Accounts - Authorizes appropriations for NOAA for: (1) executive direction and administrative activities; (2) Systems Acquisition Office activities; (3) central administrative support; and (4) aircraft services. Reduces the amount authorized to be appropriated under this Act by specified amounts to reflect the use of prior year balances. Title IV: Streamlining of Operations - Prohibits appropriating funds for seven specified programs, including National Weather Service Regional Climate Centers and the Goddard Science Center. Mandates a report to specified congressional committees certifying that all seven will be terminated by a specified date. (Sec. 402) Limits the total dollar amounts authorized to be appropriated by this or any other Act for NOAA for all activities associated with operations, research, and facilities or for capital assets acquisition. Title V: Miscellaneous - Makes it unlawful for any unauthorized person to remove, move, damage, or interfere with any National Data Buoy Center weather data buoy. Provides for civil monetary penalties and rewards. (Sec. 502) Makes the Secretary of Commerce, through the NWS, responsible for: (1) forecasts, serving as the sole official source of weather and flood warnings; (2) issuance of storm warnings; (3) collection, exchange, and distribution of meteorological, hydrological, climatic, and oceanographic data and information; and (4) preparation of hydrometeorological guidance and core forecast information. Prohibits the NWS from competing (or assisting other entities in competing) with the private sector when a service is or can be provided by commercial enterprise unless the private sector is unwilling or unable to provide the service. Removes existing provisions relating to the duties of the Secretary regarding weather forecasting. Mandates a report to specified congressional committees detailing all NWS activities not conforming to this paragraph and outlining a timetable for their termination. (Sec. 504) Mandates notice to specified congressional committees of any reprogramming of funds authorized by this Act and of any NOAA major reorganization. (Sec. 505) Declares the sense of the Congress regarding NOAA handling of the year 2000 computer systems problem. (Sec. 506) Prohibits an entity from spending funds appropriated under this Act unless the entity agrees to comply with provisions of Federal law commonly known as the Buy American Act. Declares that it is the sense of the Congress that entities receiving financial assistance under this Act should spend the assistance to purchase only American-made equipment or products.</summary>
</bill>
