<bill session="105" type="h" number="3986" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Student and Teachers Excellence in Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve education, raise standards, and attract the best teachers to the public schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="1998-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Education)"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disabled students"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grading (Students)"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Tax Incentives for Teachers Title II: Other Incentives for Teachers Student and Teachers Excellence in Education Act - Title I: Tax Incentives for Teachers - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a nonrefundable tax credit of $2,000 (pro rated if appropriate) for full-time elementary and secondary public school teachers. (Sec. 102) Allows tax deductions of up to $2,000 for the expenses paid by elementary and secondary public school teachers in connection with receiving accreditation from National Board for Professional Teaching Standards. Title II: Other Incentives for Teachers - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for cancellation of student loans for public elementary and secondary school teachers, under the Federal Family Education Loan program and the direct student loan program, with rates of discharge based on one to three years of teaching service. (Sec. 202) Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to local educational agencies that have improved student achievement in mathematics and English as demonstrated by improved national standardized test results of students completing the 4th, 8th, and 12th grades. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 203) Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide for teacher technology training. Requires professional development activities to include instruction in the use of technology. Adds technology to the list of core subject areas for the National Teacher Training Project grants program (Dwight D. Eisenhower Professional Development Program). Requires local plans for improving teaching and learning to include descriptions of how their core subject area programs will incorporate technologies which meet the educational needs of individuals who are from historically underrepresented groups, or are economically disadvantaged, or have limited English language abilities, or have disabilities. Requires authorized professional development activities to incorporate effective technology for meeting the educational needs of diverse groups of students. Includes technological innovation as a higher education activity to improve teacher education programs. (Sec. 204) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) local educational agencies should use national standardized tests to evaluate student performance in mathematics and English at the end of each school year; and (2) schools should end social promotion of students to the next grade level.</summary>
</bill>
