<bill session="108" type="h" number="3302" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-10-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Debt Reduction and Fiscal Responsibility Restoration Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a deficit reduction account in the Treasury of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400394"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/15/2003--Introduced.
Debt Reduction and Fiscal Responsibility Restoration Act of 2003 - Establishes in the Treasury the Deficit Reduction Account, to be used by the Secretary of the Treasury to pay at maturity, or to redeem or buy before maturity, any obligation of the Government held by the public and included in the public debt. Requires the Secretary to report annually to each House of Congress on the amounts and dates of deposits into the Account and on the public debt redeemed during the previous year. Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide that it shall be in order, during the reading of an appropriation bill for amendment in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union, to consider en bloc amendments proposing only to reduce appropriations among objects in the bill and to appropriate an amount not greater than the amount so reduced to the Account.</summary>
</bill>
