<bill session="104" type="h" number="2218" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Farmland Preservation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an election to exclude from the gross estate of a decedent the value of certain land subject to a qualified conservation easement, and to make technical changes to alternative valuation rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400149"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Development rights transfer"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National seashores"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1995--Introduced.
Farmland Preservation Act of 1995 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from the gross estate tax the value of land subject to a qualified conservation easement (less the amount of any indebtedness secured by such land). Includes in the gross estate tax the value of each development right retained by the donor in the conveyance of the easement. Makes such tax due upon the disposition of the property. Provides that such land subject to the exclusion will have a carryover basis for purposes of determining gain or loss. Excludes from the gift tax transfers by gift of land subject to a conservation easement. Declares that for purposes of the alternative estate valuation method: (1) a qualified conservation contribution is not a disposition; and (2) land subject to a conservation easement is not disqualified.</summary>
</bill>
