<bill session="104" type="h" number="119" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the disclosure of lobbying activities to influence the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401947"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="1995-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Standards of Official Conduct</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E44"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Honoraria"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internal revenue law"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International propaganda"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Lobbying Disclosure Title II: Congressional Gift Rules Title I: Lobbying Disclosure - Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 - Requires registration with the Office of Lobbying Registration and Public Disclosure (Office) established by this Act by any individual lobbyist (or the individual's employer, if it employs one or more lobbyists) within 30 days after the individual first makes, or is employed or retained to make, a lobbying contact with either the President, the Vice President, a Member of Congress, or any other specified Federal officer or employee. Defines a lobbyist as any individual employed or retained by a client for financial or other compensation for services that include one or more lobbying contacts (but not an individual whose lobbying activities constitute less than ten percent of the time engaged in the services provided to that client). Provides for: (1) special registration filing rules in cases involving multiple clients and contacts; and (2) registration termination in cases where a registrant is no longer employed or retained by a client to conduct lobbying activities, and does not anticipate any additional lobbying activities for such client. (Sec. 104) Specifies the contents of such registration and reports. (Sec. 105) Requires registrants to file semiannual lobbying activity reports with the Office. Provides for: (1) exemptions from such registration and reporting requirements in cases involving lobbying income of $2,500 or less (for a particular client) or total expenses of $5,000 or less (for all lobbying activities) (adjusted periodically for inflation) for the semiannual period. Requires Office regulations to permit tax-exempt charitable organizations required to report lobbying expenses by the Internal Revenue Code to report, under this Act, only good faith estimates of such expenses in order to meet specified criteria for exemption from the reporting requirements of this Act. (Sec. 106) Provides for special rules generally prohibiting registrants under this Act and the Foreign Agents Registration Act from providing gifts (including meals, lodging, transportation, entertainment, reimbursements, loans, or forbearance) to any covered legislative branch official, or to the spouse, dependent, friend, or relative of such an official if it is given with the knowledge and acquiescence of such official and is given because of his or her position. Permits certain such items under prescribed circumstances, such as lawful political contributions and informational materials sent to the official's office, and gifts given for a nonbusiness purpose and motivated by family relationship or close personal friendship. (Sec. 107) Establishes the Office as an executive agency, and specifies its duties, including making public the semiannual lobbyist activity reports. (Sec. 108) Establishes procedures for: (1) determining and resolving alleged violations of this Act; and (2) judicial review of Office decisions. (Sec. 113) Amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to: (1) eliminate references to political propaganda and, in certain cases, replace them with references to informational materials; and (2) modify registration exemption provisions. (Sec. 114) Revises (Byrd Amendment) requirements for a declaration by persons requesting or receiving a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement with respect to any payments made in connection with it which would be prohibited if made with appropriated funds. Requires, in lieu of information currently required, the: (1) name of any registrant under this Act who has made lobbying contacts on behalf of the person with respect to that Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement; and (2) certification that the declarant has not made, and will not make, any prohibited payment. (Sec. 115) Repeals: (1) the Federal Regulation of Lobbying Act; and (2) provisions on lobbyist activities of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act and the Housing Act of 1949. (Sec. 118) Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 119) Sets forth special rules for the identification of: (1) foreign and other clients on whose behalf lobbying contacts are made with a covered legislative or executive branch official; and (2) such covered officials. (Sec. 121) Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to the Congress on differences in meaning between this Act and the Internal Revenue Code of "lobbying activities," "lobbying expenditures," "influencing legislation," and related terms. Requires the President to appoint an interim Director of the Office within 30 days after enactment of this Act. Title II: Congressional Gift Rules - Makes conforming amendments to the Standing Rules of the Senate and the Rules of the House of Representatives, as well as the Ethics in Government Act and the Ethics Reform Act of 1989, with regard to the restrictions of this Act on gifts by lobbyists and foreign agents to covered subjects.</summary>
</bill>
