<bill session="104" type="h" number="908" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for each of fiscal years 1996 through 2000 for the provision of grants for construction of wastewater treatment works to serve United States colonias and for connecting residents to sewer collection systems and making any necessary plumbing improvements to enable residences to meet existing county or city code requirements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/1995--Introduced.
Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to make grants to any State along the U.S.-Mexican border or to any designated entity for the construction of treatment works to serve U.S. colonias or for connecting colonia residents to sewer collection systems and making plumbing improvements to enable colonias to meet existing county or city code requirements. Defines "U.S. colonia" as any identifiable community that: (1) is in Arizona, California, New Mexico, or Texas; (2) is within 100 kilometers of the border between the United States and Mexico; (3) is determined to be a colonia on the basis of objective criteria, including lack of potable water or adequate sewage systems; (4) is in an unincorporated area and was in existence before January 1, 1990; and (5) includes a community within a standard metropolitan statistical area (MSA) that has a population exceeding one million but does not include the entire MSA. Provides for approval of construction plans by States under appropriate EPA standards. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
