<bill session="106" type="h" number="1686" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Internet Freedom Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that the Internet remains open to fair competition, free from government regulation, and accessible to American consumers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1999-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400577" joined="1999-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2000-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400588" joined="1999-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400592" joined="1999-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1999-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400534" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1999-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E869-870"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-30">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Antitrust actions"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Internet service providers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication systems"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Antitrust and Criminal Provisions Title II: Additional Provisions Internet Freedom Act - Title I: Antitrust and Criminal Provisions - Provides that in any civil action based on antitrust violations, evidence that an incumbent local exchange carrier that has market power in the broadband service provider market area has willfully and knowingly failed to provide conditioned unbundled local loops when economically reasonable and technically feasible, or restrains the ability of another carrier to compete in the provision of such services, shall establish a presumption of an antitrust violation. Establishes an identical presumption in the case of a broadband access transport provider that has market power in the broadband service provider market who has offered access to a service provider on terms and conditions less favorable than those otherwise offered, or restrains unreasonably the ability of another provider from competing in the provision of such services. Defines: (1) broadband as a transmission capability in excess of 200 kilobits per second in at least one direction; and (2) a broadband access transport provider as one who engages in the broadband transmission of data between a user and his service provider's point of interconnection with the broadband access transport provider's facilities. Makes it unlawful for a broadband access transport provider to engage in unfair methods of competition or unfair or deceptive acts or practices in the provision of such services. Amends the Federal criminal code to provide criminal penalties against anyone who intentionally: (1) and without authorization initiates the transmission of a bulk unsolicited electronic mail message to a protected computer with knowledge that such message falsifies an Internet domain, header information, or other identifier; or (2) sells or distributes any computer program designed primarily to conceal the source or routing information on such mail, has only limited commercially significant purpose or use, or is marketed by the violator or another person acting in concert with the violator with the violator's knowledge of such use. Title II: Additional Provisions - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require each local exchange carrier to submit to the State communications commission in each State in which such carrier does business a plan to provide broadband telecommunications service in all local exchange areas in which such carrier has telephone exchange service customers, as soon as such service is economically reasonable and technically feasible. Considers such plan certified unless rejected within 45 days. Requires plan implementation within 180 days (if reasonable and feasible). Prohibits State or Federal Communications Commission (FCC) modification of such plans. Provides that interLATA services shall not include services that consist of or include the transmission of any data or information by means of the Internet or any other network that employs Internet Protocol-based or other packet-switched technology. Prohibits a Bell operating company or its affiliate from providing, by the Internet or similar network employing such technology, two-way voice only interLATA telecommunications services originating in any of its in-region States until the FCC approves the application of such company for such State.</summary>
</bill>
