<bill session="105" type="h" number="4660" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Extradition Treaties Interpretation Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Extradition Treaties Interpretation Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Extradition Treaties Interpretation Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to provide rewards for information leading to the arrest or conviction of any individual for the commission of an act, or conspiracy to act, of international terrorism, narcotics related offenses, or for serious violations of international humanitarian law relating to the Former Yugoslavia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1998-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1998-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="1998-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1998-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1998-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1998-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1998-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-10-02">
      <text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T21:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T21:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10166-10169" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T21:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-10-08T21:50:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T21:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08T21:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12604" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Amendment SP 3827 proposed by Senator Jeffords for Senator Helms.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Amendment SP 3827 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1998-10-14" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-15T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-15T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-15T13:31:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10955-10957" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-15T13:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-15">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-10-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-10-30" type="public" number="105-323">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-323.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Croatia"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Serbia"/>
    <term name="Slovenia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War crime trials"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="Yugoslavia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3827"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/14/1998--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of State Rewards Program Title II: Extradition Treaties Interpretation Act of 1998 Title I: Department of State Rewards Program - Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to revise the Department of State program of rewards for information leading to the arrest or conviction of individuals for acts of international terrorism against U.S. persons or property. Makes rewards also available for information leading to the arrest or conviction in any country of any individual for: (1) certain narcotics-related offenses, including killing or kidnapping; and (2) aiding or abetting in the commission of any such acts of intentional terrorism or narcotics-related offenses. Provides for rewards for the prevention, frustration, or favorable resolution of any such acts. (Sec. 101) Authorizes additional appropriations for such rewards. Limits the maximum reward to $5 million. Authorizes the Secretary to take necessary measures to provide for the protection of a reward recipient's identity (including that of the recipient's immediate family). Declares that all determinations of the Secretary under this Act shall be final and not subject to judicial review. (Sec. 102) Authorizes the Secretary to pay a reward for information leading to the arrest or conviction in any country, or the transfer to, or conviction by, the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia, of any individual who is the subject of an indictment by the Tribunal for serious violations of international humanitarian law. Requires the Secretary to obtain the concurrence of the Attorney General before making a reward. Title II: Extradition Treaties Interpretation Act of 1998 - Extradition Treaties Interpretation Act of 1998 - Authorizes the interpretation of the terms "kidnaping" and "kidnapping" to include international parental kidnapping for purposes of any extradition treaty to which the United States is a party.</summary>
</bill>
