<bill session="104" type="hr" number="409" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-24T12:37:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-04-24T12:37:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2715) to amend chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, popularly known as the Paperwork Reduction Act, to minimize the burden of Federal paperwork demands upon small businesses, educational and nonprofit institutions, Federal contractors, State and local governments, and other persons through the sponsorship and use of alternative information technologies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-04-23T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-532, by Mr. Linder.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-23T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2715 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Providing for consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Smalll Business now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-04-23T18:18:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="207">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 207.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3746-3749" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T12:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T12:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-04-24T12:37:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="2715"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/1996--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 2715 (Federal paperwork reduction).</summary>
</bill>
