<bill session="104" type="h" number="2601" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bottled Water Standards Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to modify the bottled drinking water standards provisions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400570"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Bottled water"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/1995--Introduced.
Bottled Water Standards Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, after the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency promulgates a national primary drinking water regulation for a contaminant under the Safe Drinking Water Act, to issue a regulation for that contaminant in bottled water or make a finding that a regulation is not necessary to protect the public health because the contaminant is not present in bottled water. Specifies that such a regulation shall take effect on the date on which the final regulation of the maximum contaminant level (MCL) takes effect. Requires the relevant MCL to provide protection of public health equivalent to the MCL provided in the national primary drinking water regulation. Makes the drinking water regulation the standard for bottled water if the Secretary fails to establish a regulation.</summary>
</bill>
