<bill session="104" type="h" number="3663" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-08-06">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act to permit the Council of the District of Columbia to authorize the issuance of revenue bonds with respect to water and sewer facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402762" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404142" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1996-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-25T21:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 104-635.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-06-25T21:18:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="318">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 318.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T12:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis asked unanimous consent discharge the Committe of the Whole House on the State of the Union and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6982-6985" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-06-27T12:59:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T12:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-07-30" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9208" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-08-01">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-08-06">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-08-06" type="public" number="104-184">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-184.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Capital budgets"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining in government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Municipal officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Municipal politics and government"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1233"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/27/1996--Passed House amended.
District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority Act of 1996 - Amends the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act to authorize the District of Columbia Council to issue revenue bonds, notes, and other obligations to borrow money to finance water and sewer facilities (defined as facilities for the obtaining, treatment, storage, and distribution of water, the collection, storage, treatment, and transportation of wastewater, storm drainage, and the disposal of liquids and solids resulting from treatment). Allows water and sewer enterprise fund revenues, assets, or other property to be used as payments and security for obligations issued with respect to water and sewer facilities. Permits the D.C. Council to delegate to the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority the authority to issue obligations to finance utilities facilities, pollution control facilities, and water and sewer facilities. Provides that such obligations issued by the Authority shall be issued by resolution of the Authority and not by an act of the Council. Makes provisions requiring congressional approval before amounts may be obligated or expended by District government employees or officers inapplicable with respect to any amount obligated or expended: (1) from the proceeds of the sale of such obligations; (2) for the payment of the principal of, interest on, or any premium for such obligations; (3) to secure such obligations; and (4) for repair, maintenance, and capital improvements to facilities financed by such obligations. Removes from the calculation of the District's debt service ceiling: (1) revenues, charges, or fees dedicated for the purposes of water and sewer facilities; and (2) obligations incurred pursuant to general obligation bonds issued before FY 1997 for the financing of Department of Public Works, Water and Sewer Utility Administration capital projects. Requires: (1) the Authority to submit to the Mayor for inclusion in the annual budget annual estimates of the expenditures and appropriations necessary for its operation for the year; and (2) the Mayor, without revision but subject to recommendations, to forward the estimates to the Council for its action. Permits the Council to comment or make recommendations concerning, but not revise, such annual estimates. Prohibits the Mayor from reducing amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to the Authority if determined necessary to reduce the District's budget in a fiscal year. Amends the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996 to require employees transferred from the Department of Public Works to the Authority to perform their duties under the personnel system developed by the Authority's Board or a collective bargaining agreement entered into after the enactment of such Act.</summary>
</bill>
