<bill session="106" type="h" number="2177" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">James Peak Wilderness Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate the James Peak Wilderness in the Arapaho National Forest in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1999-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1218"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-24">
      <text>Referred to Department of Agriculture for comments.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Antennas"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1999--Introduced.
James Peak Wilderness Act of 1999 - Amends the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 to designate specified lands in the Arapaho National Forest as the James Peak Wilderness. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture: (1) if the Colorado State Land Board informs the Secretary that it is willing to transfer to the United States some or all of the lands owned by the Board within the Wilderness, to promptly seek to reach agreement with the Board regarding terms and conditions for acquisition of such lands; (2) to enter into negotiations with the owner of lands located within the portion of the Jim Creek drainage within the Wilderness for the purpose of acquiring such lands; and (3) to report to specified House and Senate Committees upon the conclusion of an agreement for acquisition of such lands or, after one year after this Act's enactment date, on the status of negotiations. Directs the Forest Supervisor of the Arapaho and Roosevelt National Forests to: (1) establish a trailhead and corresponding facilities and services to regulate use of National Forest System lands adjacent to Alice Township and St. Mary's Glacier; (2) consult with the Clear Creek County Commissioners and residents in the immediate vicinity regarding the location of such facilities and services; and (3) inform specified House and Senate Committees regarding the amount of any additional funding required to implement such measures. Directs the Secretary to remove the abandoned radio tower and associated structures located on Mount Eva on the potential wilderness lands.</summary>
</bill>
