<bill session="106" type="h" number="3312" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-24T15:17:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-24T15:17:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Merit Systems Protection Board Administrative Dispute Resolution Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Merit Systems Protection Board Administrative Dispute Resolution Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the Administrative Dispute Resolution Act of 1996 to authorize the Merit Systems Protection Board to establish under such Act a 3-year pilot program that will provide a voluntary early intervention alternative dispute resolution process to assist Federal agencies and employees in resolving certain personnel actions and disputes in administrative programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400544"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-10">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-20">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-10-23T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 106-994, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-23T17:55:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Government Reform Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 23, 2000.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-23T17:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Government Reform discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-10-23T17:55:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="582">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 582.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Bono moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H10629-10632" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3312.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-10-24T15:17:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H10629-10631" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-24T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law judges"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employee-management relations in government"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/24/2000--Passed House amended.
Merit Systems Protection Board Administrative Dispute Resolution Act of 2000 - Amends Federal civil service law to authorize the Merit Systems Protection Board to provide Federal employees and agencies with alternative dispute resolution (ADR) processes to apply to personnel disputes involving removals, suspensions for more than 14 days, and other adverse actions and removals based on unacceptable employee performance. Allows ADR services only upon joint request of the employee and agency. Directs the Board to test and evaluate a variety of ADR techniques. Authorizes the Board to establish an early intervention ADR process, upon joint request of both parties, after an agency has issued a notice letter of proposed action to an employee but before an appeal is filed with the Board. Makes consent to early intervention confidential, and allows either party to withdraw at any time. Authorizes the Board to resolve matters ancillary to the dispute. Requires the Board to develop a training and credentialing program to ensure that program neutrals have a sufficient understanding of issues that arise during the ADR process.Requires the Board's Office of Policy and Evaluation to establish criteria for evaluating the ADR program and to prepare a report as to whether mandatory ADR is desirable, effective, and appropriate for cases decided by Federal agencies.Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 4) Establishes within the Board the Administrative Judge Pay Schedule, with pay levels comparable to that of other Federal administrative law judges. Authorizes conversion to such Pay Schedule for current Board judges after they have served in such capacity for at least three years. Outlines provisions for advancement within the Pay Schedule, as well as transition provisions for current judges. Authorizes appropriations to carry out such Schedule.</summary>
</bill>
