<bill session="106" type="h" number="4790" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hunting Heritage Protection Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Hunting Heritage Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To recognize hunting heritage and provide opportunities for continued hunting on public lands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300021"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2000-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-07-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-838.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-12T16:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="496">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 496.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2000--Reported to House amended.
Hunting Heritage Protection Act - Requires that Federal public lands be open to access and use for recreational hunting except: (1) as limited by the Federal agency with responsibility for such lands for national security or public safety reasons, or for reasons authorized in applicable Federal statutes as reasons for closure; and (2) as such hunting is limited by the State in which such lands are located.Directs the head of each Federal agency with authority to manage a natural resource or public lands on which such a resource depends to exercise that authority in a manner so as to support, promote, and enhance recreational hunting opportunities.Declares that Federal land management decisions and actions should result in no net loss of land area available for hunting opportunities on Federal public lands.Requires the heads of Federal agencies with authority to manage Federal public lands on which recreational hunting occurs to report annually to specified congressional committees on areas administered that have been closed during the previous year to recreational hunting and reasons for such closures and on areas that were open to such hunting to compensate for closed areas.Grants States the right to file civil actions in district courts in cases where Federal agencies fail to comply with State authority to manage or regulate fish and wildlife.Establishes a National Recreational Hunting Coordination Council to develop a recreational hunting and wildlife resource conservation plan for Federal public lands.Terminates the Council on the earlier of the date of submission of the final plan or three years after this Act's enactment date. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
