<bill session="106" type="h" number="5641" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commission for Comprehensive Review of the Federal Aviation Administration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a commission to review the Federal Aviation Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400435"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-12-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2126-2127"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2127-2128" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Private aviation"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2000--Introduced.
Commission for Comprehensive Review of the Federal Aviation Administration Act - Establishes the Commission for Comprehensive Review of the Federal Aviation Administration to: (1) review existing and alternative options for organizational structure of air traffic services, including a government corporation and incentive based fees for services; (2) provide recommendations for any necessary changes in structure of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) so that it will be able to support the future growth in the national aviation and airport system; (3) review aviation safety and make recommendations for the long-term improvement of safety; and (4) make additional recommendations that would advance more efficient and effective FAA for the benefit of the general traveling public and the aviation transportation system.</summary>
</bill>
