<bill session="105" type="h" number="1622" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for an annual report to Congress concerning diplomatic immunity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1997-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="759"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal liability"/>
    <term name="Diplomatic privileges and immunities"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/1997--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of State to report annually to the Congress on: (1) the number of persons and aliens residing in the United States who are entitled to diplomatic immunity from criminal prosecution, including each case involving such an alien whom appropriate law enforcement authorities reasonably believe to have committed a serious crime within the United States; and (2) the number of U.S. citizens residing in a receiving state who are entitled to diplomatic immunity from criminal prosecution there, including each case in which the United States has been requested by the government of the state to waive immunity. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Secretary should explore, in appropriate fora, whether states should enter into agreements and adopt legislation to provide: (1) jurisdiction in the sending state to prosecute crimes committed in the receiving state by persons entitled to diplomatic immunity; and (2) that where there is probable cause to believe that an individual with such immunity committed a serious crime, the sending state will waive immunity or will prosecute the individual.</summary>
</bill>
