<bill session="104" type="h" number="3664" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Government Improvement and Efficiency Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make miscellaneous and technical corrections to improve the operations of the government of the District of Columbia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="College administration"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Convention facilities"/>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Municipal officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Municipal politics and government"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water purification"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/1996--Introduced.
District of Columbia Government Improvement and Efficiency Act of 1996 - Reduces the minimum number of members of the Board of Trustees of the American University from 40 to 25. (Sec. 3) Repeals the application of the Service Contract Act of 1965 with respect to the District of Columbia. (Sec. 4) Authorizes the Mayor of the District and the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, with respect to District of Columbia convicts in any Federal penitentiary during the five-year period beginning in FY 1997, to enter into an agreement waiving requirements relating to the cost of the care and custody of D.C. convicts in Federal penitentiaries or establishing an alternative amount to be charged against the District for such convicts so long as the Director provides at least 15 days' notice of the intent to enter into the agreement to specified congressional committees. (Sec. 5) Amends the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act to exempt from review by the D.C. Council contracts: (1) entered into by the Washington Convention Center Authority for preconstruction activities, project management, design, or construction; (2) entered into by the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, other than contracts for the sale or lease of the Blue Plains Wastewater Treatment Plant; and (3) for Federal highway improvement projects at the option of the Council. (Sec. 6) Amends the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to allow, at the request of the Inspector General, the Director of Personnel to waive the residency requirement for employees of the Office of the Inspector General. (Sec. 7) Requires members of the Judicial Nomination Commission to serve without compensation for services rendered in connection with their official duties on the Commission. (Sec. 8) Renames the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act as the District of Columbia Home Rule Act.</summary>
</bill>
