<bill session="108" type="h" number="1601" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Workforce Flexibility Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for reform relating to Federal employment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400095"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service and Agency Organization.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSGO18" subcommittee="Civil Service and Agency Organization" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="129"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Pay equity"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Position classification"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2003--Introduced.
Federal Workforce Flexibility Act of 2003 - Amends Federal employment law to: (1) strike a provision excepting as a Federal agency position any position in the Drug Enforcement Administration which is excluded from competitive service requirements; (2) authorize the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to modify employee demonstration projects; (3) remove the requirement that OPM develop a plan for each project; and (4) terminate projects after ten (currently five) years, while requiring OPM to recommend, on or before the end of the project's first seven years, whether it should be made permanent.Amends Federal employee recruitment and retention provisions to: (1) provide a four-year maximum on the years required of an employee provided a recruitment bonus; (2) authorize a recruitment or retention bonus of up to 50 percent of an employee's annual salary in the case of a critical agency need; (3) require OPM to establish a plan for paying such bonuses; and (4) rename the retention allowance the retention bonus and make such bonus contingent upon the completion of a period of service to be determined.Empowers OPM (currently, only at the request of an agency) to fix the rates of critical pay.Requires part-time service performed before April 7, 1986, to be credited as full-time service for annuity determination purposes.Empowers OPM (currently the President) to provide special locality pay rates. Requires an agency head to notify OPM of any categories of employees that would not be covered under such rates. Requires a pay rate conversion for employees moving to a different locality. Considers the locality pay rate as basic pay for purposes of Federal benefits. Determines the rates of pay for employees entitled to pay retention.Requires each agency head to evaluate its agency training with respect to success in accomplishing performance plans and strategic goals, appoint a training officer, and establish a comprehensive management succession program.Authorizes annual leave for qualified non-Federal service of newly hired Federal employees.</summary>
</bill>
