<bill session="106" type="h" number="807" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-16T12:02:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-03-16T12:02:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Reserve Board Retirement Portability Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Federal Reserve Board Retirement Portability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide portability of service credit for persons who leave employment with the Federal Reserve Board to take positions with other Government agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1999-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-03-10">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-03-16T11:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 106-53.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-03-16T11:01:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="33">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 33.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-03-16T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-16T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1281-1285" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-16T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 807.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-03-16T12:02:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-03-16T12:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-16T12:04:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Security.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA07" subcommittee="International Security, Proliferation and Federal Services" name="Senate Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Pension portability"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' preference"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/1999--Passed House amended.
Federal Reserve Board Retirement Portability Act - Includes as creditable service of a Federal employee or Member of Congress for purposes of Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) provisions a period of service (other than any service already creditable under FERS, any military service, and any service performed in the employ of a Federal Reserve Bank) that was creditable under the Bank Plan (the benefit structure in which employees of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System appointed on or after January 1, 1984, participate), if the employee waives credit for such service under the Bank Plan and makes a payment to the Thrift Savings Fund equal to the amount that would have been deducted from pay had the employee been subject to FERS during such period of service (together with interest on such amount computed). Excludes from participation in FERS any employee or Member who has separated from civilian service after having been subject to the benefit structure for employees of the Board appointed before January 1, 1984, and having at least five years of civilian service (other than any service performed in the employ of a Federal Reserve Bank) creditable under such benefit structure, except for such persons who subsequently enter a position subject to FERS provisions. Makes the amendments regarding creditability and certain former Board employees applicable only to individuals who separate from service subject to FERS on or after the date of enactment of this Act. (Sec. 3) Treats as a separation from Government employment, for purposes of the Thrift Savings Plan, any transfer from a position that is subject to FERS, CSRS, or any other retirement system under which individuals may contribute to the Thrift Savings Fund through withholdings from pay, to a position that is not subject to any of them. (Sec. 4) Amends competitive service examination provisions to: (1) repeal the requirement that the Office of Personnel Management establish an appointing authority to appoint preference eligibles and veterans who have been separated from the armed forces under honorable conditions after three or more years of active service; and (2) require such a preference eligible or veteran, if selected, to acquire competitive status and receive a career or career-conditional appointment.</summary>
</bill>
