<bill session="105" type="h" number="2614" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-06">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Reading Excellence bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reading Excellence Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Reading Excellence Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Reading Excellence Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Reading Excellence Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the reading and literacy skills of children and families by improving in-service instructional practices for teachers who teach reading, to stimulate the development of more high-quality family literacy programs, to support extended learning-time opportunities for children, to ensure that children can read well and independently not later than third grade, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400578" joined="1997-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1997-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="1997-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1997-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="409228" joined="1997-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1997-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1945-1946"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-10-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-10-24T18:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 105-348.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-10-24T18:02:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="202">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 202.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T15:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodling moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T15:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10386-10398" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T15:55:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-11-08T16:41:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T16:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-05-13">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Jeffords with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 105-208.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-06-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="404">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 404.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-06">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11533-11539" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-06">
      <text>Amendment SP 3740 proposed by Senator Jeffords.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-06">
      <text>Amendment SP 3740 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-06">
      <text>The committee substitute agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1998-10-06" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bilingual education"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Class size"/>
    <term name="College sports"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Deaf"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Dropout prevention"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disabled students"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Educational television"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to adult education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to disability services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to territories"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Head Start programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Impact aid"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Kindergarten"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Middle schools"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Public broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student employment"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teachers colleges"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Truck drivers"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban education"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in education"/>
    <term name="Workplace literacy"/>
    <term name="Year round schools"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3740"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/6/1998--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Reading and Literacy Grants Title II: Amendments to Even Start Family Literacy Programs Title III: Repeals Title IV: Technical and Conforming Amendments Reading Excellence Act - Title I: Reading and Literacy Grants - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to establish a new title II part C Reading and Literacy Grants program. (Sec. 101) Directs the Secretary of Education to make grants to State educational agencies (SEAs) to make subgrants for local reading improvement programs and tutorial assistance programs. Provides for peer review panel evaluation of SEA grant applications. Requires State establishment of a reading and literacy partnership as a condition for an SEA's receiving such a grant. Limits the portions of such grants which may be used for State administrative costs and for tutorial assistance subgrants. Requires SEAs that receive such grants to make competitive two-year local reading improvement subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) with: (1) at least one school that is identified for school improvement; (2) the largest, or second largest, number of children in comparison to all other LEAs in the State; or (3) the highest, or second highest, school-age child poverty rate, in comparison to all other LEAs in the State. Allows subgrantees to train, on a fee-for-service basis, personnel from schools or LEAs that are not subgrant recipients or beneficiaries, in the instructional practices based on scientifically-based reading research used by the recipient. Requires each SEA that receives such a grant to make at least one competitive tutorial assistance subgrant to LEAs with: (1) at least one school located in an empowerment zone or an enterprise community; (2) at least one school identified for school improvement; (3) the largest, or second largest, number of children in comparison to all other LEAs in the State; or (4) the highest, or second highest, school-age child poverty rate, in comparison to all other LEAs in the State. Sets forth authorized uses of such subgrants. Directs the Secretary to: (1) conduct a national assessment of programs under this Act; (2) receive recommendations from the peer review panel in developing the criteria for the assessment; and (3) report on the assessment to the appropriate congressional committees. Requires the National Institute for Literacy to disseminate information on reliable, replicable research on reading and on subgrantee projects that have proven effective. Requires each SEA that receives such a grant to: (1) evaluate subgrantees success; and (2) submit the findings of the evaluations and performance reports to the Secretary, who will submit a summary to the appropriate congressional committees. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1999 and 2000. Title II: Amendments to Even Start Family Literacy Programs - Amends ESEA to direct the Secretary to award competitive grants to States for the planning and implementation of statewide family literacy initiatives, including specified services. (Sec. 203) Requires grant recipients to: (1) provide technical assistance for the evaluation of subgrant recipient local programs; and (2) develop indicators of program quality. (Sec. 205) Directs the Secretary to do research through grant or contract into successful family literacy services to improve the quality of existing programs and to develop models for new programs. Revises provisions for the dissemination of information. Title III: Repeals - Repeals certain unfunded education programs under various Federal laws. (Sec. 301) Repeals the Community School Partnership Act (contained in the Improving America's Schools Act of 1994). Repeals specified provisions of the Educational Research, Development, Dissemination, and Improvement Act of 1994 for a teacher research dissemination demonstration program. Repeals provisions of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) for: (1) innovative elementary school transition projects; (2) the De Lugo territorial education improvement program; (3) extended time for learning and longer school year; and (4) territorial assistance. Repeals the Family and Community Endeavor Schools Act. Repeals specified provisions of the Goals 2000: Educate America Act for grants for the study, evaluation, and analysis of education systems in other nations. Title IV: Technical and Conforming Amendments - Makes technical and conforming amendments to various Federal laws.</summary>
</bill>
