<bill session="107" type="h" number="4722" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lake Erie Western Basin International Wildlife Refuge Establishment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of the Lake Erie Western Basin International Wildlife Refuge in the States of Ohio and Michigan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2002-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2002--Introduced.
Lake Erie Western Basin International Wildlife Refuge Establishment Act - Establishes the Lake Erie Western Basin International Wildlife Refuge (Refuge), Michigan and Ohio. Includes the Ottawa National Wildlife Refuge and the Cedar Point National Wildlife Refuge within it.Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) revise Refuge boundaries to carry out its purposes or to facilitate the acquisition of property; and (2) acquire by donation, purchase, or exchange the lands and waters or interests within such boundaries. Provides for transfers from other agencies.Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, to conduct a study of fish and wildlife habitat and aquatic and terrestrial communities of the Maumee River.Directs the Secretary to: (1) administer all federally owned lands, waters, and interests within the Refuge; (2) ensure that hunting, fishing, wildlife observation and photography, and environmental education and interpretation are the priority public uses of the Refuge; and (3) encourage Ohio to use existing authorities under the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century to provide funding for acquisition and development of trails within the Refuge.Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements regarding non-Federal lands.</summary>
</bill>
