<bill session="105" type="h" number="1272" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-23T19:17:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-04-23T19:17:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY98-99, Fire Administration</title>
    <title type="popular">Fire Administration FY98-99 Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fire Administration Authorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Fire Administration Authorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Fire Administration Authorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal years 1998 and 1999 for the United States Fire Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409633"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1997-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1997-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1997-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1997-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1997-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1997-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1997-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-04-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E625"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-04-21T16:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 105-62.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-04-21T16:22:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="45">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 45.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-04-23T18:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-23T18:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1753-1757" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-23T18:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-04-23T19:17:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-04-23T19:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="1231"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Computer programming"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hotels, motels, etc."/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smoke detectors"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Year 2000 computer problem"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/1997--Passed House amended.
Fire Administration Authorization Act of 1997 - Amends the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to authorize appropriations for FY 1998 and 1999. Permits successor fire safety standards to be used as guidelines in addition to National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) Standard 74, NFPA Standard 13 or 13-R, or NFPA Standard 101 (Life Safety Code) for installation of hard-wired, single-station smoke detectors or automatic sprinkler systems in: (1) places of public accommodation affecting commerce; and (2) federally-assisted buildings. Requires the Administrator of the U.S. Fire Administration to report to the Congress at least 60 days in advance on the termination or transfer to a private sector entity of any significant function of the Administration. Prohibits funds authorized by this Act from being made available for any activity to influence legislation before the Congress, except that Federal officers or employees may communicate to Members of Congress on requests for legislation or appropriations which they deem necessary for the efficient conduct of the public business. Requires the Administrator to exclude from consideration for grant agreements made by the Administration after FY 1997 any person who received funds appropriated for a fiscal year after FY 1997 under a grant agreement from any Federal funding source for a project that was not subjected to a competitive merit-based award process. Limits such exclusion to a five-year period after the person receives such Federal funds. Makes an exception for persons who received Federal funds due to membership in a class the members of which are awarded assistance according to a formula provided by law. Requires: (1) the House Committee on Science and the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation to be notified if funds authorized by this Act are subject to a reprogramming action that requires notice to be provided to the Appropriations Committees; and (2) the Administrator to notify all such committees not later than 15 days before any major reorganization of any Administration program, project, or activity. Urges the Administration to give high priority to correcting, assess the risk to operations posed by, plan and budget for, and develop contingency plans for date-related year 2000 problems in its computer systems. Prohibits funds appropriated under this Act from being expended by an entity unless such entity complies with the Buy American Act. Expresses the sense of the Congress that entities receiving financial assistance under this Act should, in expending such assistance, purchase only American-made equipment and products. Requires the Administrator, in providing such assistance, to so notify each recipient.</summary>
</bill>
