<bill session="105" type="h" number="3239" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Managed Health Care Sunshine Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Social Security Act to require health maintenance organizations under the Medicare Program to disclose to enrollees and potential enrollees certain information on the credentials of physicians providing services by or through the organization, the financial status of the organization, and the compensation paid to officers and executives of the organization.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1998-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E168"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health care industry"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/1998--Introduced.
Medicare Managed Health Care Sunshine Act of 1998 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, to require a Medicare+Choice organization, upon request, to provide an eligible individual with descriptive information on physician credentialing. Directs Medicare+Choice organizations to report to the Secretary of Health and Human Services certain financial information, including an audited financial statement of the organization for the most recently concluded fiscal year. Provides for disclosure of the availability of such information to Medicare beneficiaries and prospective Medicare beneficiaries as part of the broad dissemination of information to promote an active, informed selection of the coverage options available under the available Medicare+Choice plans. Applies the requirements of this Act to eligible organizations with risk-sharing contracts under Medicare in the same manner that they apply to Medicare+Choice organizations.</summary>
</bill>
