<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="899" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="3915" sequence="2"/>
  <status datetime="2007-11-15T13:18:00-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <offered datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  <description>Amendment makes a number of technical and conforming changes as well as enhancemen ts to the bill including the following: (1) clarifies the definition of loan originator; (2) narrows the scope of the preemption provision to make it clear that states cannot use or adopt state laws against securitizers/assignees for violations of the national standards or to impose remedies outside of the unique Federal remedy established in the bill, and to make it clear that actions for fraud, misrepresentation, deception, false advertising or civil rights laws are not preempted; (3) clarifies the registration requirements for the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry; (4) allows consumers to obtain a cure from assignee or securitizer if creditor or other assignees cease to exist or go bankrupt; (5) clarifies the incentive compensation provision; and (6) adds a monthly disclosure requirement for mortgages.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 110-450 to make a number of technical and conforming changes as well as enhancemen ts to the bill including the following: (1) clarifies the definition of loan originator; (2) narrows the scope of the preemption provision to make it clear that states cannot use or adopt state laws against securitizers/assignees for violations of the national standards or to impose remedies outside of the unique Federal remedy established in the bill, and to make it clear that actions for fraud, misrepresentation, deception, false advertising or civil rights laws are not preempted; (3) clarifies the registration requirements for the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry; (4) allows consumers to obtain a cure from assignee or securitizer if creditor or other assignees cease to exist or go bankrupt; (5) clarifies the incentive compensation provision; and (6) adds a monthly disclosure requirement for mortgages.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-15T13:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Frank (MA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14005-14006" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2007-11-15T13:18:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Frank (MA) amendment (A002) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
