<bill session="108" type="h" number="3279" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security Alternative Voluntary Expenditure Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for an election by individuals eligible for old-age insurance benefits under such title to waive payment of benefits based on their work record, to provide for income tax deductions based on the actuarial present value of benefits foregone by reason of such an election, and to provide that special Government obligations issued exclusively for purchase by the Social Security Trust Funds shall bear interest at the average market yield then prevailing for comparable obligations issued in the private sector.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400305"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Social security beneficiaries"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2003--Introduced.
Social Security Alternative Voluntary Expenditure Act of 2003 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to authorize individuals eligible for OASDI benefits to elect to waive payment of all benefits based on their wages and self-employment income. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a deduction of 20 percent of the actuarial present value of future benefits foregone by reason of such an election. Provides a tax deduction, as well, for the divorced spouse of an individual making a waiver under this Act. Amends SSA title II to require special Government obligations issued for purchase by the social security trust funds to bear interest at the average market yield then prevailing for comparable obligations issued in the private sector.</summary>
</bill>
