<bill session="105" type="hc" number="182" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress with respect to child custody, child abuse, and victims of domestic and family violence.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1997-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1997-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1998-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1997-10-30" withdrawn="1998-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Joint custody of children"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Professional education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/1997--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that for purposes of determining child custody it is in the best interest of children to have a presumption that children should have their main physical residence with the primary caretaker parent (unless that parent is unfit). Declares that it is not in the best interest of children to: (1) force parents to share custody over parental objection, or when there is a history of domestic or family violence; (2) punish abused or protective parents who protect themselves or their children; (3) presume that allegations of domestic and family violence are likely to be false, or made for tactical advantage during custody and divorce proceedings; and (4) make "friendly parent" provisions a factor when there is an abusive parent. Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) child abuse and child sexual abuse allegations should be investigated regardless of when raised or whether the child has recanted the allegation; (2) States should be more protective of victims of family and domestic violence in custody and visitation determinations and not order mediation, couples counseling, shared custody, mutual orders of protection, unsupervised visitation, or other measures when they may endanger such victims; and (3) States should provide training in domestic violence and child abuse, as they impact custody, child support and visitation determinations, to all professionals who interact with children and parents.</summary>
</bill>
