<bill session="104" type="h" number="4039" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-17T17:31:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-09-17T17:31:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security Miscellaneous Amendments Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Social Security Miscellaneous Amendments Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical and clarifying amendments to recently enacted provisions relating to titles II and XVI of the Social Security Act and to provide for a temporary extension of demonstration project authority in the Social Security Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300014"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="1996-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1996-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-09-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-16T12:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 104-786.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-09-16T12:27:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="424">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 424.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bunning moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10478-10481" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T17:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-09-17T17:31:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Computer matching"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare recipients"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/1996--Passed House amended.
Social Security Miscellaneous Amendments Act of 1996 - Amends the Contract with America Advancement Act of 1996 with respect to disability benefits under titles II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) and XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the Social Security Act (SSA). Revises effective dates for the application of certain provisions to individuals. Provides that, with respect to the effective date of denial of disability benefits to drug addicts and alcoholics, a claim may not be considered finally adjudicated (and thus subject to such denial) if there is a pending request for administrative or judicial review or a pending readjudication pursuant to a class action or court remand. Provides that the requirement to appoint a representative payee, and refer beneficiaries for treatment, applies to beneficiaries who are allowed benefits (due to another impairment) based on a new application filed before enactment, and who continue to get benefits based on a successful redetermination filed before July 1, 1996. Repeals specified reporting requirements related to the monitoring and testing of beneficiaries on the basis of drug addiction or alcoholism who are required to undergo treatment as a condition for receipt of benefits. Declares that challenges to State disability determinations under OASDI may be made only against the Commissioner of Social Security (in all cases in which there is not a final judgment). Amends specified Acts, including the Social Security Disability Amendments of 1980 and the Social Security Independence and Program Improvements Act of 1994, to extend social security disability insurance (SSDI) program demonstration project authority. Authorizes the Commissioner to conduct demonstration projects involving SSDI applicants as well as recipients. Amends OASDI anti-assignment prohibitions to allow the withholding of taxes from any benefit under OASDI pursuant to a proper request made in accordance with the Internal Revenue Code by the person entitled to such benefit. Applies to the payment of OASDI benefits to prisoners the same requirements as enacted by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 with respect to SSI payments for agreements between the Commissioner and State or local correctional institutions for monthly identifying information, and the exchange of such information among Federal or federally-assisted cash, food, or medical assistance programs. Extends to all prisoners, regardless of offense or length of sentence, the current prohibition against the payment of social security benefits, by repealing its limitation to offenses punishable by imprisonment for more than one year. Amends the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 to require inclusion of prisoners receiving OASDI benefits in certain required studies and reports to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
