<bill session="107" type="h" number="5548" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fairness in Tax Collections Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide fairness in tax collection procedures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400188"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax liens"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2002--Introduced.
Fairness in Tax Collections Act of 2002 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit the IRS to enter into installment agreements with taxpayers that do not provide for full payment of liabilities. Requires the IRS to review partial payment installment agreements at least every two years.Extends from nine months to two years the period in which proceeds errantly acquired by the IRS may be returned.Authorizes a taxpayer to deposit money in an IRA without regard to the normally applicable limits on IRA contributions and rollovers if the IRS has sent back the money being deposited due to a wrongful levy and it originally came from an IRA. Requires the contribution to be to the same type of IRA from which the amounts were withdrawn. Stipulates that in such a scenario any tax on the withdrawal from the IRA is abated. Considers interest paid by the IRS to the taxpayer part of the original payment and is not counted as gross income.Modifies the suspension date of the statute of limitations for taxpayers suffering significant hardship by applying it only if the date of the decision by the National Taxpayer Advocate is at least seven days after the date of the taxpayer's application.Directs the Secretary to study IRS practices concerning liens and levies.Increases the allocations for low-income taxpayer clinics, from the current $6 million annually, to $15 million annually by 2003.</summary>
</bill>
