<bill session="107" type="h" number="5544" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Digital Media Consumers' Rights Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to provide that the advertising or sale of a mislabeled copy-protected music disc is an unfair method of competition and an unfair and deceptive act or practice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2002-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2002-11-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="2002-11-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-03">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-03">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1760-1762"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Copyright infringement"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Encryption"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Phonorecords"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2002--Introduced.
Digital Media Consumers' Rights Act of 2002 - Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to prohibit: (1) introduction into commerce of prerecorded digital music disc products that are mislabeled, or falsely, or deceptively advertised or invoiced; and (2) removal or mutilation of any label required by either this Act or any rules or regulations prescribed by the Federal Trade Commission before the time a prerecorded digital music disc product is sold and delivered to the ultimate consumer.States that such transactions constitute either an unfair method of competition, or an unfair and deceptive act or practice in commerce.Authorizes the Commission to develop rules and regulations governing such transactions.Amends Federal copyright law to exempt from its prohibitions against circumvention of copyright protection systems any persons acting solely in furtherance of scientific research into technological protection measures.Declares it is not a violation of copyright law, but fair use, to: (1) circumvent a technological measure in connection with access to, or the use of, a work if such circumvention does not result in an infringement of the copyright in the work; or (2) manufacture, distribute, or make noninfringing use of a hardware or software product capable of enabling significant noninfringing use of a copyrighted work.</summary>
</bill>
