<bill session="106" type="hc" number="170" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing United States policy toward the Republic of Bulgaria.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="1999-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400329" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1999-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-08-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1717"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Corporate corruption"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign economic relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Macedonia"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="NATO enlargement"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Serbia"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Turks"/>
    <term name="War"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/1999--Introduced.
Declares that it is U.S. policy to: (1) promote the development in the Republic of Bulgaria of a market-based economy and a democratic government that respects the rights of all its citizens; (2) support the territorial integrity of Bulgaria; (3) insist that its territorial integrity be respected by neighboring countries and by all political movements; and (4) support Bulgarian integration into pan-European and trans-Atlantic economic and security institutions. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Government of Bulgaria: (1) is to be commended for its efforts to ensure proper treatment of all of its citizens, for its efforts to accelerate the privatization of state-owned enterprises in a fair and transparent process, for its establishment of a currency board, and for its efforts to combat corrupt and criminal activities; (2) should continue to implement programs that may qualify Bulgaria for entrance into the European Union and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) and is to be commended for its continuing support of the NATO effort to ensure stability and democratization across Europe; (3) should ensure the ratification of all bilateral treaties that have been negotiated with the Government of the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia;(4) should halt any illicit transfer of arms and military equipment that may occur in Bulgaria or may cross Bulgarian territory; and (5) should play a central role in any NATO effort to create a joint peacekeeping military unit involving personnel from throughout the countries of southeastern Europe or in the creation of facilities in support of such a unit. Calls for the United States to join other official creditors of Bulgaria in providing Bulgaria with debt relief.</summary>
</bill>
