<bill session="105" type="hr" number="471" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-17T12:34:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-06-17T12:34:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 2646) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow tax-free expenditures from education individual retirement accounts for elementary and secondary school expenses, to increase the maximum annual amount of contributions to such accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-06-16T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-579, by Mrs. Myrick.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-16T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2646. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read when called up for consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-06-16T19:09:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="207">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 207.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-06-17T10:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4641-4643" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-17T10:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-17T10:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-17T10:54:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - The Speaker put the question on agreeing to the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Myrick objected to the voice vote based upon the absence of a quorum and the Speaker postponed further proceedings on the resolution until later in the day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-17T12:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4654" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-06-17T12:34:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="236" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 228 - 191 (Roll No. 236).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-06-17T12:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="2646"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/1998--Introduced.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the conference report on H.R. 2646 (amending the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow tax-free expenditures from education individual retirement accounts for elementary and secondary school expenses and to increase the maximum annual amount of contributions to such accounts).</summary>
</bill>
