<bill session="106" type="h" number="4200" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Worker Information Technology Skills Improvement Act of 2000 (AWITSIA)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to H-1B nonimmigrant aliens and to assure fair distribution of employment-based immigrant visas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400532" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2000-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Amnesties"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Biotechnology"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Cubans"/>
    <term name="Delinquency prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled veterans"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="El Salvador"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Guatemala"/>
    <term name="Guatemalans"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Haitians"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Honduras"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marriage"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="Nicaraguans"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Stepfamilies"/>
    <term name="Student activities"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Unemployed"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Working poor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Provisions Relating to H-1B Nonimmigrants Subtitle A: Provisions Relating to Numerical Limitations Subtitle B: Provisions Relating to H1-B Nonimmigrant Petitioner Fees Subtitle C: Information Technology Training Subtitle D: Obligations of Petitioning Employees Title II: Provisions Relating to Employment-Based Immigration Title III: Kids 2000 Title IV: Legal Amnesty Restoration Act of 2000 Title V: Central American and Haitian Adjustment Act American Worker Information Technology Skills Improvement Act of 2000 (AWITSIA) - Title I: Provisions Relating to H-1B Nonimmigrants - Subtitle A: Provisions Relating to Numerical Limitations - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to increase the number of authorized annual H-1B specialty occupation (nonimmigrant) visas, with reductions in periods of specified unemployment. Allocates specified H-1B visas for aliens with master's or PhD degrees.Subtitle B: Provisions Relating to H1-B (sic) Nonimmigrant Petitioner Fees - Amends the Act to revise collection and use of H-1B employer fee provisions. Exempts certain academic and research institutions from such fees. Obligates specified amounts for the Information Technology Training Initiative (established by this Act).Amends the American Competitiveness and Workforce Improvement Act of 1998 to expand low-income scholarship program eligibility.Amends the Act to obligate specified funds for the Kids 2000 and Net Prep Gyrls programs.Subtitle C: Information Technology Training - Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish in the Department of Labor the Information Technology Training Initiative to provide U.S. workers with information technology skills through grants to local workforce investment boards. Targets specified under-represented populations for program inclusion.Subtitle D: Obligations of Petitioning Employers - Sets forth employer attestation provisions.Title II: Provisions Relating to Employment-Based Immigration - Amends the Act to make employment-based immigrant visas available on a quarterly basis without regard to per-country limitations if unused visas are available.Authorizes a U.S.-residency extension for a nonimmigrant alien for whom an employment-based immigrant petition has been filed but who is subject to the per-country limit until resolution of such alien's application for status adjustment.Title III: Kids 2000 - Directs the Attorney General to make grants to the Boys and Girls Clubs of America for after-school technology programs, such as PowerUp.Title IV: Legal Amnesty Restoration Act of 2000 - Amends the Act to permit the Attorney General to create a record of lawful admission for permanent residence for certain aliens who entered the United States prior to 1986 (currently 1972).Title V: Central American and Haitian Adjustment Act - Amends the Nicaraguan Adjustment and Central American Relief Act to: (1) extend permanent resident status adjustment provisions to qualifying Salvadoran, Guatemalan, Honduran, and Haitian nationals; and (2) extend the application filing deadline.Permits certain pending applications filed by Salvadoran, Guatemalan, or Haitian (under the Haitian Refugee Immigration Fairness Act of 1998) nationals to be converted to status adjustment applications.Amends such Acts to: (1) authorize the Attorney General to waive certain grounds of inadmissibility; and (2) provide for issuance of immigrant visas to certain spouses and children.Provides for the limited reopening of certain orders of deportation, exclusion, or removal by certain Haitian, Cuban, or Nicaraguan nationals.</summary>
</bill>
