<bill session="105" type="h" number="4584" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Environmental Justice Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote environmental justice, public health, and pollution reduction efforts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400240"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1998-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="1998-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1998-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1998-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Agriculture, and Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental justice"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmentally induced diseases"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Groundwater pollution"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Infant mortality"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Location of industries"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Respiratory diseases"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Identification of Environmental High Impact Areas Title II: Enforcement Initiatives Title III: Community Participation Title IV: Identification and Prevention of Health Impacts Title V: Health Remedies Title VI: Pollution Reduction Title VII: Promotion of Green Space Title VIII: Funding Environmental Justice Act of 1998 - Title I: Identification of Environmental High Impact Areas - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to publish a list of 20 Environmental High Impact Areas (EHIAs) that are either counties or other geographic units in which high levels of chemicals are present and in which the population is exposed to such chemicals. Provides for revision and republication of such list at least every five years. Title II: Enforcement Initiatives - Directs the Administrator and the Assistant Secretary of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration to conduct compliance inspections or reviews of all toxic chemical facilities in EHIAs within one year after the publication of each EHIA list under title I. Title III: Community Participation - Requires the Administrator to make technical assistance grants for individuals in EHIAs for purposes of seeking guidance from experts to improve understanding of environmental and health concerns related to designation as an EHIA. Title IV: Identification and Prevention of Health Impacts - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue for public comment a report identifying the methodology used and nature and extent of acute and chronic impacts on human health in EHIAs as compared to non-EHIAs. (Sec. 402) Provides for a moratorium on the siting or permitting of any new toxic chemical facility in an EHIA shown to emit toxic chemicals in quantities causing significant adverse health impacts if the report finds significant adverse impacts of environmental pollution on human health in EHIAs. Permits such siting or permitting during a moratorium period only if the Secretary and Administrator agree that: (1) there will be no significant adverse health impacts; (2) the facility owner or operator demonstrates that the facility has a plan to maintain a comprehensive pollution prevention program; and (3) the facility demonstrates that it will minimize uncontrolled releases into the environment. Title V: Health Remedies - Requires the Secretary to establish a grant program to make available to public and nonprofit private entities awards for providing community-wide medical screening and diagnostic services for environmentally related illnesses in EHIAs shown to have adverse health outcomes related to environmental exposures. Title VI: Pollution Reduction - Directs the Administrator, in EHIAs where the Secretary has determined that adverse health outcomes are related to environmental exposures, to take efforts immediately to reduce pollution. Requires the Administrator to make available pollution reduction and prevention grants to States with EHIAs for developing pollution reduction strategies. Authorizes the Administrator to take regulatory steps to reduce pollution if significant steps have not been made to reduce pollution and risk to human health in such areas. Title VII: Promotion of Green Space - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a grant program to make available to local public or nonprofit private entities within EHIAs awards for the development of parks and recreational spaces and to provide guidance for promoting environmentally sound use of land. Title VIII: Funding - Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
