<bill session="105" type="h" number="2597" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Equity for Immigrants Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To rescind restrictions on welfare and public benefits for legal immigrants enacted by title IV of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, and to reduce arms transfer subsidies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400021" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1997-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1997-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1997-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1997-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1997-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1997-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1997-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1997-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="1997-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1997-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-01">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1922-1923"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Eritrea"/>
    <term name="Ethiopia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Greece"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="New Zealand"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Trade fairs"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="Uganda"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Termination of Provisions of Public Law 104-193 Restricting Welfare and Public Benefits for Legal Immigrants Title II: Reduction in Arms Transfer Subsidies Equity for Immigrants Act - Title I: Termination of Provisions of Public Law 104-193 Restricting Welfare and Public Benefits for Legal Immigrants - Declares that, on October 1, 1998, the provisions of title IV of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (Public Law 104-193, as amended by the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 (Public Law 105-33)), which restrict welfare and public benefits for legal immigrants, shall cease to be effective, the amendments made by that title shall be repealed, and any provision of law repealed by that title shall be reenacted. Title II: Reduction in Arms Transfer Subsidies - Amends the Arms Export Control Act to repeal provisions with respect to: (1) leases of defense articles and loan authority for cooperative research and development purposes; and (2) the President's authority to waive specified charges for sales that would significantly advance North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) standardization, standardization with armed forces of specified other countries, or foreign procurement in the United States under coproduction arrangements. (Sec. 202) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to repeal the President's authority to transfer excess defense articles to certain other countries. (Sec. 203) Amends the Arms Export Control Act to state that any sale involving the export of major defense equipment pursuant to a license or other approval, except in certain circumstances, shall include an appropriate charge, comparable to a specified charge imposed for government-to-government sales, for a proportionate amount of the nonrecurring costs incurred by the United States in the research, development, and production of such equipment. (Sec. 204) Declares that no military financing program funds under the Arms Export Control Act may be made available for: (1) grants or loans to Greece, Turkey, Ethiopia, Eritrea, Uganda, Caribbean countries, or any country eligible to participate in the Partnership for Peace Initiative in FY 1997; or (2) the Enhanced International Peacekeeping Initiative. (Sec. 205) Declares that no Economic Support Fund moneys under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 may be made available for Turkey, Haiti, or Cambodia to offset costs of purchasing defense articles or defense services from the United States. (Sec. 206) Declares that no Federal funds may be used to offset the cost of a demonstration or exhibition of defense articles or defense services at a trade show or other international arms bazaar or promotional event in a foreign country.</summary>
</bill>
