<bill session="107" type="h" number="5681" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Central Asia Child Health Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to provide assistance for the prevention, treatment, and control of HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria, polio, and other infectious diseases as such diseases affect children in the countries of Central Asia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400320"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1880-1881"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Kazakhstan"/>
    <term name="Kyrgyzstan"/>
    <term name="Malaria"/>
    <term name="Poliomyelitis"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tajikistan"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="Turkmenistan"/>
    <term name="Uzbekistan"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/16/2002--Introduced.
Central Asia Child Health Improvement Act - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development, acting through the Assistant Administrator of the Bureau for Global Programs, Field Support and Research, in order to facilitate the establishment of partnerships between U.S. medical institutions and health service providers and such institutions and providers in the Central Asian countries of Kazakstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, and Uzbekistan to carry out programs for the prevention, treatment, and control of infectious diseases affecting children, to provide assistance to support: (1) promoting compliance with clinical guidelines for tuberculosis and other infectious diseases established by the World Health Organization; (2) establishing and maintaining computer systems for telemedicine programs; and (3) providing related technical assistance.</summary>
</bill>
