<bill session="108" type="h" number="2927" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Orphan Highway Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 23, United States Code, to provide grants and technical assistance to restore orphan highways.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2003-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2003-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Bikeways"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
    <term name="Traffic signs and signals"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2003--Introduced.
Orphan Highway Restoration Act - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to make grants and provide technical assistance to States and local governments to: (1) perform preventive maintenance on or carry out projects for resurfacing, restoration, reconstruction, and rehabilitation of orphan highways; and (2) rehabilitate, repair, or construct sidewalks, medians, bike lanes, traffic-calming devices, signaling, or signage to enhance community livability on or adjacent to such highways. Defines "orphan highway" as one that: (1) is or was formerly a United States numbered highway; (2) is located within the boundaries of a local government (which includes an Indian Tribe); (3) is no longer a principal route for traffic passing through the State after construction of a bypass or Interstate; (4) currently functions as a county, parish, or city arterial or collector route or provides access to or within Federal or tribal lands; and (5) because of decreased importance to statewide transportation has received only routine maintenance, but needs significant resurfacing, restoration, reconstruction, or rehabilitation. Specifies projects to receive funding priority, such as those that include rehabilitation measures that focus on pedestrian safety, that are coordinated with State and local adopted preservation plans, that promote cost-effective and strategic investments in transportation infrastructure that minimizes adverse environmental impacts, or that foster public-private partnerships. Sets forth provisions regarding fund distribution and the Federal cost share.</summary>
</bill>
