<bill session="105" type="hr" number="289" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress that a renewed effort be made to end the violent guerrilla war in Colombia, which poses a serious threat to democracy in regions of Colombia as evidenced by the results of the recent October 26, 1997, elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1997-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-10-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2114"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Guerrilla warfare"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/29/1997--Introduced.
Recognizes the importance of the threat of the guerrilla movement to Colombia's democracy and that the acts of violence to disrupt the electoral process in the municipal elections could spill over to the congressional and presidential elections to be held in 1998. Urges the guerilla leaders of the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia and the National Liberation Army to end the violence and sever their relationship with narcotics traffickers, to negotiate a peace accord with the Colombian Government, and to take their agenda into the political arena for debate. Calls upon the international community, particularly the Organization of American States, to continue to play a more proactive role in trying to resolve the conflict. Urges the Administration to reevaluate U.S. policies toward Colombia and to encourage a peaceful resolution of the conflict.</summary>
</bill>
