<bill session="104" type="h" number="1036" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Metropolitan Washington Airports Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Metropolitan Washington Airports Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Metropolitan Washington Airports Act of 1986 to direct the President to appoint additional members to the board of directors of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority, to replace the Board of Review of the Airports Authority with a Federal Advisory Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1995-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1995-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1995-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-02-09">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Aviation Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-03-01">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-05-29T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 104-596.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-05-29T12:00:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="296">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 296.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="775"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="836"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1101"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="288"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="288"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation policy"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Limited access highways"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Party affiliation"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/29/1996--Reported to House amended.
Metropolitan Washington Airports Amendments Act of 1995 - Amends the Metropolitan Washington Airports Act of 1986 to revise the term "airport purposes" with respect to real property of the Metropolitan Washington Airports to limit the inclusion of nonprofit, public use facilities to those which are not inconsistent with the needs of aviation. (Sec. 4) Increases the number of persons on the board of directors of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority: (1) from 11 to 15 members; and (2) whom the President must appoint with the advice and consent of the Senate from one member to five members. Requires board members appointed by the President to be registered voters of States other than Maryland, Virginia, or the District of Columbia. Requires two of the members appointed to the board by the President to serve for a term of four years. Authorizes a member to serve after the expiration of that member's term until a successor has taken office. Requires vacancies on the board to be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made. Requires any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member's predecessor was appointed to be appointed only for the remainder of such term. Declares that no more than three members of the board appointed by the President may be of the same political party. Requires presidential appointees on the board to ensure that adequate consideration is given to the national interest in carrying out their duties. Requires nine votes (currently, seven) to approve bond issues and the annual budget. (Sec. 5) Establishes the Federal Advisory Commission of the Airports Authority (thereby effectively replacing the Board of Review of the Airports Authority). (Sec. 6) Requires Airports Authority actions to be submitted to the Federal Advisory Commission (currently, the Board of Review) for review. Requires certain Airports Authority decisions to remain in effect and not be set aside solely by reason of a judicial order invalidating certain functions of the Board of Review. (Sec. 7) Revises requirements for congressional review of Airports Authority actions. (Sec. 8) Provides for the removal of Federal Advisory Commission (previously, Board of Review) members by the Secretary of Transportation (currently, by a two-thirds vote of the board of directors). (Sec. 11) Directs the Airports Authority to continue to enforce certain restrictions contained in the Metropolitan Washington Airports Regulations with respect to the use of the Dulles access highway. (Sec. 13) Prohibits the Secretary from issuing an exemption under specified sections of title 14 of the Code of Federal Regulations regarding the allocation of slots at high density airports if such exemption would adversely affect safety.</summary>
</bill>
