<bill session="105" type="h" number="1066" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Jobs Opportunity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide that an individual who receives a passing grade in an examination for entrance into the competitive service shall, if such individual is a welfare recipient, be granted additional points above the individual's earned rating.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="410407" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1997-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil service system"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare recipients"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/1997--Introduced.
Federal Jobs Opportunity Act - Amends Federal law concerning Government organizations and employees to entitle an individual who receives a passing grade in an examination for entrance into the competitive service, and, on the date of taking such examination or at any time within the 14-day period immediately preceding such date, is a welfare recipient, to three additional points above the rating earned by such individual. Requires that any entitlement of an individual to additional points under the preceding in connection with a particular examination shall terminate: (1) upon the termination of the individual's entitlement to welfare benefits or within a reasonable period thereafter as may be provided for under any regulations to carry out this Act; or (2) if later, upon the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date of the examination (non-applicable if the welfare benefits are terminated by reason of fraud or for other similar reasons). Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to prescribe any regulations necessary to carry out this Act, including provisions relating to: (1) how an individual may demonstrate that he or she qualifies as a welfare recipient for purposes of this Act; and (2) procedures under which OPM, an appointing authority, or another official or agency shall be notified in the event of a termination of welfare benefits.</summary>
</bill>
