<bill session="104" type="h" number="602" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Omnibus Territories Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Guam World War II Loyalty Recognition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Insular Areas Consolidation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Territorial Administrative Cessation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform the laws concerning territories and possessions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Economic and Educational Opportunities, the Judiciary, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Native American and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held. Hearings Printed: H. Hrg. 104-5.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-05">
      <text>See H.R.1332.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII14" subcommittee="Native American and Insular Affairs" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1332"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional delegations"/>
    <term name="Congressional terms of office"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Reefs"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax rebates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/20/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Territorial Administrative Cessation Act Title II: Authority Modifications Pursuant to Covenant of Northern Mariana Islands Title III: Insular Areas Consolidation Act Title IV: Conveyance of Submerged Lands to Northern Mariana Islands Title V: Guam World War II Loyalty Recognition Act Title VI: Delegate From Puerto Rico Title VII: Consultation of and Efforts to Include Territories Regarding Free Trade Agreements Omnibus Territories Act - Title I: Territorial Administrative Cessation Act - Territorial Administrative Cessation Act - Abolishes the Office of Territorial and International Affairs of the Department of the Interior. Title II: Authority Modifications Pursuant to Covenant of Northern Mariana Islands - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide minimum wage coverage for the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands on the same basis as American Samoa. (Sec. 203) Treats the Northern Mariana Islands as a State for purposes of the Immigration and Nationality Act. Applies Federal statutes and regulations governing admission to Guam of certain workers described by such Act to individuals seeking entry into the Northern Mariana Islands for purposes of employment in the textile, hotel, tourist, or construction industries. Requires the Attorney General to limit the amount of immigrant workers in such industries to the number of such workers admitted into the Northern Mariana Islands in 1992. Authorizes an increase in such limit based on the percentage by which the current population exceeds that of the 1992 population. (Sec. 204) Removes the authority of the Northern Mariana Islands to rebate taxes. Title III: Insular Areas Consolidation Act - Insular Areas Consolidation Act of 1995 - Requires the State of Hawaii to include Baker Island, Jarvis Island, Johnston Atoll, Kingman Reef, Howland Island, the Midway Islands, and Palmyra Atoll. (Sec. 302) Subjects such islands, appurtenant reefs, and territorial waters to existing rights of use, ownership, and operation by the U.S. Government. (Sec. 303) Exempts such reef, islands, and atolls from provisions governing guano islands. (Sec. 305) Makes such consolidation subject to acceptance by the Governor of Hawaii. Title IV: Conveyance of Submerged Lands to Northern Mariana Islands - Makes specified provisions regarding the conveyance of tidelands, submerged lands, and filled lands currently applicable to Guam, the Virgin Islands, and American Samoa applicable to the Northern Mariana Islands as well. Title V: Guam World War II Loyalty Recognition Act - Guam World War II Loyalty Recognition Act - Sets forth requirements for claims for awards or benefits for compensable injuries suffered by Guamanians during World War II. (Sec. 502) Defines "compensable injury" as any of the three following categories of injury incurred during, or as a result of, World War II: (1) death; (2) personal injury; or (3) forced labor, forced march, or internment. (Sec. 503) Requires the Guam World War II Loyalty Recognition Trust Fund Board of Directors to determine eligibility for awards or benefits and certify claims for payment. (Sec. 504) Makes Guamanians who personally received compensable injuries eligible for awards and heirs or next of kin of such individuals eligible for benefits. Lists additional criteria to be met by claimants. Provides for payment for certified claims. (Sec. 505) Requires payment of the benefit (in cases where the relevant injury was death) to be divided among the heirs or next of kin claiming such payment, as provided in the Guam probate laws. (Sec. 506) Establishes the Guam World War II Loyalty Recognition Trust Fund and the Trust Fund Board of Directors for making disbursements under this Act. Permits the Board to make disbursements from the Trust Fund only: (1) to make payments of awards and benefits to eligible claimants; (2) to sponsor research and public educational activities relating to Guamanian wartime experiences; (3) to disburse funds as benefits to eligible claimants through a revolving fund for purposes such as post-secondary scholarships and first-time home ownership loans; and (4) for administrative expenses. (Sec. 510) Limits any remuneration on account of services rendered on behalf of any claimant in connection with any claim to five percent of the amount paid on such claim. Prescribes penalties for violations of such limit. (Sec. 512) Authorizes appropriations. Title VI: Delegate from Puerto Rico - Redesignates the Resident Commissioner to the United States from Puerto Rico as the Delegate from Puerto Rico. (Sec. 602) Reduces the term of office of the Delegate from four to two years. Title VII: Consultation of and Efforts to Include Territories Regarding Free Trade Agreements - Requires the President to: (1) consult with representatives chosen by the governors of Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands regarding the process advanced by the Miami Summit of the Americas Declaration of Principles that would have an impact on such territories and include such representatives in the U.S. delegation to any working group or task force regarding such process, including the development of the Free Trade of the Americas agreement; (2) provide for the same consultation and inclusion of representatives with respect to American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands regarding the process advanced by the Bogor Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Leaders' Declaration of Common Resolve that would have any impact on such territories, including the goal of free trade among APEC members. (Sec. 702) Requires the President to grant American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Virgin Islands tariff treatment comparable to that granted to parties to the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) or other free trade agreements to which the United States becomes a party. Applies such requirement only if such a territory reaches a tariff staging agreement with the President that phases out tariffs between the territory and the United States in equal annual increments over a period not to exceed ten years. (Sec. 703) Requires, upon completion of such an agreement, that: (1) such territory be included in the U.S. customs territory; and (2) the President take steps necessary to include such territory in NAFTA and all other free trade agreements to which the United States is a party.</summary>
</bill>
