<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="856" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2095" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2007-10-17T16:53:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <offered datetime="2007-10-17"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the Federal Railroad Safety Administration to issue regulations requiring owners of track carried on one or more railroad bridges to adopt safety practices to prevent the deterioration of railroad bridges and reduce the risk of human casualties, environmental damage, and disruption to the Nation's transportation system that would result from a catastrophic bridge failure. The amendment also strikes Sections 301, 610, and 616 of the reported bill because these sections were enacted in Public Law 110-53, the "Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007." The amendment would also require the Secretary to consider additional criteria regarding communities when reviewing applications for a waiver or exemption from sounding locomotive horns at highway-rail grade crossings.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 110-371 to require the Federal Railroad Safety Administration to issue regulations requiring owners of track carried on one or more railroad bridges to adopt safety practices to prevent the deterioration of railroad bridges and reduce the risk of human casualties, environmental damage, and disruption to the Nation's transportation system that would result from a catastrophic bridge failure. The amendment also strikes Sections 301, 610, and 616 of the reported bill because these sections were enacted in Public Law 110-53, the `Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007.' The amendment would also require the Secretary to consider additional criteria regarding communities when reviewing applications for a waiver or exemption from sounding locomotive horns at highway-rail grade crossings.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-17T16:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Oberstar.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11687-11689" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11687-11688" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2007-10-17T16:53:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Oberstar amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
