<bill session="104" type="h" number="3792" updated="2012-11-01T22:45:22-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">R.I.G.H.T. Congress Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restore integrity, goodwill, honesty, and trust to Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="1996-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="402524" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400584" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1996-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="406922" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="408142" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400607" joined="1996-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1996-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="410636" joined="1996-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H6977)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6977"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on Government Reform and Oversight, Rules, National Security, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-22">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Civil Service"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSRU" name="House Rules"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSAS" name="House National Security"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" name="House National Security" subcommittee="Military Readiness"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee membership"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee staffing"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional privileges and immunities"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Military aircraft"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="Military transportation"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Restaurants"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports facilities"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>07/11/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Congressional Compensation Title II: Lobbying Title III: Congressional Travel R.I.G.H.T. Congress Act - Title I: Congressional Compensation - Applies existing Federal law regarding special accrual rates for Members of Congress and congressional employees under the Civil Service and Federal Employees' Retirement Systems only with respect to congressional service performed before the beginning of the 105th Congress. Eliminates the automatic cost of living adjustment for that portion of an annuity of a Member that is based solely on service as a Member. Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to: (1) eliminate automatic pay adjustments for Members until otherwise provided under the Federal Salary Act of 1967; and (2) require a recorded vote on any pay adjustment for Members. Title II: Lobbying - Modifies the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to: (1) increase from one to two years after leaving office the period of time during which a Member or employee is prohibited from engaging in certain lobbying activities; (2) include employees of a congressional committee on which a Member serves among those persons whom former Member employees may not lobby for such period; and (3) decrease the salary level of congressional employees below which lobbying restrictions do not apply. Amends rule XXXII of the Rules of the House of Representatives to deny admission to the House floor to former Members who are registered lobbyists. Prohibits such a former member from entering any Capitol dining facility or any gymnasium facility that is reserved for Members. Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to require registered lobbyists to wear identification badges when in the U.S. Capitol or in a House or Senate office building while engaged in lobbying activities. Title III: Congressional Travel - Prohibits the Secretary of Defense from providing transportation on a military aircraft for a Member unless: (1) the transportation is provided on a space-available basis as part of scheduled operations unrelated to the provision of transportation to the Member; (2) the destination, or an airfield located within a reasonable distance thereof, is inaccessible by regularly scheduled commercial aircraft flights; or (3) the transportation is the least expensive method for the Member to reach the destination by aircraft. Requires prior approval from the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct for Members and staff travelling on military aircraft to a hearing. Prohibits a retiring Member, or such Member's personal staff, from engaging in foreign travel unless such Committee determines such travel is essential to the Member's official responsibilities. Requires that any travel award that accrues by reason of official travel of a House Member, officer, or employee be used only for official travel, or by the spouse or children of that Member for travel between Washington, D.C. and that Member's district.</summary>
</bill>
