<bill session="104" type="h" number="4028" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Great Lakes Fish and Wildlife Restoration Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Great Lakes Fish and Wildlife Restoration Act of 1990 to provide for implementation of recommendations of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service contained in the Great Lakes Fishery Restoration Study Report.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400235"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1996-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1996-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1996-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1996-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1996-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1996-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1996-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Aquatic pests"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/5/1996--Introduced.
Great Lakes Fish and Wildlife Restoration Act of 1996 - Amends the Great Lakes Fish and Wildlife Restoration Act of 1990 to: (1) include among the Act's purposes to develop and implement proposals for the restoration of fish and wildlife resources in the Great Lakes Basin (Basin); and (2) include microorganisms within the definition of "nonindigenous species." Requires the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service (Service) to: (1) ensure that proposals resulting from recommendations of the Great Lakes fishery resources restoration study or identified through an annual request to specified State and tribal entities are developed and that the highest priority proposals are implemented; and (2) annually request that State Directors and Indian Tribes submit fish and wildlife resources restoration proposals based on the results of the study or other sources. Requires the Great Lakes Fishery Commission to retain authority and responsibility for formulation and implementation of a comprehensive program for eradicating or minimizing sea lamprey populations in the Basin. Authorizes the Secretary of the Army, at the Commission's request, to construct and improve water resources projects related to sea lamprey management. Establishes the Great Lakes Fish and Wildlife Restoration Proposal Review Committee. Directs the Secretary to select proposals to be implemented and, within available appropriations, fund their implementation. Sets forth cost-sharing requirements. Authorizes appropriations for the operation of the three offices for each of FY 1998 through 2002. Revises the Act to require the Director to maintain the functions of the Great Lakes Coordination Office in East Lansing, Michigan, and of the Upper and Lower Great Lakes Fishery Resources Offices and to provide administrative and technical support services. Requires the Director, within six months after the end of every second fiscal year, to submit to specified congressional committees a report describing actions taken to implement the process for the indentification, review, and implementation of proposals, and the results of proposals so implemented. Authorizes appropriations for implementation of specified fish and wildlife restoration proposals for FY 1996 through 2002.</summary>
</bill>
