<bill session="104" type="hr" number="115" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-15T14:24:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-03-15T14:24:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1158) making emergency supplemental appropriations for additional disaster assistance and making rescissions for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1995, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-14T22:06:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-78, by Mr. Dreier.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-14T22:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1158 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. It shall be in order to consider as original text for the purpose of amendment the text of H.R. 1158 combined with the text of H.R. 1159 (except the text of sec. 306 of H.R. 1159. The bill shall be considered as read and subject to a 10 hour amendment process under the five minute rule. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in the Congressional Record prior to March 14, 1995 to H.R. 1158 or H.R. 1159. Amendments shall be debatable for not to exceed 30 minutes. The following amendments printed in the Record shall be in order, notwithstanding any rule of the House: Amendment No. 13 (to H.R. 1158); amendment No. 53 (to H.R. 1158); amendment No. 13 (to H.R. 1159).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-03-14T22:06:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="32">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 32.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-03-15T12:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3172-3193" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-15T12:23:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the resolution and on the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-15T13:35:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-15T13:42:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment and the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-03-15T14:24:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="238" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 242 - 190 (Roll no. 238).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-03-15T14:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="1158"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1159"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h292"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/15/1995--Passed House amended.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 1158 (emergency supplemental appropriations and rescissions for FY 1995).</summary>
</bill>
