<bill session="108" type="h" number="3505" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-17T14:08:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-17T14:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Bend Pine Nursery Land Conveyance Act to specify the recipients and consideration for conveyance of the Bend Pine Nursery, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400419"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17T14:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-494.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-17T14:04:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="281">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 281.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Radanovich moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3023-3024" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3505.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-05-17T14:08:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3023-3024" label="text as passed House"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="517">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 517.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1848"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="1848"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2004--Reported to House amended.
Amends the Bend Pine Nursery Land Conveyance Act to repeal the authorization for the sale or exchange of any or all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to Tract A (comprising approximately 210 acres) of the Bend Pine Nursery in Oregon. Rescinds the right of first refusal previously granted to the Bend Metro Park and Recreation District in Deschutes County, Oregon to purchase Tract A of the Bend Pine Nursery. Directs the Secretary, upon receipt of consideration in the amount of $3,505,676 from the Bend Metro Park and Recreation District, to convey all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to a parcel of real property consisting of approximately 185 acres and containing the Bend Pine Nursery to such Recreation District. Requires that the real property conveyed to the Bend Metro Park and Recreation District under this Act be used for recreation purposes only and permits it to be developed for those purposes. Provides that, if the Secretary determines that the real property subject to this condition is converted, in whole or in part, to non-recreational use, the Secretary shall require the Bend Metro Park and Recreation District to pay to the United States an amount equal to the fair market value of such property at the time of conversion, less such consideration paid. Directs the Bend Metro Park and Recreation District, after receipt of the real property described above, to convey, without consideration, a parcel of real property located in the northwest corner of such property and consisting of approximately 15 acres to the Administrative School District No. 1, Deschutes County, Oregon. Instructs that the deed of such conveyance contain a covenant requiring that the real property conveyed to the School District be used for educational purposes only.</summary>
</bill>
