<bill session="104" type="hr" number="375" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-12T17:50:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-03-12T17:50:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 1561) to consolidate the foreign affairs agencies of the United States; to authorize appropriations for the Department of State and related agencies for fiscal years 1996 and 1997; to responsibly reduce the authorizations of appropriations for United States foreign assistance programs for fiscal years 1996 and 1997, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-03-07T18:19:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-476, by Mr. Goss.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-07T18:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 1561. Upon adoption of this resolution, all points of order against the conference report and against its consideration shall be waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-03-07T18:20:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="190">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 190.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-03-12T16:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2075-2082" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-12T16:46:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-12T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-03-12T17:50:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="56" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 180 (Roll no. 56).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-03-12T17:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="1561"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/1996--Introduced.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the conference report on H.R. 1561 (consolidating the foreign affairs agencies, authorizing appropriations for the Department of State, and reducing foreign assistance).</summary>
</bill>
