<bill session="105" type="h" number="2181" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-25T14:47:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-02-25T14:47:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Witness Protection and Interstate Relocation bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Witness Protection and Interstate Relocation Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Witness Protection and Interstate Relocation Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Witness Protection and Interstate Relocation Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure the safety of witnesses and to promote notification of the interstate relocation of witnesses by States and localities engaging in that relocation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400588" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="1997-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Held by the Subcommittee on Crime and Forwarded to Full Committee by Voice Vote Prior to Introduction (July 16, 97).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-07-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 20 - 4.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18T19:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 105-258.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-09-18T19:12:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="148">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 148.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-02-24T17:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 366 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2181 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T12:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 366 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T12:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 366.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H599-609" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T12:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2181 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T12:55:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 366 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T12:55:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Vince Snowbarger to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T12:56:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T14:23:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2181.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T14:24:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-02-25T14:47:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="21" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 366 - 49, 1 Present (Roll no. 21).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T14:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="366"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="747"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h497"/>
    <amendment number="h498"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/17/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Gang-Related Witness Intimidation and Retaliation Title II: Witness Relocation and Safety Witness Protection and Interstate Relocation Act of 1997 - Title I: Gang-Related Witness Intimidation and Retaliation - Amends the Federal criminal code to set penalties for traveling in interstate or foreign commerce with intent to engage in witness intimidation or obstruction of justice. (Sec. 102) Subjects persons who conspire to obstruct justice involving victims, witnesses, and informants to the same penalties as those prescribed for carrying out such offense. Title II: Witness Relocation and Safety - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) survey all State and selected local witness protection and relocation programs to determine and report to the Congress on the extent, nature, and training needs of such programs; and (2) make available training to assist State and local law enforcement agencies in developing and managing witness protection and relocation programs. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 202) Requires the Attorney General to: (1) engage in activities which promote coordination among State and local witness interstate relocation programs; and (2) establish a model Memorandum of Understanding for States and localities that engage in interstate witness relocation. Authorizes the Attorney General to expend up to ten percent of the total amount appropriated for drug control and system improvement (Byrne program) grants under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to jurisdictions that have interstate witness relocation programs and that have substantially followed the model Memorandum of Understanding. (Sec. 203) Authorizes the use of Byrne grant funds for developing and maintaining witness security and relocation programs.</summary>
</bill>
