<bill session="105" type="h" number="3899" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-13T12:22:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-13T12:22:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Homeownership Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Affordable Housing Barrier Removal Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Manufactured Housing Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">American Homeownership Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Affordable Housing Barrier Removal Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Manufactured Housing Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand homeownership in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1998-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1998-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="1998-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1998-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400583" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="409087" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400353" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="410084" joined="1998-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E887-888"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-06">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 17 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T11:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lazio moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T11:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10691-10711" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T11:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-10-13T12:22:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T12:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development corporations"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Cooperative housing"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Estate planning"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial planning"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Home equity conversion"/>
    <term name="Home equity loans"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing codes"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Industrialized building"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Moderate income housing"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Variable rate mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="World Wide Web"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/1998--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Removal of Barriers to Affordable Housing Title II: Homeownership Through Mortgage Insurance and Loan Guarantees Title III: Section 8 Homeownership Option Title IV: Home Investment Partnerships Program Title V: Local Homeownership Initiatives Title VI: Manufactured Housing Improvement Title VII: Indian Housing Homeownership Title VIII: Transfer of Unoccupied and Substandard HUD-Held Housing to Local Governments and Community Development Corporations American Homeownership Act of 1998 - Title I: Removal of Barriers to Affordable Housing - Affordable Housing Barrier Removal Act of 1998 - Requires proposed and final agency rules to analyze their impact upon affordable housing availability, including provision for interested parties to offer alternatives, which shall be incorporated into the final rule if found to accomplish required objectives with a less deleterious effect upon housing. Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to develop model housing impact analyses. (Sec. 103) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to authorize FY 1999 through 2003 direct appropriations for State and local grants for regulatory barrier removal. Makes consortia of local governments eligible grantees. Requires grant use in coordination with the local comprehensive affordability strategy (CHAS) under the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act. (Sec. 104) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to require jurisdictions to make good faith efforts at affordable housing barrier removal in order to qualify for community development block grants (CDBG) (without creating a private right of action). (Sec. 105) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to state that the regulatory barriers clearinghouse shall be established within the Office of Policy Development of HUD under the direction of the Assistant Secretary for Policy Development and Research. Title II: Homeownership Through Mortgage Insurance and Loan Guarantees - Amends the National Housing Act to authorize the Secretary to increase the number of adjustable single family mortgages and loans that may be insured each year by up to 40 percent of the previous year's number of mortgages. (Sec. 202) Directs the Comptroller General to conduct a Federal Housing Administration (FHA) housing inspection study. (Sec. 203) Authorizes the Secretary to treat a county or statistical area and contiguous or proximate counties as a single area for certain loan insurance limitation purposes using the highest median price for such determination. (Sec. 204) Amends the National Housing Act to increase the manufactured home lot loan term from 15 years, 32 days to 20 years, 32 days. (Sec. 205) Amends the National Housing Act to repeal prior insurance requirements for new home construction. (Sec. 206) States that upon enactment, the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 shall be amended to entitle a specified section as the "Joseph P. Kennedy II Homeownership Rehabilitation Demonstration Grant Act." (Such Act was subsequently enacted as P.L.105-276.) Makes specified amounts from the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund available for the FY 1999 rehabilitation demonstration grant program. Title III: Section 8 Homeownership Option - Amends the United States Housing Act to provide an homeownership option under the section 8 housing assistance program, including downpayment assistance, beginning with FY 2000. Title IV: Home Investment Partnerships Program - Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to authorize FY 1999 through 2003 appropriations for affordable housing programs. Prohibits set-asides other than specified amounts for: (1) community housing partnership activities; and (2) activities in support of State and local housing strategies. (Sec. 402) Makes limited equity cooperatives and mutual housing associations eligible for home investment partnerships. (Sec. 403) Permits loan pool investment of partnership funds. (Sec. 404) Authorizes the Secretary to make home investment partnerships loan guarantees. Sets forth an aggregate loan guarantee limitation. Title V: Local Homeownership Initiatives - Amends the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation Act to authorize FY 1999 through 2003 appropriations for the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation, including a pilot homeownership initiative set-aside. (Sec. 502) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to revise the homeownership zone grant program, including providing: (1) grant eligibility for units of general local government (currently nonprofit organizations); and (2) assistance targeting for specified low-income homebuyers. Authorizes FY 1999 and 2000 appropriations. (Sec. 503) Expresses the sense of the Congress in favor of lease- to-own tenancies as homeownership tools. (Sec. 504) Amends the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993 to make the National Association of Housing Partnerships eligible for local capacity grants. Removes the specified amount of authorized appropriations. Title VI: Manufactured Housing Improvement - Manufactured Housing Improvement Act - Amends the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 to revise Federal construction and safety provisions for manufactured homes based upon a consensus standards development process. Eliminates the National Manufactured Home Advisory Council. Title VII: Indian Housing Homeownership - Establishes the Indian Lands Status Commission which shall analyze and evaluate the Bureau of Indian Affairs' land recording and documentation system. Terminates the Commission one year after appointment of its members. Authorizes appropriations. Title VIII: Transfer of Unoccupied and Substandard HUD-Held Housing to Local Governments and Community Development Corporations - Amends the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997 to direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to transfer ownership of qualified HUD-held properties (substandard or unoccupied multifamily or unoccupied single family properties) to local governments and community development corporations under specified conditions. (Sec. 802) States that upon enactment the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 shall be amended to permit property unable to be sold under the revitalization area disposition program to be disposed of under this title. (Sec. 803) Directs the Secretary to report on revitalization zones for HUD-held single family properties. (Sec. 804) Makes technical corrections to the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997, the Balanced Budget Downpayment Act, I, and upon enactment, the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999.</summary>
</bill>
