<bill session="104" type="h" number="1193" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Procompetitiveness and Antiboycott Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require that the United States Government hold certain discussions and report to the Congress with respect to the secondary boycott of Israel by Arab countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="1995-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1995-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409154" joined="1995-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1995-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1995-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1995-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1995-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab countries"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial blacklisting"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade policy"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Law and legislation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/1995--Introduced.
Procompetitiveness and Antiboycott Act of 1995 - Directs the U.S. Ambassador to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) to discuss with representatives from other OECD member countries and to report to the Congress on: (1) the extent to which business enterprises comply with the boycott of Israel by Arab countries; (2) the effectiveness, with respect to the secondary boycott, of antiboycott laws of countries that have them; (3) the extent to which the secondary boycott has skewed trade and investment globally as well as in the Middle East; (4) the extent to which business enterprises not complying with the boycott are placed at a competitive disadvantage; (5) the extent to which the secondary boycott contradicts OECD trade and investment policy; and (6) the development of guidelines, comparable to the prohibitions set forth under the Export Administration Act of 1979, that OECD countries can agree on to eliminate compliance with the boycott. (Sec. 4) Requires the United States Trade Representative to enter into discussions with representatives from member and prospective member countries of the World Trade Organization (WTO) and to report to the Congress on the extent to which: (1) the secondary boycott of Israel has distorted trade; (2) members and prospective members of the WTO encourage actions, including the furnishing of information or entering into agreements, which support the boycott; (3) the WTO should work to eliminate the secondary boycott; and (4) General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT) articles can be used to eliminate compliance with such boycott. (Sec. 5) Requires the President to report to the Congress on progress made to end the boycott. (Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary of Commerce to report to the Congress on OECD countries that encourage or fail to discourage compliance with such boycott. (Sec. 7) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Office of Antiboycott Compliance of the Department of Commerce should continue exercising its functions for at least two years after the Arab League renounces: (1) the boycott of Israel by Arab countries; (2) the secondary boycott; and (3) any requirement that a business enterprise comply with such boycott.</summary>
</bill>
