<bill session="106" type="h" number="3894" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dredging Alternatives Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 to restrict ocean dumping at the site off the coast of New Jersey known as the "Historic Area Remediation Site", to dumping of dredged material from States that have developed and made commercially available alternative uses for dredged material, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2000-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Dredging spoil"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2000--Introduced.
Dredging Alternatives Act of 2000 - Amends the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 to prohibit the issuance of a permit authorizing transportation of material for purposes of dumping at the Historic Area Remediation Site (dredged material disposal area located east of Sandy Hook, New Jersey) and provides that no permit authorizing such transportation shall be effective other than one for transportation of qualified dredged material.Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue regulations that establish requirements for material to be considered qualified dredged material. Provides that material is not qualified dredged material unless: (1) it is excavated or dredged in a State that has developed and made commercially available alternative uses for such material; and (2) there are no means of using or disposing of the material other than ocean dumping.</summary>
</bill>
