<bill session="108" type="h" number="4000" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia National Guard College Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to establish a program of financial assistance to enable more members of the National Guard of the District of Columbia to attend institutions of higher education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="2004-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2004-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-25">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Total Force.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS27" subcommittee="Total Force" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2004--Introduced.
District of Columbia National Guard College Access Act - Amends Federal armed forces provisions to authorize the Secretary of the military department concerned to provide financial assistance to an eligible member of the District of Columbia National Guard for expenses while enrolled in an approved institution of higher education in a degree, certificate, or other program leading to a recognized educational credential at such institution. Requires such members, in order to be eligible, to: (1) be such a member for at least 12 consecutive months preceding commencement of the assistance; (2) be enrolled or accepted for enrollment at such an institution; and (3) if already enrolled, maintain satisfactory progress in a course of study in accordance with requirements of the Higher Education Act of 1965. Prohibits assistance amounts from exceeding $2,500 per academic year and $12,500 altogether.</summary>
</bill>
