<bill session="107" type="h" number="4875" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cancer and Terminal Illness Patient Health Care Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to waive the employee portion of Social Security taxes imposed on individuals who have been diagnosed as having cancer or a terminal disease.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2002-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2002-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Terminally ill"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2002--Introduced.
Cancer and Terminal Illness Patient Health Care Act of 2002 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to waive the employee portion of the Social Security tax for any period in which a taxpayer has been certified by a physician as having cancer or a terminal illness. Applies the waiver if an individual's cancer is in remission only during the period the individual incurs significant costs (not reimbursed by insurance or otherwise) due to the disease.Reduces by 50 percent the rates of tax levied on a self-employed individual for old age, survivors and disability insurance and hospital insurance if a physician has certified the individual as having a terminal disease or cancer throughout the taxable year. Applies the reduction if an individual's cancer is in remission only during the period the individual incurs significant costs (not reimbursed by insurance or otherwise) due to the disease. Specifies that if an individual is certified as having a terminal illness or cancer for only part of a taxable year, the reduction will be the number of percentage points that bears the same ratio to 50 as the portion bears to the taxable year.Sets forth that this Act does not affect Social Security trust fund deposits or benefits under the Social Security Act.</summary>
</bill>
