<bill session="105" type="h" number="2175" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Oil Displacement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an investment credit to promote the conversion of United States coal and domestic carbonaceous feedstocks into liquid fuels.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400183"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401033" joined="1998-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Energy tax credits"/>
    <term name="Feedstock"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Oil sands"/>
    <term name="Peat"/>
    <term name="Shale oils"/>
    <term name="Synthetic fuel"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/1997--Introduced.
Foreign Oil Displacement Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an investment credit for carbonaceous fuels conversion facilities, defined as facilities for producing: (1) oil from shale and tar sands; (2) gas from geopressured brine, Devonian shale, coal seams, or a tight formation, or from biomass; and (3) liquid, gaseous, or solid synthetic fuels from coal (including lignite, standard anthracite, peat, and any byproduct from a coal, culm, or silt preparation facility containing fixed carbon and including such fuels when used as feedstocks). Provides for recapture. Allows any unused portion of a carbonaceous fuels facility credit to be sold or assigned. Provides for the treatment of the seller and acquirer. Excludes from the definitions of "taxable fuel," "gasoline," "diesel fuel," and "aviation fuel," and excludes from taxation under specified provisions, fuel produced by such a facility or that portion of a blend that is such a fuel.</summary>
</bill>
