<bill session="105" type="h" number="1537" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Keep the Government Open Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend subchapter III of chapter 13 of title 31, United States Code (popularly known as the Anti-Deficiency Act), to allow the United States to enter into contracts or obligations during a lapse in appropriations if the President determines that a sufficient appropriation is likely to be made for that purpose before the end of the fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400511"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1997-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1997-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-05-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Municipal employees"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/1997--Introduced.
Keep the Government Open Act of 1997 - Amends Federal law to allow an officer or employee of the United States or of the District of Columbia to make a contract or obligation before an appropriation is made if the President determines that an appropriation is likely for that purpose before the end of the fiscal year in an amount exceeding the contract or obligation. Allows a U.S. officer or employee to continue to supply personal services before an appropriation or continuing resolution is enacted if the President determines that an appropriation is likely for that purpose before the end of the fiscal year in an amount exceeding the cost to the government. Requires payment for those services even if no appropriation is enacted if the President so determines. Appropriates funds to pay salaries for each day on which funds are not available (unless an appropriations measure is enacted for the applicable department or agency and the measure makes no appropriation for that salary).</summary>
</bill>
