<bill session="107" type="h" number="1482" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Improve Voting Process bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Make Every Vote Count Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a grant program administered by the Federal Election Commission for the purpose of assisting States to upgrade voting systems to use more advanced and accurate voting devices and to enhance participation by military personnel in national elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2001-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2001-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-04">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-04">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Soldier voting"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
    <term name="Voting of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2001--Introduced.
Make Every Vote Count Act - Authorizes the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to award matching grants to encourage States and local voting areas to modernize applicable voting systems and enhance voter participation.Amends the Soldiers' and Sailors' Civil Relief Act of 1940 to provide that, for purposes of voting for a Federal or State office, a person absent from a State in compliance with military or naval orders shall not, solely by reason of that absence, be deemed to have: (1) lost a residence or domicile in that State; (2) acquired a residence or domicile in any other State; or (3) become resident in or a resident of any other State.Amends the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to require each State to: (1) permit absent uniformed services voters to use absentee registration procedures and to vote by absentee ballot in general, special, primary, and run-off elections for State and local offices; and (2) accept and process, with respect to any such election, any otherwise valid voter registration application from an absent uniformed services voter if the application is received by the appropriate State election official not less than 30 days before the election.</summary>
</bill>
