<bill session="106" type="h" number="4382" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Air Force Work Force Renewal Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide temporary authority to offer voluntary separation incentives and early retirement to civilian employees of the Department of the Air Force and to provide experimental hiring and personnel management authority for the Department for the purpose of maintaining continuity in the skill level of employees and adapting workforce skills to emerging technologies critical to the needs of the Department.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400538"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="2000-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-05-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E647-648"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E648-649" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advanced weapons"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service system"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Severance pay"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Veterans' preference"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2000--Introduced.
Air Force Work Force Renewal Act - Amends Federal employee provisions to authorize the payment of separation pay for the purpose of maintaining continuity of skills among Air Force civilian employees and adapting the skills of such workforce to emerging technologies critical to Air Force needs and goals.Entitles employees who are voluntarily separated for the above reasons after completing 25 years of service or after becoming 50 years of age and completing 20 years of service to an annuity under either the Civil Service Retirement System or the Federal Employees' Retirement System.Limits the provision of such pay and annuity benefits to not more than 1000 employees in a calendar year. Terminates such authority five years after the enactment of this Act.Authorizes the Secretary of the Air Force, during the five-year period beginning on the enactment of this Act, to carry out a program of experimental use of special personnel management authority to appoint scientists and engineers from outside the civil service to perform: (1) research and exploratory or advanced development; and (2) acquisition of major weapons systems. Limits the number of such appointments to 62, with 50 appointed for the research and development positions and 12 for the acquisition positions. Limits the appointment term to four years, with an authorized two-year extension when necessary to promote Air Force efficiency. Limits the total amount to be paid to employees for any 12-month period as payments in addition to basic pay (offered to recruit highly-qualified individuals). Requires an annual program report from the Secretary to the congressional defense committees during 2001 through 2006.Authorizes the Secretary, during the same period, to carry out a program of experimental hiring for the above positions, using an employee rating system based on relative degrees of merit rather than numerical ratings. Gives priority to candidates with a service- connected disability rating of ten percent or more.Authorizes the Secretary to appoint individuals to fill civilian Air Force positions without competition, provided that public notice has been given and: (1) there is a severe shortage of qualified candidates; (2) there is a need for expediting such hiring; (3) the position is unique and has special qualifications; or (4) the position has a historically high turnover rate. Authorizes the Secretary to appoint to such positions individuals with exceptional academic qualifications (grade point average of 3.5 or higher) or special experience. Gives priority to applicants who are eligible for the veterans' preference.</summary>
</bill>
