<bill session="107" type="h" number="5553" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting America's Savings Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to preserve retirement security by accelerating increases in retirement plan contribution limits and by eliminating rules that force depletion of retirement savings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2002-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2002-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="2002-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-03">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business cycles"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Defined contribution plans"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Golden parachutes"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Retirement age"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Stock exchanges"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2002--Introduced.
Protecting America's Savings Act of 2002 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (Code) to accelerate increases to: (1) the $5,000 deductible individual retirement account (IRA) contribution limit; and (2) the $15,000 elective deferral and the State, local, and tax-exempt organizations' plan limits, the $10,000 SIMPLE plan limit, and catch-up contribution limits.Increases dollar amount eligibility for IRA and Roth IRA deductibility.Amends Federal law to permit Federal employee Thrift Savings Fund catch-up contributions.Amends the Code to expand and make permanent the credit for elective deferrals and IRA contributions for certain individuals.Increases incrementally, from the current of age 70 1/2 to age 75 the required beginning date for distributions from qualified plans. Establishes: (1) $300,000 amounts not subject to minimum distribution requirements for defined contribution and individual retirement plans; and (2) $0 for defined benefit plans.Permits exempt trust and IRA rollovers to a spouse's retirement plan.Permits rollovers by nonspouse designated beneficiaries for the following retirement plans: (1) State and local government or tax-exempt organization deferred compensation plans; (2) employer-purchased employee annuity plans; and (3) certain tax-exempt organization or public school employee annuities.Provides for certain tax-free changes of "equal periodic payment" annuity determinations.Permits certain nonelective employer contributions to be made for qualifying employee "simple retirement accounts."Imposes a golden parachute excise tax on excessive employee remuneration paid by a corporation after bankruptcy.Provides for a study of defined contribution plan losses due to market volatility.</summary>
</bill>
