<bill session="108" type="h" number="4056" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22T16:01:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-22T16:01:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commercial Aviation MANPADS Defense Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Commercial Aviation MANPADS Defense Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Commercial Aviation MANPADS Defense Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage the establishment of both long-term and short-term programs to address the threat of man-portable air defense systems (MANPADS) to commercial aviation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2004-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2004-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2004-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400265" joined="2004-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-29">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-05-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T22:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 108-565, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T22:53:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on International Relations Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 23, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T22:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on International Relations discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-06-23T22:53:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="330">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 330.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6503-6508" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4056.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6613"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-07-22T16:01:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="411" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 423 - 0 (Roll no. 411).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/21/2004 H6503-6504" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22T16:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="License agreements"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Surface-to-air missiles"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2004--Passed House amended.
Commercial Aviation MANPADS Defense Act of 2004 - (Sec. 3) Directs the President to pursue, on an urgent basis, further strong international diplomatic and cooperative efforts (including bilateral and multilateral treaties) in the appropriate forum to limit the availability, transfer, and proliferation of man-portable air defense systems (MANPADS) worldwide. Urges the President to continue to pursue similar efforts to assure the destruction of excess, obsolete, and illicit stocks of MANPADS worldwide. Urges the President to enter into agreements with the governments of foreign countries that, at a minimum, would prohibit: (1) the entry into force of a MANPADS manufacturing license agreement and MANPADS co-production agreement (other than a manufacturing license or co-production agreement with a country party to such an agreement); (2) the export of a MANPADS, including any component, part, accessory, or attachment thereof, without an individual validated license, except pursuant to transfers between governments; and (3) the re-export or retransfer of a MANPADS (or any component, part, accessory, or attachment) to a third person, organization, or government unless the written consent of the government that approved the original export or transfer is first obtained. Directs the President to report to the appropriate congressional committees on the status of such diplomatic efforts and of efforts by the appropriate U.S. agencies to comply with the recommendations of the General Accounting Office report GAO-04-519, entitled "Non-proliferation: Further Improvements Needed in U.S. Efforts to Counter Threats from MANPADS." (Sec. 4) Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), as soon as practicable, but not later than, the completion date of Phase II of the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS) counter-MANPADS development and demonstration program, to establish a process for conducting airworthiness and safety certification of missile defense systems used to defend commercial aircraft against MANPADS. Directs the FAA, not later than 90 days after the first airworthiness and safety certification for a missile defense system for commercial aircraft is issued by the Administrator, and annually thereafter until December 31, 2008, to report to specified congressional committees on each airworthiness and safety certification issued for such defense system for a commercial aircraft. (Sec. 5) Urges the President to pursue strong programs to reduce the number of MANPADS worldwide. Directs the President to report to the appropriate congressional committees on the status of such programs. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to report to specified congressional committees on DHS plans to secure airports and the aircraft arriving and departing from airports against MANPADS attacks.</summary>
</bill>
