<bill session="107" type="h" number="4481" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-09T12:46:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-07-09T12:46:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airport Streamlining Approval Process Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Airport Streamlining Approval Process Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Airport Streamlining Approval Process Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, relating to airport project streamlining, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2002-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="2002-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2002-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2002-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2002-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2002-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="2002-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2002-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="2002-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="2002-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2002-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2002-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2002-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="2002-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="2002-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2002-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-04-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-06-25T17:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 107-531.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-06-25T17:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="321">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 321.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-07-09T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-09T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4361-4365" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-09T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4481.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-07-09T12:46:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4361-4362" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-07-09T12:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2002--Passed House amended.
Airport Streamlining Approval Process Act of 2002 - (Sec. 3) Amends Federal transportation law to direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to take action to encourage the construction of airport capacity enhancement projects at congested airports.(Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Transportation to develop and implement a coordinated review process for such projects, which shall provide that all environmental reviews, analyses, opinions, permits, licenses, and approvals that must be issued or made by a Federal agency or airport sponsor for such a project will be conducted concurrently in cooperation with all Federal and State agencies with jurisdiction over environmental-related matters.Requires: (1) the Secretary determine the reasonable alternatives to an airport capacity enhancement project at a congested airport; and (2) any other participating Federal or State agency to consider only those alternatives the Secretary has determined are reasonable.Authorizes the Secretary, at the request of an airport sponsor for a congested airport, to approve a restriction on use of a runway to be constructed at the airport to minimize potentially significant adverse noise impacts from the runway only if the restriction is necessary and the most appropriate and cost-effective measure (taking into consideration associated environmental trade-offs) to mitigate such impacts and expedite runway construction.Authorizes the Secretary, in specified circumstances, to allow an airport sponsor carrying out such a project to make payments, out of airport revenues (including local taxes on aviation fuel), for measures to mitigate the environmental impacts of the project, including aircraft noise.Permits the FAA Administrator to accept funds from an airport sponsor to hire additional staff or obtain the services of consultants in order to facilitate the timely processing, review, and completion of environmental activities associated with an airport development project.Authorizes appropriations to facilitate timely processing, review, and completion of environmental activities associated with airport capacity enhancement projects at congested airports.Permits a person disclosing a substantial interest in an order issued by the Secretary or the head of any other pertinent Federal agency to apply for judicial review of the order. Prescribes procedures and requirements for such an appeal.(Sec. 5) Repeals the requirement that the Secretary approve a project grant application only if the chief executive officer of the State in which the project will be located certifies that there is reasonable assurance that the project will be located, designed, constructed, and operated in compliance with applicable air and water quality standards.Revises the approval criteria without the requirement of an environmental impact statement for an airport development project that does not involve the location of an airport or runway, or a major runway extension, at an existing airport. Allows such a project without an environmental impact statement if completing the project would allow airport operations involving aircraft complying with the noise standards prescribed for "stage 3" aircraft (currently "stage 2" aircraft).(Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary to incur obligations to make grants to an operator of a congested airport and a specified unit of local government to carry out a project to mitigate noise in the area surrounding the airport, if the project is included as a commitment in an FFA record of decision for an airport capacity enhancement project, even if that airport has not met certain regulatory requirements.</summary>
</bill>
