<bill session="108" type="h" number="4517" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-16T15:27:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-06-16T15:27:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Refinery Revitalization Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">United States Refinery Revitalization Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide incentives to increase refinery capacity in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-14T20:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 671 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4503 and H.R. 4517 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-15T12:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 671 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16T10:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 671.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4178-4191" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16T10:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 4517.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16T11:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16T11:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Speaker put the question on passage of the bill and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Capps demanded the yeas and nays and the Speaker postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4206" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-06-16T15:27:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="246" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 192 (Roll no. 246).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4178-4179" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="hr" number="671"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="671"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2004--Passed House without amendment.
United States Refinery Revitalization Act of 2004 - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Energy to designate as a Refinery Revitalization Zone any area that: (1) has experienced mass layoffs at manufacturing facilities or contains an idle refinery; and (2) has an unemployment rate of at least 20 percent above the national average, as set forth at the time of designation as a Refinery Revitalization Zone. (Sec. 5) Designates the Department of Energy (DOE) as Lead Agency for coordinating Federal authorizations and related environmental reviews of the facility upon request of an applicant for a Federal authorization related to the siting and operation of a refinery facility within a Refinery Revitalization Zone. Instructs the Secretary to coordinate the Federal authorization and review process with any Indian Tribes and State and local agencies responsible for conducting any separate permitting and environmental reviews of the facility. Directs DOE, as lead agency, to prepare a single environmental review document to be used as the basis for all decisions on the proposed project. Sets forth an appeals process in the event the Federal authorization required for a refinery facility within a Refinery Revitalization Zone has been either denied, or an agency has failed to act by the deadline established by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary and the appropriate heads of Federal agencies to enter into Memoranda of Understanding to ensure timely, coordinated review and permitting of refinery facilities within a Refinery Revitalization Zone. Permits interested Indian Tribes and State and local agencies to enter into such Memoranda as well.</summary>
</bill>
