<bill congress="108" type="hr" number="1474" updated="2012-10-31T13:31:20-05:00">
  <status datetime="2003-10-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Check Clearing for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Check Clearing for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Check 21 Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Check Clearing for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Check Truncation Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Check 21 Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Check Clearing for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate check truncation by authorizing substitute checks, to foster innovation in the check collection system without mandating receipt of checks in electronic form, and to improve the overall efficiency of the Nation's payments system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor state="PA" title="Rep" thomas_id="1666" district="4" name="Hart, Melissa A."/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor name="Alexander, Rodney" district="5" title="Rep" state="LA" sponsored_at="2003-04-10" thomas_id="1727"/>
    <cosponsor name="Bachus, Spencer" district="6" title="Rep" state="AL" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="38"/>
    <cosponsor name="Boswell, Leonard L." district="3" title="Rep" state="IA" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="1466"/>
    <cosponsor name="Clay, Wm. Lacy" district="1" title="Rep" state="MO" sponsored_at="2003-04-10" thomas_id="1654"/>
    <cosponsor name="Crowley, Joseph" district="7" title="Rep" state="NY" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="1604"/>
    <cosponsor name="Cunningham, Randy (Duke)" district="50" title="Rep" state="CA" sponsored_at="2003-05-15" thomas_id="258"/>
    <cosponsor name="Ferguson, Mike" district="7" title="Rep" state="NJ" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="1659"/>
    <cosponsor name="Ford, Harold E., Jr." district="9" title="Rep" state="TN" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="1483"/>
    <cosponsor name="Gillmor, Paul E." district="5" title="Rep" state="OH" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="439"/>
    <cosponsor name="Harris, Katherine" district="13" title="Rep" state="FL" sponsored_at="2003-04-10" thomas_id="1714"/>
    <cosponsor name="Hensarling, Jeb" district="5" title="Rep" state="TX" sponsored_at="2003-04-10" thomas_id="1749"/>
    <cosponsor name="Hinojosa, Ruben" district="15" title="Rep" state="TX" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="1490"/>
    <cosponsor name="Jones, Walter B., Jr." district="3" title="Rep" state="NC" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="612"/>
    <cosponsor name="Kelly, Sue W." district="19" title="Rep" state="NY" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="624"/>
    <cosponsor name="Kennedy, Mark R." district="6" title="Rep" state="MN" sponsored_at="2003-05-15" thomas_id="1652"/>
    <cosponsor name="King, Peter T." district="3" title="Rep" state="NY" sponsored_at="2003-05-15" thomas_id="635"/>
    <cosponsor name="Lucas, Ken" district="4" title="Rep" state="KY" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="1562"/>
    <cosponsor name="Maloney, Carolyn B." district="14" title="Rep" state="NY" sponsored_at="2003-04-10" thomas_id="729"/>
    <cosponsor name="McCarthy, Carolyn" district="4" title="Rep" state="NY" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="1503"/>
    <cosponsor name="McIntyre, Mike" district="7" title="Rep" state="NC" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="1505"/>
    <cosponsor name="Moore, Dennis" district="3" title="Rep" state="KS" sponsored_at="2003-04-10" thomas_id="1561"/>
    <cosponsor name="Murphy, Tim" district="18" title="Rep" state="PA" sponsored_at="2003-05-15" thomas_id="1744"/>
    <cosponsor name="Ney, Robert W." district="18" title="Rep" state="OH" sponsored_at="2003-04-10" thomas_id="862"/>
    <cosponsor name="Norton, Eleanor Holmes" title="Rep" state="DC" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="868"/>
    <cosponsor name="Oxley, Michael G." district="4" title="Rep" state="OH" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="885"/>
    <cosponsor name="Pryce, Deborah" district="15" title="Rep" state="OH" sponsored_at="2003-04-10" thomas_id="933"/>
    <cosponsor name="Rodriguez, Ciro D." district="28" title="Rep" state="TX" sponsored_at="2003-05-15" thomas_id="1518"/>
    <cosponsor name="Ross, Mike" district="4" title="Rep" state="AR" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="1632"/>
    <cosponsor name="Royce, Edward R." district="40" title="Rep" state="CA" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="998"/>
    <cosponsor name="Sessions, Pete" district="32" title="Rep" state="TX" sponsored_at="2003-04-10" thomas_id="1525"/>
    <cosponsor name="Shays, Christopher" district="4" title="Rep" state="CT" sponsored_at="2003-04-10" thomas_id="1048"/>
    <cosponsor name="Toomey, Patrick J." district="15" title="Rep" state="PA" sponsored_at="2003-03-27" thomas_id="1594"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <referral datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </referral>
    <referral datetime="2003-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
    </referral>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-14">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-05-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-02T16:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 108-132.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-02T16:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 67.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-03T19:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 256 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1474 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 256 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 256.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4996-5005" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H5001, H5002-5005" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1474 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:08:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 256 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:08:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ray LaHood to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:08:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1474.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:52:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hart amendment under the five minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:54:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1474.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:54:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:57:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on H.R. 1474 the Chair put the question on passage of the bill, as amended, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Bachus demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T15:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5022" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2003-06-05T15:32:00-05:00">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 405 - 0 (Roll no. 246).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T15:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <referral datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs"/>
    </referral>
    <action datetime="2003-06-27">
      <text>Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-27">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8811-8815" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-27">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S.1334.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2003-06-27">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 1334 with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8811-8815" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10T18:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Tiberi asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and request a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10T18:37:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and request a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6582" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10T18:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10T18:38:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees for consideration of the House bill and the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Oxley, Bachus, LaTourette, Hart, Tiberi, Frank (MA), Sanders, and Ford.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-11">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House requests a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, agrees to request for a conference, appoints conferees Shelby; Bennett; Allard; Sarbanes; Johnson.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9431" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01T17:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 108-291 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9083-9090" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08T10:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Oxley brought up conference report H. Rept. 108-291 by previously agreed to special order.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9289-9293" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08T10:30:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 1474.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08T10:58:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2003-10-08T10:58:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9293" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08T10:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12632-12633" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2003-10-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2003-10-23">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2003-10-28">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted datetime="2003-10-28">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-100.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Automated clearing houses"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Warranties"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary date="2003-10-28" status="Public Law.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;(There are 5 &lt;a href=&quot;/cgi-bin/bdquery/z?d108:HR01474:@@@D&amp;summ1&amp;&quot;&gt;other summaries&lt;/a&gt;)">Check Clearing for the 21st Century Act, or Check 21 Act - Sets forth a statutory framework under which a substitute check is the legal equivalent of an original check for all purposes, if the substitute check: (1) accurately represents all of the information on the front and back of the original check as of the time the original check was truncated; and (2) bears the legend: "This is a legal copy of your check. You can use it the same way you would use the original check." (Sec. 3) Defines "substitute check" as a paper reproduction of the original check that: (1) contains an image of the front and back of the original; (2) bears a "MICR line" or "magnetic ink character recognition line" containing all the information appearing on the MICR line of the original check; (3) conforms, in paper stock, dimension, and otherwise, with generally applicable industry standards for substitute checks; and (4) is suitable for automated processing in the same manner as the original. Defines check truncation as removing an original paper check from the check collection or return process and sending in lieu of it a substitute check or, by agreement, information relating to the original check (including data taken from the MICR line of the original check or an electronic image of the original check), whether with or without subsequent delivery of the original paper check. (Sec. 4) Prescribes implementation guidelines covering: (1) bank endorsements and identification of the reconverting bank (a bank that creates a substitute check or is the first bank to transfer or present such a check already created by a non-bank person); (2) the applicability of Federal and State law, the Code of Federal Regulations, and the Uniform Commercial Code; (2) substitute check warranties; (3) indemnity procedures, including a comparative negligence standard; and (4) expedited recredit procedures for consumers and for claimant banks in instances where a substitute check is improperly charged to an account (including notice requirements for reversal of a recredit). (Sec. 8) Sets forth: (1) procedures for claimant banks against an indemnifying bank for expedited recredit; (2) excused bank delays owing to emergency conditions; (3) a measure of damages for breach of warranty or failure to comply with requirements that incorporates a comparative negligence standard; (4) a one-year statute of limitations under which the cause of action accrues as of the date the injured party first learns, or reasonably should have learned, of the facts and circumstances giving rise to the cause of action; and (5) consumer education requirements regarding substitute checks. (Sec. 14) States that any provision of this Act pertaining to expedited recredit procedures for banks may be varied by agreement of the banks involved. (Sec. 16) Instructs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Board) to study and report to Congress on: (1) the percentage of total checks cleared in which the paper check is not returned to the paying bank; (2) the extent to which banks make funds available to consumers for local and nonlocal checks before the expiration of maximum hold periods; (3) the length of time within which depositary banks learn of the nonpayment of local and nonlocal checks; (4) the increase or decrease in check-related losses over the study period; and (5) the appropriateness of certain time periods and amount limits applicable under the Expedited Funds Availability Act, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act. (Sec. 17) Directs the Board to include in subsequent annual reports the amount of operating costs attributable to transportation of commercial checks between Federal Reserve bank check processing centers, including an estimate of the Federal Reserve banks' imputed revenues derived from such transportation. (Sec. 18) Instructs the Comptroller General to evaluate and report to Congress on the implementation and administration of this Act. (Sec. 19) Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of the Treasury for fiscal years beginning after FY 2003 to replace the deposit of compensating balances with direct U.S. payments to reimburse financial institutions in their capacity as depositaries and financial agents of the United States for all services required by the Secretary (or a designee) to be performed on behalf of the Secretary or another Federal agency, including services rendered before FY 2004. (Currently the Secretary compensates financial institutions for various critical depositary and financial agency services provided for or on behalf of the United States by: (1) placing large compensating balances on deposit in such institutions; (2) using imputed interest on such funds to offset charges for such services; and (3) increasing or decreasing the size of such balances as interest rates fluctuate or the public debt outstanding reaches the statutory debt limit.) Prescribes procedural guidelines for the Secretary to promptly begin phasing in the use of appropriations to pay such institutions and to expedite the transition away from the use of compensating balances. Requires the Secretary to report on the use of compensating balances and on the use of appropriations authorized for such purpose for each fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
