<bill session="106" type="h" number="729" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helicopter Noise Control and Safety Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for development and implementation of certain plans to reduce risks to the public health and welfare caused by helicopter operations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1999-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Helicopter transportation"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="Heliports"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/1999--Introduced.
Helicopter Noise Control and Safety Act - Requires the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration upon determining independently, or after review of a study submitted by a requester, that helicopter operations pose a public noise and safety risk in a county or municipality with a greater than 500,000 population, to develop and implement a plan, in accordance with specified requirements, to reduce that risk. Authorizes any city, State, local government, agency, or instrumentality, or any person responsible for the operation of a heliport, to submit to the Administrator: (1) a study demonstrating that noise or safety conditions, or both, resulting from helicopter operations pose a risk to the public health and welfare of such a county or municipality; and (2) a plan to reduce the risk. Requires the Administrator to review such a plan and, upon determining that helicopter operations pose such a risk, to make any modifications necessary to conform with this Act. Specifies procedures for public comment and implementation of a plan developed in either manner.</summary>
</bill>
