<bill session="105" type="h" number="1544" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-25T15:40:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-02-25T15:40:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Agency Compliance Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Federal Agency Compliance Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Federal Agency Compliance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent Federal agencies from pursuing policies of unjustifiable nonacquiescence in, and relitigation of, precedents established in the Federal judicial circuits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400544"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="1997-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1997-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1997-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1997-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400577" joined="1997-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1997-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1997-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="1997-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1997-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1997-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1997-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1997-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1997-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="1997-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-09-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T18:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 105-395.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-11-08T18:48:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="230">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 230.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-02-24T17:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 367 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1544 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 367 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 367.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H587-598" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="H609-611"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1544 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment, the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 367 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jo Ann Emerson to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T12:33:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the end of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment, the Chair put the question and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson-Lee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T12:45:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the end of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment, the Chair put the question and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson-Lee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T12:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1544 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T14:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T14:48:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T15:22:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1544.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T15:22:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T15:22:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-02-25T15:40:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="24" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 241 - 176 (Roll no. 24).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25T15:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="367"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Administrative law judges"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government litigation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="National policy"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court decisions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h493"/>
    <amendment number="h494"/>
    <amendment number="h495"/>
    <amendment number="h496"/>
    <amendment number="h499"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>2/25/1998--Passed House amended.
Federal Agency Compliance Act - Requires a Federal agency and its officers and employees, in administering a statute, rule, regulation, program, or policy (statute) within a judicial circuit, to adhere to the existing precedent respecting the interpretation and application of such statute, as established by the decisions of the U.S. court of appeals for that circuit, with exceptions. Allows an agency to take a position, either in administration or litigation, that is at variance with such precedent if: (1) it is uncertain whether the administration of the statute will be subject to review by the appeals court that established that precedent or a court of appeals for another circuit; (2) the Government did not seek further review of the case in which that precedent was first established in that appeals court or the U.S. Supreme Court because neither the United States nor any agency or officer thereof was a party to the case or because the decision establishing that precedent was otherwise substantially favorable to the Government; or (3) it is reasonable to question the continued validity of that precedent in light of a subsequent decision of that appeals court or the U.S. Supreme Court, a subsequent change in any pertinent statute or regulation, or any other subsequent change in the public policy or circumstances on which that precedent was based. Requires: (1) the officers of any Federal agency supervising the conduct of litigation to ensure that the initiation, defense, and continuation of proceedings in the U.S. courts within, or subject to the jurisdiction of, a particular judicial circuit avoids unnecessarily repetitive litigation on questions of law already consistently resolved against the U.S. position in precedents established by the U.S. courts of appeals for three or more other judicial circuits; (2) decisions on whether to initiate, defend, or continue litigation for purposes of this Act to take into account specified factors, including the effect of intervening changes in pertinent law or the public policy or circumstances on which the established precedents were based; and (3) the Attorney General to report annually to specified congressional committees on the Federal agency efforts to comply with such requirements. Specifies that a decision on whether to initiate, defend, or continue litigation is not subject to court review on the grounds that the decision violates such requirements.</summary>
</bill>
