<bill session="105" type="h" number="52" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Health Information Practices Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a code of fair information practices for health information, to amend section 552a of title 5, United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400505"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1997-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E30-31"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Government Reform and Oversight, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Withdrew Measure from Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-28">
      <text>Re-referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO04" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative responsibility"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debit cards"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forensic medicine"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Guardian and ward"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Power of attorney"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Records management"/>
    <term name="Research ethics"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Fair Health Information Practices Subtitle A: Duties of Health Information Trustees Subtitle B: Use and Disclosure of Protected Health Information Subtitle C: Access Procedures and Challenge Rights Subtitle D: Miscellaneous Provisions Subtitle E: Enforcement Title II: Amendments to Title 5, United States Code Title III: Regulations, Research, and Education; Effective Dates; Applicability; and Relationship to Other Laws Fair Health Information Practices Act of 1997 - Title I: Fair Health Information Practices - Subtitle A: Duties of Health Information Trustees - Requires, subject to exceptions, health care providers, health oversight agencies, health benefit plan sponsors, or public health authorities to permit an individual to examine his or her own protected health information (physical or mental health records created or received by a health care provider, a health benefit plan sponsor, health oversight agency, or public health authority). Excepts certain mental health or other records which may endanger the individual. Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) notice of information practices; (2) disclosure histories; and (3) security. Subtitle B: Use and Disclosure of Protected Information - Sets forth the general rule that health information trustees (health care providers, health oversight agencies, health benefit plan sponsors, public health authorities, and health researchers) may use protected information only for a purpose: (1) that is compatible with and directly related to the purpose for which the information was collected or received by the trustee; or (2) for which the trustee has received disclosure authorization. Makes exceptions regarding: (1) next of kin and directory information; (2) public health; (3) health research; (4) emergencies; (5) judicial and administrative purposes; (6) law enforcement; and (7) subpoenas, warrants, and search warrants. Subtitle C: Access Procedures and Challenge Rights - Sets forth access and challenge procedures for subpoenas, warrants, and search warrants concerning protected health information. Subtitle D: Miscellaneous Provisions - Permits a health information trustee to disclose only such information as is necessary to process a payment when payment is made by a debit, credit, or other payment card. (Sec. 143) Mandates establishment of electronic documents transmission, receipt, and maintenance standards. (Sec. 147) Directs a State to establish a process under which any created or recorded protected health information is delivered to and maintained by the State or its designated entity. Subtitle E: Enforcement - Sets forth civil and criminal penalties for violations of this Act's provisions. Mandates alternative dispute resolution methods to resolve the civil complaints. Title II: Amendments to Title 5, United States Code - Amends provisions of title 5 (Government Organization and Employees) of the United States Code concerning agency records maintained on individuals to direct the head of any agency that is a health information trustee to promulgate rules to exempt a system of records within the agency from stated provisions of title 5, to the extent that the such system contains protected health information. Title III: Regulations, Research, and Education; Effective Dates; Applicability; and Relationship to Other Laws - Authorizes the Secretary to sponsor research concerning protected health information. Directs the Secretary to establish education and awareness programs concerning such information. Establishes, in the Office of the Secretary, the Office of Information Privacy. (Sec. 303) Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) the applicability of the provisions of this Act to protected health information; and (2) the relationship of the provisions of this Act to other laws.</summary>
</bill>
