<bill session="104" type="hr" number="440" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-22T18:41:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-05-22T18:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3448) to provide tax relief for small businesses, to protect jobs, to create opportunities, to increase the take home pay of workers, and for other purposes, and for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1227) to amend the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 relating to the payment of wages to employees who use employer owned vehicles.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21T22:07:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-590, by Mr. Solomon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21T22:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3448 and H.R. 1227 with 5 hours of general debate. Providing for the consideration of H.R. 3448 and H.R. 1227 in the House. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means to H.R. 3448 now printed in the bill shall be considered as read and all points of order against the amendment (except those arising under sec. 425(a) of the Budget Act, shall be waived. The bill and amendment shall be debatable for one hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motion except a motion to recommit with or without instructions. The yeas and nays shall be considered as ordered on passage and on any conference report. After disposition of H.R. 3448, it shall be in order without intervening point of order to consider the bill H.R. 1227 in the House. The amendment in the nature of a substitut...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-05-21T22:07:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="230">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 230.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5432-5445" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-05-22T18:41:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="189" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 211 (Roll no. 189).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="1227"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3448"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="3448"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/1996--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 3448 (income tax revisions) and H.R. 1227 (payment of wages to employees who use employer owned vehicles).</summary>
</bill>
