<bill session="105" type="h" number="1728" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-08-03T14:10:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-08-03T14:10:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Park Service Administrative Amendment of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Park System New Area Studies Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Park System New Area Studies Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the development of a plan and a management review of the National Park System and to reform the process by which areas are considered for addition to the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1997-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-06-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-07-14T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-612.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-07-14T13:52:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="345">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 345.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T14:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Jones moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6912-6913" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-08-03T14:10:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T14:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-01">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Parks, Preservation and Recreation.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks, Historic Preservation and Recreation" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/1998--Passed House amended.
National Park System New Area Studies Act - Amends Federal law to repeal provisions which require: (1) the Secretary of the Interior to annually report to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and to the President of the Senate on areas of national significance that have been studied for potential inclusion in the National Park System (NPS) and requiring, within such report, a listing of not less than 12 such areas; and (2) a synopsis to accompany the annual listing of the areas, for each report previously submitted, of the current and changed condition of the resource integrity of the area and other relevant factors compiled as a result of continual periodic monitoring and embracing the period since the previous such submission or initial report submission one year earlier. Directs the Secretary to submit to the Committee on Resources of the House and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, along with the annual budget, a list of areas recommended for study for potential inclusion in the NPS. Requires the Secretary to give: (1) consideration to those areas that have the greatest potential to meet the established criteria of national significance, suitability, and feasibility; and (2) special consideration to themes, sites, and resources not already adequately represented in the NPS. Prohibits studies of potential areas for inclusion in the NPS from being initiated after the enactment of this Act, except as specifically authorized by an Act of Congress. Provides that nothing in this Act shall: (1) limit the authority of the National Park Service to conduct preliminary resource assessments, gather data on potential study areas, provide technical and planning assistance, prepare or process nominations for administrative designations, update previous studies, or complete reconnaissance surveys of individual areas requiring a total expenditure of less than $25,000; or (2) be construed to apply to the study of any river segment or any trail for potential addition to the national wild and scenic rivers system or the national trails system. Directs the Secretary to complete the study for each area for potential inclusion in the NPS within three complete fiscal years following the date of enactment of specific legislation providing for the study. Requires: (1) each study to consider specified factors, including similar resources already protected, costs, public support, and alternatives for protecting the area; (2) each study to be completed in compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969; and (3) the letter transmitting each completed study to the Congress to contain a recommendation regarding the Secretary's preferred management option for the area. Requires the Secretary to submit to such Committees, along with the annual budget, a list of areas which have been previously studied which contain primarily historical resources, and a list of areas which have been previously studied which contain primarily natural resources, in numerical order of priority for addition to the NPS. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
