<bill session="105" type="h" number="2383" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-09-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the enforcement by State and local governments of certain Federal Communications Commission regulations regarding use of citizens band radio equipment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400119"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1997-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="1997-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Citizens band radio"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/3/1997--Introduced.
Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to allow a State or local government to enforce regulations of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) that prohibit: (1) a use of citizens band radio equipment not authorized by the FCC; or (2) the unauthorized operation of citizens band radio equipment on a frequency between 24 and 35 megahertz. Provides that possession of a station license issued by the FCC in any radio service for the operation at issue shall preclude action by a State or local government. Requires the FCC to provide technical guidance to State and local governments regarding the detection and determination of violations of such regulations. Permits a person affected to submit to the FCC an appeal of the decision of a State or local government enforcing a regulation on the grounds that such entity acted outside the authority provided in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
