<bill session="105" type="h" number="193" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Historic Preservation Act to prohibit the inclusion of certain sites on the National Register of Historic Places and to prohibit the designation of the Mt. Shasta area in the State of California as a historic district, historic sites, or national monument under the National Historic Preservation Act or the Antiquities Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="1997-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mountains"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Natural monuments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Amends the National Historic Preservation Act to prohibit unimproved or unmodified natural landscape features that do not contain artifacts or other physical evidence of human activity or have unique significance in history or pre-history as established by or pursuant to an Act of Congress from being: (1) eligible for inclusion on the National Register of Historic Places or designation as a National Historic Landmark; (2) included on the Register or designated as such Landmark; or (3) considered to be a historic or pre-historic property or historic resource for purposes of the Act or other Federal laws. Provides that nothing in this Act shall invalidate or otherwise affect determinations made before this Act's enactment with respect to any natural landscape feature. Prohibits the Mt. Shasta area in California from being designated by any U.S. agency or authority as a historic district, historic site, or national monument under the Act or the Antiquities Act. Ceases the force and effect of any inconsistent designation made before enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
