<bill session="108" type="h" number="1719" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Security Initiative Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote enhanced nonproliferation cooperation between the United States and the Russian Federation and foster various other actions that will increase the national security of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400428"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2003-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2003-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2003-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400302" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400372" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400398" joined="2003-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2003-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armenia"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Azerbaijan"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missile defenses"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional delegations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Former Soviet states"/>
    <term name="Georgia (Republic)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Kazakhstan"/>
    <term name="Kyrgyzstan"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Military surveillance"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear engineering"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Plutonium"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Reconnaissance satellites"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Tajikistan"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Turkmenistan"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Uzbekistan"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2003--Introduced.
Nuclear Security Initiative Act of 2003 - Declares it is the policy of the United States to seek to cooperate with the Russian Federation and each other independent state of the former Soviet Union to: (1) effect as quickly as is reasonably practical basic security measures at each facility in the Russian Federation and each such state that is used for storing nuclear weapons or nuclear materials and is not yet protected by such measures; (2) the Russian Federation to accelerate the closure of facilities in the Russian Federation used for the production of nuclear weapons; (3) improve the security at facilities, in the Russian Federation and each such state, that contain radioactive materials that could be used in radiological dispersal devices; and (4) improve border controls and other measures to track and intercept illicit transfers of weapons of mass destruction and the materials and technologies for developing and producing such weapons. Authorizes the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) to expand the International Nuclear Materials Protection and Cooperation program of the Department of Energy to encompass countries other than the Russian Federation and the other independent states of the former Soviet Union. Declares it is the policy of the United States to seek to: (1) cooperate with all appropriate nations to attempt to ensure that all nuclear weapons and nuclear materials worldwide are secure and accounted for according to stringent standards; (2) work with international partners to install, at critical international ports, appropriate devices to detect and intercept illicit transfers of weapons of mass destruction that are nuclear or radiological in nature and the materials and technologies for developing and producing such weapons; (3) prevent the proliferation, from the Russian Federation and the other independent states of the former Soviet Union to countries of proliferation concern, of scientists, engineers, and technicians possessing the expertise to develop and produce weapons of mass destruction; (4) establish and promote programs to prevent the proliferation, from scientists, engineers, and technicians of the Russian Federation and other independent states of the former Soviet Union to countries of proliferation concern, of expertise to develop and produce weapons of mass destruction; and (5) seek to assist independent states of the former Soviet Union that have been helpful to the United States in the war on terrorism so as to promote the creation of jobs that foster economic stability and democracy. Authorizes appropriations for accelerated disposition for highly enriched uranium. Directs the Secretary to carry out a Silk Road Initiative to develop sustainable employment opportunities in the United States and in Silk Road nations (Armenia, Azerbaijan, Georgia, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, and Uzbekistan) for scientists, engineers, and technicians formerly engaged in activities to develop and produce weapons of mass destruction in such nations. Authorizes appropriations to assist the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Science for Peace program. Directs the Secretary to: (1) analyze and report to Congress on the effect on threat reduction and nonproliferation programs of applicable congressional oversight measures; (2) report annually to Congress on the use of funds appropriated for threat reduction and nonproliferation programs in the Russian Federation and the other independent states of the former Soviet Union. Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2002, as amended by section 1205 of the Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003, to direct the President submit to Congress a comprehensive, detailed plan to: (1) secure and destroy all chemical and biological weapons, and the chemical and biological materials designed for use in such weapons, that are located in Russia and the independent states of the former Soviet Union; and (2) prevent the outflow from those states of the technology and scientific expertise that could be used for developing those weapons, including delivery systems. for coordination of chemical and biological weapons nonproliferation programs with states of the former soviet union. Declares it is U.S. policy to seek to establish jointly with the Russian Federation comprehensive inventories and data exchanges of Russian Federation and U.S. nuclear weapons-grade material and nuclear weapons, with particular attention to tactical warheads and warheads that are no longer operationally deployed. Urges the United States to seek to work with the Russian Federation to develop such inventories. Establishes a Duma-Congress Nuclear Threat Reduction Working Group as an interparliamentary group of the United States and the Russian Federation. Declares it is U.S. policy that the President should seek to ensure that the United States takes the lead in arranging for the United States, in conjunction with NATO, to enter into appropriate cooperative relationships with the Russian Federation with respect to the development and deployment of theater-level ballistic missile defenses. Declares it is U.S. policy: (1) to encourage joint efforts by the United States and the Russian Federation to reduce the chances of a Russian nuclear attack anywhere in the world as the result of misinformation or miscalculation by developing the capabilities and increasing the reliability of Russian ballistic missile early-warning systems, including the Russian-American Observation Satellite (RAMOS) program; and (2) to encourage other United States-Russian programs to ensure that the Russia Federation has reliable information, including real-time data, regarding launches of ballistic missiles anywhere in the world. Directs the Secretary of Defense to ensure interim funding of the RAMOS program pending the execution of a new agreement between the United States and the Russian Federation providing for it. Directs the Secretary of Energy to seek to enter into an agreement with the Minister of Atomic Energy of the Russian Federation to carry out a cooperative venture, to be known as the (Edward) Teller-(Igor) KurchatovAlliance for Peace, to develop and promote peaceful, safe, and environmentally sensitive uses of nuclear energy. Authorizes the Administrator for Nuclear Security to award international exchange Teller-Kurchatov Fellowships in the nuclear nonproliferation sciences to scientists employed at the Kurchatov Institute of the Russian Federation and Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (California). Declares the sense of Congress in favor of discussions on nuclear and radiological security and safety between the International Atomic Energy Agency and the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development for the purpose of exploring issues of nuclear and radiological security and safety, including the creation of new sources of revenue (including debt reduction) for states to provide nuclear security; and (2) the discussions referred to in paragraph (1) should also provide a forum to explore possible sources of funds in support of the G-8 Global Partnership Against the Spread of Weapons and Materials of Mass Destruction.</summary>
</bill>
