<bill session="108" type="h" number="3982" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-04T14:58:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-04T14:58:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Interior to convey certain land held in trust for the Paiute Indian Tribe of Utah to the City of Richfield, Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2004-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-22">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-09-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30T18:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-715.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-09-30T18:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="437">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 437.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gibbons moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7969-7970" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3982.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-10-04T14:58:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7969-7970" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/2004--Passed House without amendment.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey specified land held by the United States in trust for the Paiute Indian Tribe of Utah (Tribe) to the city of Richfield, Utah. Specifies that the conveyance shall be subject to the following conditions: (1) that the Secretary ensure that the terms of the sale have been approved by a tribal resolution; (2) consideration given by the city for such property shall be not less than the property's appraised fair market value; (3) the city pay all costs related to the conveyance; and (4) proceeds from the conveyance be given immediately to the Tribe. Makes land acquired in trust for the Tribe after February 17, 1984, part of the Tribe's reservation. Directs the Secretary, pursuant to a tribal resolution of the Tribe, to remove land held in trust for the Tribe and place such land in trust for the Shivwits or Kanosh Bands of the Paiute Indian Tribe. Amends the Paiute Indian Tribe of Utah Restoration Act to change the name of the Cedar City Band of Paiute Indians to the Cedar Band of Paiute Indians.</summary>
</bill>
