<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="1082" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:19-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="4973" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2006-06-27T14:31:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400307"/>
  <offered datetime="2006-06-27"/>
  <description>Manager's amendment consists of the text of the amendment contained in House Report 109-530 and printed on page H4598 in the Congressional Record for June 27, 2006.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 109-530 which contains a number of technical and conforming changes, including: clarification that the provisions governing the phasing-in of actuarial rates for nonresidential and non-primary residence properties will apply on the date on which the director of FEMA submits a required report to Congress, as opposed to the date of this legislation's enactment; clarification that the $1 million cap on penalties for non-enforcement of mandatory flood insurance purchase requirements will not apply to a regulated institution or enterprise, for a calendar year, if in any 3 of the past 5 calendar years that institution or enterprise was assessed a penalty of $1 million; clarifications regarding the requirements for states to request FEMA participation in state-run disaster claims mediation programs and certain other provisions of the bill related to the claims mediation process; clarification of the timeline for FEMA's inclusion of certain features on updated floodplain maps; and clarification of the FEMA Director's authority regarding his ability to issue interim post-disaster flood elevation building requirements.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-27T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Oxley.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4598-4599l" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4598-4599" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2006-06-27T14:31:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Oxley amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
