<bill session="104" type="hr" number="5" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04T16:48:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-01-04T16:48:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 6) adopting the Rules of the House of Representatives for the One Hundred Fourth Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04T14:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10-23" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04T14:34:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04T15:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 6 with 30 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Bill is closed to amendments. The question of adopting the resolution shall be divided among nin parts, to wit: each of the eight sections of title I; and title II. Each portion of the divided question shall be debatable separately for 20 minutes, to be equally divided and controlled by the Majority and Minority Leaders, and shall be disposed of in the order stated. Pending the question of adopting the ninthe portion of the divided question, it shall be in order to move that the House commit the resolution to a select committee, with or without instructions. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to commit to final adoption without intervening motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04T16:11:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 232 - 199 (Roll no. 3).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04T16:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Bonior moved to commit with instructions to Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04T16:32:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to commit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 196 - 235 (Roll no. 4).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H22" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-01-04T16:48:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="5" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 251 - 181 (Roll no. 5).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04T16:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="hr" number="6"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.Res. 6 (adopting and revising the Rules of the House of Representatives for the 104th Congress).</summary>
</bill>
