<bill session="104" type="h" number="4185" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Intradialytic Parenteral Nutrient Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to pay for parenteral nutrients provided as part of renal dialysis services as part of payment for renal dialysis services under the medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1698"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Vitamins"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/1996--Introduced.
Medicare Intradialytic Parenteral Nutrient Act of 1996 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide for reimbursement of intradialytic parenteral nutrients provided to patients with end stage renal disease as part of the payment under Medicare for renal dialysis services. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish criteria to determine medically appropriate uses of such nutrients when provided to a patient determined to have such disease. Conditions Medicare payment for such nutrients after a certain future date on their meeting such criteria.</summary>
</bill>
