<bill session="106" type="h" number="5120" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Reclamation Water Resources Project Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Reclamation Projects Act of 1956 to establish a partnership program in the Bureau of Reclamation for small reclamation projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Droughts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Multipurpose projects"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban beautification"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2000--Introduced.
Small Reclamation Water Resources Project Act of 2000 - Amends the Small Reclamation Projects Act of 1956 (the Act) to: (1) add irrigation projects to authorized projects; (2) include an Indian tribe as an organization eligible for assistance under the Act; and (3) revise the definitions of "project" and "water quality improvements."Establishes within the Bureau of Reclamation a program under which the Secretary of the Interior may make grants to organizations to carry out reclamation projects. Outlines proposal requirements for organizations seeking grant assistance. Requires each organization receiving assistance to contribute at least 25 percent of the estimated project cost. Makes the maximum Federal share per project $30 million as of January 2000, to be adjusted annually to reflect construction cost increases. Requires project approval or disapproval by the Secretary within one year. Limits to 50 percent of the maximum Federal share per grant the amount of any grant made under an approved project. Authorizes the Secretary to make a loan to an organization for remaining project costs.Establishes within the Bureau a small grant and loan program, to be known as the Small Reclamation Water Resources Management Partnership Program, to implement projects that can be performed by the recipient organization's workforce or contractors with streamlined documentation in 18 months or less. Limits partnership grants to $2.5 million each, to be matched on a 50 percent basis. Limits loans to the same amount, requiring repayment within five years after project completion. Includes as eligible activities under the partnership program water conservation, water quality improvements, water management for urban landscapes, drought assistance, fish and wildlife improvements, and public safety improvements. Authorizes the Secretary to include additional activities, after public notice and notification of specified congressional committees. Requires project applications to be submitted by April 1 of each year (under specified requirements) and approved or disapproved by September 1 of that year. Allows only one proposal per project area during each five-year period.Establishes within the Bureau a demonstration program for guaranteeing loans for projects receiving grants or loans or grants for approved projects. Allows up to ten percent of amounts authorized to be used for such loan guarantees. Directs the Secretary to adopt and use competitive procedures in selecting organizations to receive such guarantees. Requires 75 percent of the loan guarantee amount to be used for the reclamation projects, and 25 percent to be used for the partnership projects. Prohibits the maximum guarantee percentage for loans from exceeding 75 percent of total project costs. Requires a report from the Secretary to Congress on the beneficial use and suggested improvements of loan guarantees as a mechanism for project construction. Prohibits any guarantee from being issued after six years following initial funding of projects under this Act.Requires each proposal for a loan, grant, or guarantee under this Act to be accompanied by a payment of $5,000 or one tenth of one percent of the Federal project share, whichever is greater, to defray the costs of proposal examination.</summary>
</bill>
