<bill session="106" type="h" number="2901" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Women and Children's Resources Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program of formula grants to the States for programs to provide pregnant women with alternatives to abortion, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400320"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2000-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1999-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400135" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="1999-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="2000-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400248" joined="2000-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1999-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400294" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400501" joined="1999-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1999-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="1999-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1906"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9028"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Abortion counseling"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Childbirth"/>
    <term name="Church and social problems"/>
    <term name="Church and state"/>
    <term name="Churches"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contraceptives"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Nonmarital births"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Poor women"/>
    <term name="Pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Prenatal care"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Sexual abstinence"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/1999--Introduced.
Women and Children's Resources Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to States for programs designed to provide alternative-to-abortion services to eligible individuals. Makes eligible for such services: (1) pregnant individuals; (2) individuals (male or female) who are the parent or legal guardian of an infant under 12 months; or (3) spouses or other partners of such individuals. Requires grants funds to be awarded only to States that assure that the program will: (1) give priority to serving individuals from low-income families; and (2) not impose a charge on such individuals except to the extent that payment will be made by a third party authorized or legally obligated to pay such charge.Sets forth provisions regarding operation of such programs, including contracting and grant expenditure requirements. Requires prime contractors to have a stated policy of actively promoting childbirth instead of abortion. Bars prime contractors or service providers from performing abortions, providing abortion counseling or referrals, or advocating abortions.Requires States applying for grants under this Act to assure that no grant funds will be expended for: (1) performing abortions, providing abortion counseling or referrals, or advocating abortion; or (2) providing, making referrals for, or advocating the use of contraceptives.(Sec. 5) Makes religious organizations eligible to provide services under State programs established under this Act on the same basis as other nongovernmental organizations. Provides certain safeguards to such organizations, including certain rights with respect to employment practices. Requires States to provide an eligible individual with names and addresses of alternative service providers in the case of an objection to an organization's religious character. Bars such organizations from discriminating against an individual with regard to providing services on the basis of religion, a religious belief, or refusal to participate in a religious practice. Prohibits the use of funds obtained pursuant to this Act for sectarian worship, instruction, or proselytization.(Sec. 7) Bases the allotment of funds to a State on the State-calculated percentage of the total appropriations authorized under this Act. Requires such percentage to be determined by dividing: (1) the number of children born in the State to women who were not married at the time of the birth plus the number of abortions performed in the State; by (2) the number of children born in all States to women who were not married at the time of the birth plus the number of abortions performed in all States as last reported by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.(Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 12) Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that overall funding for the Department of HHS should not be increased under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
