<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1077" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="6003" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2008-06-11T12:32:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-06-11"/>
  <description>Amendment provides that none of the funds may be used to employ workers in violation of section 274A of the Immigration and Nationality Act; requires the Secretary of Transportation to conduct a study on ways to streamline compliance with National Historic Preservation Act requirements for federally funded railroad infrastructure projects; inserts provisions regarding the Northeast Corridor; requires studies regarding the expansion of the South Central High-Speed Rail Corridor to Memphis and to far south Texas; requires proposals for building station stops for the proposed high-speed rail system in the Northeast Corridor; authorizes intercity passenger rail grants to be used for bicycle access into rolling stock and would provide bicycle racks in trains and makes technical corrections to the bill.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 110-703 to provide that none of the funds may be used to employ workers in violation of section 274A of the Immigration and Nationality Act; require the Secretary of Transportation to conduct a study on ways to streamline compliance with National Historic Preservation Act requirements for federally funded railroad infrastructure projects; insert provisions regarding the Northeast Corridor; require studies regarding the expansion of the South Central High-Speed Rail Corridor to Memphis and to far south Texas; require proposals for building station stops for the proposed high-speed rail system in the Northeast Corridor; authorize intercity passenger rail grants to be used for bicycle access into rolling stock and would provide bicycle racks in trains and make technical corrections to the bill.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11T12:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Oberstar.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5245-5249" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5245-5246" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2008-06-11T12:32:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Oberstar amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
