<bill session="108" type="h" number="2690" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Native American Languages Act Amendments Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Native American Languages Act to provide for the support of Native American language survival schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400434"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2003-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2003-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2003-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2003-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2003-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2003-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Pacific Islanders"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2003--Introduced.
Native American Languages Act Amendments Act of 2003 - Amends the Native American Languages Act to require the Secretary of Education to make grants to, or enter into contracts with, Native American language educational organizations, Native American language colleges, Indian tribal governments, organizations that demonstrate the potential to become Native American language educational organizations, or consortia of such entities to establish Native American nests that meet specified requirements for students under the age of seven and families of the students. Requires the Secretary to make grants to, or enter into contracts with, Native American language educational organizations, Native American language colleges or universities where such languages are taught, Indian tribal governments, or consortia of such entities, to operate, expand, and increase the number of Native American language survival schools throughout the United States and its territories for Native American children and Native American language-speaking children. Specifies eligibility requirements for recipients of such funds. Requires the Secretary to make grants, or enter into contracts, to establish four demonstration programs that will provide assistance to Native American language survival schools and Native American languages nests located at: (1) Ka Haka 'Ula O Ke'elikolani College of the University of Hawaii at Hilo, in consortium with the 'Aha Punana Leo, Inc., and with other entities if determined to be appropriate by the College; (2) Piegan Institute of Browning, Montana; (3) the Alaska Native Language Center of the University of Alaska at Fairbanks, in consortium with other entities as the Center determines to be appropriate; and (4) the Native American Studies Department of the University of New Mexico at Albuquerque in consortium with the Linguistic Institute for Native Americans and other entities as determined to be appropriate by the consortium.</summary>
</bill>
