<bill session="106" type="h" number="1391" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Brownfields Reuse and Real Estate Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program under which States may be certified to carry out voluntary environmental cleanup programs and to amend CERCLA regarding the liability of landowners and prospective purchasers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400334"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="1999-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Brownfields"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Factories"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/1999--Introduced.
Brownfields Reuse and Real Estate Development Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to: (1) establish certification criteria for State programs for voluntary cleanup of eligible facilities; and (2) certify qualified States to carry out cleanup programs at eligible facilities in lieu of administrative or judicial actions under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) or the Solid Waste Disposal Act. Defines "eligible facility," with exceptions, as an abandoned, idled, or under-used commercial or industrial facility or property for which real or perceived environmental contamination complicates expansion, redevelopment, or reuse. Requires the Administrator to cooperate with States to ensure that State programs continue to meet the terms of certification by assisting States in remedying any deficiency. Sets procedures for withdrawal of certification where deficiencies are not resolved. Requires a State program, to be certified, to provide: (1) adequate opportunities for public participation; (2) technical assistance throughout each voluntary cleanup; (3) adequate resources for cleanup and administration of the program; (4) adequate oversight and enforcement authority; (5) State documentation, to be provided to the owner or prospective purchaser of an eligible facility, that the cleanup is complete; and (6) assurance that the cleanup will protect human health and the environment. (Sec. 7) Amends CERCLA, with respect to defenses to liability of an owner of after-acquired property, to deem a person to have made (under current law, "undertaken") appropriate inquiry into the property's previous ownership and uses if the person establishes that an environmental site assessment was conducted which meets specified requirements (compliance with an American Society for Testing and Materials standard or with standards issued by the Administrator) and the person fulfills certain responsibilities concerning information compilation. (Sec. 8) Absolves from liability for response actions bona fide prospective purchasers to the extent liability at a facility for a release or threat thereof is based solely on ownership or operation of a facility. Gives a lien upon a facility to the United States for unrecovered response costs in any case in which there are such unrecovered costs for which the owner is not liable by reason of this Act and the facility's fair market value has increased above that which existed six months before the action was taken. (Sec. 9) Adds CERCLA provisions governing owner-operator status of persons owning or operating property contiguous to a release site.</summary>
</bill>
