<bill session="105" type="h" number="909" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize certain construction at military installations for fiscal year 1998, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400302" joined="1997-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Installations and Facilities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-18">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.1119.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS04" subcommittee="Military Installations and Facilities" name="House National Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="1119"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Air bases"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Italy"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military construction operations"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Naval bases"/>
    <term name="Naval hospitals"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title XXI (sic): Army Title XXII: Navy Title XXIII: Air Force Title XXIV: Defense Agencies Title XXV: North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program Title XXVI: Guard and Reserve Forces Facilities Title XXVII: Expiration and Extension of Authorizations Title XXVIII: General Provisions Subtitle A: Military Construction Program and Military Family Housing Changes Subtitle B: Other Matters Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998 - Title XXI (sic): Army - Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes the Secretary to construct or acquire family housing units, to carry out architectural planning and design activities, and to improve existing military family housing in specified amounts. Authorizes appropriations to the Army for fiscal years after 1997 for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions of the Army. Limits the total cost of construction projects authorized by this title. Title XXII: Navy - Provides, with respect to the Navy, authorizations paralleling those provided for the Army under the previous title. Title XXIII: Air Force - Provides, with respect to the Air Force, authorizations paralleling those provided for the Army. (Sec. 2305) Amends the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1997 to increase the authorized amount for a military construction project at McConnell Air Force Base, Kansas. Title XXIV: Defense Agencies - Authorizes the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out architectural planning and design activities and to improve existing military family housing units, in specified amounts. (Sec. 2404) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out specified energy conservation projects. (Sec. 2405) Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for fiscal years after 1997 for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions. Limits the total cost of authorized construction projects. (Sec. 2406) Reallocates specified funds made available due to the closure of the McClellan Air Force Base, California, to fund medical construction projects at Andersen Air Base, Guam, and Tinker Air Force Base, Oklahoma. (Sec. 2407) Amends the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1995 to increase the funding for military construction projects at the Pine Bluff Arsenal, Arkansas, and the Umatilla Army Depot, Oregon. Title XXV: North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program - Authorizes the Secretary to make contributions for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program. Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 1997. Title XXVI: Guard and Reserve Forces Facilities - Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 1997 for the Guard and Reserve forces for acquisition, architectural and engineering services, and construction of facilities. Title XXVII: Expiration and Extension of Authorizations - Terminates all authorizations contained in the preceding titles of this Act on October 1, 2000, or the date of enactment of an Act authorizing funds for FY 2001, whichever is later, with exceptions. Extends certain prior-year military construction projects. (Sec. 2704) Extends until a specified conditional date the authorization of appropriations for the Over-the-Horizon Radar at the Naval Station Roosevelt Roads, Puerto Rico, as authorized under a prior military construction authorization Act. Title XXVIII: General Provisions - Subtitle A: Military Program and Military Family Housing Changes - Repeals a current Federal provision prohibiting the Secretary of a military department (Secretary concerned) from entering into certain real property transactions of over $200,000 until 30 days after a report concerning the proposed transaction is submitted to the Senate and House Armed Services and National Security Committees. Subtitle B: Other Matters - Increases from $200,000 to $500,000 the maximum amount of real property that the Secretary concerned may acquire in the interest of national defense. (Sec. 2803) Authorizes DOD to accept funds from a non-Federal party for expenses incurred whenever the Secretary concerned exchanges real property with, or grants an easement, lease, or license to, such a party. (Sec. 2804) Authorizes the Secretary of the Navy to lease in Naples, Italy, structures and real property associated with a regional hospital complex that are needed for military purposes. Provides a lease term of up to 20 years. Terminates such authority on September 30, 2002.</summary>
</bill>
