<bill session="106" type="hr" number="86" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-03T10:50:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-03-03T10:50:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 661) to direct the Secretary of Transportation to prohibit the commercial operation of supersonic transport category aircraft that do not comply with stage 3 noise levels if the European Union adopts certain aircraft noise regulations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-03-02T15:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-38, by Mr. Hastings (WA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-02T15:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 661 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Points of Order for failure to comply with clause 4(a) of rule XIII are waived. After general debate, the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. The Chairman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority to those who have printed their amendments in the Congressional Record. At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment, the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the House with amendments as may have been adopted. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-03-02T15:42:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="15">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-03-03T10:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H899-900" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-03T10:44:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 86.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-03T10:50:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1999-03-03T10:50:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-03-03T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="661"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/1999--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 661 (prohibiting commercial operation of supersonic transport category aircraft under certain conditions).</summary>
</bill>
