<bill session="104" type="h" number="3971" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Walker River Basin Conservation and Stabilization Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assist in the conservation and stabilization of water quantity and quality for fish habitat and recreation in the Walker River Basin consistent with Decree C-125, issued by the United States District Court for the District of Nevada.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411178"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation districts"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/1996--Introduced.
Walker River Basin Conservation and Stabilization Act of 1996 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to participate in efforts by the Walker River Basin Water Users Association, the Walker River Irrigation District, and the Walker River Paiute Tribe (locally affected interests) to conduct studies relating to, and to implement, specified projects to assist in the stabilization of water quantity and quality at Walker Lake for purposes of conserving fish habitat and recreation in the Walker River Basin, including projects to establish a locally managed Walker River Water Bank to facilitate voluntary water transfers within the Walker River Basin in Nevada and California, and projects to encourage the locally affected interests to voluntarily conserve water in the Basin. Directs the Secretary to provide funds and technical assistance to the locally affected interests, subject to specified requirements. Sets forth cost-sharing provisions. Authorizes appropriations. Prohibits the Secretary from taking any action that would undermine, contradict, or diminish water rights confirmed in a specified case, other than action deemed necessary and within the Secretary's authority as trustee for the Walker River Paiute Tribe.</summary>
</bill>
