<bill session="105" type="hc" number="221" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that a renewed effort be made by all sides to end the violent guerrilla war in Colombia, which poses a serious threat to democracy as well as economic and social stability as evidenced by the recent increase in guerrilla and paramilitary violence which victimizes public officials and Colombian and foreign nationals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1998-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Guerrilla warfare"/>
    <term name="Hostages"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Missionaries"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/1998--Introduced.
Recognizes the importance of the threat of escalating guerrilla and paramilitary violence to Colombia's democracy and to the upcoming congressional and presidential elections. Urges: (1) the guerrilla leaders of the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) and the National Liberation Army (ELN) to end the violence, sever their relationship with narcotics traffickers, negotiate a peace accord with the Colombian Government, and take their agenda into the political arena for debate; (2) the FARC and ELN leadership to release the U.S. missionaries being held hostage in Colombia or account for their whereabouts; (3) the Colombian Government to end the guerrilla conflict and take greater action against paramilitary units that commit gross human rights violations; (4) the international community, particularly the Organization of American States, to play a more proactive role in resolving the conflict; and (5) the administration to reevaluate U.S. policies toward Colombia and consider that government's request for U.S. assistance in resolving the conflict.</summary>
</bill>
