<bill session="105" type="h" number="2956" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Biennial Budgeting and Appropriations Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a biennial budget process and a biennial appropriations process and to enhance oversight and the performance of the Federal Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400529"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1998-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1998-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2277"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biennial budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget reconciliation"/>
    <term name="Capital budgets"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
    <term name="Federal budget process"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fiscal year"/>
    <term name="House Appropriations"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Senate Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/1997--Introduced.
Biennial Budgeting and Appropriations Act - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (CBA) to revise the Federal and congressional budget processes by establishing a two-year budgeting and appropriations cycle and timetable. Defines the budget biennium as the two consecutive fiscal years beginning on October 1 of any odd-numbered year. Sets forth a special timetable for any first session that begins in any year immediately following a leap year and during which the term of a President begins (except one who starts a second successive term). Devotes the first session of any Congress to the budget resolution and to appropriations decisions, retaining current deadlines in most cases. Changes certain deadlines to conform to the biennial scheme. Devotes each second session to authorization activity, subject to specified deadlines. (Sec. 3) Revises provisions relating to the reconciliation process. (Sec. 4) Sets forth revised pay-as-you-go provisions for the Senate. (Sec. 5) Conforms provisions governing the President's budget to the biennial framework. (Sec. 6) Requires all Acts making regular appropriations for the support of the Government to be enacted for a biennium and to specify the amount of appropriations provided for each fiscal year in that period. (Sec. 7) Amends CBA to provide that it shall not be in order in the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider: (1) any bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report that authorizes appropriations for a period of less than two fiscal years, unless the program, project, or activity for which the appropriations are authorized will require no further appropriations and will be completed or terminated after the appropriations have been expended; and (2) in any odd-numbered year, any authorization or revenue bill or joint resolution until Congress completes action on the biennial budget resolution, all regular biennial appropriations bills, and all reconciliation bills. Provides that, in the Senate, such point of order shall not apply to: (1) any measure that is privileged for consideration pursuant to a rule or statute; (2) any matter considered in Executive Session; or (3) an appropriations measure or reconciliation bill. (Sec. 8) Changes to a biennial basis specified requirements for certain Government strategic and performance plans, performance reports in budget submissions, and program performance reports. Requires congressional committee reviews of such plans and reports. (Sec. 9) Provides that it shall not be in order in the House or the Senate in any odd-numbered year to consider any regular bill providing new budget authority or a limitation on obligations under the jurisdiction of any Appropriations subcommittee for only the first fiscal year of a biennium unless the program, project, or activity for which such authority or limitation is provided will require no additional authority beyond one year and will be completed or terminated after the amount provided has been expended. (Sec. 10) Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to report to the Budget Committees on the impact and feasibility of changing the definition of a fiscal year and the budget process based on that definition to a two-year fiscal period with a two-year budget process based on the two-year period.</summary>
</bill>
