<bill session="107" type="hr" number="483" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-16T16:53:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-07-16T16:53:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5093) making appropriations for the Department of the Interior and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-07-15T22:06:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 107-577, by Mr. Hastings (WA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-15T22:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Waives all points of order against consideration of the bill and provides that amendments printed in the Rules Committee report (H.Rept. 107-577) shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole. Waives points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI (prohibiting unauthorized appropriations or legislative provisionsin an appropriations bill), except as specified in the resolution. Waives points of order during consideration of the bill against amendments for failure to comply with clause 2(e) of rule XXI (prohibiting non- emergency designated amendments to be offered to an appropriations bill containing an emergency designation). The rule authorizes the Chair to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-07-15T22:08:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="193">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 193.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-07-16T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4710-4719" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-16T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 483.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2002-07-16T16:53:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="302" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 322 - 101 (Roll no. 302).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4710" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-07-16T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="107" type="h" number="5093"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2002--Reported to House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 5093 (FY 2003 Department of the Interior and related agencies appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
