<bill session="108" type="hr" number="179" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-08T17:37:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-04-08T17:37:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the systematic human rights violations in Cuba committed by the Castro regime, calling for the immediate release of all political prisoners, and supporting respect for basic human rights and free elections in Cuba.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400107"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400131" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400167" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2003-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Ros-Lehtinen moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H2887-2895" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 179.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T17:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H2910-2911" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2003-04-08T17:37:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="117" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 414 - 0, 11 Present (Roll no. 117).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H2887-2888" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T17:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Switzerland"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/2003--Passed House without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced on April 7, 2003. The summary of that version is repeated here.)Condemns the brutal crackdown of the Cuban Government on the island's peaceful pro-democracy movement.Calls for the immediate release of all Cuban political prisoners.Supports the right of the Cuban people to exercise fundamental political and civil liberties, including freedom of expression, assembly, association, movement, press, and the right to multiparty elections.Calls on the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations and other International Organizations in Geneva, Switzerland, to work with the member countries of the United Nations Commission on Human Rights to ensure a resolution that includes the strongest possible condemnation of the current crackdown of dissidents and of the gross human rights violations committed by the Cuban Government.Calls on the Latin American and Caribbean group (GRULAC) at the Commission to exclude Cuba from its slate of candidates for the Commission, and urges all member nations to oppose renewing Cuba's membership on the Commission until the Government of Cuba adheres to international human rights standards, such as those delineated in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</summary>
</bill>
