<bill session="104" type="h" number="3921" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Business and Education Sharing Technology Act (BEST)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To recognize businesses which show an exemplary commitment to participating with schools to enhance educators' technology capabilities and to make every student technologically literate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1398-1399"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="White House (Washington, D.C.)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/1996--Introduced.
Business and Education Sharing Technology Act (BEST) - Establishes a program to give local and national recognition to businesses which show an exemplary commitment to participating with schools to enhance educators' technology capabilities and to make every student technologically literate. Directs U.S. Representatives who choose to participate in such program to notify local educational agencies and individual schools in their congressional districts and request nominations of local businesses. Directs U.S. Senators who choose to participate in such program to notify the State educational agency and request nominations of businesses engaged in statewide or regional technology partnerships with schools. Provides for appointment of a board of qualified individuals to select businesses engaged in regional or statewide technology partnerships with schools to receive a Business and Education Sharing Technology (BEST) recognition award. Sets forth criteria for BEST recognition awards. Directs the board to forward information regarding businesses selected for recognition to the White House and the Department of Education. Requires an annual White House ceremony to honor such businesses, as well as Department of Education online dissemination of information regarding such programs and partnerships, provided that all costs of such ceremony and dissemination are covered by private donations.</summary>
</bill>
