<bill session="105" type="h" number="4704" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freedom to Market Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the General Accounting Office to prepare a report assessing the impact and effectiveness of economic sanctions imposed by the United States, to prohibit the imposition of unilateral sanctions on exports of food, other agricultural products, medicines, or medical supplies or equipment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400292"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-05">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-05">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1998--Introduced.
Freedom to Market Act - Directs the Comptroller General to conduct, and submit to specified congressional committees, a report that: (1) examines all unilateral and multilateral economic sanctions affecting U.S. businesses, including an evaluation of their effectiveness in meeting stated policy goals; (2) examines the economic impact of sanctions on U.S. producers and exporters; (3) assesses humanitarian conditions within sanctioned countries, including how sanctions have affected particular states; and (4) assesses potential countries, not now subject to sanctions, that may be sanctioned under existing U.S. law or executive authority. Prohibits the President from restricting or otherwise prohibiting any exports (including restricted commercial or Federal financing) of food, other agricultural products (including fertilizer), medicines, or medical supplies or equipment as part of any policy of existing or future unilateral economic sanctions imposed against a foreign government. Authorizes the President to waive such requirements if it is in the national security interests of the United States. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to report annually to the Congress on: (1) the Secretary's assessment of all markets where U.S. exports of agricultural commodities are limited because of multilateral or unilateral economic sanctions, including its economic impact on producers; (2) the extent to which displaced U.S. commodities are being supplied by foreign competitors; (3) the expected longer-term consequences of interrupting U.S. exports; and (4) any assistance provided by the Foreign Agricultural Service to offset lost markets due to the sanctions. Directs the Secretary to expand, to the maximum extent permitted by law and by the obligations of the United States pursuant to the Agreement on Agriculture under the Uruguay Round Agreements, agricultural export assistance under U.S. market development, food assistance, or export promotion programs to offset projected losses of agricultural commodity markets from unilateral and multilateral sanctions.</summary>
</bill>
