<bill session="108" type="h" number="1641" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Passenger Van Safety Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require increased safety testing of 15-passenger vans, ensure the compliance of 15-passenger vans used as schoolbuses with motor vehicle safety standards applicable to schoolbuses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400002" joined="2003-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="2003-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2003-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="2003-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2003-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E675"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="717"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bus drivers"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="School buses"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2003--Introduced.
Passenger Van Safety Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) develop a dynamic test on rollovers by 15-passenger vans for the purposes of a consumer information program, and carry out a program of conducting such tests; and (2) require the testing of 15-passenger vans at various load condition levels as part of the rollover resistance program of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration's New Car Assessment Program. Directs the Secretary to test and evaluate various technological systems (including electronic stability control systems, rear-view mirror-based rollover warning systems, traction systems, lane departure systems, and antilock brakes) to determine their effectiveness in assisting drivers of 15-passenger vans to control them under conditions that cause vehicle rollover. Requires the Secretary to issue a final rule initiated pursuant to a specified proposed rulemaking on the application of Federal Motor Carrier Safety Regulations to the commercial operation of 15-passenger vans. Amends the Federal transportation code to prohibit any person from purchasing, renting, or leasing any motor vehicle designed or used to transport nine to 15 passengers that the person knows or reasonably should know will be used significantly to transport preprimary, primary, and secondary school students to or from school or an event related to school, unless the motor vehicle complies with the certain motor vehicle standards prescribed for schoolbuses. Establishes a civil penalty for violation of this prohibition, or for manufacture, sale, offer for sale, introduction or delivery for introduction into interstate commerce, or importation, of a schoolbus or related equipment that fails to meet such standards.</summary>
</bill>
