<bill session="107" type="h" number="5426" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fort Donelson National Battlefield Expansion Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand the boundaries of the Fort Donelson National Battlefield to authorize the acquisition and interpretation of lands associated with the campaign that resulted in the capture of the fort in 1862, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400431"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2002-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military parks"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2002--Introduced.
Fort Donelson National Battlefield Expansion Act of 2002 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire for inclusion in the Fort Donelson National Battlefield land, interests, and improvements: (1) within the boundaries of the Battlefield; and (2) outside such boundaries if the land has been identified by the American Battlefield Protection Program as part of the battlefield associated with Fort Donelson or if the Secretary otherwise determines that acquisition will protect critical resources associated with the Battle of Fort Donelson in1862 and the Union campaign that resulted in the capture of the Fort. Limits the total area encompassed by the Battlefield to 2,000 acres.Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into a memorandum of understanding to facilitate cooperatively protecting and interpreting the remaining vestige of Fort Henry and other remaining Civil War resources in the Land Between the Lakes National Recreation Area affiliated with the Fort Donelson campaign.</summary>
</bill>
