<bill session="108" type="hj" number="66" updated="2013-07-14T19:03:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to provide for terms of office for Members of the House of Representatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400389"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2003-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2003-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400177" joined="2003-07-24" withdrawn="2004-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional terms of office"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2003--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Increases the term of office of a member of the House of Representatives from two to fours years, except for terms corresponding to general elections conducted in years corresponding to the decennial census, which shall be for two years. Provides that nothing in this Amendment shall be construed to limit the number of consecutive terms a Representative may serve. Makes this Amendment effective beginning with the first general election for Representatives held after the ratification of this Article; except that if a general election for Representatives is conducted in 2008, Representatives so elected shall serve two-year terms. States that if a Member of the House is a candidate for the Senate, the term of such Representative shall end 30 days from the date on which such Representative files a notice of candidacy, and the Representative shall not be eligible to serve in the House for two years from such date. Requires, as soon as the Representative becomes a candidate for the Senate, the executive authority of the State from which the Representative was chosen to issue writs of election to fill the vacancy to be created by the Representative's candidacy. Deems the person elected to fill such vacancy to have been elected to the term of office of the Representative who the person is replacing.</summary>
</bill>
