<bill session="105" type="hr" number="414" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-30T16:03:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-04-30T16:03:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving a requirement of clause 4(b) of rule XI with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400265"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-502, by Mr. McInnis.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The requirement of clause 4(b) of rule XI for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules the same day is presented to the House is waived with respect to any resolution reported from that committee before May 1, 1998, providing for consideration of the bill H.R. 3579.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-04-29T19:06:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="173">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 173.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30T15:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2671-2672" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30T15:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate the Speaker put the question on agreeing to the resolution and announce that, by voice vote, the resolution was agreed to. Mr. Hall (OH) demanded the Yeas and Nays and further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30T16:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-04-30T16:03:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="120" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 211 - 196 (Roll No. 120).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30T16:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/1998--Introduced.
Waives provisions of rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives that require a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to a resolution reported by such Committee before May 1, 1998, to provide for the consideration or disposition of H.R. 3579 (emergency supplemental appropriations), including any amendment, conference report, or any amendment from conference in disagreement thereon.</summary>
</bill>
