<bill session="106" type="h" number="3428" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Milk Marketing Orders bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the modification and implementation of the final rule for the consideration and reform of Federal milk marketing orders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400034"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>See also H.R. 3194.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock and Horticulture.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Livestock and Horticulture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="1402"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="3194"/>
    <bill relation="includes" session="106" type="h" number="3194"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Interstate commissions"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Marketing orders"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/1999--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to implement, with specified modifications, the Class I fluid milk price structure known as Option 1A "Location-Specific Differentials Analysis" as part of the final rule to consolidate Federal milk marketing orders.States that if the Secretary announces minimum milk prices under a marketing order prior to implementation of the rule under this Act, such prices shall be the applicable minimum prices for the months so covered.States that the Option 1A requirement shall not be subject to specified requirements regarding: (1) notice and hearing; (2) referendum; (3) rulemaking notice and public participation; (4) paperwork reduction; and (5) judicial decision or order.(Sec. 2) Expresses the congressional finding that certain Class III and IV milk pricing formulas require further emergency rulemaking because they do not adequately reflect public comment and are sufficiently different from the proposed rule. States that the Secretary shall: (1) conduct formal rulemaking, and implement such final formulas on January 1, 2001 (with an extension if necessitated by judicial restraining order); and (2) collect no marketing order assessments (without reducing service levels) during any period of noncompliance with such time frame.(Sec. 3) Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act, reenacted with amendments by the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, to direct the Secretary to implement a dairy forward pricing pilot program through December 31, 2004. Applies such program to federally regulated milk that: (1) is not Class I milk or otherwise intended for fluid use; and (2) is in or directly affects interstate or foreign milk commerce.Directs the Secretary to study the impact of forward contracting on milk prices paid to U.S. producers.(Sec. 4) Amends the Agricultural Market Transition Act to extend congressional consent for the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact through September 30, 2001.</summary>
</bill>
