<bill session="104" type="h" number="1311" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Risk Assessment in Women's Health Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a review of all Federal programs that assess or mitigate the risks to women's health from environmental exposures, and for a study of the research needs of the Federal Government relating to such risks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Basic Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Basic Research" name="House Science"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Pesticide residues"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/1995--Introduced.
Federal Risk Assessment in Women's Health Act of 1995 - Directs the Office of Science and Technology Policy to conduct a review of all Federal programs that assess or mitigate the risks to women's health from environmental exposures, including programs setting standards for exposure to various pollutants, toxic substances, pesticide use, and pesticide residues. Requires the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences to enter into a contract with the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences to study the status of the science base and needs of the Federal Government for research relating to the risks to women's health from environmental exposures, for the purpose of assessing and mitigating such risks. Requires results of such review and study to be reported to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
