<bill session="105" type="h" number="4034" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Protective Service Reform Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Act of June 1, 1948, to provide for reform of the Federal Protective Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400611"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1998-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1998-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1998-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1998-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="1998-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="1998-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1998-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1081"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Buildings and Economic Development.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW08" subcommittee="Public Buildings and Economic Development" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Burglary protection"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1998--Introduced.
Federal Protective Service Reform Act of 1998 - Amends the Act of June 1, 1948, to redesignate special policemen of the General Services Administration (GSA) as police officers. (Sec. 3) Extends the powers of sheriffs and constables granted to such police officers upon Federal property under the GSA Administrator's control to any area within 500 feet from such property and makes such powers concurrent with State and local law enforcement authorities in the area in which the property is located. Empowers such police officers to: (1) carry firearms; (2) petition Federal courts for and execute arrest and search warrants; (3) make arrests without a warrant; and (4) conduct investigations, on and off the property of offenses on such property; and (5) coordinate with other law enforcement agencies that have intelligence gathering authority for the protection of such persons and property. Authorizes police officers to exercise any power granted in such an area if: (1) the officer reasonably believes that the action is necessary to prevent or stop a felony in progress; (2) the felony is being committed in the presence of the officer; and (3) there is a known, immediate threat. (Sec. 4) Increases from $50 to $5,000 the maximum penalty for violations of any rules or regulations with respect to Federal property. (Sec. 5) Empowers nonuniformed special law enforcement officers with the same authority outside Federal property (within 500 feet of a Federal area) as police officers have. (Sec. 6) Directs the Administrator to establish the Federal Protective Service (FPS) as a separate operating service of GSA. Provides for the FPS to be headed by a Commissioner who: (1) shall be appointed by and report directly to the Administrator; and (2) has at least five years of professional law enforcement experience in a command or supervisory position. Requires the Commissioner to: (1) assist the Administrator; (2) serve as the principal U.S. law enforcement officer and security official with respect to the protection of Federal officers and employees in such property; (3) render assistance to other Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies upon request; and (4) carry out his or her duties in coordination with the Commissioner of the Public Buildings Service. (Sec. 7) Requires FPS police officers' and criminal investigators' pay and benefits to be determined in accordance with a pay and benefits package established by the Administrator that is equivalent to the pay scale and benefits package applicable to U.S. Secret Service Uniformed Division members. (Sec. 8) Requires there to be at least 730 full-time police officers in the FPS one year after the enactment of this Act. Prohibits any reduction in such number of officers unless specifically authorized by law. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report on the feasibility of merging all building security forces of the executive branch within and under the FPS's supervision. (Sec. 9) Directs the Commissioner to prescribe standards for the contracting of security personnel for Federal property. Provides for such standards to ensure that contract personnel receive adequate training and are subject to the same background check requirements as FPS police officers.</summary>
</bill>
