<bill session="106" type="h" number="2912" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to eliminate the termination of additional Federal payments to States under the Medicaid Program for administrative costs related to certain outreach and eligibility determinations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400553"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/1999--Introduced.
Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) with respect to the transitional increased Federal matching rate for increased administrative costs related to Medicaid-eligibility determinations of individuals receiving aid or assistance under SSA title IV part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF). Repeals the expiration of additional Federal funds for such Medicaid-eligibility determinations (thus making such provisions permanent and such additional Federal funds available on a fiscal year basis). Includes as administrative expenditures those attributable to the administrative costs of eligibility determinations under SSA title XXI (Children's Health Insurance) (CHIP) with regard to children and pregnant women and outreach to such populations likely to be eligible for such benefits.</summary>
</bill>
