<bill session="104" type="h" number="2056" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Older Americans Act Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to provide for Federal-State performance partnerships, to consolidate all nutrition programs under the Act in the Department of Health and Human Services, to extend authorizations of appropriations for programs under the Act through fiscal year 1998, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-07-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1458-1459"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities. for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Age and employment"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Brain diseases"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congregate housing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against the elderly"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Elder abuse"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Gerontology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to the aged"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mentally ill"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority aged"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and the aged"/>
    <term name="Old age assistance"/>
    <term name="Older women"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Respite care"/>
    <term name="Rural elderly"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senior centers"/>
    <term name="Social workers"/>
    <term name="Socially handicapped"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the aged"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in social service"/>
    <term name="White House conferences"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Performance Partnerships Title II: Other Amendments to the Older Americans Act of 1965 Title III: White House Conference on Aging Older Americans Act Amendments of 1995 - Title I: Performance Partnerships - Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 (OAA) to direct the Assistant Secretary of Health and Human Services for Aging (Assistant Secretary) to negotiate an agreement proposed by each State and included as part of its State plan under OAA's basic State grants program in order to receive its share of program funding that contains certain objectives selected by it for accomplishing the goals of such program and those of the vulnerable elder rights protection program as well. (Sec. 101) Authorizes the Assistant Secretary to make incentive awards to States which have performed effectively under a performance partnership agreement. (Sec. 103) Requires each State to establish an Advisory Council to: (1) review and comment on the State's proposed agreement; and (2) evaluate and report on the State's performance under the final agreement negotiated with the Assistant Secretary. (Sec. 104) Revises area and State plan provisions, among other changes, incorporating requirements for performance partnerships. Title II: Other Amendments to the Older Americans Act of 1965 - Reauthorizes, revises, and extends OAA, making various specified changes, technical and otherwise, among other areas with regard to: (1) the National Eldercare Locator Service; (2) the basic State grant program (including providing for the coordination of services for individuals with disabilities under area plans, the transfer of funds between different grant programs, and the availability of disaster relief funds for tribal organizations); (3) the basic authority for research, development, and demonstrations (adding a new overall statement of purpose for such authority, as well as new components for certain centers to improve the quality of services for older individuals and for information dissemination and related activities); (4) the community service employment program (transferring jurisdiction of such program from the Department of Labor to the Department of Health and Human Services); and (5) the vulnerable elder rights protection program.Authorizes appropriations. Title III: White House Conference on Aging - Directs the President to convene, by a certain deadline, the White House Conference on Aging for developing recommendations for additional research and action on aging. (Sec. 303) Establishes a policy committee and other related committees to assist with the matters above. (Sec. 306) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
