<bill session="104" type="h" number="824" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">States' Disaster Responsibility Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act and other laws to return primary responsibility for disaster relief to the States, to establish a private corporation to insure States against risks and costs of disasters otherwise borne by the States, and to provide for reimbursable Federal assistance to States for activities in response to disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400300"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="1995-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1995-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="1995-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Banking and Financial Services, Small Business, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Resource Conservation, Research and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG27" subcommittee="Resource Conservation, Research and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Prefabricated buildings"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication systems"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: National Disaster Insurance Program Title II: Termination of Federal Disaster Loan Programs Title III: Federal Program for Reimbursable Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance States' Disaster Responsibility Act - Title I: National Disaster Insurance Program - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to establish a national disaster insurance program. Directs the National Disaster Insurance Corporation (established by this Act) to establish and carry out such insurance program to provide coverage to States against certain losses and costs arising from disasters. Provides that such program shall be funded solely by State premiums and payments (after an initial Federal contribution) and operate on an actuarially sound basis. (Sec. 101) Sets forth provisions for program terms and conditions, coverage, annual premium charges, and claims. Establishes the Corporation, which shall not be an agency or establishment of the Federal Government. Requires the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to call an organizational meeting for the Corporation. Authorizes appropriations to the Corporation according to a certain formula, as the initial Federal contribution, and prohibits any additional Federal financial assistance to the Corporation. Establishes the Disaster Insurance Advisory Commission. Directs the Comptroller General to conduct and report on audits of the Corporation and the Commission. Title II: Termination of Federal Disaster Loan Programs - Terminates the Small Business Administration (SBA) disaster loan program. Prohibits the Administrator of SBA from making any loan, or entering into an agreement to participate in any loan, under such program. Repeals specified provisions of the Small Business Act to conform to such program termination. (Sec. 202) Repeals provisions for the Consolidated Farm Service Agency emergency loan program under the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act. (Sec. 203) Repeals the emergency relief program for repair of highways under specified Federal law. (Sec. 204) Amends the National Housing Act to terminate the following Department of Housing and Urban Development mortgage insurance programs for disaster victims: (1) single family home mortgage insurance; and (2) insurance for rehabilitation loans. Title III: Federal Program for Reimbursable Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to require reimbursement of the Federal Government. (Sec. 303) Revises provisions relating to: (1) waiver of administrative conditions; (2) emergency support teams; (3) performance of services; (4) procedure for declaration of major disaster; (5) general Federal disaster assistance; (6) essential disaster assistance; (7) repair, restoration, and replacement of damaged facilities; (8) debris removal; (9) temporary housing assistance; (10) unemployment assistance; (11) crisis counseling assistance and training; (12) emergency communications; (13) emergency public transportation; (14) fire suppression assistance (terminating grants for such assistance); (15) timber sale contracts; and (16) the procedure for declaration of emergency, and Federal emergency assistance. (Sec. 307) Replaces insurance provisions with provisions for reimbursement agreements and conditions. Replaces provisions regarding duplication of benefits with provisions for treatment of assistance. Replaces provisions for advance of non-Federal share with provisions for advance of State expenditures. (Sec. 309) Repeals provisions for recovery of assistance from liable parties, hazard mitigation, minimum standards for public and private structures, individual and family grant programs, community disaster loans, simplified procedure, appeals of assistance decisions, and amount of assistance.</summary>
</bill>
