<bill session="106" type="h" number="1274" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lifesaving Vaccine Technology Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit for medical research related to developing vaccines against widespread diseases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400314"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="1999-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400532" joined="1999-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1999-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1999-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1999-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1999-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="1999-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1999-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1999-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1999-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="1999-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1999-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="1999-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1999-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Malaria"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Research and development tax credit"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/1999--Introduced.
Lifesaving Vaccine Technology Act of 1999 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish an income tax credit for 30 percent of the qualified expenses (excluding amounts funded by any grant, contract, or otherwise by another person or any governmental entity) for medical research related to developing vaccines against widespread diseases like malaria, tuberculosis, HIV, or any infectious disease (of a single etiology) which, according to the World Health Organization, causes over one million human deaths annually. States that any qualified vaccine research expenses for a taxable year to which an election under this Act applies shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining the credit allowable for increasing research expenditures. Denies such a credit with respect to any vaccine research (other than human clinical testing) conducted outside the United States. States that the vaccine research credit shall include an amount equal to 20 percent of the amount paid by the taxpayer to acquire qualified research stock in a corporation if the corporation waives its own right to the credit and meets other specified criteria. Declares that it is the sense of Congress that if the vaccine research credit is allowed to any corporation or shareholder of a corporation, the corporation should certify to the Secretary of the Treasury that, within one year after that vaccine is first licensed, the corporation will establish a good faith plan utilizing technology transfer, differential pricing, in-country production, or other mechanisms to maximize international access to high quality and affordable vaccines. Directs the Institute of Medicine to study and report to Congress on the effectiveness of the vaccine research credit in stimulating vaccine research. Expresses the sense of Congress that the President and Federal agencies (including the Departments of State, Health and Human Services, and the Treasury) should work together in vigorous support of the creation and funding of a multi-lateral, international effort, such as a vaccine purchase fund, to accelerate the introduction of vaccines to which the vaccine research credit applies and of other priority vaccines into the poorest countries in the world. Expresses the sense of Congress that flexible or differential pricing for vaccines, providing lowered prices for the poorest countries, is one of several valid strategies to accelerate the introduction of vaccines in developing countries.</summary>
</bill>
