<bill session="105" type="h" number="950" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Job Creation and Infrastructure Restoration Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Jobs 2000 Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a national public works program to provide incentives for the creation of jobs and address the restoration of infrastructure in communities across the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1997-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1997-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1997-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="1998-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1998-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1997-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="1997-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1998-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1997-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1997-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1997-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1997-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1997-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="1998-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="1997-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1997-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400600" joined="1997-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1997-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1998-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="1997-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1997-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1997-03-05" withdrawn="1997-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Buildings and Economic Development.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW08" subcommittee="Public Buildings and Economic Development" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Architecture and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asbestos abatement"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Employment subsidies"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Industrial research"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor disputes"/>
    <term name="Labor productivity"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Labor-management committees"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Lead abatement"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Plant shutdowns"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Product development"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public service employment"/>
    <term name="Public works"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seasonal labor"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Small farms"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Underemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployed"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' preference"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Welfare recipients"/>
    <term name="Welfare work participation"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of Commerce Grants Title II: Public Works and Job Restoration Subtitle A: Jobs 2000 Subtitle B: Employment in Support of Community Renewal Subtitle C: Employment Activities; Repair and Renovation of Educational Facilities Title III: General Provisions Job Creation and Infrastructure Restoration Act of 1997 - Title I: Department of Commerce Grants - Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to make grants to any State or local government for construction, renovation, repair, restoration, or other improvement of local public works projects, including those for which Federal financial assistance is authorized under other titles or Acts. Limits the Federal share to not more than 90 percent of project cost. Prohibits any new grants after the expiration of any three-month period during which the national unemployment rate remains below five percent for each such month, or after September 30, 2001, whichever occurs first. (Sec. 103) Provides for allocation of funds and for preferences. Gives priority to State or local governments with unemployment rates higher than the national average. Requires State and local prioritization of applications. Allows localization of unemployment determinations. (Sec. 105) Sets forth general limitations, including Buy American and minority participation requirements and applicability of laws regarding individuals with disabilities. Requires public authorities, as part of the process of competitive bidding for contract awards under this Act, to: (1) seek to obtain Project Agreements with Building Trades Councils, including the establishment of Project Committees; and (2) assign to each project an enforcement official to enforce standards under this Act and Project Committee orders. (Sec. 106) Authorizes appropriations and deems them to be emergency spending. Title II: Public Works and Job Restoration - Subtitle A: Jobs 2000 - Jobs 2000 Act of 1997 - Provides for jobs for the unemployed and underemployed, especially youth, through payments for labor and related costs for: (1) construction, repair, or rehabilitation of community and educational facilities; (2) reclamation and conservation of public lands; and (3) creation, repair, rehabilitation, and restoration of public safety, public transportation, health, social services, and recreation facilities and other activities necessary to the public welfare. (Sec. 203) Sets forth participant eligibility and certification requirements, duration and extent of subsidized employment, participation priorities, special considerations for welfare recipients and veterans, and equal employment opportunities for traditionally underrepresented groups. (Sec. 204) Requires that at least 75 percent of funds made available to any recipient under subtitles B and C be used for wages and related employment benefits for work which the recipient certifies has been performed in authorized activities. Sets forth other limitations on use of funds, except training costs in specified circumstances. Subtitle B: Employment in Support of Community Renewal - Part A: Community Improvement Projects - Requires participants to be employed in community improvement projects in various specified activities under the categories of: (1) repair, rehabilitation, or improvement of public facilities; (2) conservation, restoration, rehabilitation, or improvement of public lands; and (3) public safety, health, social service, and other activities necessary to public welfare. (Sec. 210) Provides for joint programs, public lands projects limitations, eligibility and qualification of administrative entities, allotment of funds, requirements for receipt of funds, reports, and project design priorities and coordination. Requires, in the case of projects or activities that involve construction, reconstruction, repair, or renovation of physical structures, that: (1) each project for which a grant is made under this title be performed by contract on the basis of competitive bidding, unless the Secretary finds that an alternative method is in the public interest under circumstances related to the project; and (2) public authorities awarding such contracts seek Project Agreements with Building Trades Councils, including establishing Project Committees, and assign project enforcement officers. Part B: Community Improvement and Renewal Activities for Youth Trainees - Authorizes use of funds for wages and benefits for eligible youth for part-time employment up to 32 hours per week in authorized youth trainee activities at a work site of a public or private nonprofit or for-profit employer, in a manner which requires and is consistent with enrollment in high school, an equivalency program, or a program of basic skills, skills training, or employability development for at least eight hours per week. (Sec. 221) Provides for joint programs, youth eligibility requirements, exemption from unemployment duration requirements, priority for the economically disadvantaged, and equitable service for school dropouts. Part C: State Job Programs - Reserves five percent of State allotments for: (1) authorized State-administered programs and activities; (2) special assistance for areas with sudden or severe economic dislocations; (3) State-directed emergency aid to cope with natural disasters; and (4) special assistance to seasonal farmworkers and small farmers in areas with severe economic disruption. (Sec. 231) Sets forth requirements for program and activity selection and design. Subtitle C: Employment Activities; Repair and Renovation of Educational Facilities - Part A: Elementary and Secondary School Facility Improvement Jobs - Requires making funds under this part available to any eligible local education agency in an eligible jurisdiction to provide employment to eligible participants in repair, renovation, restoration, or rehabilitation of public school facilities. (Sec. 241) Provides for use of quick-start projects, permitted uses of funds, tribal school projects, allotment of funds, and receipt requirements. Part B: Higher Education Facility Improvement Projects - Requires funds under this part to be made available to higher education institutions in eligible jurisdictions to provide employment to eligible participants in work on repair, restoration, renovation, or rehabilitation of academic facilities. (Sec. 251) Provides for use of quick-start projects, permitted uses of funds, selection of projects, allotment of funds, and receipt requirements. Part C: Special Definitions for Subtitle C - Sets forth special definitions for subtitle C. Part D: Authorization of Appropriations - Authorizes appropriations. Title III: General Provisions - Sets forth general requirements, including wage rates, labor standards, fiscal controls and sanctions, and judicial review procedures.</summary>
</bill>
