<bill session="107" type="h" number="5203" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-04T18:53:00-04:00">PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-09-04T18:53:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Education Savings and School Excellence Permanence Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that the education savings incentives of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 shall be permanent, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400190"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hulshof moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6022-6028" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6022" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5203.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T17:14:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T18:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6028-6029" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="2002-09-04T18:53:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="371" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 213 - 188 (Roll no. 371).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Age (Law)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education of disabled students"/>
    <term name="Education savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home schooling"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Service academies"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/4/2002--Failed of passage in House.
Education Savings and School Excellence Performance Act of 2002 - Makes the sunset provisions of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 inapplicable to provisions of such Act relating to education savings incentives, thus making those provisions permanent.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for tax-free expenditures from education savings accounts for elementary and secondary education expenses at home schools (currently the Code provides for tax-free treatment of expenses at public, private, and religious schools only).Permits an exemption to the tax increase assessed to an individual for receiving a payment or distribution from an education individual retirement account which is includible in gross income if the payment or distribution is made on account of attendance of the account holder at a U.S. Military Academy. States that the exemption shall only apply to the extent that the amount of the payment or distribution does not exceed the costs of advanced education attributable to such attendance.</summary>
</bill>
