<bill session="104" type="h" number="12" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Farm Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from the gross estate the value of land subject to a qualified conservation easement if certain conditions are satisfied, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411247"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Development rights transfer"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Tax assessment"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Family Farm Protection Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from the gross estate, for estate tax purposes, the value of certain land subject to a qualified conservation easement (reduced by the amount of any indebtedness secured by such land). Includes in the gross estate the value of each development right retained by the donor in the conveyance of the easement. Makes such tax due on a date certain after the disposition of such property. Provides that such land subject to the exclusion will have a carryover basis for purposes of determining gain or loss. Excludes from the gift tax transfers by gift of land subject to a qualified conservation easement. Excludes from gross income gain from the sale or exchange of eligible farmland that is subject to a qualified covenant which does not permit any use of such farmland for purposes other than as farmland.</summary>
</bill>
