<bill session="104" type="h" number="979" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of the Army to submit to Congress a report regarding the management of the Chemical Stockpile Emergency Preparedness Program and to require that additional emergency warning sirens be provided for communities near chemical stockpile sites.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401854"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1995-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1995-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Procurement.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS20" subcommittee="Military Procurement" name="House National Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/1995--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Army to report to specified congressional committees on expenditures for the Chemical Stockpile Emergency Preparedness Program since 1986, requiring: (1) an accounting for the various expenses under the Program; and (2) a justification for all Program administrative expenses. Directs the Secretary to approve immediate placement of a minimum of three additional outdoor sirens (to warn local citizens of possible emergencies arising out of the destruction of chemical munitions at a stockpile site) in every county in the United States that is situated within a designated immediate response and protective action zone. Requires funds for the sirens to be provided from Program funding.</summary>
</bill>
