<bill session="104" type="h" number="519" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freedom and Self-Determination for the Former Soviet Union Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit foreign assistance to Russia unless certain requirements relating to Russian intelligence activities, relations between Russia and certain countries, Russian arms control policy, and the reform of the Russian economy are met.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1995-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1995-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404367" joined="1995-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="405033" joined="1995-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="405560" joined="1996-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="1995-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1995-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1995-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="1995-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1995-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1995-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411997" joined="1995-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H374-375"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advanced weapons"/>
    <term name="Aggression"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="CIS countries"/>
    <term name="Capital movements"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conventional weapons"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Espionage"/>
    <term name="Estonia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="International arbitration"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Latvia"/>
    <term name="Lithuania"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Moldova"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Serbia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Yugoslavia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/13/1995--Introduced.
Freedom and Self-Determination for the Former Soviet Union Act - Prohibits foreign assistance from being obligated or expended for Russia for any fiscal year unless the President certifies to the Congress for such fiscal year that: (1) the President has received satisfactory assurances from the Government of Russia, which have been confirmed by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, that Russia's intelligence activities in the United States are confined to routine, non-adversarial information gathering; (2) Russia is making progress toward the unconditional implementation of the Russian-Moldovan troop withdrawal agreement and that the Russian Government is not providing military assistance to any military forces in the Transdniestra region of Moldova; (3) Russian troops in the Kaliningrad region of Russia are respecting the sovereign territory of Lithuania and neighboring countries and are not offensively postured against any other countries; (4) the activities of Russia in the independent states of the former Soviet Union do not represent an attempt by Russia to diminish the sovereignty and independence of such states; (5) Russia is not providing military assistance to any Bosnian Serb military units or to the Government of the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia; (6) the Russian Government has ceased the unilateral demarcation of the border between Russia and Estonia, is engaged in dialogue with Estonia to resolve the border dispute, and has demonstrated a willingness to submit this issue to international arbitration; (7) Russia is not providing any intelligence information to Cuba or assistance to Cuba with respect to the signal intelligence facility at Lourdes; (8) Russia is not providing goods or technology which could contribute to the acquisition of chemical, biological, nuclear, or advanced conventional weapons to Iran, Iraq, Syria, or other countries whose governments have provided support for international terrorism; (9) Russia is in compliance with a specified convention regarding biological weapons and the Wyoming Memorandum of Understanding on chemical weapons; and (10) Russia is committed to reforming the Russian economy along free-market lines. Prohibits, with respect to FY 1995 and 1996, obligating or expending foreign assistance for Russia unless the President certifies to the Congress that the Russian Government has: (1) ceased its military offensive in Chechnya and is committed to resolving the status of Chechnya through negotiations; and (2) provided a full accounting of the espionage activities of Aldrich Ames and has reimbursed the United States for amounts paid to Rosario Ames since her arrest. Requires the President and the Comptroller General to report to the Congress for each fiscal year: (1) the amount of foreign assistance provided to Russia for the preceding fiscal year; (2) a detailed accounting of the amount of foreign assistance appropriated which has not been expended and its status; and (3) an estimate of the total amount of capital exported from Russia during the previous fiscal year and an analysis of reasons for such export. Directs the President to instruct the U.S. executive directors of the international financial institutions to oppose assistance to Russia unless Russia is in compliance with this Act's requirements.</summary>
</bill>
