<bill session="104" type="h" number="2739" updated="2012-11-01T22:44:50-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-08-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-08-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a representational allowance for Members of the House of Representatives, to make technical and conforming changes to sundry provisions of law in consequence of administrative reforms in the House of Representatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T16:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on House Oversight. H. Rept. 104-482.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T16:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 232.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-19T15:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Ehlers moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-19T15:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (CR H2350-2361)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2350-2361" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-19T15:49:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-03-19T16:02:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-19T16:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-19">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Stevens with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-19">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 441.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1996-06-28">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent. (CR S7339)</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7339" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T16:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-08-02T16:40:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to without objection. (CR H9898)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9898" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T16:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-09">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-20">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-08-20">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-186.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Bail"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional allowances"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional joint committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional leadership"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional office operations"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
    <term name="Congressional witnesses"/>
    <term name="Constituent relations"/>
    <term name="Contested elections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Government internships"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative reference services"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Position classification"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>06/28/1996--Passed Senate amended.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;(There are 4 &lt;a href="/cgi-bin/bdquery/z?d104:HR02739:@@@D&amp;summ1&amp;"&gt;other summaries&lt;/a&gt;).
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Provisions Relating to Allowances and Accounts in the House of Representatives and Other Administrative Matters Title II: Technical and Conforming Amendments and Repeals Relating to Administrative Reforms in the House of Representatives House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act - Title I: Provisions Relating to Allowances and Accounts in the House of Representatives and Other Administrative Matters - Establishes for the House of Representatives a single allowance, the Members' Representational Allowance (MRA), to be used to support the conduct of official and representational duties of House Members with respect to the district from which they are elected. Merges into the MRA the Clerk Hire Allowance, the Official Expenses Allowance, and the Official Mail Allowance. Makes such changes effective as of September 1, 1995. (Sec. 102) Authorizes the Committee on House Oversight to fix and adjust the MRA (currently, all allowances of the House) for Members and various House leadership. (Sec. 103) Allows the adjustment of MRAs for reasons other than those currently specified (price or technological changes or increases in the General Schedule) only by House resolution. (Sec. 104) Allows each House Member to employ under the MRA no more than 18 permanent clerks and four additional clerk hire employees in specified categories. Excludes interns and temporary employees from the operation of certain Federal employment provisions and requirements. (Sec. 105) Prohibits any payments from being made from applicable House accounts unless sanctioned by the Oversight Committee. (Sec. 106) Directs the Chief Administrative Officer of the House to submit semiannually to the House a detailed, itemized report of the disbursements for House operations. Outlines information required in such reports, with an exception in the case of vouchers of payments to individuals for attendance as witnesses before a congressional committee in executive session. (Sec. 107) Directs the Clerk of the House, at the request of a Member, to furnish to such Member for official use only one set of a privately published annotated version of the United States Code, including appropriate supplements and pocket parts. (Sec. 108) Authorizes the Chief of the Capitol Police to designate a member of such Police to be responsible for citation release with respect to bonds for persons arrested on Capitol grounds. Provides appropriate authority for D.C.'s Superior and U.S. District courts with respect to bond or collateral proceedings after such arrests. Title II: Technical and Conforming Amendments and Repeals Relating to Administrative Reforms in the House of Representatives - Makes various technical and conforming amendments and appropriate repeals to specified Federal provisions as necessitated by administrative reforms adopted in the House, including provisions concerning: (1) the election of Representatives; (2) congressional organization; (3) Member compensation and allowances; (4) House officers and employees; (5) membership on the Joint Committee of Congress on the Library under the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946; (6) congressional and committee procedure and investigations; (7) the classification of employees; (8) payroll administration; (9) contested elections; (10) the Joint Committee on Congressional Operations; (11) the Congressional Budget Office; (12) Federal Government organization and employees; (13) commerce and trade, foreign relations and intercourse, money and finance, and the postal service; (14) public buildings and related property and public works; (15) public health and welfare; (16) public printing and documents; (17) territories and insular possessions; and (18) miscellaneous uncodified provisions relating to the House. Replaces in many cases functions and duties of: (1) the Committee on House Administration with the Committee on House Oversight; and (2) the Doorkeeper or Sergeant-at-Arms with the Chief Administrative Officer.</summary>
</bill>
