<bill session="106" type="h" number="1726" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Youth Violence Prevention Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To allow States to develop or expand instant gun checking capabilities, to allow a tax credit for the purchase of safe storage devices for firearms, to promote the fitting of handguns with child safety locks, and to prevent children from injuring themselves and others with firearms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1999-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="1999-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="1999-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="1999-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E895"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Firearms injuries"/>
    <term name="Firearms owners"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="School violence"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Youth violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Expansion of Instant Gun Check Capabilities Title II: Nonrefundable Credit for Purchase of Safe Storage Devices for Firearms Title III: Handgun Child Safety Locks Title IV: Child Firearm Access Prevention Youth Violence Prevention Act of 1999 - Title I: Expansion of Instant Gun Check Capabilities - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the use of drug control and system improvement (Byrne) grants to develop or expand a State instant criminal background check system that includes allowing a person who sells a firearm and who is not a licensed dealer only limited access of the system regarding the eligibility status of a proposed firearm purchaser (after receiving the purchaser's express authorization). (Sec. 102) Amends such Act to: (1) require each State which receives grants to allocate not less than six (currently, five) percent of funds received to the improvement of criminal justice records; and (2) authorize the use of such funds to develop or expand a State instant criminal background check system that includes allowing only such limited access. Title II: Nonrefundable Credit for Purchase of Safe Storage Devices for Firearms - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a non-refundable personal credit against Federal income tax for qualified firearm safe storage device expenses for a taxable year. Limits the aggregate amount of expenses paid by an individual which may be treated as qualified firearm safe storage device expenses for any taxable year to the excess (if any) of $250 over the aggregate amounts treated as qualified firearm safe storage device expenses with respect to such individual for all prior taxable years. Title III: Handgun Child Safety Locks - Prohibits the manufacture of a handgun in the United States unless a child safety lock (i.e., a lock which, while activated or attached, prevents the firearm from being discharged) is attached to, or is an integral part of, the firearm. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to impose a civil fine of $5,000 on any person who violates such prohibition. Sets forth provisions regarding judicial review and inapplicability of this prohibition to governmental entities within the United States. Title IV: Child Firearm Access Prevention - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to subject any person who keeps a loaded firearm, or an unloaded firearm and ammunition, within any premise under such person's control and who knows, or reasonably should know, that a juvenile is capable of gaining access to the firearm without the permission of the parent or legal guardian, to one year's imprisonment and a $10,000 fine if a juvenile obtains access and causes death or bodily injury or illegally exhibits the firearm in a public place or school zone. Directs the Secretary to ensure that a copy of such prohibition appears on the form required to be obtained by a licensed dealer from a prospective transferee of a firearm.</summary>
</bill>
