<bill session="106" type="h" number="3024" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Netizens Protection Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to restrict the transmission of unsolicited electronic mail messages.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2037"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Direct mail advertising"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet service providers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Mailing lists"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1999--Introduced.
Netizens Protection Act of 1999 - Prohibits any person from initiating the transmission of an unsolicited electronic mail (e-mail) message in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce if such message: (1) does not contain the name, physical address, and e-mail address of the sender; (2) does not provide an electronic method for contacting the sender to request that no further messages be sent; or (3) is part of a bulk transmission of such messages and includes information that is false or misleading with respect to the body of the message. Provides a private right of action for violations of such prohibition.Requires each interactive computer service provider to make available to each of its customers its policy regarding unsolicited e-mail, including options for the customer to elect to receive or not receive such e-mail. Prohibits customers from using the equipment or facilities of the provider to initiate the bulk transmission of an unsolicited e-mail message if the provider's policy prohibits such bulk transmissions. Provides a right of action for providers adversely affected by customer violations of such prohibition.States that a provider who in good faith takes action to restrict or prevent the receipt of unsolicited e-mail by its customers shall not be liable for any harm resulting from the failure to prevent such receipt.</summary>
</bill>
