<bill session="107" type="h" number="5623" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for prioritization of transportation of nuclear waste from utilities to a permanent repository on the basis of renewable energy use.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400529"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Agricultural wastes"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biodegradation"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Geothermal power plants"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Ocean energy resources"/>
    <term name="Paper and paper products"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Renewable natural resources"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Solar power plants"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/2002--Introduced.
Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to direct the Secretary of Energy to establish a priority listing among utilities for the transportation of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel from them to a specified permanent repository.Mandates that the highest priority be assigned to utilities that derive the highest percentage of energy produced or sold from renewable energy resources, including solar, wind, ocean, or geothermal energy, biomass, landfill gas, a generation offset (reduced electricity usage metered at a site where a customer consumes energy from a renewable energy technology), or incremental hydropower.Instructs the Secretary to: (1) establish the listing not later than one year before the projected date of the first transportation of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel to the permanent repository; and (2) coordinate the transportation of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel from sources other than utilities for which priorities are established under this Act with transportation from such utilities, with the goal of minimizing the number of shipments by combining them whenever possible.</summary>
</bill>
