<bill session="106" type="h" number="3086" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Benefit Equity and Emergency Access to Prescription Drugs Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make changes in payment methodologies under the Medicare Program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act, and to provide for short-term coverage of outpatient prescription drugs to Medicare beneficiaries who lose drug coverage under Medicare+Choice plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400509"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="1999-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1999-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-14">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-14">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/1999--Introduced.
Medicare Benefit Equity and Emergency Access to Prescription Drugs Act of 1999 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish clinical profiles of the practice and payment patterns of health care providers furnishing items and services under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act in order to determine how their practice and payment patterns compare to each other on a local, State, and national basis; (2) establish a method for disseminating summary information to the public on such clinical profiles; and (3) reduce annually overpayments to providers by five percent of the overpayment amount.Authorizes the Secretary, for items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2003, to adjust the amount of the payments made under Medicare to such health care providers in order to encourage their provision of services in a medically appropriate manner and to discourage significant deviations in underservice or overservice from generally accepted norms of medical practice.Amends Medicare part C (Medicare+Choice) to provide for adjustment in Medicare+Choice payment rates to overpaid counties.Provides that for a contract year consisting of a calendar year beginning on or after January 1, 2000, for which the Secretary has determined there is an overpaid payment area, the Secretary shall adjust the annual per capita rate of payment for specified Medicare+Choice payment areas to increase the blended capitation rate applicable to such areas under Medicare+Choice blended capitation rates by the aggregate amount of reductions in payments attributable to this Act.Directs the Secretary to: (1) provide for coverage of outpatient prescription drugs to eligible Medicare beneficiaries and to provide for such coverage by entering into agreements with eligible organizations to furnish such coverage; (2) provide coverage of outpatient prescription drugs to such a beneficiary for a specified period beginning when such beneficiary loses coverage of outpatient prescription drugs under the Medicare+Choice plan in which they are enrolled; and (3) impose specified cost-sharing requirements under coverage of outpatient prescription drugs.Establishes in the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund under Medicare the Emergency Reserve Outpatient Prescription Drug Account, consisting of specified amounts deposited in the Trust Fund, including amounts attributable to reductions in provider overpayments, to pay for outpatient prescription drugs.</summary>
</bill>
