<bill session="108" type="h" number="3916" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Presidential $1 Coin Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Presidential $1 Coin Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve circulation of the $1 coin, create a new bullion coin, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2004-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2004-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2004-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="2004-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2004-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2004-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2004-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E332-333"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-06-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 108-568.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-06-24T16:49:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="331">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 331.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights workers"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Ex-presidents"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Presidential families"/>
    <term name="Vending machines"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Women's voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2004--Reported to House amended.
Presidential $1 Coin Act of 2004 - (Sec. 3) Amends Federal monetary law to set forth requirements for the redesign and issuance of circulating $1 coins emblematic of each President of the United States beginning January 1, 2006, and ending when each President who has finished his or her period of service has been so honored. Requires inscription of the year of minting or issuance of the coin and the inscriptions "E Pluribus Unum" and "In God We Trust" to be edge-incused into the coin. Prohibits inclusion of a President who has not completed his or her term of service (sitting President). (Sec. 4) Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) issue gold bullion $10 coins emblematic of the spouse of each such President during the same period in which the $1 coins are issued; (2) prescribe the maximum number of bullion coins issued with each design selected; and (3) announce the maximum number of bullion coins that will be issued before the issuance of each such design. Provides for the design of such a bullion coin in the case of any President who served without a spouse. Authorizes the Secretary to strike and sell bronze medals that bear the likeness of such authorized bullion coins. (Sec. 5) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the American tradition of not issuing a coin with the image of a living person has served the country well and deserves to be continued as a general practice; (2) the full circulation potential and cost-savings benefit projections for the presidential $1 coin program are not likely to be achieved unless the coins are delivered in ways useful to ordinary commerce; (3) the Director of the U.S. Mint should take all reasonable steps to ensure that specified coins, remain tarnish-free for as long as possible without incurring undue expense; (4) if the Secretary of the Treasury determines to include a mark denoting the U.S. Mint facility at which the coin was struck on any $1 coin minted under this Act a, such mark should be edge-incused; (5) at such time as the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System determines appropriate, it should separate, sequester, and not put back into circulation, any $1 coin that does not bear the designs specified in this Act; (6) the presidential $1 coin program should not be introduced with an overly expensive taxpayer-funded public relations campaign; (7) the Director of the U.S. Mint should work to ensure to take all steps necessary to expand the marketplace for bullion coins, and reduce barriers to their sale; and (8) the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Secretary of the Treasury should take specified steps to ensure that an adequate supply of $1 coins are available for commerce and collectors.</summary>
</bill>
