<bill session="105" type="h" number="4825" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Childhood Lead Poisoning Protection Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require proof of screening for lead poisoning and to ensure that children at highest risk are identified and treated.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Head Start programs"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicaid managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/1998--Introduced.
Childhood Lead Poisoning Protection Act of 1998 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to provide for a reduced Federal medical assistance percentage for States that fail to meet specified minimum blood lead screening rates established by this Act, subject to waiver by the Secretary of Health and Human Services in the case of a State that has performed during a fiscal year such a significant number of lead blood level assessments that the State reasonably cannot be expected to achieve the appropriate minimum blood lead screening rate. Requires the State Medicaid plan to provide for reporting to the Secretary: (1) the number of children who are not more than two years of age and enrolled in the Medicaid program; and (2) the number and results of lead blood level assessments performed by the State, along with demographic and identifying information consistent with the recommendations of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) with respect to lead surveillance. Requires each contract between the State and an entity responsible for provision of medical assistance under the State plan to provide for: (1) compliance with mandatory screening requirements for lead blood level assessments commensurate with guidelines and mandates issued by the Secretary through the Administrator of the Health Care Financing Administration; as well as (2) coverage of appropriate qualified lead treatment services, as prescribed by CDC guidelines, for children with elevated levels of lead in their blood. Allows reimbursement for qualified lead treatment services for children with elevated blood lead levels. Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 and the Head Start Act to mandate lead poisoning screening for an infant or child to be eligible to participate in either the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children, or early Head Start programs.</summary>
</bill>
