<bill session="105" type="h" number="2525" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Planning and Choice Protection Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect women's reproductive health and constitutional right to choice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="1997-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1997-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="1998-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1998-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1997-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="1997-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1997-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1997-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1997-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1997-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1997-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="1997-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1998-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1998-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1997-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1998-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1997-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1997-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1998-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1997-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1998-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1998-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1997-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1998-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1997-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="1998-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1997-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1997-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Abortion clinics"/>
    <term name="Abortion counseling"/>
    <term name="Abortion procedures"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Birth control"/>
    <term name="Breast cancer"/>
    <term name="Cervical cancer"/>
    <term name="Chlamydia infections"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contraceptives"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human fertility"/>
    <term name="Incest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Prenatal care"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="RU 486 (Drug)"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court decisions"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women soldiers"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Prevention Subtitle A: Family Planning Subtitle B: Prescription Equity and Contraceptive Coverage Subtitle C: Emergency Contraceptives Title II: Research Title III: Choice Protection Family Planning and Choice Protection Act of 1997 - Title I: Prevention - Subtitle A: Family Planning - Amends the Public Health Service Act (PHSA) to authorize appropriations for voluntary family planning projects. (Sec. 102) Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to prohibit, notwithstanding any other provision of law, any authority of the United States, in or through any health care services or information program or activity administered or assisted by that authority, from limiting any person's right to provide or receive nonfraudulent information regarding reproductive health care services. Subtitle B: Prescription Equity and Contraceptive Coverage - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the PHSA to prohibit a group health plan, and an insurer providing coverage in connection with a group plan, from restricting benefits for prescription contraceptive drugs, devices, or outpatient services if the plan provides benefits for other outpatient prescription drugs, devices, or services. Prohibits related denial of eligibility or enrollment, monetary payments or rebates to covered individuals, and penalties or incentives to health care professionals. Amends the PHSA to apply these prohibitions to insurers in the individual market. Declares that this paragraph does not preempt State law providing greater enrollee protections. Subtitle C: Emergency Contraceptives - Mandates development and dissemination to the public and health care providers of information on drugs or devices designed to be used after sexual relations to prevent pregnancy. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Research - Declares the sense of the Congress regarding adequate funding for PHSA provisions regarding sexually transmitted diseases, breast and cervical cancers, and research on contraception and infertility. Title III: Choice Protection - Declares that it is the sense of the Congress that: (1) Federal and State governments should provide funding for abortion services to women eligible for assistance through title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act; (2) Federal resources are necessary to ensure safety for women and health professionals regarding reproductive health facilities and services; and (3) it is necessary and appropriate to use Federal resources to combat violence and harassment against reproductive health centers. (Sec. 303) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) ensure that a Food and Drug Administration decision to approve the drug called Mifepristone or RU-486 is made only on the basis provided in law; and (2) assess initiatives to promote the testing, licensing, and manufacturing in the United States of the drug or other antiprogestins. (Sec. 304) Prohibits a State from restricting a woman's freedom to choose pregnancy termination before fetal viability. Allows a State to: (1) restrict that freedom after viability unless termination is necessary to preserve the woman's life or health; and (2) impose requirements on abortions if the requirements are medically necessary to protect the woman's health. (Sec. 306) Amends Federal law to allow funds available to the Department of Defense (DOD) to be used for abortions when the pregnancy resulted from rape or incest or when the abortion is medically necessary or appropriate. Replaces provisions prohibiting (with exceptions) the use of DOD facilities to perform abortions with provisions declaring that certain provisions do not limit performing abortions in a uniformed services facility outside the 48 contiguous States if the cost is fully paid by non-DOD funds, abortions are not prohibited by the facility's jurisdiction, and the abortion would otherwise be permitted under laws regarding health care for uniformed services members and former members and their dependents in that facility.</summary>
</bill>
