<bill session="104" type="hr" number="492" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-31T13:47:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-07-31T13:47:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving a requirement of clause 4(b) of rule XI with respect to consideration of a certain resolution reported from the Committee on Rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400265"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30T18:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-720, by Mr. McInnis.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30T18:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Waiving the requirement of clause 4(b) of rule XI for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on teh same day it is presented to the House with respect to a resolution reproted before August 1, 1996, providing for consideration or disposition of a conference report to accompany the bill H.R. 3734, to provide for reconciliation pursuant to section 201(a)(1) of the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 1997.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-07-30T18:00:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="260">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 260.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9388-9392" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>During the course of debate, Ms. Delauro objected to the display of an exhibit. Pursuant to the provisions of rule XXX, the Speaker put the question on permitting the use of the exhibit and announced that, by voice vote, its use was permitted. Ms. DeLauro objected to the vote on the ground that a quorum was not present and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. The Yeas and Nays were ordered.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31T13:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31T13:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-07-31T13:47:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/1996--Introduced.
Waives provisions of rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives that require a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to a resolution reported by such Committee before August 1, 1996, to provide for the consideration or disposition of a conference report on H.R. 3734 (budget reconciliation).</summary>
</bill>
