<bill session="106" type="h" number="2731" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Choice and Sweepstakes Control Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 39, United States Code, to establish a notification system under which individuals may elect not to receive mailings related to skill contests or sweepstakes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400518"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="1999-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" subcommittee="Postal Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lotteries"/>
    <term name="Mailing lists"/>
    <term name="Postal crimes"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
Consumer Choice and Sweepstakes Control Act - Declares that matter otherwise legally acceptable in the mails is nonmailable, shall not be carried or delivered by mail, and shall be disposed of as the Postal Service directs, if it: (1) is a skill contest or sweepstakes addressed to an individual who made an election to be excluded from all mailing lists used by promoters of skill contests or sweepstakes by mailing a removal request form to the notification system established under this Act; or (2) is in noncompliance with the promoter requirements of this Act.Requires any promoter who mails a skill contest or sweepstakes to: (1) provide with each mailing a clear and conspicuous statement that includes the address or toll-free telephone number of such notification system and states that it can be used to prohibit the mailing of any skill contest or sweepstakes to such individual; and (2) establish and maintain a notification system that provides for any individual or other duly authorized person to notify the system of the individual's election to have his or her name and address excluded from all lists of names and addresses used by that promoter to mail such material.Prohibits the commercial use of any list of names and addresses used, maintained, or created by the system.Establishes civil penalties for: (1) persons who violate the prohibition; and (2) promoters who recklessly mail such nonmailable matter or fail to comply substantially with the notification system requirements.</summary>
</bill>
