<bill session="106" type="h" number="3381" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-12-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Export Enhancement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Export Enhancement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Overseas Private Investment Corporation and the Trade and Development Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400252"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="1999-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17T12:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17T12:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12146-12147" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17T12:41:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3381.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-11-17T12:49:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12146" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17T12:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1999-11-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14923" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1999-11-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1999-12-09">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1999-12-09" type="public" number="106-158">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-158.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="1993"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="688"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy industries"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental auditing"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Marketing research"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Overseas Private Investment Corporation"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Trade and Development Agency"/>
    <term name="Trade fairs"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/1999--Introduced.
Export Enhancement Act of 1999 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to extend through FY 2003 the Overseas Private Investment Corporation's (OPIC) authority to issue investment insurance and guarantees.(Sec. 3) Revises certain OPIC requirements to prohibit the OPIC Board of Directors from voting in favor of any proposed action likely to have significant adverse environmental impacts that are sensitive, diverse, or unprecedented, unless: (1) an environmental impact assessment or initial environmental audit has been completed by the project applicant and made available to the Board of Directors; and (2) such assessment or audit has been made available to the U.S. public, locally affected groups in the host country, and host country nongovernmental organizations. Requires OPIC in conjunction with each Board of Directors' meeting to hold a public hearing in order to afford an opportunity for any person to present views regarding OPIC activities.(Sec. 4) Revises the composition of the OPIC Board of Directors.(Sec. 5) Revises the purposes of the Trade and Development Agency to include, with respect to the promotion of U.S. private sector participation in development projects in developing and middle-income countries, special emphasis on economic sectors with significant U.S. export potential, such as energy, transportation, telecommunications, and environment. Directs the Agency to require corporations and other entities to: (1) share the costs of feasibility studies and other project planning services; and (2) reimburse the Agency those funds it has provided, if the corporation or entity concerned succeeds in project implementation. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 6) Requires the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee (TPCC) to: (1) report on actions taken to eliminate the areas of overlap and duplication identified among Federal export promotion activities; (2) coordinate efforts to sponsor or promote any trade show or trade fair; (3) work with all relevant State and national organizations, including the National Governors' Association, that have established trade promotion offices; and (4) report to Congress on actions taken to promote better coordination among State, Federal, and private sector export promotion activities.(Sec. 7) Amends the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to change the deadline for TPCC annual reports from September 30 to March 30.</summary>
</bill>
