<bill session="108" type="h" number="4601" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend that Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to recognize Alexander Creek as Native village, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2004--Introduced.
Amends the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to recognize Alexander Creek in Seward Meridian, Alaska, as a Native village. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to establish the Alexander Creek account in the Treasury to be available to Alexander Creek Incorporated (an Alaska Native Group corporation) for bidding on and purchasing property sold at public sale, subject to this Act. Requires the: (1) Secretary of the Interior to enter into negotiations to attempt to conclude a land exchange to acquire the surface estate in lands not within any conservation system unit from the State of Alaska or the Matanuska-Susitna Borough to enable Alexander Creek to select additional public lands within its original withdrawal area; and (2) conveyance, without consideration, of the subsurface estate to such conveyed lands to the Cook Inlet Region Incorporated (the Regional Corporation for Alexander Creek). Provides that: (1) upon certification by the Secretary of the appraisal of lands selected for purchase, the Alexander Creek Incorporated shall be deemed to have accepted the terms of this Act in lieu of any other land entitlement it could have received pursuant to this Act; and (2) the acceptance shall satisfy all claims such Corporation had or may have had against the United States on the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
