<bill session="107" type="hr" number="367" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-03-13T12:17:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-03-13T12:17:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2341) to amend the procedures that apply to consideration of interstate class actions to assure fairer outcomes for class members and defendants, to outlaw certain practices that provide inadequate settlements for class members, to assure that attorneys do not receive a disproportionate amount of settlements at the expense of class members, to provide for clearer and simpler information in class action settlement notices, to assure prompt consideration of interstate class actions, to amend title 28, United States Code, to allow the application of the principles of Federal diversity jurisdiction to interstate class actions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400327"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-03-12T19:58:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 107-375, by Ms. Pryce (OH).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-12T19:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2341 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-03-12T20:01:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="131">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 131.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T10:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H838-846" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T10:46:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 367.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T12:17:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 221 - 198 (Roll no. 55).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2002-03-13T12:17:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H838" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-03-13T12:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="107" type="h" number="2341"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2002--Reported to House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule (modified closed) for the consideration of H.R. 2341 (class action fairness).</summary>
</bill>
