<bill session="104" type="h" number="1732" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patent Reexamination Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 30 of title 35, United States Code, to afford third parties an opportunity for greater participation in reexamination proceedings before the Patent and Trademark Office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407899"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="1995-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="409650" joined="1995-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-15">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.3460.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3460"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="1070"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/1995--Introduced.
Patent Reexamination Reform Act of 1995 - Amends Federal patent law to expand reexamination request authority to authorize the filing of such requests by any person on the basis of patent specification requirements except for the best mode requirement. (Current law permits reexamination requests only on the basis of prior art.) Establishes procedures for reexamination proceedings based upon third-party (persons who are not the patent owner) requests. Requires documents filed in such proceedings, other than the request, to be served on all parties. Authorizes third-party requesters to file written comments not less than one month from the date of service of the patent owner's response to any Patent and Trademark Office action on the merits of reexamination. Grants third-party requesters the right to appeal final reexamination decisions on the same basis such right is available to patent owners. Estops a third-party requester who files a notice of appeal or who participates as a party to an appeal from later asserting the invalidity of any claim determined to be patentable on appeal on any ground which was or could have been raised during reexamination. Bars patent owners and third-party requesters, once an order for reexamination has been issued, from filing a subsequent reexamination request until a reexamination certificate is published. Prohibits a party, once a final decision has been entered in a civil action that the party has not sustained the burden of proving the invalidity of a patent claim, from requesting reexamination on issues that were or could have been raised in the civil action. Requires the Board of Patent Appeals and Interferences to review adverse decisions of examiners in reexamination proceedings and authorizes appeals to the Board by patent owners and third-party requesters with respect to reexamination decisions. Permits appeals of Board decisions to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.</summary>
</bill>
