<bill session="106" type="h" number="2727" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Telephone Services Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to improve protections against telephone service "slamming" and provide protections against telephone billing "cramming", to provide the Federal Trade Commission jurisdiction over unfair and deceptive trade practices of telecommunications carriers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1999-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1999-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1999-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1999-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1999-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="1999-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2000-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1999-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1999-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1999-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="1999-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400334" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1999-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2000-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="1999-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1999-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customer service"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Telephone rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
Telephone Services Consumer Protection Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 (the Act) to require a telecommunications carrier or reseller, in order to verify a subscriber's selection of a telephone exchange (local) or toll (long-distance) service provider, to require such subscriber to: (1) affirm that the subscriber is authorized to effect such selection; (2) acknowledge the type of service to be changed; (3) affirm the subscriber's intent to select such provider; (4) acknowledge that such selection will result in a change of service provider; and (5) provide other information as considered appropriate by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) for the subscriber's protection. Requires the appropriate carrier or reseller to notify the subscriber, in writing, not more than 15 days after such a change has been processed. Provides carrier or reseller penalties for unauthorized subscriber changes, including disqualification from the provision of such services (with reinstatement under certain conditions). Requires local exchange carriers to submit to the FCC quarterly reports on the number of complaints of unauthorized changes submitted by its subscribers. Directs the FCC to use such information to identify carriers or resellers that engage in a pattern and practice of unauthorized changes. Provides criminal penalties against such carriers or resellers.(Sec. 3) Prohibits any person from causing a charge to be included on a subscriber's bill for exchange or toll service unless such charge has been specifically and knowingly authorized by the subscriber or is otherwise authorized or required by law. Requires billing agents to include on such bills certain information identifying and explaining such charges. Prohibits the disruption of telephone service based on a charge dispute. Requires a toll-free number for the resolution of disputed charges. States that a subscriber who notifies a provider of charges included on his or her bill in violation of these provisions shall not be liable to such provider for such charges during the period that the entity provides such service. Requires repayment to a subscriber of payments made for such excess charges. Provides civil penalties for violations of such requirements. Requires local exchange carriers to submit to the FCC quarterly reports on the number of complaints of unauthorized bill charges. Directs the FCC to use such information to identify providers that engage in a pattern and practice of unauthorized charges.(Sec. 4) Authorizes the FCC to assess and recover any required penalty, fine, or forfeiture and to impose any other sanction required against an entity that is not a telecommunications carrier for a violation of any provisions of the Act to the extent that such entity provides billing services or other services for charges which appear on subscriber bills.(Sec. 5) Empowers the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to prevent telecommunications carriers from using unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce.(Sec. 6) Directs the FCC to provide monthly to the FTC information collected by the FCC as a result of complaints regarding telephone services fraud, to be incorporated into the FTC's Consumer Sentinel online database.(Sec. 7) Directs the FCC to study and report to Congress on the feasibility and advisability of requiring telephone service billing agents to establish and provide consumer billing controls which permit subscribers to prevent the inclusion of unauthorized charges on telephone bills.</summary>
</bill>
