<bill session="106" type="h" number="2504" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the United States participation in and appropriations for United States contributions to various international financial institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Gold reserves"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/1999--Introduced.
Amends certain Acts to authorize appropriations for: (1) the U.S. contribution to the twelfth replenishment of the International Development Association; (2) the U.S. contribution to the eighth replenishment of the African Development Fund; (3) the United States to subscribe to additional shares of capital stock of the African Development Bank, Inter-American Investment Corporation, and the Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency; and (4) the U.S. contribution to the Heavily Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) Trust Fund.Amends the Bretton Woods Agreements Act to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. Executive Director of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to vote to: (1) approve the sale of up to 10 million ounces of IMF gold and transfer the earnings on the invested profits of such sale to the Trust for Special ESAF Operations for the HIPC and the Interim ESAF Subsidy Operations (ESAF-HIPC Trust Fund); and (2) support a decision that would make available to the ESAF-HIPC Trust Fund the resources in Special Contingency Account 2 (SCA-2) of the IMF derived from the extended burdensharing arrangements adopted pursuant to IMF Decision No. 9471 (90/98), as amended, including any funds attributable to the U.S. participation in such arrangements.</summary>
</bill>
