<bill session="105" type="hr" number="537" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-16T11:08:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-09-16T11:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4300) to support enhanced drug interdiction efforts in the major transit countries and support a comprehensive supply eradication and crop substitution program in source countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15T20:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-720, by Mrs. Myrick.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15T20:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4300 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the Congressional Record and numbered 1 pursuant to clause 6 of rule XXIII. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule for a period not to exceed three hours. Points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substitute for failure to comply with clause 7 of rule XVI are waived. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. The Chairman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whether the Member offering an amendment has caused it to be printed in ...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-09-15T20:15:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="247">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 247.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T10:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7817-7819" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T10:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T11:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-09-16T11:08:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-09-16T11:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="4300"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/1998--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (modified open) for the consideration of H.R. 4300 (Western Hemisphere drug elimination).</summary>
</bill>
