<bill session="106" type="h" number="2009" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Handgun Standards Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To apply the same quality and safety standards to domestically manufactured handguns that are currently applied to imported handguns.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="h" number="2003"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/1999--Introduced.
American Handgun Standards Act of 1999 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit the manufacture, transfer, or possession of a junk gun that has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce. Defines a "junk gun" as any handgun that does not meet specified criteria for authorization by the Secretary of the Treasury for importation into the United States. Makes such provision inapplicable to: (1) the possession or transfer of any junk gun otherwise lawfully possessed under Federal law on the date of this Act's enactment; (2) any firearm or replica of a firearm that has been rendered permanently inoperative; (3) the manufacture for, transfer to, or possession by the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State of a junk gun, or a transfer to or possession by a law enforcement officer employed by such an entity for law enforcement purposes (whether on or off duty); (4) the transfer to or possession by a rail police officer employed by a rail carrier and certified or commissioned as a police officer under the laws of a State of a junk gun for such purposes; or (5) the manufacture, transfer, or possession of a junk gun by a licensed manufacturer or licensed importer for the purposes of testing or experimentation authorized by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
