<bill session="104" type="h" number="307" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Air Flexibility Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify certain regulatory requirements of the Environmental Protection Agency regarding motor vehicle inspection and maintenance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400591"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Automobile repair"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle registration"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Clean Air Flexibility Act of 1995 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to revise, update, and republish the guidance for States for motor vehicle inspection and maintenance programs required by the Clean Air Act, taking into consideration investigations and audits of such programs. Authorizes the guidance to be incorporated into State implementation plans. Requires States, within two years of the promulgation of regulations relating to emission control diagnostics, to submit revisions to programs to meet prescribed requirements. Provides that the rule regarding vehicle inspection and maintenance programs published in the Federal Register on November 5, 1992, shall cease to be effective. Authorizes States with implementation plans that contain provisions for enhanced vehicle inspection and maintenance programs to submit, revise, or amend such plans within one year of publication of the Administrator's guidance. Amends the Clean Air Act to authorize (currently, requires) States to comply with the Administrator's guidance for enhanced vehicle inspection and maintenance programs in Serious, Severe, and Extreme nonattainment areas. Permits (currently, requires) specified minimum elements to be included in such programs.</summary>
</bill>
