<bill session="104" type="h" number="2115" updated="2012-11-01T22:44:31-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Voter Opportunity To Inform Congress Effectively (V.O.I.C.E.) on Term Limits Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a national advisory referendum on limiting the terms of Members of Congress at the general election of 1996.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400182"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400583" joined="1995-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="405033" joined="1995-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400547" joined="1995-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1995-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400607" joined="1995-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="410636" joined="1995-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1995-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-07-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7793)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7793"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H8166-8169)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8166-8169"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional terms of office"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Term limits"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>07/26/1995--Introduced.
National Voter Opportunity To Inform Congress Effectively (V.O.I.C.E.) on Term Limits Act of 1995 - Provides for a national referendum on congressional term limits at the 1996 general election. National Voter Opportunity To Inform Congress Effectively (V.O.I.C.E.) on Term Limits Act of 1995 - Requires the Clerk of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate to certify to the appropriate State election agencies for inclusion on the 1996 general election ballot in every congressional district a national advisory referendum that poses the question of whether the Congress should approve a constitutional amendment to limit the number of terms that a Member of Congress can serve in office. Requires States and territories to be reimbursed at four cents per voter for the costs incurred in placing the advisory question on ballots in November 1996. Authorizes appropriations for such reimbursement. Requires tabulation and certification of the election results under customary procedures. Makes the Clerk of the House and the Secretary of the Senate responsible for transmitting such results to each Member. Requires the results to be taken under advisement by the House and the Senate Judiciary Committees, with recommendations for response reported back to the Congress within six months of the general election. Requires the State election agencies to forward to the Clerk of the House and the Secretary of the Senate their comments or suggestions regarding changes or improvements in procedures for conducting national nonbinding referenda in future general elections.</summary>
</bill>
