<bill session="108" type="h" number="3396" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-10-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Inequity Adjustment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a process under which a provider of services or other health care provider under the Medicare Program may petition the Secretary for an adjustment of the rate of payment made to that provider under the Medicare Program based on a significant inequity between the rate of payment applicable to that provider, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400220"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/29/2003--Introduced.
Medicare Inequity Adjustment Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a process under which a provider of services or other health care provider under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act may petition the Secretary for an adjustment of the rate of payment made to that provider under the Medicare program based on a significant inequity between the rate of payment applicable to that provider and the rate of payment applicable to similar providers located in adjoining areas.</summary>
</bill>
