<bill session="106" type="h" number="2903" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-12-21">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coral Reef Conservation and Restoration Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Striped Bass Conservation, Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Management, and Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assist in the conservation of coral reefs.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To reauthorize the Striped Bass Conservation Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-31T22:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-31T22:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11704-11706" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-10-31T22:31:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11704-11705" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-31T22:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-31T22:31:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-12-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11754" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-12-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-12-08">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-12-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-12-21">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-12-21" type="public" number="106-555">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-555.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Coast (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Coral reef conservation"/>
    <term name="Coral reefs"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Ecological surveys"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine biology"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine mammal protection"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research ships"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Sustainable fisheries"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
    <term name="Whales"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/31/2000--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Subtitle A: Atlantic Striped Bass Conservation Subtitle B: Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Cooperative Management Title II: John H. Prescott Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Grant Program Title I: Atlantic Coastal Fisheries - Subtitle A: Atlantic Striped Bass Conservation - Amends the Atlantic Striped Bass Conservation Act to extend the authorization of appropriations to carry out such Act through FY 2003.(Sec. 102) Requires the Secretaries of Commerce and the Interior to: (1) conduct a study to determine if the distribution of year classes in the Atlantic striped bass population is appropriate for maintaining adequate recruitment and sustainable fishing opportunities; and (2) report results to specified congressional committees along with a long-term plan to ensure a balanced and healthy population structure of Atlantic striped bass. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle B: Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Cooperative Management - Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Act of 2000 - Amends the Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Cooperative Management Act to extend the authorization of appropriations to carry out such Act through FY 2005. Authorizes amounts to be used to support the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission's cooperative statistics program.Title II: John H. Prescott Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Grant Program - Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Act of 2000 - Amends the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish the John H. Prescott Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Grant Program to provide assistance to eligible stranding network participants for: (1) marine mammal recovery and treatment; (2) data collection from living or dead marine mammals; and (3) facilities operation.Caps grants at $100,000. Requires a 25 percent non-Federal matching amount, which may be in-kind contributions. Authorizes FY 2001 through 2003 appropriations.(Sec. 203) Requires the Secretary to study environmental and biological factors responsible for the significant increase in mortality events of the eastern gray whale population and other potential impacts these factors may be having on such population. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 204) Authorizes the Secretary to convey a retired National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration fishery research vessel to the Government of American Samoa.(Sec. 205) Amends the National Marine Sanctuaries Act to revise sanctuary designation standards.(Sec. 206) Amends the Sustainable Fisheries Act to authorize appropriations for each fiscal year for grants to carry out Western Pacific fishery demonstration projects to promote traditional indigenous fishing practices.</summary>
</bill>
