<bill session="104" type="h" number="3953" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-08-02T16:28:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-08-02T16:28:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Aviation Security and Antiterrorism Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To combat terrorism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1996-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="1996-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1996-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T00:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 508 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3953. Upon adoption of this resolution, it shall be in order at any time on the calendar day of Friday, August 2, 1996, for the Speaker to entertain a motion offered by the majority leader or his designee that the House suspend the rules and pass a bill or joint resolution relating to the subject of combating terrorism.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T15:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 508 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T15:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 508, the House proceeded with consideration of H.R. 3953 under suspension of the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cox moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T15:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9886-9896" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T15:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-08-02T16:28:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="401" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 389 - 22 (Roll no. 401).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 3953.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-09-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="571">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 571.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="508"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Airline employees"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Alien property"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arson"/>
    <term name="Assassination"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Hostages"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Loyalty-security program"/>
    <term name="Management audit"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Mass destruction weapons"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Offshore structures"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Plastics"/>
    <term name="Police dogs"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential protection"/>
    <term name="Protection of foreign officials"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court justices"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Aviation Security Title II: Antiterrorism Aviation Security and Antiterrorism Act of 1996 - Title I: Aviation Security - Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to: (1) facilitate the interim deployment of commercially available explosive detection devices that will significantly enhance aviation security; (2) require that an employment investigation, including a criminal history record check in specified cases, be conducted for individuals who will be responsible for screening passengers or property and their supervisors; and (3) provide for the periodic audit of criminal history record checks. Requires employment standards for air carrier and airport security personnel to include performance standards for airport and airline security personnel, including counter personnel, and guidelines for encouraging the retention of security personnel responsible for passengers and cargo. Direct the FAA, the Secretary of Transportation, the intelligence community, and the law enforcement community to continue to assist air carriers in developing computer-assisted passenger profiling programs. (Sec. 106) Permits the use of airport improvement project grant funds and passenger facility fees to expand and enhance air transportation security programs and other activities at airports to ensure the safety and security of passengers and others involved in air travel. (Sec. 107) Requires the Administrator to review: (1) FAA oversight of inspections of shipments of mail and cargo by domestic and foreign air carriers; (2) the need for additional security measures with respect to such inspections; and (3) the adequacy of inspection and screening of cargo on passenger air carriers. Directs the President to submit relevant legislative proposals to the Congress. Requires the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to assure that FBI agents assigned to an area where there are high- risk airports carry out periodic threat and vulnerability assessments of security at least every three years at such airports. Requires the operator of each major airport to use dogs or other appropriate animals to supplement existing equipment used for screening passengers and cargo for plastic explosives and other devices or materials which may be used in aircraft piracy, subject to specified limitations. Directs the Administrator to initiate a rulemaking to revise Federal regulations regarding airplanes having fewer than 61 passenger seats to enhance safety and security of travel in such planes. (Sec. 110) Replaces a provision permitting grants to continue the program to detect explosives at airports and on aircraft with provisions directing the Secretary of Transportation to make grants for expenses of training and evaluation of dogs for the explosive detection K-9 team training program and extending such program to the largest 50 airports in the United States within 180 days of the enactment of the Aviation Security Improvement Act of 1996. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 112) Establishes the Civil Aviation Security Review Commission to conduct a comprehensive review of aviation security. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Antiterrorism - Adds specified terrorist offenses as predicate offenses under the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act. (Sec. 202) Enhances penalties for unlawfully disclosing specified material under the civil and criminal remedy provisions of the Privacy Act and under wiretap provisions of the Federal criminal code. (Sec. 203) Urges the President to commence diplomatic efforts to establish a multilateral sanctions regime against nations certified under the Export Administration Act of 1979 as having repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism. Requires the President to provide to: (1) the Congress an action plan for inducing such nations to cease their support for such acts; and (2) the House and Senate intelligence committees a report on the capability of the U.S intelligence community to detect, assess, and eliminate international terrorist activities. (Sec. 204) Directs: (1) the Secretary of State to designate, before October 1, 1996, foreign terrorist organizations pursuant to the Antiterrorism and Effective Death Penalty Act of 1996; (2) the Secretary of the Treasury, if possible, as justified by the evidence, and consistent with the needs of law enforcement and intelligence, to freeze assets; and (3) the Attorney General to initiate the removal of known alien terrorists and criminals. (Sec. 205) Requires the Director of the National Institute of Justice to: (1) contract for an independent study of the feasibility, safety, and law enforcement effectiveness of including taggants in black and smokeless powder; and (2) submit to the Congress recommendations for legislation for the addition of taggants to black and smokeless powder manufactured in or imported into the United States if specified conditions are met. (Sec. 206) Establishes the National Commission on Terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
