<bill session="104" type="h" number="4114" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve and expand the system of safety of precautions that protects the welfare of professional boxers, to assist State boxing commissions to provide proper oversight for professional boxing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411677"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1996-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="h" number="4167"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="66"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Ambulances"/>
    <term name="Boxing"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Professional associations"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/1996--Introduced.
Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 - Prohibits any person from arranging, promoting, organizing, producing, or fighting in a professional boxing match held in a State that has no boxing commission unless the match is: (1) supervised by a commission from another State; and (2) subject to the most recent Association of Boxing Commissions (ABC) guidelines, as well as any additional relevant professional regulations and requirements of such other State. Requires, for any professional boxing match: (1) a physical examination of each boxer to determine fitness to compete; (2) the presence of an ambulance or medical personnel and a physician on site; and (3) health insurance coverage for each boxer. (Sec. 6) Requires each professional boxer to register with the commission of the State in which such boxer resides or, in the case of a boxer who is a resident of a foreign country or a State in which there is no such commission, the commission of any other State. Directs a commission to issue to each registering boxer an identification card that contains a recent photograph, a social security or similar identification number, and a personal identification number assigned by a boxing registry. (Sec. 7) Directs each commission to establish procedures to: (1) evaluate the professional records and physician's certification of each boxer participating in a match in the State and to deny fight authorization where appropriate; (2) ensure that no boxer is permitted to box while under suspension from any commission due to a recent knockout or series of consecutive losses, an injury, a required medical procedure, a physician denial of certification, failure of a drug test, or use of false aliases, identification cards, or documents; (3) review a suspension when appealed by a boxer; and (4) revoke a suspension where appropriate proof is presented that a suspension was not, or is no longer, merited by the facts. Authorizes a commission to allow a boxer who is under suspension in any State to participate in a boxing match: (1) for any reason other than those listed above if such commission notifies the suspending commission in writing prior to its approval; or (2) if the boxer appeals to the ABC and the ABC determines that the suspension was without sufficient grounds, for an improper purpose, or not related to the boxer's health or safety or the purposes of this Act. (Sec. 8) Requires the supervising commission, within 48 business hours after the conclusion of a fight, to report fight results and any related suspensions to each boxer registry. (Sec. 9) Outlines conflict-of-interest requirements for commission members or employees, persons who administer or enforce State boxing laws, and members of the ABC. (Sec. 10) Authorizes the Attorney General to bring a civil action against persons in violation of this Act for appropriate relief, including match injunctions. Prescribes criminal penalties for violations of this Act. (Sec. 11) Requires each promoter who intends to hold a match in a State that does not have a boxing commission, at least 14 days before such fight, to provide written notification to the supervising boxing authority containing: (1) assurances that the requirements of this Act will be met; and (2) the identity of any participating fighter who is under suspension from a boxing commission and the identity of such commission. (Sec. 12) Requires a study by: (1) the Secretary of Labor on the feasibility and cost of a national pension system for boxers; and (2) the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop recommendations for health, safety, and equipment standards for boxers and matches. (Sec. 13) Authorizes an Indian tribal organization to regulate, or enter into a contract for a boxing commission to regulate, matches held on a reservation. Requires a tribal organization that regulates its own matches to establish and implement health and safety standards, licensing, and related requirements that are at least as restrictive as: (1) the standards of the State in which the reservation is located; or (2) the most recent ABC guidelines.</summary>
</bill>
