<bill session="104" type="h" number="1268" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Wetlands Conservation and Management Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to establish a comprehensive program for conserving and managing wetlands in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1995-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3340"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29">
      <text>See H.R.961.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="961"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="352"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Excavation"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland ecology"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/1995--Introduced.
Comprehensive Wetlands Conservation and Management Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to prohibit, unless such activity is undertaken pursuant to a permit issued by the Secretary of the Army: (1) the discharge of dredged or fill material into U.S. waters; or (2) the draining, channelization, excavation, or flooding of wetlands, construction of structures in and diversion of water from wetlands, or the conduct of any activity which adversely affects wetlands. Requires the Secretary, upon receiving permit applications, to: (1) classify as Type A wetlands those that are of critical significance to the long-term conservation of an ecosystem; (2) classify as Type B wetlands those that provide habitat for a significant population of wildlife or provide other significant wetlands functions; and (3) classify as Type C wetlands those that serve marginal functions but exist in such abundance that regulation of activities is not necessary to conserve wetlands values and functions, or are lands that do not serve significant wetlands functions. Permits owners of interests in Type A wetlands to seek compensation for the fair market value of such lands. Provides that title for such lands shall pass to the United States upon acceptance of an offer for compensation. Requires the Secretary to deny a permit authorizing activities in Type A wetlands unless: (1) such activities can be undertaken with minimal alteration or disturbance; (2) there are public interest concerns that require use of the lands for purposes other than conservation; or (3) the proposed use of the land will result in overall environmental benefits. Authorizes the Secretary to issue a permit for activities in Type B wetlands subject to conditions that ensure that the wetland ecosystem does not suffer loss or degradation. Imposes requirements for mitigation when such activities result in permanent wetland loss or degradation. Directs the Secretary to establish a mitigation banking program in each State to ensure compensation for loss and degradation of wetlands. Requires the primary objective of such programs to be to provide for the restoration, enhancement, or creation of ecologically significant wetlands on an ecosystem basis. Exempts specified activities from this Act's requirements. Requires the Director of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to undertake a project to identify and classify U.S. wetlands. Authorizes civil actions and prescribes penalties for permit violations. Authorizes States to administer permit programs for activities covered by this Act, subject to the Secretary's approval.</summary>
</bill>
