<bill session="106" type="h" number="1611" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Individual Investment Account Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a deduction for contributions to individual investment accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="1999-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1999-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="1999-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="2000-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/1999--Introduced.
Individual Investment Account Act of 1999 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a deduction for amounts contributed to individual investment accounts. Allows tax-free distributions, limited to $15,000 for all taxable years, from such accounts for use in the purchase of a principal residence by a first-time homebuyer. Makes such accounts tax-exempt unless the individual engages in prohibited transactions. Exempts such an account from the additional tax on prohibited transactions even if the account ceases to be an individual investment account as the result of a prohibited transaction. Adjusts dollar limitations under this Act for inflation. Allows such deduction in determining adjusted gross income. Exempts such accounts from estate tax. Excludes from gross income gain from the sale or exchange of property if, during the five-year period ending on the date of the sale or exchange, such property has been owned and used by the taxpayer as a principal residence for periods aggregating two years or more. Limits such exclusion to the amount paid to an individual investment account during the one-year period beginning on the date of the sale or exchange. Provides for adjusting the basis of a residence acquired through the use of an individual investment account.</summary>
</bill>
