<bill session="104" type="h" number="2316" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Exempt Organization Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose an excise tax on amounts of private excess benefits from certain charitable organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1995-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-09-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1765-1766"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Executives"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/1995--Introduced.
Exempt Organization Reform Act of 1995 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excess benefit transactions excise tax on a disqualified person and on an organization manager. Defines excess benefit transaction as any transaction in which an economic benefit is provided by a tax-exempt organization to or for the use of a disqualified person, if the value of the benefit exceeds the value of the consideration. Defines disqualified person and organization manager. Requires 501(c)(3) and 501(c)(4) organizations to report certain excise taxes paid. Revises requirements concerning the public inspection of the returns of exempt organizations. Requires certain organizations to disclose, in a conspicuous and easily recognizable format, in an advertisement or solicitation the nonexempt status of such organization. Provides for a penalty, not to exceed $10,000, of $1,000 for each day on which a failure occurred to disclose such nonexempt status with respect to any advertisement or solicitation. Provides for an increase in penalties on exempt organizations for failure to file complete and timely annual returns. Provides for a larger penalty for exempt organizations having gross receipts exceeding $1,000,000 for any year.</summary>
</bill>
