<bill session="106" type="h" number="2130" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Date-Rape Prevention Drug bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hillory J. Farias Date-Rape Prevention Drug Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Hillory J. Farias Date-Rape Prevention Drug Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Hillory J. Farias Date-Rape Prevention Drug Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Hillory J. Farias and Samantha Reid Date-Rape Drug Prohibition Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Hillory J. Farias and Samantha Reid Date-Rape Drug Prohibition Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to add gamma hydroxybutyric acid and ketamine to the schedules of control substances, to provide for a national awareness campaign, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An act to amend the Controlled Substances Act to direct the emergency scheduling of gamma hydroxybutyric acid, to provide for a national awareness campaign, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400414"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1999-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="1999-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1999-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1999-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="1999-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1999-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1999-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400434" joined="1999-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05T21:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Pryce (OH) asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Commerce have until midnight on Sept. 7 to file a report on H.R. 2130. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-27T20:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Commerce. H. Rept. 106-340, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-27T20:55:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 8, 1999.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-08T12:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-10-08T12:09:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="214">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 214.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-10-12T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Upton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-12T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9863-9872" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-12T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2130.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-12T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-12T19:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9876-9877" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-10-12T20:00:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="493" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 423 - 1 (Roll no. 493).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9863-9864" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-10-12T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-12T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14872-14877" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 1561 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1999-11-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 1561 with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-31T14:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Upton moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-31T14:17:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-31T14:34:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-01-31T18:33:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="3" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 339 - 2 (Roll no. 3).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H53-54" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H55-57" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-01-31T18:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-01-31">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-02-09">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-02-18">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-02-18" type="public" number="106-172">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-172.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="3457"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="106" type="s" number="1561"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1561"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="106" type="s" number="1561"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Acquaintance rape"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Burglary protection"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forensic medicine"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hallucinogenic drugs"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="High school students"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital personnel"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Rape victim services"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Sedatives"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/1999--Passed Senate amended.
Hillory J. Farias and Samantha Reid Date-Rape Drug Prohibition Act of 1999 - Directs the Attorney General to issue, within 60 days, a final order that schedules gamma hydroxybutyric acid (GHB) (together with its salts, isomers, and salts of isomers) in the schedule under the Controlled Substances Act (CSA) relating to imminent hazards to public safety, with specified exceptions regarding: (1) manufacture, distribution, or possession of the drug in accordance with an exemption under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) involving drugs for research; and (2) new drug products under the FFDCA. Deems GHB to be so scheduled if such final order is not issued within that period.Amends the CSA and the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to provide additional penalties relating to GHB.Adds gamma butyrolactone (GBL) as an additional list I chemical.(Sec. 4) Amends the CSA to authorize the Attorney General to establish specified reporting requirements for GHB products in Schedule III, including annual reports of end-of-year inventories and requirements that dispensing practitioners maintain certain records regarding prescriptions.(Sec. 5) Specifies that the designation of GBL or any other chemical as a listed chemical under the CSA does not preclude a finding that the chemical is a controlled substance analogue. Includes controlled substance analogues within the scope of provisions regarding penalties for distribution of a controlled substance.(Sec. 6) Directs the Attorney General to: (1) develop model protocols for the collection of toxicology specimens and the taking of victim statements in connection with investigations into and prosecutions related to possible violations of the CSA or other Federal or State laws that result in or contribute to rape, other crimes of violence, or other crimes involving abuse of GHB, and other controlled substances, or so-called "designer drugs," and develop model training materials for law enforcement personnel involved in such investigations; and (2) make such protocols and training materials available to Federal, State, and local personnel responsible for such investigations.Directs the Attorney General to make a grant, in such amount and to such public or private person or entity as the Attorney General considers appropriate, for the development of forensic field tests to assist law enforcement officials in detecting the presence of GHB and related substances. Authorizes appropriations. Sets forth reporting requirements.(Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to submit to Congress annual reports each of which provides an estimate of the number of incidents of the abuse of date-rape drugs that occurred during the most recent one-year period for which data are available, with the first such report submitted by January 15, 2000.Requires the Secretary to develop a plan for carrying out a national campaign to educate young adults, youths, law enforcement personnel, educators, school nurses, counselors of rape victims, and hospital emergency room personnel on: (1) the dangers of date-rape drugs; (2) the applicability of the CSA to such drugs, including penalties; (3) recognizing the symptoms that indicate an individual may be a victim of such drugs, including symptoms of sexual assault; and (4) appropriately responding when an individual has such symptoms.Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish an advisory committee, composed of individuals who collectively possess expertise on the effects of, and detecting and controlling, date-rape drugs, to make recommendations regarding the plan; and (2) commence carrying out the national campaign within 180 days after its establishment. Requires the Comptroller General to submit to Congress, within two years, an evaluation of the effects with respect to date-rape drugs of the national campaign.(Sec. 8) Directs the Attorney General, within 60 days after this Act's enactment, to establish within the Operations Division of the Drug Enforcement Administration a special unit which shall assess the abuse and trafficking in GHB, flunitrazepam, ketamine, other controlled substances, and other designer drugs whose use has been associated with sexual assault, including: (1) examining the threat posed by such substances and drugs on a national and on a regional basis; and (2) making recommendations regarding allocations and reallocations of resources to address the threat.Directs the Attorney General, within 180 days, to submit to specified congressional committees a report setting forth the recommendations of the special unit, and specifying the allocations and reallocations of resources that the Attorney General proposes to make in response to the recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
