<bill session="108" type="h" number="1460" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-24T13:30:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-24T13:30:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Entrepreneurship Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Veterans Entrepreneurship and Benefits Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans Entrepreneurship and Benefits Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to permit the use of education benefits under such title for certain entrepreneurship courses, to permit veterans enrolled in a vocational rehabilitation program under chapter 31 of such title to have self-employment as a vocational goal, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve education and entrepreneurship benefits, housing benefits, and certain other benefits for veterans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400336"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400002" joined="2003-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400020" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400045" joined="2003-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2003-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2003-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2003-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2003-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="2003-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2003-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2003-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E603"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-07">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T14:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 108-142, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Small Business Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 7, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-23T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-23T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5675-5679" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-23T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1460.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-23T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5743-5744" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-06-24T13:30:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="304" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 421 - 0 (Roll no. 304).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/23/2003 H5675-5676" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T13:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T13:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="241"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="761"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="1949"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2297"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Education)"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Deaf"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2003--Passed House amended.
Veterans Entrepreneurship and Benefits Improvement Act of 2003 - Authorizes a State agency to approve entrepreneurship (business education) courses for attendance by veterans using veterans' basic educational assistance provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs. Prohibits the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from treating a business owner as already qualified for such purposes. Includes entrepreneurship courses within authorized programs of veterans' education assistance. Amends the Small Business Act to authorize a Federal contracting officer to award a sole source contract to any certified small business (one owned and controlled by service-disabled (qualified) veterans) if: (1) the certified business is determined to be responsible with respect to the performance of the contract opportunity and the contracting officer does not expect two or more such businesses to submit offers for such contract; (2) the anticipated award price of the contract will not exceed a specified amount; and (3) the contract award can be made at a fair and reasonable price. Allows a contracting officer to restrict contract competition to such businesses if the officer can reasonably expect two or more such businesses to submit offers. Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), at least every three years, to: (1) complete a survey of qualified veterans receiving such benefits; and (2) report survey results to Congress. Prohibits a contracting officer from making a procurement under this Act: (1) unless the officer has determined that such procurement cannot be made on the basis of a preference provided under another provision of the Small Business Act; or (2) if the procurement would otherwise be made from a different source under provisions of the Federal criminal code governing Government procurement of prisoner products or services or of the Javits-Wagner-O'Day Act. Outlines the appropriate order of priority, with the highest priority under small business start-up loans guaranteed by the SBA. Provides priority requirements with respect to a contracting officer of the Department of Veterans Affairs. Terminates that priority with respect to Department procurements after FY 2007. Authorizes the Secretary to provide adapted housing assistance to certain categories of disabled military personnel (having suffered loss of limbs, organs, partial blindness or deafness, etc.) serving on active duty if the disability is the result of an injury or disease contracted or aggravated during such duty.Increases from 65 to 85 the percentage of the number of purchases during a fiscal year of real property acquired by the Secretary as a result of default on guaranteed loans for the purchase or construction of homes for veterans that may be financed by a loan made by the Secretary.Requires the payment of all accrued monetary benefits (currently limited to two years' worth) of a deceased veteran's beneficiary to the veteran or any other surviving dependent.</summary>
</bill>
