<bill session="106" type="hr" number="538" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-28T23:04:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-06-28T23:04:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4461) making appropriations for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400107"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T03:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-704, by Mr. Diaz-Balart.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T03:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4461 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-28T03:29:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="247">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 247.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T21:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5415-5423" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T21:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 538.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T21:38:00-04:00">
      <text>WORDS TAKEN DOWN - In the course of debate, exception was taken to certain statements made at that time. Mr. Obey demanded that the words be taken down and ruled upon by the Speaker pro tempore.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T21:38:00-04:00">
      <text>WITHDRAWAL OF WORDS - Mr. Diaz-Balart asked unanimous consent to withdraw certain words from his debate statement. Agreed to without objection. The House continued with debate on H. Res. 538.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T22:42:00-04:00">
      <text>WORDS TAKEN DOWN - In the course of debate, exception was taken to certain statements made at that time. Mr. Obey demanded that the words be taken down and ruled upon by the Speaker pro tempore. Subsequently, Mr. Obey withdrew his request.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T22:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2000-06-28T23:04:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="358" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 232 - 179 (Roll no. 358).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5415" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T23:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="hr" number="513"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="hr" number="513"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="4461"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2000--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 4461 (Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
