<bill session="107" type="h" number="4697" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Human Research Subject Protections Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to the protection of human subjects in research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400101"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2002-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2002-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="2002-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Management audit"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mentally disabled"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Research ethics"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2002--Introduced.
Human Research Subject Protections Act of 2002 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require all human subject research conducted, supported or otherwise subject to Federal regulation to be conducted in accordance with the common rule and the vulnerable-population rules, as set forth in the Code of Federal Regulations. Defines such terms according to different regulations for human subject research subject to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to review all such regulations to harmonize them where feasible with a subsequent proposed rule, explaining remaining differences.Sets forth the authority of the Secretary to modify regulations.Requires informed consent, as specified.Requires an Institutional Review Board to approve all human subject research proposals.Directs the Secretary to establish criteria for identifying and monitoring high risk clinical trials.Prohibits the use of Federal funds for classified human subject research, as specified.Requires the Secretary to determine whether an entity has violated these requirements, as specified.Establishes an Office of Human Research Protections within the Office of the Secretary to make grants, conduct research and Institutional Review Board audits (requiring corrective action if necessary), and coordinate Federal efforts. Requires the Director to notify the relevant regulatory agency if deficiencies are found.Authorizes the Director of such Office to make grants for the development of a model education program.Requires coordination with the Commissioner of Food and Drugs.Continues the National Research Protections Act Advisory Committee.Requires the Secretary to promulgate regulations addressing the participation of people with diminished decisionmaking capacity in human subject research.</summary>
</bill>
