<bill session="104" type="hr" number="426" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-08T16:18:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-05-08T16:18:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2406) to repeal the United States Housing Act of 1937, deregulate the public housing program and the program for rental housing assistance for low-income families, and increase community control over such programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-05-07T22:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-564, by Mr. Dreier.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-07T22:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2406 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Banking now printed in the bill. Amendment shall be considered by title rather than by section. Prior to consideration of any other amendment, it shall be in order to consider a Lazio amendment printed in the Congressional Record of May 7, 1996, debatable for 10 minutes and not subject to further amendment. If that amendment is adopted, the bill, as amended, shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment. After passage of t...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-05-07T22:17:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="218">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 218.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4559-4569" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 218 - 208 (Roll no. 153).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-05-08T16:18:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="2406"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/1996--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 2406 and S. 1260 (public and assisted housing).</summary>
</bill>
