<bill session="105" type="hr" number="481" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drug-Free Professional and Olympic Athlete Responsibility Resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that professional sports leagues and the International Olympic Committee should help reinforce the unacceptability and harmfulness of illegal drug use by establishing clear guidelines and penalties, and that athletes using illegal drugs who do not identify the person who provided the illegal drugs and successfully complete a drug treatment program should be suspended from play for a minimum of one year without pay.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400541"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="1998-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400353" joined="1998-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs and athletes"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/1998--Introduced.
Drug-Free Professional and Olympic Athlete Responsibility Resolution - Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) all professional sports leagues and the International Olympic Committee should help reinforce the unacceptability and harmfulness of substance abuse by establishing clear guidelines and penalties regarding drug abuse; and (2) athletes who are using illegal drugs who do not identify the person who provided such drugs and successfully complete a drug treatment program should be suspended from play for a minimum of one year without pay.</summary>
</bill>
