<bill session="104" type="h" number="3788" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Parks Capital Improvements Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to assess up to $2 per person visiting the Grand Canyon or other national park to secure bonds for capital improvements to the park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400226"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1280-1281"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-23">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/1996--Introduced.
National Parks Capital Improvements Act of 1996 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a memorandum of agreement with an entity to act as an authorized fundraising organization for the benefit of the Grand Canyon National Park and any other national park designated by the Secretary that has an approved general management plan with capital needs in excess of $5 million. Requires the organization to issue taxable bonds in return for a park surcharge. Exempts the United States from liability for the security of such bonds, unless the surcharge authorized under this Act is not imposed or is reduced or eliminated. Authorizes the Secretary to permit the Superintendent of the park to charge and collect, in addition to the park entrance fee, a surcharge of not to exceed two dollars per individual. Requires the fundraising organization to: (1) use the surcharge to amortize the bond issue, provide for the reasonable costs of administration, and maintain a sufficient reserve consistent with industry standards; and (2) remit any excess funds to the National Park Foundation (NPF) to be used for the benefit of all National Park System (NPS) units. Allows bond proceeds to be used for a park facility project that is consistent with: (1) the laws governing the NPS and the park; and (2) the general management plan for the park. Prohibits bond proceeds (other than interest) from being used to defray administrative expenses. Requires interest earned on bond proceeds to be used by the organization to meet reserve requirements and defray administrative expenses incurred in connection with the management and sale of the bonds, with any excess to be remitted to the NPF for the benefit of all NPS units.</summary>
</bill>
