<bill session="105" type="h" number="2600" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act and section 4626 of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 to prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from providing any incentive payments to hospitals to reduce the number of residents in graduate medical education programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="1997-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1997-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="1997-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1997-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-01">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-01">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/1997--Introduced.
Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA), as amended by the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, to repeal the authority and mandate for incentive payments under plans for voluntary reduction in the number of residents in a graduate medical education residency training program. Amends the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 to prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from approving or providing any payments for any demonstration project that provides for additional Medicare payments in connection with such a reduction for any residency training year beginning on or after July 1, 1998 (currently before July 1, 2006). Provides that the April 1995 Health Care Financing Administration interpretation of Medicare secondary payer requirements for group health plans with regard to individuals with end stage renal disease (ESRD) shall not apply retroactively to a group health plan that paid benefits primary to SSA title XVIII (but would have paid benefits secondary to such title in the absence of such requirements) on or after August 10, 1993, and before April 24, 1995, on behalf of certain individuals who became entitled or eligible for the ESRD program. Amends the Internal Revenue Code, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and the Public Health Service Act to extend COBRA continuation coverage for qualified ESRD Medicare beneficiaries for 36 months. Amends SSA title XVIII to provide for an extension of the Medicare ESRD secondary payer period from 30 to 36 months.</summary>
</bill>
