<bill session="105" type="hr" number="604" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-20T18:06:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-20T18:06:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (S. 1132) to modify the boundaries of the Bandelier National Monument to include the lands within the headwaters of the Upper Alamo Watershed which drain into the Monument and which are not currently within the jurisdiction of a Federal land management agency, to authorize purchase or donation of those lands, and for other purposes, and for consideration of the bill (S. 2133) an act to preserve the cultural resources of the Route 66 corridor and to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide assistance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-10-16T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-823, by Mr. Dreier.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-16T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of S. 1132 and S. 2133 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. It shall be in order without the intervention of any point of order to consider in the House, S. 1132. One hour of debate shall be equally divided and controlled by the Chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Resources. It shall be in order without the intervention of any point of order to consider in the House, S. 2133. One hour of debate shall be equally divided and controlled by the Chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Resources. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-10-16T13:28:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="279">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 279.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11553-11558, H11591-11592" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-10-20T14:37:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on agreeing to the resolution by voice vote and announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hall of Ohio objected to the voice vote and demanded the yeas and nays. Further proceedings on the resolution were postponed.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T17:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-10-20T18:06:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="537" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 229 - 189 (Roll No. 537).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T18:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="1132"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="s" number="1132"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="2133"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="s" number="2133"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/16/1998--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (closed) for the consideration of S. 1132 (Bandelier National Monument, New Mexico boundary modification and watershed protection) and S. 2133 (preservation of the cultural resources of the Route 66 corridor).</summary>
</bill>
