<bill session="105" type="h" number="599" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Corporate Welfare Reduction Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce tax benefits for foreign corporations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1997-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1998-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1997-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400532" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1997-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1997-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1997-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/1997--Introduced.
Corporate Welfare Reduction Act of 1997 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to determining the foreign tax credit, to replace the formula for reducing the amount of oil and gas extraction taxes taken into account. Disallows as creditable amounts: (1) any taxes paid or accrued to a foreign country with respect to foreign oil and gas income (including extraction income) which are not imposed under the country's generally applicable income tax law; and (2) any other taxes on such income to the extent that the country's law is structured or operates so that the tax amount imposed will generally be materially greater, over a reasonable period, than the amount generally imposed on other income. Separates such income, for purposes of certain limitations on the application of the credit, into foreign oil and gas extraction income and foreign oil related income. Removes the deferral, for purposes of taxation of controlled foreign corporations, of tax on extraction income or income from consumption in the foreign country. Provides that the Secretary of the Treasury's authority, in allocating income, deductions, credits, and allowances among taxpayers owned or controlled by the same interests, shall not be limited by any restriction on the ability of the entities to transfer or receive money or property. Revises provisions concerning the exclusion of foreign earned income by U.S. citizens living abroad. Treats the gain or loss of a nonresident alien individual or foreign corporation that is a ten-percent shareholder in a domestic corporation upon disposition of such a corporation's stock as if the taxpayer were engaged during the taxable year in a trade or business within the United States and such gain or loss attributable to a permanent U.S. trade or business establishment. Imposes a 26-percent minimum tax on nonresident alien individuals. Provides for the withholding of tax on such dispositions, except in the case of stock which is not regularly traded. Excepts such gain from the branch profits tax imposed on foreign corporations. Requires notice to the Secretary upon distributions by a U.S. person to a foreign person in redemption of stock or complete liquidation of a subsidiary. Removes the exemption of ten-percent shareholders from the tax on interest of nonresident alien individuals received from portfolio debt investments. Redefines portfolio interest as only interest paid on obligations issued by governmental entities. Provides special rules for determining the source of income from the sale of inventory property.</summary>
</bill>
