<bill session="106" type="h" number="4476" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dual Degree Achievement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize a program of assistance for partnerships between minority-serving institutions and other institutions of higher education that enable students attending minority-serving institutions to earn dual degrees and enter fields in which students from those institutions are underrepresented, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="2000-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2000-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="2000-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="2000-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="2000-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2000-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2000-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2000-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="2000-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority college graduates"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2000--Introduced.
Dual Degree Achievement Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a Dual Degree Achievement program of assistance for partnerships between minority-serving institutions (MSIs) and other institutions of higher education (IHEs) that enable students attending MSIs to earn dual degrees and enter fields in which students from MSIs are underrepresented.Directs the Secretary of Education to make five-year grants to eligible partnerships to carry out the program activities. Requires such partnerships to include one or more MSIs that award baccalaureate degrees and one or more partner IHEs that offer baccalaureate or post-baccalaureate degrees not awarded by the MSIs with which they are partnered. Allows such partnerships also to include other public and private entities, including MSIs (such as community colleges) that do not award baccalaureate degrees, community-based organizations, and businesses. Sets forth application requirements, including assurances that each participating student: (1) is enrolled in an academic program that leads to a five-year baccalaureate or post-baccalaureate degree not awarded by the MSI; and (2) upon successful completion of the program, will be awarded a baccalaureate degree from the MSI and a baccalaureate degree or a master's degree from the partner IHE that the student attends. Directs the Secretary to publish an annual list of baccalaureate and post-baccalaureate degree fields of study associated with professions in which students attending MSIs are underrepresented.Requires grants to be used for: (1) support services for participating students, including tutoring, mentoring, academic and personal counseling, and transition services; (2) scholarships to students in their fourth and fifth years in the program; (3) reimbursement to MSIs for the amount of tuition that they would have received had participating students attended those MSIs during their fourth year of the program instead of the partner IHE; and (4) academic program enhancements at the MSI that increase program quality and the number of student participants in the dual degree program. Requires that such scholarships: (1) reflect any additional amount of tuition and fees charged the participating student by the partner IHE compared to that charged by the MSI during the student's third year in the program; and (2) not be considered for the purposes of awarding Federal Pell Grants. Requires a majority of funds received under this program to be expended for such scholarships to students and such reimbursement to MSIs.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
