<bill session="106" type="h" number="1962" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Supercomputer Post-shipment Verification Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the export of high-performance computers to certain countries until certain applicable provisions of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998 are fulfilled.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400517" joined="1999-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Military technology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Supercomputers"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/1999--Introduced.
Supercomputer Post-shipment Verification Act of 1999 - Prohibits the export or reexport of digital computers with a composite theoretical performance of more than 2,000 MTOPS to a country that has been a recipient of such exports for which post-shipment verifications have not been made during the period beginning on November 18, 1997, and ending September 30, 1998. Prohibits the subsequent export or reexport of such computers to such country until all post-shipment verifications have been made. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to report annually to specified congressional committees on the results of post-shipment verifications during the previous fiscal year. Directs the Secretary of Defense to report to specified congressional committees on the impact on national security of the export of such computers to countries listed as "Computer Tier 3" eligible under section 740.7 of title 15 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</summary>
</bill>
