<bill session="107" type="h" number="5177" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Gila River Indian Community Judgment Fund Distribution Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the use and distribution of the funds awarded to the Gila River Pima-Maricopa Indian Community under United States Court of Federal claims Docket Nos. 236-C, 236-D, 236-N, and 228, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400173"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Estates (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2002--Introduced.
Gila River Indian Community Judgment Fund Distribution Act of 2002 - Requires the per capita distribution of funds paid in settlement of claims made in Docket Nos. 236-C and 236-D, Gila River Pima-Maricopa Indian Community V. Unite States, to enrolled members of the Gila River Indian Community.Requires the Community to prepare a payment role according to specified criteria.Directs the Secretary of the Interior to disburse funds within 30 days after Community approval of the payment roll. Makes special provision for deceased or legally incompetent individuals and minors.Permits payments of eligible individuals not on the roll out of residual funds and Community-owned funds, as specified.Revises the treatment of minors' per capita shares and final disbursement of judgment funds awarded in Dockets 228 and 236-N.Waives repayment of expert assistance loans to the Gila River Indian Community, the Oglala Sioux Tribe, and the Seminole Nation of Oklahoma, as specified.</summary>
</bill>
