<bill session="107" type="hj" number="110" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Liberation of the Iraqi People Resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Authorizing the use of United States Armed Forces against Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2002-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2002-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2002-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2002-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="2002-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2002-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="2002-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2002-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-09-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1636"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="hj" number="114"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arabs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control verification"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Economic stabilization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2002--Introduced.
Liberation of the Iraqi People Resolution - Condemns Saddam Hussein's ongoing efforts to repress the freedoms of the Iraqi people. Calls on the President to: (1) exhaust all peaceful and diplomatic avenues for disarming the threat to U.S. interests before using military force against Iraq; (2) obtain allied support for any preemptive strike against Iraq through a United Nations Security Council resolution; and (3) consider that a military invasion will not achieve the desired results in the absence of a post-invasion plan for ensuring the democracy, security, and stability of Iraq. Expresses concern for the well being of the Iraqi people.Authorizes the President to use U.S. armed forces to defend U.S. national security interests against the threat posed by Iraq only after: (1) certifying to Congress that Iraq is continuing to attempt to obtain conventional, chemical, biological and nuclear weapons and carry out ballistic missile programs, that Iraq poses an imminent threat to the United States or its interests, and that the United States has used all appropriate diplomatic and other peaceful means to obtain Iraq's compliance with Security Council resolutions and has sought a resolution expressing dissatisfaction with Iraq's noncompliance; and (2) transmitting to Congress a comprehensive plan of action that contains a commitment that the war on terrorism will remain the highest U.S. priority, a plan for stabilization in a free Iraq, a U.S. commitment to protect the safety of the Iraqi people and of U.S. allies and interests, and a plan for the continued stabilization of Afghanistan.Declares that this Act is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization for use of the armed forces, consistent with requirements of the War Powers Resolution.Requires the President to report to Congress every 60 days on the status of efforts authorized under this resolution.</summary>
</bill>
