<bill session="107" type="h" number="2760" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Advisory Voter Initiative Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that the voters of the United States be given the right, through advisory voter initiative, to propose the enactment and repeal of Federal laws in a national election.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400182"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional allowances"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2001--Introduced.
National Advisory Voter Initiative Act of 2001 - Gives the people in each State who have the qualifications requisite for electors of the most numerous branch of the State legislature the right to propose any law which the Congress has authority to pass and to propose the repeal of any provision of law passed by Congress which has become law.Outlines the procedure for the people to exercise such right through petition and State vote.Provides that if a law or repeal proposed under this Act receives a majority of the votes cast in 3/5 of the several States, the proposed law or repeal shall be introduced in the House of Representatives by the Speaker of the House and in the Senate by the President pro tempore on the first day of the first session of Congress following the vote.</summary>
</bill>
