<bill session="105" type="h" number="1815" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Privacy in the Age of New Technologies Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the privacy of health information in the age of genetic and other new technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1997-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1997-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1997-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1997-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1997-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1997-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-05">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-05">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health care fraud"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospital accreditation"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Individuals' Rights' Subtitle A: Review of Protected Health Information by Subjects of the Information Subtitle B: Establishment of Safeguards Title II: Restrictions on Use and Disclosure Title III: Sanctions Subtitle A: Civil Sanctions Subtitle B: Criminal Sanctions Title IV: Miscellaneous Medical Privacy in the Age of New Technologies Act of 1997 - Defines "health information trustee" (HIT) to mean a person or entity that creates, receives, obtains, maintains, uses, or transmits protected health information (PHI) and any employee, agent, or contractor of such a person. Title I: Individuals' Rights - Subtitle A: Review of Protected Health Information by Subjects of the Information - Requires a HIT to permit an individual who is the subject of PHI to inspect and copy the information, subject to cost reimbursement and exceptions. Subtitle B: Establishment of Safeguards - Requires a HIT to maintain: (1) administrative, technical, and physical confidentiality and accuracy safeguards; and (2) a record of any PHI disclosure not related to treatment. Prohibits HIT retaliation for actions under this Act. Title II: Restrictions on Use and Disclosure - Prohibits disclosures except: (1) as allowed under this title; (2) as compatible with the purposes for which the information was obtained or for the specific purpose for which an individual authorized disclosure; and (3) in the minimum amount necessary to accomplish the disclosure's purpose. (Sec. 202) Regulates disclosure authorizations, the disclosure of nonidentifiable information, and the creation of coded information. (Sec. 205) Specifies the criteria for disclosure: (1) to an individual's next of kin; (2) regarding directory information to any person; (3) in emergencies placing the information subject or another individual at serious risk; (4) to a health oversight agency; (5) to an accrediting body; (6) by a health care provider to a public health authority; (7) by a HIT to a health researcher; (8) by specified entities in connection with certain judicial and administrative proceedings; (9) by specified entities pursuant to a subpoena; and (10) by specified entities regarding subpoenas and warrants. Title III: Sanctions - Subtitle A: Civil Sanctions - Imposes a civil penalty for material failure to comply with this Act. Provides, if the violations have occurred with such frequency as to constitute a general business practice, for a higher civil penalty or exclusion from Medicare and Medicaid (titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act) or any other federally funded health care programs. (Sec. 302) Allows an individual aggrieved by a violation of this Act to bring a civil action for preliminary and equitable relief, actual or liquidated damages, and punitive damages. Allows assessment of attorney's fees. Subtitle B: Criminal Sanctions - Provides for criminal fines, imprisonment, or exclusion from Medicare, Medicaid, or any other Federally funded health care program (or some combination of those penalties) for violations of this Act or this title. Title IV: Miscellaneous - Provides for: (1) the promulgation of regulations (and establishment of a related advisory group); and (2) the relationship of this Act to other laws.</summary>
</bill>
