<bill session="106" type="h" number="4250" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Predatory Lending Consumer Protection Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Home Ownership and Equity Protection Act of 1994 and other sections of the Truth in Lending Act to protect consumers against predatory practices in connection with high cost mortgage transactions, to strengthen the civil remedies available to consumers under existing law, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="2000-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2000-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2000-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-04-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E541"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2405"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2415"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Credit insurance"/>
    <term name="Credit life insurance"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Mortgage interest rates"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2000--Introduced.
Predatory Lending Consumer Protection Act of 2000 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act guidelines governing certain credit transactions secured by the consumer's principal dwelling (high-cost mortgage), including: (1) the annual percentage rate of interest that shall be taken into account; (2) total points and fees incumbent upon the consumer at closing; and (3) the criteria defining a high-cost mortgage lender as creditor.(Sec. 3) Requires additional disclosures to the consumer that the consumer is contracting to pay a much higher loan than most people pay. Sets forth additional proscriptions against prepayment penalties. Prohibits all balloon payments (currently restricted to mortgages with a term of less than five years).Requires a creditor to make a case-by-case assessment of a consumer debtor's ability to pay that is based upon financial resources without taking into account equity in the dwelling which is the security for the credit.Subjects an assignee or holder of a high-cost mortgage which was made, arranged, or assigned by persons financing consumer home improvements to all the affirmative claims and defenses which the consumer may have against specified parties regarding such mortgage or home improvements.States that consummation of a high-cost mortgage that is not in compliance with this Act shall be treated as a failure to deliver requisite material disclosures.(Sec. 4) Prohibits the terms of a high-cost mortgage from including advance collection of a premium on a single premium basis for specified credit insurance products.Restricts the amount of points and fees which a creditor may finance in connection with a high-cost mortgage. Prohibits certain creditors from financing the prepayment fees or penalties due from the consumer.Prohibits a high-cost mortgage creditor from: (1) accelerating the debt in its sole discretion; (2) taking actions that encourage debtor's default; (3) charging a fee for mortgage modification or payment deferral unless such actions bestow a material benefit upon the consumer; (4) extending mortgage credit unless specified warnings have been furnished, including the availability of home ownership credit counseling services; and (5) requiring mandatory arbitration or any other nonjudicial procedure as a method for resolving any controversy or claims arising from the transaction.(Sec. 5) Declares that a consumer's waiver of the right of rescission shall not be effective if the creditor either advised or encouraged such waiver, or required it as a precondition for a transaction.(Sec. 6) Increases: (1) civil money penalties for creditor violations; and (2) the statute of limitations from one to three years for violations of this Act.(Sec. 7) Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to mandate that each high-cost mortgage creditor (including the successor creditor) report the debtor's complete payment history to certain consumer reporting agencies in accordance with regulations or guidelines established by participants in the secondary mortgage market.(Sec. 8) Instructs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to publish implementing regulations.</summary>
</bill>
