<bill session="107" type="h" number="5561" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for and approve settlement of certain land claims of the Wyandotte Nation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400282"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2002-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1781-1782"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2081"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian gambling operations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2002--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of the Interior to take specified Settlement Lands into trust for the benefit of the Wyandotte Nation as part of the settlement of claims in a certain lawsuit of the Wyandotte Nation against the United Government of Kansas City and Wyandotte County, Kansas, if there are no adverse legal claims on the Settlement Lands. Declares this action a mandatory trust acquisition.Declares transfers of land or natural resources within the Settlement Lands made before the enactment of this Act to be valid. Extinguishes any aboriginal title held by any Indian, Indian nation, or tribe or band of Indians on Settlement Lands. Conditions the transfer of the Settlement Lands to the Secretary in trust as part of this claims settlement upon the Secretary's receipt of a duly enacted resolution of the elected tribal council or business committee of the Wyandotte Nation agreeing to the extinguishment of all claims against the United States, the Unified Government, or any person or entity.Declares that if the State of Kansas and the Wyandotte Nation have not entered into a tribal-State compact under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act within 90 days, the Secretary shall prescribe gaming procedures on the Settlement Lands.</summary>
</bill>
