<bill session="108" type="h" number="1527" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-15T13:49:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-05-15T13:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Transportation Safety Board Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Transportation Safety Board Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Transportation Safety Board Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize appropriations for the National Transportation Safety Board for fiscal years 2003 through 2006, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2003-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2003-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2003-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-04-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 108-83.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-05-01T16:19:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="47">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 47.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-05-13T19:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 229 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1527 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 229 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 229.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4157-4168" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4160, H4162" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1527 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 229 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lee Terry to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1527.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Udall (CO) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T13:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica reserved a point of order on the amendment and subsequently withdrew his reservation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cardin appealed the ruling of the Chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T13:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On sustaining the ruling of the Chair. Agreed to by recorded vote: 225 - 200 (Roll no. 191).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T13:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica reserved a point of order on the amendment and subsequently withdrew his reservation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T13:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1527.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-05-15T13:49:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="229"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="579"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="National Transportation Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Truck drivers"/>
    <term name="Victims"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h132"/>
    <amendment number="h133"/>
    <amendment number="h134"/>
    <amendment number="h135"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/15/2003--Passed House amended.
National Transportation Safety Board Reauthorization Act of 2003 - (Sec. 2) Amends Federal transportation law to extend the authorization of appropriations for the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB), including the NTSB Academy, for FY 2003 through 2006.Authorizes such appropriations as may be necessary to increase the emergency fund from $2 million to $6 million.(Sec. 3) Requires an NTSB employee, in any case in which the employee determines that an occurrence associated with the operation of an aircraft constitutes an accident (except when there is loss of life), to notify the owner or operator of that aircraft of the right to appeal that determination to the NTSB.(Sec. 4) Revises requirements for the Secretary of Transportation's annual report to Congress on each transportation safety recommendation of the NTSB and the Secretary's response. Requires the Secretary to report annually to Congress and the NTSB on the regulatory status of each significant NTSB safety recommendation. Requires the NTSB to report to Congress any failure of the Secretary to make such a report.Defines the term "significant safety recommendation" as a recommendation included in the Board's "most wanted list" and any recommendation concerning 15-passenger van safety, railroad grade crossing safety, and medical certifications for a commercial driver's license.(Sec. 5) Relieves the NTSB of the duty to render specified assistance to families of passengers involved in an aircraft accident if the NTSB has relinquished its investigative priority to investigate it and the Federal agency to which it has relinquished such priority is willing and able to provide assistance to the victims and families of the passengers. Requires the NTSB, however, even if it has relinquished such priority, to assist, to the maximum extent possible, the agency to which it has relinquished it in assisting families with respect to the accident.Directs the NTSB and the Federal Bureau of Investigation to revise their 1977 agreement on the investigation of accidents to take into account the amendments made by this Act, and to submit such revision to specified congressional committees.</summary>
</bill>
