<bill session="104" type="h" number="1470" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financing Corporation and Savings Association Insurance Fund Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for sufficient funding to cover the costs of the Financing Corporation, to provide funds to carry out the purposes of the Savings Association Insurance Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E855-856"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Financing Corporation"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Resolution Trust Corporation"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/1995--Introduced.
Financing Corporation and Savings Association Insurance Fund Reform Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Home Loan Bank Act to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer into a trust fund managed by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) certain funds appropriated (but not yet paid) to the Resolution Trust Corporation (RTC). Instructs the FDIC Board of Directors to invest trust fund proceeds not required to meet the short-term requirements of either the RTC or the Savings Association Insurance Fund (SAIF). Mandates that: (1) the interest earned on such trust fund investments be paid to meet the obligations of the Financing Corporation; (2) the balance in such trust fund be made available to cover actual or anticipated SAIF losses until its reserve ratio meets or exceeds the applicable designated reserve ratio; (3) the trust fund be abolished and any remaining balance returned to the Treasury after the Financing Corporation has repaid certain obligations; and (4) the assessments paid by SAIF members to the Financing Corporation be treated as insurance outlays for purposes of Federal law. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (FDIA) to authorize the FDIC to impose a one-time special SAIF capitalization assessment on each SAIF member. Amends the FDIA to repeal the minimum assessments requirements for any deposit insurance fund risk-based assessment system. Limits the average assessment rate differential between former Bank Insurance Fund and SAIF members to a maximum of nine basis points.</summary>
</bill>
