<bill session="104" type="h" number="1105" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Credit and Charge Card Disclosure and Interest Rate Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to require additional disclosures with respect to credit card accounts, to require a study of the competitiveness of the credit card industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services. subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Finance charges"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/1995--Introduced.
Credit and Charge Card Disclosure and Interest Rate Amendments Act of 1995 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act of 1989 to expand the disclosure requirements for credit card accounts including: (1) the total amounts paid; (2) the total finance charges paid; and (3) the date by which the debtor will complete paying the current outstanding balance. Requires the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to establish and publicize a toll-free telephone line for consumers to call for free information on low-rate credit cards. Requires due notice to the cardholder before any increase in the annual percentage rate or any change in credit card terms may take effect. Permits the cardholder to subsequently: (1) rescind the use of the account upon receipt of such notice; and (2) repay the outstanding balance pursuant to the rate and terms in effect on the date that the cardholder received notification of the change in terms. Prohibits: (1) the imposition of finance charges upon certain credit card accounts before the date that the extension of credit is posted to that account; and (2) the disclosure of certain cardholder information for direct marketing purposes unless the issuer has notified the cardholder. Requires the Comptroller General to study and report to the Congress on the degree of competition in the credit card market. Mandates an annual statement to the cardholder disclosing the total amount of fees and finance charges paid in the preceding year. Requires a card issuer to provide, upon request, a copy of the agreement establishing the terms of the credit card account.</summary>
</bill>
