<bill session="104" type="h" number="3044" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Parks and Refuges Small Business Fairness Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to provide disaster assistance loans for small businesses that operate within a unit of the National Park System or the National Wildlife Refuge System, and have suffered substantial economic injury as a result of a partial shutdown of the Federal Government during the period beginning December 15, 1995, and ending January 5, 1996.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/1996--Introduced.
Parks and Refuges Small Business Fairness Act of 1996 - Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the provision of disaster assistance loans under such Act to assist any small business that: (1) has a concessions contract or incidental business license to operate within a unit of the National Park System or Wildlife Refuge System; and (2) has suffered substantial economic injury as a result of a partial Federal Government shutdown during the period beginning December 15, 1995, and ending January 5, 1996. Prohibits such loans if the applicant can obtain credit elsewhere. Limits each loan to $100,000. Authorizes the Small Business Administration to permit deferral of principal and interest payments on such loans for a one-year period. Prohibits the loan interest rate from exceeding four percent.</summary>
</bill>
