<bill session="106" type="h" number="2563" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Woodrow Wilson Bridge Financing Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Authority Act of 1995 to provide an authorization of contract authority for fiscal years 2004 through 2007, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400569" joined="1999-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1999-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1999-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1999-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1999-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1999-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Ground Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW10" subcommittee="Ground Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/1999--Introduced.
Woodrow Wilson Bridge Financing Act of 1999 - Amends the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Authority Act of 1995 to authorize appropriations for FY 2004 through 2007 to the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) to pay the costs of the project for upgrading the Interstate Route 95 Potomac River crossing, which includes the rehabilitation of the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge. (Under current law, priority is given to costs associated with the Bridge, other than design costs.)Limits the total amount made available from the Highway Trust Fund for the Federal contribution to $1.5 billion and requires amounts from the Fund for the project in excess of such amount to be provided by the Capital Region jurisdictions (jurisdictions).Requires, for FY 2004 through 2007, that every one dollar provided from the Fund be matched by at least 67 cents provided by such jurisdictions. Requires such jurisdictions to allocate payment of the matching funds as they determine to be appropriate.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to make Fund amounts available for U.S. obligations incurred pursuant to such Act.</summary>
</bill>
