<bill session="105" type="h" number="1447" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Housing Management Reform Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform the United States Housing Act of 1937, deregulate the public housing program and the program for rental housing assistance for low-income families, and increase community control over such programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1997-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="784"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism treatment"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug addicts"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment subsidies"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Eviction"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Households"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Housing codes"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing management"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Public service employment"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in social service"/>
    <term name="Welfare work participation"/>
    <term name="Welfare-to-work"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Public Housing and Rent Reforms Title II: Section 8 Streamlining and Other Program Improvements Title III: "One Strike And You're Out" Occupancy Provisions Public Housing Management Reform Act of 1997 - Title I: Public Housing And Rent Reforms - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to establish public housing Operating and Capital Funds. (Sec. 101) Revises specified public housing and section 8 rent provisions. (Sec. 104) Exempts (for 18 months with a subsequent three-year phase-in) earned income from a previously unemployed family member from public housing and section 8 rent and family contribution determinations. (Sec. 105) Authorizes a public housing agency (PHA) project sale to an organization acting as a tenant conduit under specified conditions. (Sec. 106) Sets forth PHA plan contents. (Sec. 107) Sets forth performance indicators for PHAs with fewer than 250 units (small PHAs). (Sec. 109) Revises provisions regarding defaulting and troubled PHAs. (Sec. 111) Establishes community service requirements for public and section 8 housing. (Sec. 112) Revises small PHA modernization plan requirements. Eliminates specified preference provisions. Increases PHA set-asides for disaster and emergency assistance. (Sec. 113) Increases permitted PHA fund uses. Authorizes mixed-finance development (public and non-public housing units). (Sec. 114) Revises public housing demolition and disposition provisions, including operating fund and comprehensive grant amounts. Eliminates the one-for-one replacement requirement. (Sec. 116) Revises the severely distressed public housing assistance program. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 117) Establishes a PHA performance evaluation board. (Sec. 118) Directs the Secretary to make grants for public housing tenant economic development and supportive services. (Sec. 120) Provides that a PHA not providing acceptable basic housing conditions shall be designated as a troubled PHA. (Sec. 121) Revises volunteer provisions to exempt from contract wage requirements volunteers performing services in accordance with the Community Improvement Volunteer Act of 1994. (Makes related amendments to such Act.) (Sec. 122) Authorizes specified appropriations for the Operation Safe Home program. Title II: Section 8 Streamlining And Other Program Improvements - Makes certain public housing preferences under The Balanced Budget Downpayment Act, I, permanent. Amends the Act, as amended by such Act, to base specified public and section 8 housing tenant selection criteria upon local conditions rather than upon the comprehensive housing affordability strategy under the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act. (Sec. 202) Amends the Act to revise public and section 8 housing income-based eligibility and occupancy provisions. (Sec. 203) Provides for section 8 rental payment standards which shall neither exceed nor be less than 80 percent of the "fair market rent-exception rent limit" (as defined by this Act). (Sec. 204) Amends the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997 to increase specified section 8 administrative fees. (Sec. 205) Amends the section 8 home ownership option, including provision for cooperative eligibility. Eliminates the family self-sufficiency escrow. (Sec. 206) Authorizes a welfare to work (housing) certificate demonstration program to assist families in welfare to work transition. (Sec. 207) Prohibits a family in public or section 8 housing from receiving a rental reduction based upon lowered income resulting from failure to comply with certain public assistance self-sufficiency or work requirements. (Sec. 209) Amends the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code with respect to certain income verification provisions. (Sec. 210) Provides for: (1) nondiscrimination against section 8 voucher and certificate holders; and (2) recapture of certain PHA excess reserve funds. (Sec. 212) Amends the Public and Assisted Housing Drug Elimination Act of 1990 to: (1) expand coverage to include other than drug-related crimes; (2) establish formula funding; and (3) authorize appropriations and revise set-aside provisions. Title III: "One Strike And You're Out" Occupancy Provisions - Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) public housing ineligibility, or tenancy or assistance termination, based upon prior drug activity or serious lease violations, or current drug or alcohol abuse; (2) related lease requirements; and (3) availability of criminal records for tenant screening and eviction.</summary>
</bill>
