<bill session="108" type="h" number="3854" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Prescription Drug Cost Containment Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To contain the costs of the Medicare prescription drug program under part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400016" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2004-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2004-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2004-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400131" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2004-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400287" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2004-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2004-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-02-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-26">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-26">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="2130"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/2004--Introduced.
Medicare Prescription Drug Cost Containment Act of 2004 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, on the same date on which the President submits a budget to Congress, to submit to Congress a determination as to whether there is projected to be excess general revenue Medicare prescription drug funding for the fiscal year for which the budget is submitted, and if there is an affirmative determination it shall be treated as a Medicare part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) funding warning in the fiscal year beginning on October 1 of the year in which the determination is submitted to Congress. Amends Federal money and finance law, as amended by the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, to direct the President to submit to Congress proposed legislation to respond to such a Medicare part D funding warning made in a year within the 15-day period beginning on the date of the budget submission to Congress for the succeeding year. Provides that such amendment shall not apply if, during the year in which the warning is made, legislation is enacted which eliminates excess general revenue Medicare funding for the period beginning with the fiscal year for which the determination is made and ending on September 30, 2013, as certified by the Board of Trustees of the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund not later than 30 days after the enactment of such legislation. Expresses the sense of Congress that legislation submitted pursuant to such amendment in a year should be designed to eliminate excess general revenue Medicare funding for the period that begins with the fiscal year for which the determination is made and ends on September 30, 2013. Sets out the special procedures for House and Senate consideration of the President's legislative proposal in response to such warning.</summary>
</bill>
