<bill session="108" type="h" number="2143" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-10T19:05:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-10T19:05:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Internet Gambling Prohibition bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Unlawful Internet Gambling Funding Prohibition Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Unlawful Internet Gambling Funding Prohibition Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Unlawful Internet Gambling Funding Prohibition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent the use of certain bank instruments for unlawful Internet gambling, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="2003-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-05-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-02T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 108-133, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-02T16:39:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="68">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 68.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-03T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Financial Services, H. Rept. 108-133, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09T19:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 263 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2143 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate, the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T16:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 263 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T16:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 263.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5136-5153" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5145-5146" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T16:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2143 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate, the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. Makes in order only those amendments printed in House Report 108-145. Provides that the amendments may be considered only in the order printed, offered only by a Member designated in the report, considered as read, debatable for the time specified, equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, not be subject to amendment, and not be subject to a demand for a division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole. Waives all points of order against the amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 263 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lee Terry to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2143.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T17:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 263 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kelly amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 263 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson-Lee, (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson-Lee, (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Subsequently, Ms. Jackson-Lee asked unanimous consent to withdraw her request for a recorded vote. Without objection her request is agreed to and the Chair announced that the amendment failed by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 263, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with twenty minutes of debate on the Sensenbrenner amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T18:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2143.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T18:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-06-10T19:05:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="255" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 319 - 104 (Roll no. 255).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T19:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2143.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="263"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="21"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="627"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="International banking"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h157"/>
    <amendment number="h158"/>
    <amendment number="h159"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/10/2003--Passed House amended.
Unlawful Internet Gambling Funding Prohibition Act - Directs Federal functional regulators, within six months of this Act's enactment, to prescribe regulations requiring any designated payment system to establish policies and procedures reasonably designed to: (1) identify restricted transactions by means of code in authorization messages or other means and to block such transactions; and (2) prevent the acceptance of the products or services of the payment system in connection with a restricted transaction. Defines a "restricted transaction" as any transaction or transmittal to anyone engaged in the business of betting or wagering in connection with another person's participation in unlawful Internet gambling of credit, electronic fund transfers, checks, or the proceeds of any other form of financial transaction as regulators may prescribe. Requires such regulators and the Federal Trade Commission to enforce such regulations (under applicable law in the manner provided under the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act) after considering specified factors concerning the extent of the violation, the history of compliance, and the feasibility and burden of implementing a remedy. Requires regulators to consider exempting restricted transactions if the regulators find that it is not reasonably practical to identify and block, or otherwise prevent, such transactions.Provides that no provision of this Act shall be construed as affecting any law relating to, affecting, or regulating gambling within the United States.</summary>
</bill>
