<bill session="106" type="h" number="5292" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Flexible Funding for Child Protection Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase State flexibility in funding child protection programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400205"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Flexible Funding Demonstrations Title II: Waivers Modification Flexible Funding for Child Protection Act of 2000 - Title I: Flexible Funding Demonstrations - Amends title XI of the Social Security Act (SSA) to replace provisions on the effect of failure to carry out a State plan with provisions on demonstrations of flexible funding. Authorizes a State to apply to conduct a demonstration project with respect to one or more categories of foster care or adoption expenditures, in order to determine whether providing States with flexible funding for child protection: (1) has an effect on caseload levels; and (2) enhances availability and use of services, efficiency of service delivery, and child safety, permanency, and well-being. Makes necessary appropriations.Title II: Waivers Modification - Amends SSA title XI with regard to demonstration projects that the Secretary finds likely to promote the objectives of part B (Child-Welfare Services) or E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of SSA title IV. Eliminates the limitation on the number of such projects for FY 1998 through 2002. Prohibits the Secretary of Health and Human Services from refusing to grant a waiver to a State on the grounds that a purpose of the waiver or of the demonstration project for which the waiver is necessary would be the same as or similar to a purpose of another waiver or project that is or may be conducted under such demonstration projects.Prohibits the Secretary from imposing any limit on the number of waivers that may be granted to a State, or the number of demonstration projects that a State may be authorized to conduct under such demonstration projects.Requires the Secretary to develop a streamlined process for consideration of amendments proposed by States to demonstration projects.Urges the Secretary to consider use of historical baselines of foster care utilization, designs involving random assignment, or designs involving comparison groups under cost neutrality provisions.</summary>
</bill>
