<bill session="106" type="h" number="2718" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Brownfields Remediation Waste Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to provide for the management of remediation waste at Brownfields and other remediation sites.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400307"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1999-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1768-1769"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Brownfields"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
Brownfields Remediation Waste Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act (the Act) to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide alternative requirements for management of remediation waste in lieu of restrictions under the Act or this Act. Defines "remediation waste" as all solid and hazardous wastes and all media and debris that contain listed hazardous wastes or that themselves exhibit a hazardous characteristic and are managed for implementing cleanup. Provides that such requirements shall be protective of health and the environment and remove disincentives to remediation, streamline regulation, and achieve greater flexibility for State remediation programs. Deems specified rules regarding hazardous remediation waste management promulgated by the Administrator on November 30, 1998, to be alternative requirements and to remain in effect unless the Administrator takes action to modify such rules. Prohibits the Administrator from publishing any proposal to modify such rules before reporting to Congress on problems associated with their implementation. Provides that placement of remediation waste in temporary units, staging piles, or corrective action management units designated under Federal or State authorities shall not be deemed to be engaging in land disposal and shall not be subject to specified requirements under the Act regarding hazardous waste management. Authorizes, notwithstanding the rules of November 30, 1998, and where protective of health and environment, the designation of: (1) temporary units and staging piles at another location owned or operated by a person engaged in remediation at the first location to facilitate consolidated waste management; (2) corrective action management units at one remediation waste management site to receive remediation waste from another such site; and (3) a staging pile to allow for mixing or blending for the primary purposes of subsequent waste consolidation or enhancement. Allows remediation waste management units or activities to be authorized through permits, interim status, orders, or other authorization available under the Act. Permits States to administer and enforce remediation waste management programs pursuant to programs authorized under the Act or this Act. Sets forth required elements of such programs. Authorizes States with approved programs to carry out such programs in lieu of the Federal program.</summary>
</bill>
