<bill session="105" type="h" number="356" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Health Access District Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve health status in medically disadvantaged communities through comprehensive community-based managed care programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicaid managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Comprehensive Health Access District Act - Defines: (1) "comprehensive health access district" as a community in which unemployment and the percentage of residents with incomes below the poverty line are greater than the national average, and in which a majority of certain diseases and conditions occur at rates greater than the national average; and (2) "comprehensive community-based health access plan" as an entity that provides health care services on a prepaid, capitated basis, or any other risk basis, and that the Secretary of Health and Human Services has certified meets certain requirements. (Sec. 3) Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require, among other things, that each Medicaid State plan provide that each comprehensive health access district located within the State is served by a comprehensive community-based health access district plan. (Sec. 4) Requires each Health Alliance or other health insurance purchasing cooperative created out of comprehensive health care reform legislation that receives premiums on behalf of persons formerly insured under Medicaid, and whose boundaries encompass a comprehensive health access district, to ensure that at least one comprehensive community-based health access plan is available to persons living in such district. (Sec. 5) Sets forth specified requirements for an entity to be certified as a comprehensive community-based health access plan. (Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary to designate a community a comprehensive health access district and to certify an entity as a comprehensive health access plan provided they meet certain criteria. (Sec. 7) Requires each health access plan, in order to evaluate its performance in improving the health status of persons living in comprehensive health access districts, to provide the Secretary with specified health-related information.</summary>
</bill>
