<bill session="104" type="h" number="4043" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve in the State of Kansas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300083"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grassland ecology"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/1996--Introduced.
Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve Act of 1996 - Establishes the Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve to provide for the preservation, restoration, and interpretation of the Spring Hill Ranch area of the Flint Hills of Kansas. Specifies that the Preserve shall be a unit of the National Park System, including for purposes of charging entrance and admission fees. Sets forth provisions regarding liability of the United States and of landowners. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to expend Federal funds for the cooperative management of private property within the Preserve for research, resource management, and visitor protection and use. Requires the Secretary to: (1) prepare and submit to specified congressional committees a general management plan; and (2) acquire, by donation, not more than 180 acres of real property within the boundaries of the Preserve and the improvements on such property. Sets forth provisions regarding payments to local governments in lieu of taxes for such real property. Prohibits: (1) such property from being acquired without the owner's consent; and (2) U.S. acquisition of fee ownership of any lands within the Preserve other than these lands. Establishes the Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve Advisory Committee. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
