<bill session="104" type="h" number="452" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938, as amended.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400611"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="1996-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1995-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1995-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1995-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1995-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1996-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1995-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1995-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1995-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1996-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1995-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1995-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1996-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E80-81"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International propaganda"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Political consultants"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/9/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to replace references to: (1) "agent" with "representative"; and (2) "propaganda" with "promotional or informational materials." Includes within the definition of "representative of a foreign principal" any person who engages in political activities to further commercial, industrial, or financial operations with a foreign principal. Excludes from such definition any incorporated, nonprofit membership organization organized under U.S. laws that is registered under the Federal Regulation of Lobbying Act, that has obtained tax-exempt status, and whose activities are directed in whole by U.S. citizens. Provides that a foreign principal shall be considered to control a person in major part if: (1) such principal holds more than 50 percent equitable ownership in such person; or (2) subject to rebuttal evidence, such principal holds from 20 to 50 percent equitable ownership in such person. Includes within the definition of "political consultant" any person who distributes political promotional or informational materials to a Federal officer or employee, in his or her capacity as an officer or employee. Requires representatives of foreign principals who have filed registration statements to file supplements to such statements with the Attorney General on January 31 and July 31 of each year. Authorizes representatives with accounting systems using different fiscal years to petition the Attorney General to permit the filing of statements at the close of the first and seventh month of such fiscal year in lieu of the required dates. Repeals an exemption to registration requirements for persons representing foreign governments whose defense is deemed vital to the defense of the United States. Provides that the exemption from the registration requirement for individuals providing legal representation for a foreign principal before a U.S. agency shall apply only to representation before the Patent and Trademark Office. Provides for civil penalties for failures to file registration statements and for omitting material facts or making false statements on registration statements. Authorizes the Attorney General to serve civil investigative demands on persons in control of materials relevant to investigations concerning violations of registration requirements. Redesignates the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 as the Foreign Interests Representation Act.</summary>
</bill>
