<bill session="106" type="h" number="3458" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Abuse Prevention and Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Jennifer's Law</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce the incidence of child abuse and neglect, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400327"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Crime and the press"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="DNA fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Missing children"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="X-rays"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: The Child Abuse Prevention and Enforcement Act Title II: Jennifer's Law Child Abuse Prevention and Enforcement Act - Title I: The Child Abuse Prevention and Enforcement Act - Child Abuse Prevention and Enforcement Act - Amends the Crime Identification Technology Act of 1998 to authorize the use of State grants for programs that establish or enhance the capability of the criminal justice system to deliver criminal history record information to child welfare entities engaged in risk assessment and other activities pertaining to child protection (including protection against child abuse) and foster care placement.Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the use of funds under the drug control and system improvement (Byrne) grant program for: (1) enforcement of child abuse and neglect laws, including protection against child sexual abuse; and (2) cooperative information sharing programs between law enforcement and media organizations pertaining to the identification and apprehension of suspected criminal offenders.Amends the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 to increase the amount of funds in the Crime Victims Fund for child abuse prevention and treatment grants in specified circumstances.Title II: Jennifer's Law - Jennifer' s Law - Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to enable States to improve the reporting of unidentified and missing persons. Authorizes the use of such grant awards to establish or expand programs developed to improve the reporting of unidentified persons. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
