<bill session="104" type="h" number="792" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Domestic Investment Economic Growth Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for investments in tax enterprise zone businesses and domestic businesses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/1995--Introduced.
Domestic Investment Economic Growth Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income gain on qualified investments in an enterprise zone business and a domestic business. Excludes 100 percent of such gain from investment in an enterprise zone business or an urban enterprise zone, and 50 percent of such gain from other qualified investments. Provides for the establishment of investment savings accounts. Allows an individual a deduction of 50 percent of the qualified contributions to an investment savings account. Limits the maximum annual deduction to $100,000. Defines qualified contributions. Defines an investment savings account. Provides that any amount distributed out of such an account shall be included in the gross income of the distributee, except for amounts held in the account for at least ten years. Makes such accounts tax-exempt, except for the imposition of the tax on unrelated business income of charitable, etc., organizations. Imposes, in the case of a distribution from an investment savings account, an additional tax of ten percent of the amount of the distribution which is includible in the gross income of the distributee. Makes such tax inapplicable to distributions held in such accounts for at least five years if such distributions were made for: (1) home purchase expenses; (2) automobile purchase expenses; (3) education expenses; and (4) medical expenses. Makes such tax inapplicable if the distribution is made after the individual for whose benefit the account is established attains age 59 and one-half years or becomes disabled. Allows the deduction for contributions to investment savings accounts in computing adjusted gross income. Declares that such contributions are not subject to the gift tax. Subjects such accounts to the tax on excess contributions, the tax on prohibited transactions, and the penalty for failure to provide reports on individual retirement accounts or annuities. Imposes a penalty on any person who promotes a nonqualified investment as eligible under the provisions of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
