<bill session="106" type="h" number="4117" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Collegiate Athletics Due Process Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide collegiate student-athletes who attend NCAA-member institutions the same rights and privileges afforded to all citizens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2000-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="2000-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2000-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2000-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2000-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2000-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="College sports"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational associations"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Grievance arbitration"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Students' rights"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2000--Introduced.
Collegiate Athletics Due Process Act of 2000 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to oblige institutions of higher education, under student aid program participation agreements, to ensure that student-athletes' due process rights are respected if they are accused of violations or infractions of amateur sports rules, including rules and legislation of the National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA).Requires the institution to provide any such accused student- athlete with separate independent legal counsel at the institution's expense immediately upon any investigation or alleged violation or infraction, and through the entire investigation, until all matters and facts of the pending case (and any other investigations that may arise out of the initial investigation) have concluded to the satisfaction of all parties involved.Requires the accused student-athlete to be given: (1) notice and opportunity to be heard before an arbitrator, neutral party, or tribunal not associated with the NCAA or a member institution, before any enforcement actions are administered by the institution; and (2) at all hearings, the opportunity to be heard and the right of controverting every material fact bearing on individual or private rights involved.Requires any enforcement action taken by the institution in compliance with rules or legislation of the NCAA for amateur sports violations to be clearly established on the basis of specific standards and guidelines for all possible infractions, including punishment or restitution.Makes this Act inapplicable to disciplinary actions taken by a coach or college administrator for violations of the institution's policy or conduct rules that apply to the entire student body of the institution.</summary>
</bill>
