<bill session="108" type="h" number="2555" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-10-01">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Homeland Security Appropriations, FY 2004 bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2004</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2004</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2004</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2004</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2004</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2004, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400340"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-23T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 108-169, by Mr. Rogers (KY).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-06-23T15:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="84">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 84.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-23T21:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 293 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2555 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The bill shall be read for amendment by paragraph. Waives points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with sec. 501 of H. Con. Res. 95, (prohibiting advanced appropriations) and clause 2 of rule XXI (prohibiting unauthorized appropriations or legislative provisions in an appropriations bill), except as specified in the resolution. Bill is open to amendments. Authorizes the Chair to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 293 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T13:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 293.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5744-5795" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5754, H5756" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5757, H5759, H5761, H5764" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5769, H5770-5771" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5771-5772" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5772-5773, H5775" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T13:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2555 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The bill shall be read for amendment by paragraph. Waives points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with sec. 501 of H. Con. Res. 95, (prohibiting advanced appropriations) and clause 2 of rule XXI (prohibiting unauthorized appropriations or legislative provisions in an appropriations bill), except as specified in the resolution. Bill is open to amendments. Authorizes the Chair to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T13:32:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 293 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T13:32:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Paul E. Gillmor to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T13:33:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2555.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Filner amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T15:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Filner amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Filner demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 293, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T15:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with discussion on the Obey amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey appealed the ruling of the Chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>On sustaining the ruling of the Chair. Agreed to by recorded vote: 222 - 200 (Roll no. 305).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T15:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the LoBiondo amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T15:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Terry amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Maloney amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Brady (TX) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Mica stated that section 514 of the bill proposed to change existing law and constituted legislation in an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T17:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Mica stated that section 521 of the bill sought to change existing law and constituted legislation in an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Mica stated that section 522 of the bill proposed to change existing law and constituted legislation in appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T17:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hayes amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T17:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Markey amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T18:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Markey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 293, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Manzullo amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T18:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Filner appealed the ruling of the Chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T18:57:00-04:00">
      <text>On sustaining the ruling of the Chair. Agreed to by recorded vote: 385 - 28 (Roll no. 306).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson-Lee, (TX) amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Baldwin amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T19:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Waters amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T19:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Tancredo amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T19:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jakcson-Lee amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T20:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Tancredo amendment under the five minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T21:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2555.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T21:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T21:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-06-24T21:39:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="310" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 425 - 2 (Roll no. 310).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T21:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-07-10">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported by Senator Cochran with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-86.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-07-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="192">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 192.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Homeland Security. Approved for full committee consideration with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9623-9626, S9628-9629" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9672-9697" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR S9672-9680" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22">
      <text>The committee substitute agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-23">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9748-9788" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9830-9887" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2003-07-24" how="roll" result="pass" roll="306" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 93 - 1. Record Vote Number: 306.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR 7/25/2003 S9980-9986" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Cochran; Stevens; Specter; Domenici; McConnell; Shelby; Gregg; Campbell; Craig; Byrd; Inouye; Hollings; Leahy; Harkin; Mikulski; Kohl; Murray.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (KY) asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8107-8111" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T12:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sabo moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8107" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8107" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T12:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Sabo motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the managers on the part of the House to insist on inclusion of the highest possible level of funding for each Homeland Security, preparedness and disaster response program within Title II, III and IV and on inclusion of House General Provision 521.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on the Sabo motion to instruct, the Chair put the question on the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sabo requested the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of the motion until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 347 - 74 (Roll no. 494).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8117-8118" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Rogers (KY), Young (FL), Wolf, Wamp, Latham, Emerson, Granger, Sweeney, Sherwood, Sabo, Price (NC), Serrano, Roybal-Allard, Berry, Mollohan, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-17">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23T15:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 108-280 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8425-8459" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23T20:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 374 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2555. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T11:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 374 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T11:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (KY) brought up conference report H. Rept. 108-280 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 374.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8793-8802" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T11:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 374 the House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 2555.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T12:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T12:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sabo moved to recommit with instructions to the conference committee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8801-8802" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8801" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T12:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions to conference committee was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T13:10:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions to conference committee Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 198 - 226 (Roll no. 514).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T13:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T13:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="2003-09-24T13:17:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="515" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 417 - 8 (Roll no. 515).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11891-11897" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2003-09-24" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2003-09-26">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2003-10-01" type="public" number="108-90">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-90.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP14" subcommittee="Department of Homeland Security" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="293"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="374"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Antibiotics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Automation"/>
    <term name="Automobile insurance"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Expatriation"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forensic medicine"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missing children"/>
    <term name="Motorcycles"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Patrol aircraft"/>
    <term name="Patrol ships"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Plants"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Psychology"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Surface-to-air missiles"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Undercover operations"/>
    <term name="United States Postal Service"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h176"/>
    <amendment number="h177"/>
    <amendment number="h178"/>
    <amendment number="h179"/>
    <amendment number="h180"/>
    <amendment number="h181"/>
    <amendment number="h182"/>
    <amendment number="h183"/>
    <amendment number="h184"/>
    <amendment number="h185"/>
    <amendment number="h186"/>
    <amendment number="h187"/>
    <amendment number="h188"/>
    <amendment number="h189"/>
    <amendment number="h190"/>
    <amendment number="s1317"/>
    <amendment number="s1318"/>
    <amendment number="s1319"/>
    <amendment number="s1320"/>
    <amendment number="s1321"/>
    <amendment number="s1322"/>
    <amendment number="s1323"/>
    <amendment number="s1324"/>
    <amendment number="s1325"/>
    <amendment number="s1326"/>
    <amendment number="s1327"/>
    <amendment number="s1328"/>
    <amendment number="s1329"/>
    <amendment number="s1330"/>
    <amendment number="s1331"/>
    <amendment number="s1332"/>
    <amendment number="s1333"/>
    <amendment number="s1334"/>
    <amendment number="s1335"/>
    <amendment number="s1336"/>
    <amendment number="s1341"/>
    <amendment number="s1342"/>
    <amendment number="s1343"/>
    <amendment number="s1344"/>
    <amendment number="s1345"/>
    <amendment number="s1346"/>
    <amendment number="s1348"/>
    <amendment number="s1350"/>
    <amendment number="s1351"/>
    <amendment number="s1352"/>
    <amendment number="s1353"/>
    <amendment number="s1354"/>
    <amendment number="s1355"/>
    <amendment number="s1356"/>
    <amendment number="s1357"/>
    <amendment number="s1358"/>
    <amendment number="s1359"/>
    <amendment number="s1361"/>
    <amendment number="s1362"/>
    <amendment number="s1363"/>
    <amendment number="s1364"/>
    <amendment number="s1365"/>
    <amendment number="s1366"/>
    <amendment number="s1367"/>
    <amendment number="s1368"/>
    <amendment number="s1370"/>
    <amendment number="s1371"/>
    <amendment number="s1372"/>
    <amendment number="s1373"/>
    <amendment number="s1374"/>
    <amendment number="s1375"/>
    <amendment number="s1376"/>
    <amendment number="s1377"/>
    <amendment number="s1378"/>
    <amendment number="s1379"/>
    <amendment number="s1380"/>
    <amendment number="s1381"/>
    <amendment number="s1382"/>
    <amendment number="s1383"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/1/2003--Public Law.
Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2004 - Title I: Departmental Management and Operations - Makes FY 2004 appropriations to the Department of Homeland Security (Department) for: (1) the Office of the Secretary and Executive Management; (2) the Office of the Under Secretary for Management; (3) Department-Wide Technology Investments; and (4) the Office of the Inspector General. Title II: Security, Enforcement, and Investigations - Makes FY 2004 appropriations for: (1) the Office of the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security (salaries and expenses, and U.S. visitor and immigrant status indicator technology), (2) customs and border protection (salaries and expenses, automation modernization, and construction); (3) immigration and customs enforcement (salaries and expenses, Air and Marine interdiction, operations, maintenance and procurement); (4) Federal air marshals; (5) the Federal Protective Service; (6) the Transportation Security Administration (aviation security, maritime and land security, intelligence, research and development, and administration); (7) the U.S. Coast Guard (including a rescission of funds, operating expenses, environmental compliance and restoration, reserve training, acquisition, construction, and improvements, alteration of bridges, research, development, test, and evaluation, and retired pay); (8) the U.S. Secret Service (salaries and expenses); and (9) acquisition, construction, improvements, and related expenses. Title III: Preparedness and Recovery - Makes FY 2004 appropriations for: (1) the Office for Domestic Preparedness; (2) firefighter assistance grants; (3) the Counterterrorism Fund; (4) the Office of the Under Secretary for Emergency Preparedness and Response (including for securing medical countermeasures against biological terror attacks); (5) the Radiological Emergency Preparedness Program; (6) disaster relief; (7) the Disaster Assistance Direct Loan Program Account; (8) the National Pre-Disaster Mitigation Fund; (9) the Flood Map Modernization Fund; (10) the National Flood Insurance Fund; (11) the National Flood Mitigation Fund; (12) emergency management performance grants; (13) emergency food and shelter; and (14) Cerro Grande fire claims. Title IV: Research and Development, Training, Assessments, and Services - Makes FY 2004 appropriations for: (1). citizenship and immigration services; (2) the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center (salaries and expenses, acquisition, construction, improvements, and related expenses); (3) information analysis and infrastructure protection; and (4) science and technology (research, development, acquisition, and operations). Title V: General Provisions - (Sec. 503) Prohibits the availability of funds provided in this Act, provided by previous appropriations Acts to the agencies in or transferred to the Department, or from any accounts in the Treasury derived by the collection of fees available to the agencies funded by this Act for obligation or expenditure through a reprogamming of funds that: (1) creates new programs; (2) eliminates programs, projects, or activities; (3) increases funds for programs, projects, or activities that have been denied or restricted by Congress; or (4) proposes to use funds that have been directed for a specific activity by the appropriations committees for a different activity unless such committees are notified 15 days in advance. (Sec. 505) Authorizes the use of appropriated funds for FY 2004 and thereafter for: (1) the purchase of uniforms without regard to the general purchase price limitations for the current fiscal year; (2) the purchase of insurance for official motor vehicles operated in foreign countries; (3) entering into contracts with the Department of State to furnish health and medical services to employees and their dependents serving in foreign countries; (4) the employment of experts and consultants; and (5) the hire and purchase of motor vehicles. (Sec. 508) Deems any funds made available by this Act for intelligence activities to be specifically authorized by Congress under the National Security Act of 1947 during FY 2004 until enactment of an Act authorizing such activities for FY 2004. (Sec. 509) Directs the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center to establish an accrediting body of both Federal and non-Federal law enforcement training experts to establish standards for measuring and assessing the quality and effectiveness of Federal law enforcement training programs, facilities, and instructors. Requires the Center to ensure that all training centers under its control are operated at optimal capacity throughout the fiscal year. (Sec. 513) Prohibits the use of Department funds: (1) for the production of customs declarations that do not inquire whether the passenger had been in the proximity of livestock; (2) for any activity or Government employee salary that would prohibit the enforcement of the ban of the Tariff Act of 1930 against the importation of goods mined, produced, or manufactured by convict labor; or (3) to allow the importation of goods (or the release of goods on which there is in effect a detention order) mined, produced, or manufactured by forced or indentured child labor. (Sec. 517) Prohibits the use of funds in this Act to pursue or adopt regulations requiring airport sponsors to provide, without cost to the Transportation Security Administration (TSA), building construction, maintenance, utilities and expenses, or space for services relating to aviation security (excluding space for necessary checkpoints). Permits negotiations of below-market rates for these items. (Sec. 518) Prohibits the use of funds in this Act in contravention of the Buy American Act. (Sec. 519) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this or previous appropriations Acts for deployment or implementation on other than a test basis of the Computer Assisted Passenger Prescreening System (CAPPS II) until the General Accounting Office has reported to the Committees on Appropriations that: (1) a system of due process exists by which passengers considered to pose a threat may appeal their delay or prohibition from boarding a flight; (2) the underlying error rate of databases will not produce a large number of false positives that will result in a significant number of passengers being treated mistakenly or security resources being diverted; (3) the TSA has stressed-tested and demonstrated the efficacy and predictive accuracy of all search tools in CAPPS II; and (4) the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) has established an internal oversight board to monitor the manner in which CAPPS II is being developed and prepared. (Sec. 520) Requires the Secretary, for FY 2004 and thereafter, to charge reasonable fees for providing credentialing and background investigations in the field of transportation. (Sec. 521) Directs the Secretary to research, develop, and procure certified systems to inspect and screen air cargo on passenger aircraft at the earliest possible date and to take certain preventive measures in the interim.</summary>
</bill>
