<bill session="105" type="hr" number="394" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-25T14:50:00-05:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-03-25T14:50:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2515) to address the declining health of forests on Federal lands in the United States through a program of recovery and protection consistent with the requirements of existing public land management and environmental laws, to establish a program to inventory, monitor, and analyze public and private forests and their resources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T14:49:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-464, by Mr. Hastings (WA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T14:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2515 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. In lieu of the amendment recommended by the Committee on Agriculture now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of H.R. 3530. Each Section number of the amendment shall be considered as read. Points of order against the amendment for failure to comply with clause 7 of rule XVI or clause 5(a) of rule XXI shall be waived.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-25T14:50:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="162">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 162.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T20:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (OR) asked unanimous consent to discharge from the House Calendar and agree.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T20:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1623" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T20:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T20:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to an earlier unanimous consent agreement, the resolution was deemed agreed to.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="2515"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1998--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 2515 (forest recovery and protection).</summary>
</bill>
