<bill session="108" type="h" number="5322" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Managing Our Medicare and Medicaid Services and Protecting Our Parents Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title IV of the Public Health Service Act to establish a loan repayment program for nurse practitioners and physician assistants serving in underserved nursing homes, to establish a mentoring program for training nursing home administrators, to encourage high family involvement in nursing homes, and to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to restore payment levels for health care institutions and to increase the Federal medical assistance percentage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2004-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2004-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2004-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2004-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Management"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Welfare recipients"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2004--Introduced.
Managing Our Medicare and Medicaid Services and Protecting Our Parents Act - Amends the Public Health Services Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a loan repayment program for nurse practitioners and physician assistants serving in underserved nursing homes. Directs the Secretary to establish a mentoring program for training nursing home administrators. Requires the Director of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to provide, in implementing the Nursing Home Quality Initiative, the degree of family involvement among the quality indicators for the evaluation of the quality of nursing homes. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to reinstitute certain payment levels for health institutions (Boren Amendment Medicaid payment methodology) and to increase the Federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP).</summary>
</bill>
