<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="162" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:44-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="728" sequence="19"/>
  <status datetime="1995-02-14">offered</status>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <offered datetime="1995-02-14"/>
  <description>Amendments en bloc: permit local law enforcement block grant funding to be used by State police units to provide protection in rural areas that do not have their own local police force; establish cooperative task forces between adjoining units of local government working cooperatively to prevent and combat criminal activity, particularly drug and gang-related involvement; establish a multijurisdictional task force in rural areas where local and Federal law enforcement officials work to prevent and control crime; provide for a systematic evaluation on the impact of school security and crime prevention measures and report annually to the Bureau of Justice; provide for the investigation into possible inaccuracies of data relating to part 1 violent crimes; and provide that any funds remaining after 5 years be applied to the Federal deficit.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment comprised of 6 amendments offered en bloc to permit the bill's local law enforcement block grant funding to be used by state police units to protect rural areas; to establish cooperative task forces between adjoining units of local government to work to prevent and combat criminal activity; to establish a multijurisdictional task force in rural areas; to add new language regarding unavailability and inaccuracy of information; to add language regarding school protection; and language regarding the reversion of funds to reduce the deficit.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-02-14T16:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendments (A019) offered by Mr. McCollum.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-14T16:56:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the McCollum amendments (A019) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
