<bill session="106" type="h" number="2274" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the transfer of 10 percent of a State's apportionment of certain highway funds to the State's highway safety apportionment if the State does not suspend the driver's license of individuals under the age of 21 convicted of driving while under the influence of alcohol.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400611"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Ground Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW10" subcommittee="Ground Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Age (Law)"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/1999--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Transportation to transfer ten percent of a State's apportionment of certain highway funds for a fiscal year to the State's apportionment for highway safety programs to be used for alcohol-impaired driving countermeasures, especially for individuals under age 21, if a State has not enacted or is not enforcing a law requiring the revocation or suspension of the driver's license of any such individual who is convicted of driving while under the influence of alcohol. Requires that such suspension or revocation to be until the individual's 21st birthday. Prohibits the transfer of a State's apportionment if the State allows an individual convicted while driving under the influence of alcohol to drive, during the period of revocation or suspension of the individual's driver's license in accordance with this Act, only for the purposes of going to and from such individual's place of employment or to and from a college or other institution of higher education or a trade school.</summary>
</bill>
