<bill session="108" type="h" number="5292" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pension Fairness Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to limit the availability of benefits under an employer's nonqualified deferred compensation plans in the event that any of the employer's defined pension plans are subjected to a distress or PBGC termination in connection with bankruptcy reorganization or a conversion to a cash balance plan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2004-11-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2004-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2004-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400181" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2004-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2004-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="2004-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2004-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2004-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2004-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1892-1893"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Executives"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Pension trust guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2004--Introduced.
Pension Fairness Act of 2004 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code to limit the availability of benefits for corporate directors and executives under an employer's nonqualified deferred compensation plans in the event that any of such employer's defined pension plans are subjected to a distress termination, or to a termination where the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) takes over plan liabilities, in connection with bankruptcy reorganization or a conversion to a cash balance plan. Sets forth a termination fairness standard for nonqualified deferred compensation plans in cases where the corporation which is plan sponsor of a defined benefit plan adopts a plan amendment which: (1) terminates an underfunded workers' pension plan; or (2) converts a workers' pension plan into a cash balance plan that cuts benefits for workers with ten or more years of service under the plan, or takes away their choice to stay in their original plan. Disqualifies any director or executive officer of the corporation, for a five-year period after adoption of such an amendment, from: (1) accruing any amount under a nonqualified deferred compensation plan; and (2) receiving any distribution of accrued deferred compensation, if a nonqualified deferred compensation plan or amendment is established or adopted during or after the one-year period preceding the notice date of the defined benefit plan termination or conversion.</summary>
</bill>
