<bill session="108" type="h" number="3377" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dietary Supplement Access and Awareness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to dietary supplements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2003-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2004-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2004-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2004-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2004-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2003-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2150"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3663"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Herbs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2003--Introduced.
Dietary Supplement Access and Awareness Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require reports to the Secretary of Health and Human Services by: (1) manufacturers and processors of dietary supplements respecting dietary supplement product listing (including labeling, ingredient, and discontinuance information); and (2) manufacturers and distributors of dietary supplements respecting serious adverse experiences resulting from a supplement's use (requires manufacturer or distributor investigation of such occurrence). Authorizes the Secretary to require a manufacturer to: (1) provide postmarket surveillance if there is a reasonable possibility of a supplement causing adverse health consequences; and (2) demonstrate that a supplement is not adulterated if the Secretary has reasonable grounds for believing that a supplement may be adulterated (permits distribution during such demonstration period unless determined to be an imminent public health hazard, and requires a final determination of adulteration by the Secretary). Deems a supplement as adulterated for noncompliance with such safety demonstration provisions. Authorizes the Secretary to make a determination that a dietary supplement may pose a significant risk to individuals under the age of 18, and prohibit (as misbranded while held for sale) the supplement's sale to such individuals. Includes among prohibited acts failure to comply with the requirements added by this Act (other than safety demonstration requirements). Extends inspection authority to records, controls, and facilities related to a determination of supplement adulteration. Directs the Secretary to carry out dietary supplement education programs for health care professionals and consumers.</summary>
</bill>
