<bill session="105" type="h" number="1577" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Energy Abolishment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Federal Power Asset Privatization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To abolish the Department of Energy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400405"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1998-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="1998-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1998-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400590" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="406863" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400510" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="408142" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400294" joined="1997-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="408459" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="408476" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="408553" joined="1997-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400353" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400607" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="410136" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="1998-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="1997-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="1997-05-08" withdrawn="1997-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on National Security, Science, Resources, Rules, and Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Basic Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOE, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Procurement.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS20" subcommittee="Military Procurement" name="House National Security"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Basic Research" name="House Science"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Biological weapons"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear propulsion"/>
    <term name="Nuclear research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear ships"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radioactive waste disposal in the ground"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Abolishment of Department of Energy Title II: Energy Laboratory Facilities Title III: Privatization of Federal Power Marketing Administration Title IV: Transfer and Disposal of Reserves Title V: National Security and Environmental Management Programs Subtitle A: Defense Nuclear Programs Agency Subtitle B: Environmental Restoration Activities at Defense Nuclear Facilities Title VI: Disposition of Miscellaneous Particular Programs, Functions, and Agencies of Department Title VII: Civilian Radioactive Waste Management Title VIII: Miscellaneous Provisions Department of Energy Abolishment Act - Title I: Abolishment of Department of Energy - Redesignates the Department of Energy (DOE) as the Energy Programs Resolution Agency (the Agency), headed by an Administrator to perform the previous functions of the Department of Energy. Provides for the continuation of service of the Secretary of Energy as the interim Administrator. (Sec. 105) Authorizes the Administrator to establish, consolidate, alter, or discontinue in the Energy Programs Resolution Agency any organizational entities that were entities of DOE. Sunsets the Agency three years after enactment of this Act. Directs the Comptroller General to report to the Congress on the most efficient way to accomplish the complete abolishment of DOE and the transfer or termination of its functions. Title II: Energy Laboratory Facilities - Establishes an independent Energy Laboratory Facilities Commission to privatize and reduce energy laboratories and programs. Prescribes procedural guidelines. (Sec. 205) Establishes the Energy Laboratory Facility Closure Account to fund implementation of such guidelines. Title III: Privatization of Federal Power Marketing Administrations - Federal Power Asset Privatization Act of 1997 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to sell, at the highest possible price, all Federal electric power generation and transmission facilities supervised by, or coordinated with, the Federal Power Marketing Administrations (except the Bonneville Power Administration (BPA)). Restricts such sales to domestic entities or U.S. citizens. Requires the Secretary to terminate Federal Power Marketing Administration operations (except BPA operations) upon completion of the sales. Directs the Secretary to retain a private sector firm through a competitive bidding process to serve as financial advisor with respect to such sales. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the purchaser of any such facilities should offer to employ former Federal Power Marketing Administration personnel. Mandates that sale proceeds be deposited into the Treasury. Sets forth a sales completion deadline for each Power Marketing Administration concerned. (Sec. 305) Mandates that the pertinent sales agreements require each purchaser providing electric power to customers within any region to insure that the price of electric power does not increase above the baseline price at a rate greater than ten percent annually. (Sec. 306) Directs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to issue to the purchaser of a hydroelectric generation facility a ten-year original license under the Federal Power Act to insure that the project will continue operations under the same conditions as were applicable prior to the sale. Grants FERC Federal Power Act jurisdiction over any such facility sold. (Sec. 307) Amends the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act of 1993 to repeal the prohibition against the use of appropriated funds for studies regarding a changeover from an "at cost" to a "market rate" or other noncost-based methodology for pricing hydroelectric power. (Sec. 308) Transfers to the Secretary of the Interior all DOE functions affecting the BPA. Instructs the Secretary to study and report to the Congress on the most cost-effective option of disposing of the BPA. Title IV: Transfer and Disposal of Reserves - Transfers to the Secretary of the Interior all former DOE functions affecting the Strategic Petroleum Reserve. Instructs the Secretary to: (1) sell the reserves held at Weeks Island, Louisiana; and (2) appoint an advisory board to monitor the sale of such reserves and report to the Congress on whether the United States should maintain or dispose of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve. (Sec. 402) Transfers to the Administrator of the Energy Programs Resolution Agency all functions performed with respect to the naval petroleum reserves, except Naval Petroleum Reserve Numbered 1 (Elk Hills). Instructs the Administrator to: (1) obtain the highest possible price for the naval petroleum reserves; and (2) develop a joint plan with the Secretary of the Interior for disposal of the naval petroleum reserves within a specified timeframe. Title V: National Security and Environmental Management Programs - Subtitle A: Defense Nuclear Programs Agency - Establishes the Defense Nuclear Programs Agency (the Agency) in the Department of Defense (DOD), headed by an Under Secretary for Defense Nuclear Programs with primary responsibility for defense nuclear programs. (Sec. 504) Transfers to the Under Secretary all supervisory functions previously performed by: (1) DOE over Sandia, Los Alamos, and Lawrence Livermore National Laboratories; (2) Defense Special Weapons Agency of DOD relating to nuclear weapons systems; and (3) the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to transfer other nuclear weapons-related functions to the Under Secretary. (Sec. 505) Places restrictions upon the transfer of funds by the Agency. (Sec. 508) Requires the Energy Laboratory Facilities Commission to transmit recommendations to the Congress for a civilian entity that should perform the functions previously performed by DOE relating to the naval nuclear propulsion program. Precludes Commission consideration of the Defense Nuclear Programs Agency or any other entity within DOD. Subtitle B: Environmental Restoration Activities at Defense Nuclear Facilities - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to require the Under Secretary to review ongoing and planned remediation activities consistent with this Act. (Sec. 521) Sets forth guidelines for site-specific risk assessment, including a cost-benefit analysis of risk reduction, before the selection of a remedial action at a defense nuclear facility. (Sec. 523) Instructs the Under Secretary to renegotiate the terms of any compliance agreement entered into with the Secretary of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, and the relevant State in order to have it reflect this Act. Title VI: Disposition of Miscellaneous Particular Programs, Functions, and Agencies of Department - Limits authorizations for enumerated energy research and development programs through FY 2002. (Sec. 601) Directs the Energy Laboratory Facilities Commission to identify for the Congress all DOE research and development activities carried out at energy laboratories or institutions of higher education that perform a critical research function important to the long-term economic well-being of the United States. Directs the Secretary of Energy to terminate all DOE clean coal technology research and development activities. Authorizes appropriations for DOE fossil energy and energy conservation research and development activities. Terminates such activities 1at the end of FY 2000. Transfers from DOE to DOD specified weapons and defense activities. (Sec. 602) Transfers to the Department of the Treasury all functions performed by the Energy Information Administration (EIA). Authorizes appropriations for the EIA. Transfers to the Attorney General all functions performed by the Energy Regulatory Administration. Title VII: Civilian Radioactive Waste Management - Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to terminate the Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management and transfer to the Army Corps of Engineers (the Corps) its authority and assets with respect to a repository for radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel. Requires: (1) the Corps to assume all obligations of the Office affecting the Yucca Mountain site; and (2) reissuance of Nevada State permits for the Corps. Prescribes procedural guidelines for Corps preparation and implementation of a Yucca Mountain site characterization plan. (Sec. 702) Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to reaffirm that the obligation of the Secretary of Energy to accept high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel beginning by January 31, 1998, is absolute and is not dependent on commencement of operation of a repository or a monitored retrievable storage facility. States that such obligation shall be neither voided nor delayed for any reason. Repeals: (1) the site selection limitation placed upon the siting of a monitored retrievable storage facility; and (2) the licensing conditions placed upon such facility. (Sec. 703) Prescribes procedural guidelines for the licensing and expansion of an initial uranium storage facility. Title VIII: Miscellaneous Provisions - Authorizes the Office of Management and Budget to make any determination regarding functions transferred under this Act and incidental transfers.</summary>
</bill>
