<bill session="106" type="h" number="3398" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Surface Transportation Board Modernization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that a national railroad system is maintained or created which is adequate to provide the transportation services needed for the United States economy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400289"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Ground Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2427"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW10" subcommittee="Ground Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="Railroad abandonments"/>
    <term name="Railroad electrification"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad equipment"/>
    <term name="Railroad finance"/>
    <term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
    <term name="Railroad maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Railroad management"/>
    <term name="Railroad mergers"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad rates"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroad terminals"/>
    <term name="Railroad yards"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Surface Transportation Board"/>
    <term name="Tax assessment"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/1999--Introduced.
Surface Transportation Board Modernization Act - Amends Federal transportation law to authorize appropriations for Surface Transportation Board activities for FY 2000 through 2002.(Sec. 4) Declares that a rail carrier, corporation, or person participating in the consolidation, acquisition of control, or merger of another rail carrier is exempt from the antitrust laws and from State and local laws governing such transactions to the extent necessary. Subjects the activities of a rail carrier participating in or resulting from such transaction to State and Federal law, after such transaction is completed, to the same extent as any other similarly situated rail carrier that has not participated in or resulted from such transaction.(Sec. 5) Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) circuitous routing of rail traffic; (2) the revision of certain conditions with respect to the approval of the consolidation, merger, or acquisition of control of rail carriers by the Board; (3) preservation and restoration of railroad service; (4) the sale of certain connecting railroad lines; (5) prohibitions against acts that unreasonably burden or discriminate against interstate commerce to include within such prohibited acts the increase in an assessment on rail transportation property on the basis of improvements directly related to the provision of railroad transportation; (6) the response of a rail carrier to requests for a carrier's rates and other service terms for a movement between any two points on its system or for an entire movement between a point on its system and any other point; (7) prohibitions against rail carrier rate discrimination to declare that a rate discriminates unreasonably against a connecting line if such rate is designed to divert traffic from or to that connecting line to a less direct route or if it excludes traffic from or to that connecting line; (8) restrictions prohibiting a rail carrier from establishing a rate which discriminates against the interchange of traffic as between carriers on any basis except actual cost based on mileage traveled and services rendered; (9) changes from discretionary to mandatory the use of terminal facilities by another rail carrier provided certain conditions are met; (10) the repeal of provisions authorizing a rail carrier, without the approval of the Board, to enter into arrangements for the joint ownership or joint use of spur, industrial, team switching, or side tracks; (11) restrictions prohibiting the Board from charging a fee for the filing of a complaint, protest, or other request for relief in an amount greater than fees charged by Federal district courts for comparable filings; (12) the revision of certain requirements regarding the approval of the consolidation or merger of two or more rail carriers (including arrangements for the protection of the interests of rail carrier employees) by the Board; and (13) restrictions prohibiting the Board from considering evidence of product or geographic competition when making market dominance determinations in rail rate proceedings.(Sec. 17) Establishes a Federal Railroad Advisory Committee to make recommendations to Congress and the President on the condition and capacity of the present physical plant of the Nation's railway system and the adequacy of that plant to meet the needs of the 21st century.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
