<bill session="108" type="h" number="1941" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Voter Freedom Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enforce the guarantees of the first, fourteenth, and fifteenth amendments to the Constitution of the United States by prohibiting certain devices used to deny the right to participate in certain elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E848-849"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1385-1386"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Third parties (U.S. politics)"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2003--Introduced.
Voter Freedom Act of 2003 - Declares that an individual shall have the right to be placed as a candidate on, and to have his or her political party, body, or group affiliation in connection with such candidacy placed on, a ballot or similar voting materials to be used in a congressional election, if certain conditions are met.Requires the individual to present a petition stating that its signers desire the individual's name and political party, body, or group affiliation, if any, to be placed on the ballot or other similar voting materials to be used in the election with respect to which such rights are to be exercised. Requires such petition to have at least 1,000 signatures of registered voters in the district, or, if the State in which the district is located does not provide for voter registration, to bear the signatures of at least 1,000 eligible voters in that State and district.Specifies the period during which a petition must be circulated.</summary>
</bill>
