<bill session="106" type="h" number="3390" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Atlantic Highly Migratory Species Conservation Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To conserve Atlantic highly migratory species of fish, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1999-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fish kills"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Foreign fishing"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International fishery management"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Overfishing"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seizure of vessels and cargoes"/>
    <term name="Sharks"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tuna fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/1999--Introduced.
Atlantic Highly Migratory Species Conservation Act of 1999 - Prohibits commercial fishermen from engaging in pelagic longline fishing in the: (1) Atlantic Conservation Zone for Highly Migratory Species (HMS); (2) Gulf of Mexico Conservation Zone for Swordfish from January 1 through Memorial Day; and (3) Gulf of Mexico Conservation Zone for HMS from Memorial Day through Labor Day for the next four years. Provides the geographic coordinates for each Zone. Makes such restrictions inapplicable to longline fishery research authorized by the Secretary of Commerce.(Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to conduct a voluntary Pelagic Longline Vessel Permit Holder Compensation Program, under which vessels prohibited from engaging in such commercial fishing are compensated for fish catch losses. Identifies eligible vessels. Terminates vessel eligibility if the vessel or any Federal fishing permit or license applicable to that vessel is transferred to a different person after November 10, 1999. Requires notification of each eligible permit holder. Provides a compensation (buyout) amount of $125,000 plus either: (1) zero for any eligible holder that did not report any landings (catches) of HMS for the period between January 1 and October 1, 1999; or (2) for every other eligible holder, a landing payment determined by the Secretary. Provides for payment determination and prohibits such payment from exceeding $325,000. Outlines provisions concerning the buyout offer and its acceptance. Authorizes the Secretary to provide up to $10 million for such payments through a direct loan obligation for any payments not fully paid for by appropriated funds. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 8) Requires the revocation of all commercial fishing permits or licenses held by those accepting payments under this Act, prohibiting such vessels from being used anywhere in the world for commercial fishing. Prohibits the foreign transfer or registry of such vessels. Provides criminal and civil penalties for violations of this section, including seizure and forfeiture. Requires revocation information to be recorded in the Federal vessel identification system maintained by the Secretary of Transportation.(Sec. 9) Establishes a fishery conservation fee system, administered by the Secretary, for repayment of direct loans made under this Act. Provides fee amounts and payment requirements, including fees required from commercial Atlantic swordfish dealers.States that a vessel registered in an affected State (South Carolina, Georgia, Florida, Alabama, Mississippi, Louisiana, and Texas) shall not be required to purchase a Federal fishery conservation permit if such State, within 240 days after the enactment of this Act, makes a binding agreement to pay fully, within four years, that State's recreational share allocation, plus associated interest. Provides State share allocations.Directs the Secretary to issue for $25 each an annual fishery conservation permit to vessels over 18 feet in length wishing to engage in recreational HMS fishing in any area closed to commercial fishing under this Act. Prohibits any such vessels without permits from engaging in such fishing.(Sec. 10) Considers a person violating this Act shall to also have committed an act prohibited under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act.(Sec. 11) Establishes within the National Marine Fisheries Service at the Southeast Fisheries Science Center a Pelagic Longline Billfish Bycatch and Mortality Reduction Research Program to identify and test a variety of fishing gear configurations and uses for reducing billfish bycatch mortality in the pelagic longline fisheries of the Gulf of Mexico and in the exclusive economic zone north of the Atlantic Conservation Zone established by this Act. Requires observers to be placed on such vessels for monitoring purposes. Provides for Program design, monitoring by the Secretary, and reports to specified congressional committees.(Sec. 12) Prohibits interim regulations (with exceptions) by the Secretary prior to such report with respect to any time-area closures for pelagic longline fishing in the Atlantic by U.S. fishing vessels that are in addition to, or expand, regulations established by this Act.(Sec. 13) Prohibits, after the 165th day of enactment of this Act, any pelagic longline vessel from operating within the Atlantic HMS fishery without a vessel monitoring device approved by the Secretary. States that vessels accepting buyouts under this Act will not be required to carry such a device.(Sec. 15) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
