<bill session="107" type="hr" number="489" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-18T14:18:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-07-18T14:18:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5121) making appropriations for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400107"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-07-17T22:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 107-586, by Mr. Diaz-Balart.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-17T22:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Provides that the bill shall be considered as read through page 61, line 16 and waives points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI (prohibiting unauthorized appropriations or legislative provisions in an appropriations bill), except as specified in the resolution. Provides that where points of order are waived against part of a paragraph, points of order against a provision in another part of that paragraph may be made only against that provision and not against the entire paragraph. Provides that no amendment shall be in order except the amendment printed in H. Rept. 107-586 and except pro forma amendments offered at any time by the chairman or ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations or their designees for the purpose of debate. Provides that the amendment printed in the report may be offered only by a member specified in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent andan opponent, and shall not be subject to amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-07-17T22:58:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="196">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 196.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18T12:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4878-4884" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18T12:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 489.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18T13:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2002-07-18T14:18:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="319" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 206 (Roll no. 319).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4878" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-07-18T14:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="107" type="h" number="5121"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2002--Reported to House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule (modified closed) for the consideration of H.R. 5121 (FY 2003 legislative branch appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
