<bill session="107" type="h" number="3677" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safeguarding America's Retirement Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide new protections under applicable fiduciary rules for participants and beneficiaries under 401(k) plans and to provide for 3-year vesting of elective deferrals under such plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2002-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2002-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Corporate collapse"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defined contribution plans"/>
    <term name="Employee ownership"/>
    <term name="Employee pensions"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/2002--Introduced.
Safeguarding America's Retirement Act of 2002 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to prohibit individual account plans which include cash or deferred arrangements, under the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) section 401(k), from using employee contributions to acquire or hold more than ten percent of their value in employer securities.Requires such plans to give a participant or beneficiary whose nonforfeitable accrued benefit attributable to employee contributions is invested in whole or in part in employer securities a reasonable opportunity periodically (at least quarterly) to invest such accrued benefit in investment vehicles, other than employer securities, selected to permit diversification.Prohibits plan sponsors, administrators, or other fiduciaries from imposing any lockdown in connection with the nonforfeitable accrued benefit of a participant or beneficiary.Amends ERISA and IRC to provide for vesting (a nonforfeitable right to all of the participant's accrued benefits) of elective deferrals under such plans for participants who have completed three years of plan participation.</summary>
</bill>
