<bill session="107" type="h" number="1573" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security Protection and Tax Relief Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide more revenue for the Social Security system by imposing a tax on certain unearned income and to provide tax relief for more than 80,000,000 individuals and families who pay more in Social Security taxes than income taxes by reducing the rate of the old age, survivors, and disability insurance Social Security payroll tax.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400306"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Social security beneficiaries"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2001--Introduced.
Social Security Protection and Tax Relief Act of 2001 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a 12 percent tax on an individual's "social security taxable income." Defines such income as adjusted gross income reduced by the greater of: (1) the sum of the standard deduction applicable to the taxpayer (or which would be applicable if the taxpayer did not elect to itemize deductions for the taxable year) and the deduction for personal exemptions (determined without regard to the phase out); or (2) the aggregate exempt income of the taxpayer for the taxable year. Defines such exempt income as amounts received as a pension or annuity, social security benefits, and earned income. Decreases the old age, survivors, and disability income (social security taxes) tax rates.</summary>
</bill>
