<bill session="106" type="h" number="4909" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Compensation Equity Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to permit retired members of the Armed Forces who retired with over 20 years of service, were awarded the Purple Heart, and have a service-connected disability compensable by the Department of Veterans Affairs to receive compensation from the Department of Veterans Affairs concurrently with military retired pay, without reduction of either, and to provide for the preservation of certain benefits for surviving spouses of veterans and retired members of the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled veterans"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medals, decorations, etc."/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2000--Introduced.
Veterans Compensation Equity Act of 2000 - Authorizes the concurrent receipt of veterans' disability compensation and military retired pay, without deduction from either, for individuals who retired from the armed forces with at least 20 years of service, were awarded the Purple Heart, and have a service-connected disability.Makes the rate of dependency and indemnity compensation (DIC) for the surviving spouse of a veteran who was awarded the Purple Heart the same as the rate of compensation for service-connected disability or death that would be paid to a veteran if the veteran were not deceased (thereby continuing the DIC payment beyond the veteran's death).Makes annuities under the Survivor Benefit Plan 100 percent of the base amount. (Currently, such annuities are specified percentages of such base amount based on age.) Repeals: (1) the requirement for annuity reduction at age 62; and (2) an alternative computation of such annuity for certain beneficiaries. Requires the recomputation of existing annuities due to amendments made by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
