<bill congress="106" type="hr" number="2467" updated="2012-10-31T13:23:49-05:00">
  <status datetime="1999-08-06">REFERRED</status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Worker Paycheck Fairness Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require labor organizations to secure prior, voluntary, written authorization as a condition of using any portion of dues or fees for activities not necessary to performing duties relating to the representation of employees in dealing with the employer on labor-management issues, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor state="PA" title="Rep" thomas_id="447" district="19" name="Goodling, William F."/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor name="Toomey, Patrick J." district="15" title="Rep" state="PA" sponsored_at="2000-10-12" thomas_id="1594"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <referral datetime="1999-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </referral>
    <referral datetime="1999-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
    </referral>
  </actions>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor union finances"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Labor union welfare activities"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Labor unions and social problems"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Union dues"/>
    <term name="Union security"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary date="1999-07-12" status="Introduced">Worker Paycheck Fairness Act of 1999 - Requires a labor union accepting payment of any dues or fees from an employee as a condition of employment to secure from each employee a prior, voluntary, written authorization for any portion of such dues or fees which will be used for activities not necessary to performing the duties of exclusive representation in dealing with the employer on labor-management issues. Gives employees a right of civil action against any labor union which violates this requirement. Requires employers to post notice relating to such requirement. Amends the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 to require every labor union to attribute and report expenses by function classification in detail necessary to allow its members to determine whether such expenses were necessary to performing the duties of exclusive representation in dealing with the employer on labor-management issues. Requires disclosure under such Act to employees required to pay any union dues or fees (under a union security agreement) as well as to union members. Makes it unlawful for any labor organization to coerce, intimidate, threaten, interfere with, or retaliate against any employee in the exercise of, or on account of having exercised, any right granted or protected by this Act. Directs the Federal Election Commission to provide assistance to the Secretary of Labor in prescribing regulations under this Act, including providing the Secretary with an analysis comparing this Act and the amendments it makes with related provisions regarding labor organizations and their members under the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971.</summary>
</bill>
