<bill congress="106" type="hr" number="2317" updated="2012-10-31T13:23:46-05:00">
  <status datetime="1999-06-28">REFERRED</status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lower Delaware Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate a portion of the Delaware River and associated tributaries as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor state="PA" title="Rep" thomas_id="465" district="8" name="Greenwood, James C."/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor name="Andrews, Robert E." district="1" title="Rep" state="NJ" sponsored_at="2000-05-24" thomas_id="21"/>
    <cosponsor name="Fattah, Chaka" district="2" title="Rep" state="PA" sponsored_at="2000-05-24" thomas_id="371"/>
    <cosponsor name="Holt, Rush D." district="12" title="Rep" state="NJ" sponsored_at="1999-06-23" thomas_id="1580"/>
    <cosponsor name="Roukema, Marge" district="5" title="Rep" state="NJ" sponsored_at="1999-06-23" thomas_id="990"/>
    <cosponsor name="Toomey, Patrick J." district="15" title="Rep" state="PA" sponsored_at="1999-06-25" thomas_id="1594"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <referral datetime="1999-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </referral>
    <referral datetime="1999-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </referral>
    <action datetime="1999-06-28">
      <text>Referred to Department of the Interior for comments.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary date="1999-06-23" status="Introduced">Lower Delaware Wild and Scenic Rivers Act - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate specified portions of the Lower Delaware River and associated tributaries in New Jersey and Pennsylvania for inclusion in the Wild and Scenic Rivers System.Requires the Secretary of the Interior to carry out the Lower Delaware River management plan to bring such portions into compliance with such Act. Authorizes the Secretary to provide planning, financial, and technical assistance to municipalities through which such portions flow to protect the natural, economic, and historic resources of the Lower Delaware River corridor. Authorizes the Secretary to continue to work with appropriate municipalities in order to add to the System additional River segments not designated under this Act.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
