<bill session="106" type="h" number="5231" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pharmaceutical Reform Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and title 35, United States Code, with respect to abbreviated applications for the approval of new drugs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400281"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2000-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400578" joined="2000-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2000-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Genetic engineering"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Inventions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Recombinant DNA"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2000--Introduced.
Pharmaceutical Reform Act of 2000 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to cease consideration of, and to terminate, a petition to approve an abbreviated drug application for a new drug if the Secretary determines that the person submitting the petition received valuable consideration from an entity whose financial interests are served by an order approving such application.Prohibits a patent from being considered to claim a listed drug unless, with respect to such drug, the patent claims an active ingredient.Provides the effective date of the approval of an abbreviated application for a new drug containing a certification that its patent is invalid or will not be infringed by the manufacture, use, or sale of the new drug for which the application is submitted.Prohibits any State or political subdivision from: (1) taking any action with respect to a drug approved under such Act that is different from or in addition to any listed requirement; or (2) establishing or continuing in effect a prohibition against the use of a drug as a substitute for any listed drug to which the drug is therapeutically equivalent.Expresses the sense of Congress that a specified provision of the Public Health Service Act authorizes the submission of an abbreviated application for the approval of a new drug that is a biological product.</summary>
</bill>
