<bill session="104" type="h" number="3276" updated="2012-11-01T22:45:03-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Attendance Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that, to receive their pay, Members of Congress are required to certify that they have performed their congressional duties, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409228"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1996-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1996-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1996-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1996-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>04/18/1996--Introduced.
Congressional Attendance Reform Act - Requires each Member of Congress to certify in writing that he or she has performed official congressional duties commensurate with such Member's pay as a condition of receiving pay each month. Requires the certification to: (1) be made to the Secretary of the Senate or the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, as applicable; and (2) include a specification of any absence of the Member on a day during which any vote is taken in the House involved, together with the reason for such absence. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) publication of the certification; and (2) criminal penalties for Members of Congress who make false statements in such certification. Prohibits payment of a Member for a day on which he or she is absent and during which any vote is taken in the House involved, unless the absence was for personal illness, family illness, or congressional business. Allows citizens to bring civil actions in district court against the Secretary or the Chief Administrative Officer for injunctive relief in the case of any payment in violation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
