<bill session="108" type="h" number="4185" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Security Enhancement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the coordination of the Federal Government in identifying and responding to weak or failing countries that endanger international security or stability, to improve the coordination and conduct of pre-conflict stabilization operations and post-conflict reconstruction operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400167" joined="2004-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2004-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bank employees"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Civil engineering"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crisis management"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Haiti compilation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Volunteer forces"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2004--Introduced.
International Security Enhancement Act of 2004 - Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to direct the Secretary to establish within the Department of State an Office of Overseas Contingencies and Stabilization, which shall: (1) be headed by the Undersecretary for Overseas Contingencies and Stabilization; and (2) have primary responsibility for planning and administering non-military aspects of overseas contingency operations, including pre-conflict stabilization operations and post-conflict reconstruction operations, in countries of impending or immediate risk. Organizes the Office into: (1) the Bureau of Contingency Planning; (2) the Bureau of Contingency Training, which shall contain an International Contingency Training Center, and a Civilian Overseas Contingency Force; and (3) the Bureau of Contingency Coordination. Directs the Undersecretary to identify weak or failing countries and categorize such countries according to risk levels (country of risk, country of impending risk, and country of immediate risk). Sets forth: (1) identification and categorization criteria; and (2) planning and monitoring requirements for countries so categorized. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to establish in the Treasury the Department of State Emergency Stabilization Operations Support Fund. Authorizes the President to provide Fund amounts to the Office for a country of impending or immediate risk. Amends Federal law to provide that whenever the commander of a regional combatant command begins planning for a contingency operation, the commander shall establish within the combatant command a joint interagency task force to prepare for any post-conflict reconstruction operations that may result from such operation. Establishes in the Executive Office of the President the Joint Task Force for Stabilization, Reconstruction, and Contingency Operations Coordination, which shall ensure Federal coordination before, during, and after instances in which the United States participates in foreign pre-conflict stabilization operations, contingency operations, and post-conflict reconstruction operations. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) funds appropriated to carry out the amendments made by this Act should be offset by reductions in redundant or duplicative functions and foreign assistance programs of the Department of State; and (2) increased staff levels required by the amendments made by this Act should be offset by the transfer of staff within the Department of State, and the elimination of resultant redundant Department of State functions.</summary>
</bill>
