<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1037" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="5522" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2008-04-30T18:07:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-04-30"/>
  <description>Amendment made four adjustments to the bill: (1) corrected the short title; (2) provided that engineering controls required by the interim standard shall be effective 6 months after issuance of the standard (rather than 30 days); (3) maintained the provision that DOL shall include appropriate and relevant NFPA standards in the final standard but eliminates references to specific NFPA standards; and (4) clarified that the final standard shall be conducted in accordance with usual rulemaking procedural requirements, including those that provide for small business review.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 110-613 to make four adjustments to the bill: (1) correct the short title; (2) provide that engineering controls required by the interim standard shall be effective 6 months after issuance of the standard (rather than 30 days); (3) maintain the provision that DOL shall include appropriate and relevant NFPA standards in the final standard but eliminates references to specific NFPA standards; and (4) clarifie that the final standard shall be conducted in accordance with usual rulemaking procedural requirements, including those that provide for small business review.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. George Miller.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2914-2915, H2918-2919" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2914" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2008-04-30T18:07:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="230">
      <text>On agreeing to the Miller, George amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 412 - 0 (Roll no. 230).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
