<bill session="104" type="h" number="3283" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Aboveground Petroleum Storage Tank Consolidation and Regulatory Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue a regulation that consolidates all environmental laws administered by the Agency and health and safety laws applicable to the construction, maintenance, and operation of aboveground storage tanks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1996-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1996-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1996-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-04-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E596"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Industrial standards"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Petroleum storage"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Underground petroleum tanks"/>
    <term name="Underground storage"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1996--Introduced.
Aboveground Petroleum Storage Tank Consolidation and Regulatory Improvement Act - Redesignates the Office of Underground Storage Tanks of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and establishes it as the Office of Storage Tanks (OST), to be headed by a Director. Transfers to OST authorities of other EPA officers under the environmental laws. Requires the Administrator, acting through the Director, to enter Memorandums of Understanding with the Secretaries of Labor and Transportation to clarify the authorities of EPA and the respective Secretaries under: (1) the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 and worker protection standards provisions of the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act of 1986; and (2) pipeline safety provisions. Requires the Director, by regulation, to restate the laws he or she administers in consolidated form and streamline their application to owners and operators of aboveground and underground storage tanks. Expresses congressional intent that this direction is not intended to modify the laws' requirements. Imposes, as part of such regulations, a requirement that an owner or operator of an aboveground storage tank report to the national response center established under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act a release of a regulated substance (one regulated under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 or petroleum or a petroleum substance) above a specified threshold, including a description of corrective action taken. Allows the EPA Administrator, after release from an aboveground storage tank of a regulated substance posing an imminent threat to human health, public safety, or the environment, to prohibit the use or operation of all or any portion of a storage tank farm within a facility in which the tank is located until the prohibition is no longer necessary or corrective action has been taken. Authorizes the Director to include in the above regulations release detection, prevention, and correction regulations applicable to owners and operators of aboveground petroleum storage tanks. Requires the Director to determine if there are deficiencies in the law applicable to aboveground petroleum storage tanks and examine industry standards addressing the deficiencies, giving substantial weight to these in designing the regulations. Requires the Director, in conjunction with the restatement of laws required by this Act, to provide that the storage capacity of a facility does not include the capacity of underground storage tanks that are: (1) currently subject to EPA regulations concerning technical standards and corrective action requirements; or (2) permanently closed under such regulations. Establishes requirements for reports to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
