<bill session="105" type="hr" number="579" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-07T18:21:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-07T18:21:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 4104) making appropriations for the Treasury Department, the United States Postal Service, the Executive Office of the President, and certain Independent Agencies, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1999, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400265"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9911-9920" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 579, waiving points of order against consideration of the conference report to accompany H.R. 4104.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-790, by Mr. McInnis.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 4104 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-10-07T17:07:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="269">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 269.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07T17:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-10-07T18:21:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="490" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 194 (Roll No. 490).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="hr" number="563"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="4104"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/1998--Introduced.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the conference report on H.R. 4104 (making appropriations for the Department of the Treasury, U.S. Postal Service, Executive Office of the President, and certain independent agencies).</summary>
</bill>
