<bill session="104" type="h" number="919" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Poverty Data Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 13, United States Code, to require that the Secretary of Commerce produce and publish, at least every 2 years, current data relating to the incidence of poverty in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400539"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E324"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Security, International Affairs and Criminal Justice.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO06" subcommittee="National Security, International Affairs and Criminal Justice" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Population statistics"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Socially handicapped children"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/1995--Introduced.
Poverty Data Improvement Act - Requires the Secretary of Commerce to biennially produce and publish data relating to the incidence of poverty for each State, county, and local government (compiled from the most recent decennial census) and for each school district. Authorizes such data to be produced by means of sampling, estimation, or any other method that the Secretary determines will produce current, comprehensive, and reliable data. Authorizes the Secretary to aggregate school districts if reliable data could not otherwise be produced for each school district, but only to the extent necessary to achieve reliability. Requires such data to be appropriately identified and accompanied by a detailed explanation as to how and why aggregation was used (including the measures taken to minimize any such aggregation). Requires the Secretary, if unable to produce and publish such data for any area, to report to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives on each government or school district excluded and the reasons therefor.</summary>
</bill>
