<bill session="104" type="h" number="4141" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Housing and Urban Development Owner-Occupancy Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that purchasers of single family residential properties owned by the Department of Housing and Urban Development are notified of the penalties authorized for intentionally misrepresenting the purchaser's intent to occupy the properties after purchase and that purchasers indicating an intent to use such properties as their principal residences use the properties in such manner.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400553"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/1996--Introduced.
Department of Housing and Urban Development Owner-Occupancy Enforcement Act - Requires that purchasers of single family homes owned by the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) be notified about the penalties for fraud and false statements regarding their intention to occupy and use such residence as their principal residence. Bars violators from future HUD assistance or program participation.</summary>
</bill>
