<bill session="104" type="h" number="3643" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-16T13:39:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-07-16T13:39:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to extend through December 31, 1998, the period during which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs is authorized to provide priority health care to certain veterans who were exposed to Agent Orange or who served in the Persian Gulf War and to make such authority permanent in the case of certain veterans exposed to ionizing radiation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300151"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="1996-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404142" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="407838" joined="1996-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400329" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1996-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="410695" joined="1996-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1996-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T20:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 104-648.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-06-27T20:48:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="327">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 327.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Stump moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7546-7552" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-07-16T13:39:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>See H.R.3118.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="882"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1565"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1565"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3118"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3118"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3418"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agent Orange"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Atomic bomb"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dentists"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Gulf War syndrome"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Herbicides"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Ionizing radiation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leukemia"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mammography"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mentally ill"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf War"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Psychiatric research"/>
    <term name="Psychiatry"/>
    <term name="Psychology"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Radiation victims"/>
    <term name="Rape trauma syndrome"/>
    <term name="Rape victim services"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social workers"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vietnam veterans"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women veterans"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/1996--Passed House amended.
Makes herbicide-exposed veterans eligible for hospital and nursing home care for any disease among those for which the National Academy of Sciences has determined: (1) there is sufficient evidence to conclude a positive association between occurrence of the disease and exposure to a herbicide agent; (2) there is evidence which suggests such an association, though such evidence is limited in nature; or (3) available studies are insufficient to permit a conclusion about the presence or absence of such an association. Makes such veterans eligible for such care for a disease for which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines there is credible evidence suggestive of such an association. Makes radiation-exposed veterans eligible for such care for any disease currently listed among covered diseases or any other disease for which the Secretary determines there is credible evidence of a positive association between occurrence of the disease and exposure to such radiation. Extends through 1998 the authority to provide such care. Extends: (1) through 1998 the authority to provide outpatient care to herbicide-exposed veterans; and (2) permanently the authority to provide such care to radiation-exposed veterans. Authorizes priority health care for veterans who may have been exposed to a toxic substance or environmental hazard while serving on active duty in Israel or Turkey during the period between August 2, 1990, and July 31, 1991. (Sec. 2) Authorizes the Secretary to establish in the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) of the Department of Veterans Affairs a Committee on Care of Severely Chronically Mentally Ill Veterans, which shall continually assess the capability of VHA to meet the treatment and rehabilitation needs of mentally ill veterans (including women) whose mental illnesses are severe and chronic and who are eligible for health care furnished by the Department. Requires various reports with respect to such Committee and its assessments. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to establish and operate centers for mental illness research, education and clinical activities to represent various U.S. geographic regions. Allows the designation of no more than five centers. Outlines requirements for proposals submitted for designation as a center. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1998 through 2001 for basic support of center activities. Directs the Under Secretary of Health for the VHA to allocate other Department funds for such centers. Requires annual reports. Requires at least one center to be designated by January 1, 1998. (Sec. 4) Authorizes the use of disbursement agreements for the administration of pay, benefits, and records of medical residents and interns serving in Department facilities furnishing hospital care or medical services (currently, only Department hospitals). (Sec. 5) Authorizes the Secretary to suspend special pay agreements in the case of Department physicians and dentists who enter residency training programs, such suspension to last for the duration of the program. (Sec. 6) Amends the Veterans Health Care Act of 1992 to extend through 1998 and include additional information in an annual reporting requirement on the provision of health care and services for, and research relating to, women veterans. (Sec. 7) Directs the Center for Women Veterans of the Department to assess the use by women veterans of health services through the Department, including counseling for sexual trauma and mental health services. Requires related reports. (Sec. 8) Prohibits a mammogram from being performed at a Department facility not accredited for such purpose by a designated private nonprofit organization. Directs the Secretary to prescribe quality assurance and control standards relating to the performance and interpretation of mammograms and the use of Department mammogram equipment and facilities consistent with related standards under the Public Health Service Act. Requires an annual inspection of such equipment and facilities. Requires the Secretary to prescribe and report on implementation of mammogram standards. (Sec. 9) Directs the Secretary to conduct a survey of, and report to the Congress on, deficiencies of each Department medical center relating to privacy afforded to women patients which may interfere with appropriate patient treatment. Requires high priority to be given to any plans and steps to correct such deficiencies. (Sec. 10) Authorizes the Secretary to modify the reversionary restrictions placed on specified real property conveyed to Milwaukee County, Wisconsin, in 1954 in order to allow such County to transfer such property to another party as long as the property is used only for civic and recreational purposes.</summary>
</bill>
