<bill session="106" type="h" number="3630" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 23, United States Code, to make certain passenger rail projects eligible for funding under the highway program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Ground Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW10" subcommittee="Ground Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="Railroad commuting traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad rolling stock"/>
    <term name="Railroad terminals"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2000--Introduced.
Amends Federal highway provisions to include among eligible projects: (1) for the National Highway System funds the acquisition, construction, reconstruction, and rehabilitation of, and preventative maintenance for, intercity rail passenger facilities and rolling stock; (2) under the for Surface Transportation Program funds capital costs for transit projects eligible for assistance involving rail or a combination of bus and rail; and (3) under the for Congestion Mitigation and Air Quality Improvement Program funds those projects or programs that will have air quality benefits through acquisition, construction, reconstruction, and rehabilitation of, and preventative maintenance for, intercity rail passenger facilities and rolling stock.Directs that highway and transit funds made available and transferred to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak) or to any publicly-owned intercity or intracity passenger rail line be administered by the Secretary of Transportation in accordance with specified guidelines. Federal provisions governing rail programs.</summary>
</bill>
