<bill session="108" type="h" number="1903" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 to improve the surplus property disposal process for closed or realigned military installations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400129"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2003--Introduced.
Amends the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 to: (1) require (currently, authorizes) the transfer to a local redevelopment authority (LRA) by the Secretary of Defense of real and personal property at a closed or realigned military installation, including existing housing units and real property designated for future housing units, to be without consideration (if the LRA takes certain steps); (2) remove the requirement that the Secretary seek to obtain consideration for such transfers with respect to military installations for which the date of approval of closure or realignment is after January 1, 2005; (3) remove the Secretary's authority to recommend that an installation be placed in an inactive status for national security or other U.S. interests; and (4) make the LRA the single community based organization responsible for monitoring Federal environmental remediation activities with respect to the installation.</summary>
</bill>
