<bill session="105" type="h" number="2458" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Protection and Hazardous Fuels Reduction Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide new authority to the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to safeguard communities, lives, and property from catastrophic wildfire by eliminating hazardous fuels buildup, and to undertake other forest management projects to protect noncommodity resources, on Federal lands where wildlands abut, or are located in close proximity to, urban areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="1997-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="1997-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1997-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="1997-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-09-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1737-1738"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-05">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Grassland ecology"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Management of Wildland-Urban Interface Areas Title II: Fire Danger Reduction By Removal of Grasses and Forbs Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions Community Protection and Hazardous Fuels Reduction Act of 1997 - Title I: Management of Wildland-Urban Interface Areas - Requires the Bureau of Land Management and the Forest Service to identify wildlife-urban interface areas (areas of Federal land in close proximity to communities and human habitations) with hazardous fuels buildups and other forest management needs. (Sec. 102) Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture or of the Interior to (temporarily) enter into forest product sales contracts in order to reduce hazardous fuels buildups in such areas, which may require the purchaser to undertake forest management projects under specified conditions in return for forest management credits. Title II: Fire Danger Reduction by Removal of Grasses and Forbs - Authorizes the Secretary concerned, upon local certification of fire hazard due to excessive grasses and forbs in such areas, to enter into livestock grazing contracts for such vegetation's removal. Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions - Requires the Secretary concerned to issue implementing regulations within a specified time. Authorizes program appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
