<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="641" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:57-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="5116" sequence="6"/>
  <status datetime="2010-05-12T18:16:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <offered datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  <description>Amendment establishes a program to support the development and commercial application of clean energy technologies through a Clean Energy Consortium selected competitively by the Secretary of Energy. The Consortium would be regionally based and include research universities, national labs, industry, and other state and nongovernmental organizations with research or technology transfer expertise in clean energy technology. The Consortium would have a technology focus to which at least 50 percent of support would be directed. The grant to establish and operate the Consortium is for an amount not more than $10,000,000 per year and is for a period not to exceed 3 years.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 10 printed in Part B of House Report 111-479 to establish a program to support the development and commercial application of cleamount not more than $10,000,000 per year and is for a period not to exceed 3 years.he Secretary of Energy. The Consortium would be regionally based and include research universities, national labs, industry, and other state and nongovernmental organizations with research or technology transfer expertise in clean energy technology. The Consortium would have a technology focus to which at least 50 percent of support would be directed. The grant to establish and operate the Consortium is for an amount not more than $10,000,000 per year and is for a period not to exceed 3 years.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12T16:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Markey (MA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3396-3398, H3407" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3396-3397" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2010-05-12T18:16:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="264">
      <text>On agreeing to the Markey (MA) amendment (A006) Agreed to by recorded vote: 254 - 173 (Roll no. 264).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
