<bill session="105" type="h" number="1943" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Carlsbad Irrigation Project Acquired Land Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To convey certain real property within the Carlsbad Project in New Mexico to the Carlsbad Irrigation District.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400534"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-25">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 8 - 4.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation districts"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/1997--Introduced.
Carlsbad Irrigation Project Acquired Land Transfer Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Carlsbad Irrigation District specified real property within the Carlsbad Project in New Mexico and all U.S. interests in the irrigation and drainage system of the Project and all related lands, including ditch rider houses, the maintenance shop and buildings, and the Pecos River Flume. Requires the conveyed lands to continue to be managed and used for the purposes for which the project was authorized. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Secretary should complete such conveyance within nine months after the enactment of this Act. Requires a report from the Secretary to the Congress if the conveyance is not completed in such time. Directs the Secretary to: (1) provide a written identification of all mineral and grazing leases in effect on such lands; and (2) notify all such leaseholders of the conveyance made by this Act. Provides that the District shall assume all U.S. rights and obligations for all mineral and grazing leases, licenses, and permits existing on the conveyed lands and shall be entitled to any associated receipts. Requires receipts paid into the reclamation fund as credits to the Carlsbad Project to be made available to the District for Project purposes. Authorizes the Secretary to expend a specified amount annually from Bureau of Reclamation operation and maintenance funds to implement water conservation practices at the Project. Requires the District to provide matching funds. Indemnifies the United States from damages arising out of any act or omission related to the conveyed property (with an exception for negligence).</summary>
</bill>
