<bill session="107" type="h" number="1080" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Election Reform Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit national political parties from using soft money, to restrict the use of soft money by corporations and labor organizations, to impose additional reporting requirements under such Act on corporations, labor organizations, and nonprofit organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2002-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor union finances"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2001--Introduced.
Federal Election Reform Act of 2001 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to: (1) prohibit any political committee established and maintained by a national political party from soliciting, receiving, spending, or directing to another person any funds which are not subject to FECA limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements (soft money); (2) prohibit the use of soft money by corporations and labor organizations for certain activities; and (3) require corporations, labor organizations, and nonprofit organizations which make a disbursement or transfer of funds which is not otherwise treated as a contribution or expenditure under FECA for any activity in connection with an election for Federal office to file reports containing the same information with respect to such disbursement or transfer which would be required if the disbursement or transfer were treated as a contribution or expenditure under FECA.</summary>
</bill>
