<bill session="106" type="h" number="3845" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-14T14:26:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-03-14T14:26:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Investment Corrections Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Small Business Investment Corrections Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make corrections to the Small Business Investment Act of 1958, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2000-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-14T12:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 106-520.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-03-14T12:01:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="289">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 289.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-03-14T14:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Kelly moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-14T14:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H940-942" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-14T14:17:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3845.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-03-14T14:26:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H940-941" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-03-14T14:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Venture capital"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2000--Passed House amended.
Small Business Investment Corrections Act of 2000 - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to: (1) state that certain venture investment in a small business shall not cause such business to be considered not independently owned and operated, regardless of the allocation of control during the investment period; and (2) define as long term, when used in connection with equity capital or loan funds invested in any small business or smaller enterprise, any period of one year or more.Revises the subsidy fee charged in connection with debentures purchased by the Small Business Administration (SBA) to guarantee loans to participating small businesses from a flat one percent to a charge, established annually by the SBA Administrator with respect to debentures issued after September 30, 2000, of not more than one percent as necessary to reduce to zero the cost of purchasing and guaranteeing such debentures. Makes an identical revision with respect to the fee charged for securities issued after September 30, 2000, by participating companies for small business loans guaranteed by the SBA.Authorizes small businesses which are limited partnerships or subchapter S corporations to make quarterly distributions at any time during a calendar quarter (currently, only at the end of a calendar quarter).</summary>
</bill>
