<bill session="104" type="hr" number="44" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-25T14:41:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-01-25T14:41:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the concurrent resolution (H. Con. Res. 17) relating to the treatment of Social Security under any Constitutional amendment requiring a balanced budget and providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 1) proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-01-24T17:58:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-4, by Mr. Solomon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-24T17:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 17 and H.J. Res. 1 with 4 hours of general debate. The rule provides for 1 hour of general debate in the House on H. Con. Res. 17, and 3 hours of general debate on H.J. Res. 1. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the concurrent resolution to final adoption without intervening motion. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider H.J. Res. 1 in the Committee of the Whole, with 3 hours of general debate. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Comittee on the Judiciary printed in the joint resolution shall be debatable for one hour. No furter amendment shall be in order except those designated in section 3 of this resolution, if offered in the order and manner specified. If more than one amendment is adopted, the amendment receiving the greatest number of affirmative votes shall be considered as finally adop...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-01-24T17:58:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="3">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 3.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25T12:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H605-619" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25T12:39:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25T13:50:00-05:00">
      <text>EXTENDED DEBATE - Mr. Solomon asked unanimous consent for an additional period of debate for not to exceed 10 minutes equally divided and controlled, for the purpose of discussing the amendment. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25T14:04:00-05:00">
      <text>ORDERING THE PREVIOUS QUESTION - At the conclusion of extended debate, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question on the amendment and the resolution. By a voice vote, the Chair declared that the ayes had prevailed and subsequently, Mr. Moakley objected to the voice vote based on the absence of a quorum and the Yeas and Nays were ordered.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25T14:22:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 233 - 196 (Roll no. 37).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-01-25T14:41:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="39" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 255 - 172 (Roll no. 39).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25T14:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hc" number="17"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="hc" number="17"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="hj" number="1"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h16"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>1/25/1995--Passed House amended.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H. Con. Res. 17 (relating to the treatment of Social Security under any constitutional amendment requiring a balanced budget) and H.J. Res. 1 (proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution).</summary>
</bill>
