<bill session="105" type="h" number="3237" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a national registry from which adopted children may obtain medical information voluntarily provided by their birth parents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Adopted children"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/1998--Introduced.
Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a national registry to which birth parents of an adopted child may voluntarily provide medical information about themselves for release to the adopted child upon the child's request. Prohibits the release of identifying information about a birth parent to the adopted child unless the parent and child have signed a notarized statement of consent. Mandates: (1) the confidentiality of all national registry information; and (2) the written informed consent of the individual before release of any registry information. Proscribes any national registry attempt to contact an individual for the purpose of facilitating a reunion. Mandates that the registry: (1) be a centralized nationwide data repository; and (2) operate independently of any other data system maintained by the Department of Health and Human Services. Authorizes the Secretary to charge fees for services provided under this Act. Subjects violators of this Act to specified criminal penalties. Declares that this Act does not preempt any State or local law concerning adoption and the confidentiality of its sealed adoption record policy.</summary>
</bill>
