<bill session="105" type="hr" number="433" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-21T14:47:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-05-21T14:47:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Calling upon the President of the United States to urge full cooperation by his former political appointees and friends and their associates with congressional investigations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-14T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 436 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 432 and H. Res. 433 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Providing for consideration of these resolutions in the House. After disposition of or postponement of further proceedings on H. Res. 432, it shall be in order to consider in the House the resolution H. Res. 433, debatable for one hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the resolution to final adoption without intervening motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 436 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 432 and H. Res. 433 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Providing for consideration of these resolutions in the House. After disposition of or postponement of further proceedings on H. Res. 432, it shall be in order to consider in the House the resolution H. Res. 433, debatable for one hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the resolution to final adoption without intervening motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 436.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3646-3666" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T13:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-05-21T14:47:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="177" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 342 - 69, 12 Present (Roll No. 177).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T14:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="436"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Clinton Administration"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional witnesses"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Presidential ethics"/>
    <term name="Self-incrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/1998--Introduced.
Urges the President to: (1) immediately call upon his friends, former associates and appointees, and the associates of those individuals, who have asserted fifth amendment privileges or fled the country to avoid testifying in congressional investigations, to come forward and testify fully and truthfully before the relevant congressional committees; and (2) use all legal means at his disposal to compel people who have left the country to return and cooperate with the investigation.</summary>
</bill>
