<bill session="108" type="h" number="2869" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Northern Nevada Rural Economic Development and Land Consolidation Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to sell certain public lands subject to mining operations in Eureka, Lander, White Pine, Elko, and Humboldt Counties, Nevada, for the reclamation of abandoned mines in Nevada, to promote and enhance economic development, education, and local government revenues, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2003-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-08-08">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2003--Introduced.
Northern Nevada Rural Economic Development and Land Consolidation Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, upon the submission of the relevant application or applications by the Placer Dome U.S. Inc., Denver, Co., and Graymont Western U.S. Inc., Murray, Utah (together the Claimant), to sell the Claimant whatever portion is requested of certain public lands subject to mining operations in Eureka, Lander, White Pine, Elko, and Humboldt Counties, Nevada. Directs that the sale of the lands be at market price. States that the value of locatable minerals in such lands shall not be considered or included in the market value of the lands. Subjects all public lands conveyed under this Act to a royalty payable to the United States on locatable minerals, except for lands subject to unpatented mining claims for which the Claimant demonstrates the discovery of a valuable mineral deposit. Directs the Secretary to accept from the Claimant a conveyance of any of certain specified private lands in northern Nevada, with the Claimant to receive a credit equal to the market value of each such transferred property. Subjects all lands conveyed under this Act to valid existing rights. Directs that the proceeds from the sales of the lands be used: (1) to support the State's general education program; (2) to support a trust fund for the California Trail Interpretative Center in Elko County; (3) for the rehabilitation of lands in Nevada that were subject to historic mining activities; and (4) for the reimbursement of costs incurred by the Nevada State Office and relevant Field Offices of the Bureau of Land Management in conducting the sales.</summary>
</bill>
