<bill session="105" type="h" number="4525" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide further protections for the watershed of the Little Sandy River as part of the Bull Run Watershed Management Unit, Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="1998-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-09">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-09">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="2509"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Logging"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/1998--Introduced.
Amends Federal law to reestablish and add acreage to the Bull Run Watershed Management Unit in Oregon. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture or the Interior, as applicable, to prohibit the cutting of trees on Federal land in the entire unit. Repeals a provision of the: (1) Oregon Resource Conservation Act of 1996 which requires certain Unit lands that are not contained in the Bull Run River Drainage to be managed in accordance with the law establishing the Unit; and (2) Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 regarding the Unit. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture: (1) upon application by the city of Portland, Oregon, to enter into negotiations with the city for the transfer of National Forest System land underlying the city's Bull Run water supply facilities to the city in exchange for city- owned land lying within the boundaries of any unit of the National Forest System in Oregon or Washington; and (2) to expedite the negotiations and complete such land exchange not later than September 30, 2001.</summary>
</bill>
