<bill session="104" type="hj" number="128" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-11-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making further continuing appropriations for the District of Columbia for fiscal year 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 13772"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Municipal officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/28/1995--Introduced.
Appropriates funds for FY 1996 for such amounts as may be necessary under the authority and conditions provided in the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1995 (the Act) for continuing the Federal payment to the District of Columbia and the Federal contribution to the District of Columbia Retirement Funds. Appropriates out of the general fund, enterprise funds, and other non-Federal funds of the District for FY 1996 such necessary amounts under the authority and conditions provided in the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1995 for continuing the operations of the District government and other activities chargeable against District revenues that were conducted in FY 1995 and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority would be available in the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1996. Prohibits obligations or expenditures of such funds until the Mayor of the District provides written notification to the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority. Requires the pertinent project or activity to be continued at a rate not exceeding the lowest of the current rate, the rate under the 1996 Act as passed by the House of Representatives, or the rate under the 1996 Act as passed by the Senate. Limits the total operating expenses for the District for FY 1996 to $4.994 million. Prohibits obligations or expenditures from being made pursuant to this Act until: (1) the Mayor of the District has provided to the Authority a proposed allocation of any reductions required because of such limitation; and (2) the Authority has reviewed and approved such allocations. (Sec. 2) Provides that appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this Act shall be available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) the enactment of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this Act; (2) the enactment of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1996 without any provision for such project or activity; or (3) September 30, 1996. (Sec. 3) Specifies additional requirements and limitations with respect to appropriations made available or authority granted under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
