<bill session="106" type="h" number="974" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-12">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia College Access Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">District of Columbia College Access Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">District of Columbia College Access Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">District of Columbia College Access Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">District of Columbia College Access Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">District of Columbia College Access Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program to afford high school graduates from the District of Columbia the benefits of in-State tuition at State colleges and universities outside the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1999-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1999-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1999-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1999-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1999-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1999-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1999-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1999-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-04">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-05-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 106-158, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Ways and Means Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than May 24, 1999.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-05-24T12:04:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="88">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 88.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis (VA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3465-3469" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 974.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-05-24T14:32:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3465-3466" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-08-03">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Thompson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 106-154. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-09-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="275">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 275.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-10-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12851-12853" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S12851-12853" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-19">
      <text>Amendment SP 2317 proposed by Senator Specter for Senator Thompson.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-19">
      <text>Amendment SP 2317 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-19">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1999-10-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-10-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-01T15:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis (VA) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-01T15:51:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on agreeing to the Senate amendment to H.R. 974.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1999-11-01T16:27:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11170-11176" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-01T16:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-01">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1999-11-12">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1999-11-12" type="public" number="106-98">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-98.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, Restructuring and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="College entrance requirements"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2317"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/19/1999--Passed Senate amended.
District of Columbia College Access Act of 1999 - Directs the Mayor of the District of Columbia to award grants to eligible public institutions of higher education in Maryland or Virginia (or outside such States if specified conditions are met) that enroll eligible District of Columbia students to pay the difference between in-State and out-of-State tuition and fees on behalf of such students. Limits a student to an award of not more than $10,000 per year, and a total of not more than $50,000. Requires the Mayor to prorate award payments for eligible part-time students.Provides a formula for the ratable reduction of such payments if the funds appropriated under this Act for any fiscal year are insufficient to meet such limitations. Allows the Mayor to adjust the reduction based on: (1) the financial need of the eligible students to avoid undue hardship to them; or (2) undue administrative burdens on the Mayor. Authorizes the Mayor, also, to prioritize the making or amount of tuition and fee payments based on the income and need of eligible students.Authorizes the Mayor, if it would be more efficient, to enter into a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement with another public or private entity to administer the program. Requires the Secretary of Education to enter into a Memorandum of Agreement that describes the manner in which the Mayor shall consult with the Secretary with respect to program administration and any technical or other assistance the Secretary shall provide. Requires the Mayor to report annually to Congress on the number of eligible students attending each eligible institution and the amount of the grant awards (including any ratable reductions) paid to those institutions on behalf of such students, and the progress in obtaining recognized academic credentials of the cohort of eligible students for each year.Requires the Comptroller General to: (1) monitor the effect of the program on educational opportunities for eligible students; (2) analyze whether eligible students had difficulty gaining admission to eligible institutions because of any preference afforded in-State residents by eligible institutions; (3) analyze the extent to which there are an insufficient number of eligible institutions to which District students can gain admission, including admission aided by assistance under this Act, due to caps on the number of out-of-State students the institution will enroll, significant barriers imposed by academic entrance requirements, and absence of admission programs benefitting minority students; and (4) assess the impact of the program assisted under this Act on enrollment of the University of the District of Columbia (University). Requires reports to Congress and the Mayor.Authorizes appropriations for FY 2000 and for each of the five succeeding fiscal years.(Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary of Education to provide financial assistance to the University for each fiscal year to enable it to carry out activities authorized under the Higher Education Act of 1965.Authorizes appropriations for FY 2000 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.(Sec. 5) Requires the Mayor to award grants, on behalf of an eligible student, to: (1) an eligible private, nonprofit, associate or baccalaureate degree-granting institution whose main campus is located in the District, in the cities of Alexandria, Falls Church, or Fairfax, or the counties of Arlington or Fairfax, Virginia, or in the counties of Montgomery or Prince George's, Maryland; or (2) a private historically Black college or university whose main campus is located in Maryland or Virginia.Limits a student to an award of not more than $2,500 per year and a total of not more than $12,500. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2000 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.(Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary of Education to arrange for the assignment of an individual to serve as an adviser to the Mayor with respect to the programs assisted under this Act.Limits fiscal year administrative expenses for public and private school programs under this Act to seven percent of funds made available.Subjects each of such programs to audit and other review by the Inspector General of the Department of Education in the same manner as programs are audited and reviewed under the Inspector General Act of 1978.</summary>
</bill>
