<bill session="107" type="hc" number="39" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-02-27T17:27:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-02-27T17:27:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Honoring the ultimate sacrifice made by 28 United States soldiers killed by an Iraqi missile attack on February 25, 1991, during Operation Desert Storm, and resolving to support appropriate and effective theater missile defense programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400428"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="2001-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-02-27T15:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Weldon (PA) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-02-27T15:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H426-429" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-02-27T15:22:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-02-27T15:41:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-02-27T17:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H429-430" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-02-27T17:27:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="16" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 395 - 0, 2 Present (Roll no. 16).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H426-427" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-02-27T17:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-02-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="sc" number="19"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Air defenses"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Antimissile missiles"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Army personnel"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Guided missiles"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf War"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2001--Passed House without amendment.
Extends sympathy and thanks to the families of Specialist Steven E. Atherton, Corporal Stanley Bartusiak, Specialist John A. Boliver, Jr., Sergeant Joseph P. Bongiorni III, Sergeant John T. Boxler, Specialist Beverly S. Clark, Sergeant Allen B. Craver, Corporal Rolando A. Delagneau, Specialist Steven P. Farnen, Specialist Duane W. Hollen, Jr., Specialist Glen D. Jones, Specialist Frank S. Keough, Specialist Anthony E. Madison, Specialist Steven G. Mason, Specialist Christine L. Mayes, Specialist Michael W. Mills, Specialist Adrienne L. Mitchell, Specialist Ronald D. Rennison, Private First Class Timothy A. Shaw, Specialist Steven J. Siko, Corporal Brian K. Simpson, Specialist Thomas G. Stone, Specialist James D. Tatum, Private First Class Robert C. Wade, Sergeant Frank J. Walls, Corporal Jonathan M. Williams, Specialist Richard V. Wolverton, and Specialist James E. Worthy, all of whom were killed by an Iraqi missile attack on February 25, 1991, while in service to their country.Resolves to support appropriate and effective theater missile defense programs to help prevent attacks on forward deployed U.S. forces from occurring again.</summary>
</bill>
