<bill session="104" type="h" number="1455" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tobacco Health Tax and Agricultural Conversion Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the tax on tobacco products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1995-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1995-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1995-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E809-810"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diversification in industry"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Farm produce"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free ports and zones"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
    <term name="Tobacco tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/1995--Introduced.
Tobacco Health Tax and Agricultural Conversion Act of 1995 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the excise tax on: (1) cigars; (2) cigarettes; (3) cigarette papers and tubes; (4) snuff; and (5) chewing and pipe tobacco. Imposes an additional tax on packs of cigarettes containing fewer than 20 cigarettes. Provides an inflation adjustment of such tax rates. Imposes a tax on the floor stocks of such tobacco products which are removed before October 1, 1995. Imposes such tax on such products entered into the United States from foreign trade zones before such date. Requires tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes transferred or removed in bond from domestic factories and export warehouses (and thereby exempt from tax) to be appropriately labeled for export. Imposes a civil penalty on any person who sells, relands, or receives tobacco products labeled for export. Restricts the importation of previously exported tobacco products. Repeals the following exemptions from tax: (1) sales to employees of tobacco products manufacturers; (2) sales to the United States; and (3) books of cigarette papers containing 25 or fewer papers. Imposes minimum capacity or activity requirements (prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury) for granting of a permit to commence business as a tobacco products manufacturer or export warehouse proprietor. Imposes an excise tax on the manufacture or importation of roll-your-own tobacco. Establishes in the Treasury the Tobacco Conversion and Health Education Trust Fund (consisting of a Tobacco Conversion Account and a Health Education Account), to which the Secretary shall transfer an amount equivalent to three percent of the net increase in revenues attributable to the tax increases imposed by this Act. Makes funds in the Tobacco Conversion Account available to: (1) assist farmers in converting from tobacco to other crops; and (2) provide grants and loans, including assistance to convert from tobacco production, to communities and persons involved in tobacco growing and tobacco product manufacture who are adversely affected by the tax increases in this Act. Makes funds in the Health Education Account available for expenditures to increase public awareness of health risks, including those of tobacco use. Establishes in the Treasury the National Fund for Medical Research, to which nine percent of the revenues resulting from the tax increases imposed by this Act shall be transferred for distribution to the member institutes and centers of the National Institutes of Health. Transfers the balance of the revenues from these increases to the Hospital Insurance Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
