<bill session="106" type="h" number="1607" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Charity Empowerment Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Charitable Choice Expansion Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assist States in providing individuals a credit against State income taxes or a comparable benefit for contributions to charitable organizations working to prevent or reduce poverty and protect and encourage donations to charitable organizations, to prohibit discrimination against nongovernmental organizations and certain individuals on the basis of religion in the distribution of government funds to provide government assistance and the distribution of such assistance, to allow such organizations to accept such funds to provide such assistance without impairing the relegious character of such organizations, to provide for tax-free distributions from individual retirement accounts for charitable purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400590"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="1999-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="1999-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400605" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1999-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="997"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Child care block grants"/>
    <term name="Church and state"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate philanthropy"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Factories"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Flat-rate tax"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="General aviation aircraft"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Hate crimes"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Industrial accidents"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental tax relations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Liability for aircraft accidents"/>
    <term name="Liability for traffic accidents"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State constitutions"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Assistance to States in Providing Charity Tax Credits Title II: Budget Offset Title III: Tort Reforms Relating to Charitable Contributions Title IV: Charitable Choice Expansion Act Title V: Tax-Free Distributions from Individual Retirement Accounts for Charitable Purposes Charity Empowerment Act of 1999 - Title I: Assistance to States in Providing Charity Tax Credits - Authorizes States with a charity tax credit under State law to allocate certain Federal grant funds for specified purposes. Requires any charity receiving creditable donations primarily to assist poor individuals.(Sec. 103) Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress on the effects of the charity tax credit under this title.Title II: Budget Offset - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reduce the earned income credit for individuals without children.Title III: Tort Reforms Relating to Charitable Contributions - Relieves business entities of civil liability (except in cases of gross negligence or intentional misconduct) relating to any injury or death: (1) resulting from use of equipment the entity donates, or from the operation (outside the scope of business of the entity) of aircraft or a motor vehicle loaned, to a nonprofit organization; (2) occurring at a facility of the entity used by a nonprofit organization (outside the scope of business of the entity), or during a tour of the facility (in an area otherwise not accessible to the general public). Preempts State liability law in this matter, but allows a State to elect not to allow this title to apply.Title IV: Charitable Choice Expansion Act - Charitable Choice Expansion Act of 1999 - Amends the Revised Statutes to prohibit the Federal Government and State or local governments receiving Federal funds for any assistance program (except certain education and child care programs) from discriminating against an organization providing assistance under, or applying to provide assistance under, such a program, on the basis that the organization has a religious character.Title V: Tax-free Distributions from Individual Retirement Accounts for Charitable Purposes - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from an individual's gross income any qualified distributions from individual retirement accounts to tax-exempt charitable organizations, charitable remainder trusts, pooled income funds, and charitable gift annuities.</summary>
</bill>
