<bill session="104" type="h" number="3411" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tenth Amendment Enforcement Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the rights of the States and the people from abuse by the Federal Government; to strengthen the partnership and the intergovernmental relationship between State and Federal Governments; to restrain Federal agencies from exceeding their authority; to enforce the Tenth Amendment to the Constitution; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400368"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="1629"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="Regulatory reform"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States' rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/1996--Introduced.
Tenth Amendment Enforcement Act of 1996 - Requires that, on or after January 1, 1997, any statute enacted by the Congress must include specified findings and declarations about the Constitutional authority of the Congress in enacting such statute to preempt State and local laws. Makes it out of order for the Senate or House of Representatives to consider any legislation that does not include such declarations, unless a supermajority in either House vote otherwise. Amends Federal law to prohibit any executive department or agency (Federal agency) from construing any statutory authorization to issue regulations as authorizing preemption of State law or local ordinance by rule-making or other agency action, unless the statute expressly authorizes issuance of preemptive regulations and the agency concludes that the exercise of State power directly conflicts with the exercise of Federal power under the Federal statute, such that the State statutes and the Federal rule promulgated under the Federal statute cannot be reconciled or consistently stand together. Provides for notice and opportunity for State comment when a Federal agency proposes preemptive rule making or other agency action. Requires each Federal agency to publish in the Federal Register a plan for periodic review of rules and regulations preempting State or local government powers.</summary>
</bill>
