<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="979" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:52-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2202" sequence="19"/>
  <status datetime="1996-03-21T18:09:00-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="400322"/>
  <offered datetime="1996-03-21"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to change the current H-2A temporary agriculture worker program by replacing the labor certification requirement with a labor attestation requirement; establish a three year pilot program which would have required employers to file a form with the State employment security agency in the area of intended employment; require employers to offer temporary agriculture workers housing or to offer a reasonable housing allowance; require employers to withhold 25 percent of the temporary worker's salary in a trust fund and accessible only when the worker returned home; and require that guest workers be issued an identification card including a picture and fingerprints that the employee must present to access the funds in the trust account.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to change the current temporary agriculture worker program by replacing the labor certification requirement with a labor attestation requirement. The end result is a three year alternative pilot program which would require employers to file a form with the state employment security agency in the area of intended employment. The amendment requires employers to offer temporary agriculture workers housing or to offer a "reasonable" housing allowance; directs the employer to hold 25% of the temporary worker's salary in a trust fund to be administered by the Justice Department and accessible only when guest workers return to their native countries; and requires that guest workers be issued an identification card including a picture and fingerprints that the employee must present to access the fund in the trust account.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21T16:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A019) offered by Mr. Pombo.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1996-03-21T18:09:00-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="85">
      <text>On agreeing to the Pombo amendment (A019) as amended Failed by recorded vote: 180 - 242 (Roll no. 85).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
