<bill session="106" type="h" number="1597" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Deadly Driver Reduction and Burton H. Greene Memorial Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 23, United States Code, to provide for national minimum sentences for individuals convicted of operating motor vehicles under the influence of alcohol.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1999-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Ground Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW10" subcommittee="Ground Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1005"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1005"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism treatment"/>
    <term name="Community service (Punishment)"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/1999--Introduced.
Deadly Driver Reduction and Burton H. Greene Memorial Act - Amends Federal transportation law to require the Secretary of Transportation to withhold five percent of the funds authorized for Federal aid highway programs for FY 2003, and ten percent of such amounts for subsequent fiscal years, from any State that has not enacted and is not enforcing a law that provides the following minimum sentences: (1) for a first conviction of operating a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcohol, revocation of the driver's license for six months, imposition of a $500 fine, and an assessment of the individual's degree of alcohol abuse and treatment; (2) for a first conviction of operating a motor vehicle with a blood alcohol concentration of .16 or greater, revocation of the individual's license for six months, or two years if the individual refused to take a breath test to determine the individual's blood alcohol concentration at the time of arrest, imposition of a requirement prohibiting the individual from operating a motor vehicle with a blood alcohol concentration of .05 or greater for five years, impoundment or immobilization of the individual's motor vehicle for 30 days, requiring the installation of an ignition interlock system on the individual's motor vehicle for 180 days, imposition of a $750 fine, ten days' imprisonment or 60 days' community service, and assessment of the individual's degree of alcohol abuse and treatment; (3) for a third conviction for operating a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcohol, revocation of license for one year, or two years if the individual refused to take a breath test, imposition of a requirement prohibiting the individual from operating a motor vehicle with a blood alcohol concentration of .05 or greater for five years, impoundment or immobilization of the individual's motor vehicle for 60 days, requiring the installation of an ignition interlock system on the individual's motor vehicle for one year, imposition of a $1,000 fine, ten days' imprisonment or 60 days' community service, and assessment of the individual's degree of alcohol abuse and treatment; and (4) for a third or subsequent conviction for operating a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcohol or for a second such conviction if the individual's first conviction was for operating a motor vehicle with a blood alcohol concentration of .16 or greater, permanent revocation of the individual's license (without exception). Allows funds withheld from a State during FY 2003 to be available for up to three fiscal years after such date (to allow a State to meet such requirement within such period), but allows no grace period with respect to funds withheld during the subsequent fiscal years.</summary>
</bill>
