<bill session="105" type="h" number="3116" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Examination Parity and Year 2000 Readiness for Financial Institutions Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Examination Parity and Year 2000 Readiness for Financial Institutions Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Examination Parity and Year 2000 Readiness for Financial Institutions Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Examination Parity and Year 2000 Readiness for Financial Institutions Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To address the Year 2000 computer problems with regard to financial institutions, to extend examination parity to the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision and the National Credit Union Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1998-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1998-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1998-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1998-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1998-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-02-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-02-24T14:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Banking and Financial Services. H. Rept. 105-417.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-02-24T14:33:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="238">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 238.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-02-24T14:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Leach moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-24T14:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H512-515" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-24T14:34:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-02-24T14:54:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-02-24T14:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-03-06" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1539-1540" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1998-03-06">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1998-03-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-03-10">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-03-20">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-03-20" type="public" number="105-164">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-164.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Bank management"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contractors"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal home loan banks"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Year 2000 computer problem"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/24/1998--Passed House amended.
Examination Parity and Year 2000 Readiness for Financial Institutions Act - Requires each Federal banking agency and the National Credit Union Administration Board (Board) to offer seminars to all depository institutions and insured credit unions under their respective jurisdictions on the implication of the Year 2000 computer problem for: (1) the safety and soundness of such institutions; and (2) their transactions with other financial institutions (including Federal reserve banks and Federal home loan banks). Requires such agencies and the Board to make available to all the institutions under their jurisdiction model approaches to common Year 2000 computer problems with regard to project management, vendor contracts, testing regimes, and business continuity planning. Defines Year 2000 computer problem as any problem which prevents information technology from accurately processing, calculating, comparing, or sequencing date or time data: (1) from, into, or between the 20th and 21st centuries, or the years 1999 and 2000; or (2) with regard to leap year calculations. Amends the Home Owners' Loan Act to place under the regulatory authority of the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision a service corporation or subsidiary owned by a savings association. Permits the Director to authorize any other Federal banking agency to examine the service corporation or subsidiary if the agency supervises any other person maintaining an ownership interest in it. Subjects the corporation or subsidiary to the insurance termination prescriptions of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act. Provides that if such service corporation or subsidiary causes services to be performed for itself that are also authorized under this Act, such services shall also fall within the Director's regulatory purview. Amends the Federal Credit Union Act to subject a credit union organization owned in whole or in part by an insured credit union to examination and regulation by the Board to the same extent as an insured credit union. Permits the Board to authorize any other Federal agency to examine a credit union organization if such agency has supervisory authority over any activity of a credit union organization, or over any person maintaining an ownership interest in such organization. Subjects such corporation or subsidiary to the insurance termination and disciplinary requirements of the Federal Credit Union Act. Provides that if an insured credit union or credit union organization causes services to be performed for itself that are also authorized under this Act, such services shall also fall within the Board's regulatory purview. Terminates all power and authority conferred upon the Board by this Act as of December 31, 2001.</summary>
</bill>
