<bill session="105" type="h" number="4850" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate as wilderness certain lands within Rocky Mountain National Park, in Colorado.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409954"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-10-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11031-11033"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/16/1998--Introduced.
Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness Act of 1998 - Designates certain lands in Rocky Mountain National Park, Colorado, as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, which shall be known as the Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness. Provides that activities on, under, or affecting the lands designated as wilderness by this Act relating to the monitoring, operating, maintenance, repair, replacement, or use of the Colorado- Big Thompson Project (Project) and its facilities which were allowed as of June 1, 1998, shall be allowed to continue, and shall not be affected by the designation of such lands as wilderness. Allows any other activities necessary to respond to catastrophic events or emergencies and affecting continued use of such Project and its facilities, subject to reasonable restrictions established by the Secretary of the Interior to protect the wilderness values of such lands that will not permanently reduce the water supply capability of the Project or the Windy Gap Project.</summary>
</bill>
