<bill session="104" type="h" number="2770" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-13T20:28:00-05:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-12-13T20:28:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit Federal funds from being used for the deployment on the ground of United States Armed Forces in the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina as part of any peacekeeping operation, or as part of any implementation force.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403545"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401081" joined="1995-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1995-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="1995-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1995-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1995-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1995-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="408142" joined="1995-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1995-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1995-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1995-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T16:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 304 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2770 with 1 hour of general debate. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on the question of deploying troops to the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina. After general debate, it shall be inorder to consider in the House, H.R. 2770, debatable for 1 hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill without intervening motion, except one motion to recommit. After disposition of or postponement of further proceedings on H.R. 2770, it shall be in order to consider in the House H. Res. 302, relating to the deployment of troops in the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina, debatable for one hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motion. After disposition or postponement of the resolution, it shall be in order</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 304 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on National Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T18:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on International Relations discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T18:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on National Security discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T18:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 304.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14838-14849" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T18:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2770 with 1 hour of general debate. The resolution provides for 1 hour of general debate on the question of deploying troops to the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina. After general debate it shall be in order to consider in the House H.R. 2770, debatable for 1 hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill without intervening motion, except one motion to recommit. After disposition of or postponement of further proceedings on H.R. 2770, it shall be in order to consider in the House H. Res. 302, relating to the deployment of troops in the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina, debatable for 1 hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motion. After disposition or postponement of the resolution, it shall be in order to consider another resolution relating to Bosnia and Herzegovina, debatable for 1 hour.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T18:47:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T20:07:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE" datetime="1995-12-13T20:28:00-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="856" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 210 - 218 (Roll no. 856).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T20:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="304"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/1995--Introduced.
Prohibits the appropriation of Federal funds for the deployment on the ground of U.S. armed forces in Bosnia and Herzegovina as part of any peacekeeping operation or implementation force.</summary>
</bill>
