<bill session="106" type="h" number="1550" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-11-13">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fire Administration Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Fire Administration Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Fire Administration Authorization Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Earthquake Hazards Reduction Authorization Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Fire Administration Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Fire Administration Authorization Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for the United States Fire Administration for fiscal years 2000 and 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1999-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-10T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 106-133.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-05-10T14:27:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="72">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 72.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2946-2950" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1550.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11T18:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2960" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-05-11T18:22:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="121" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 417 - 3 (Roll no. 121).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-18">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-18">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10740" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-10-18" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-27T12:53:00-04:00">
      <text>House agreed to Senate amendment with amendments pursuant to H. Res. 655.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H11400-11401" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-27">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendments to Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-31">
      <text>Senate agreed to the House amendments to the Senate amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S11433-11336" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR S11433-14336" label="text as Senate agreed to House amendment to Senate amendment"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-31">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-31">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-11-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-11-13">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-11-13" type="public" number="106-503">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-503.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="hr" number="655"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1639"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Arson"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Earthquake engineering"/>
    <term name="Earthquake prediction"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seismology"/>
    <term name="Simulation methods"/>
    <term name="Smoke detectors"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Test facilities"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4324"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/27/2000--House agreed to Senate amendment with amendment.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: United States Fire Administration Title II: Earthquake Hazards Reduction Title I: United States Fire Administration - Fire Administration Authorization Act of 2000 - Amends the Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to authorize appropriations for FY 2001 through 2003, earmarking specified amounts for: (1) research activities; (2) contracts or grants to non-Federal entities for data analysis, including general fire profiles and special fire analyses and report projects; and (3) anti-terrorism training, including associated curriculum development for fire and emergency services personnel. Prohibits the obligation of authorized funds for FY 2002 unless the Administrator of the U.S. Fire Administration certifies to specified congressional committees that the obligation is consistent with the strategic plan transmitted pursuant to this Act.(Sec. 103) Requires the Administrator to report to specified congressional committees: (1) a five-year strategic plan of program activities for the Administration; and (2) the Administration's research agenda (to be used in the preparation of the strategic plan), as well as a plan for implementing such agenda. Specifies the contents of the strategic plan and the report.(Sec. 105) Directs the Administrator to make publicly available, including through the Internet, information on procedures for: (1) acquiring surplus and excess Federal equipment or property that may be useful to State and local fire, emergency, and hazardous material handling service providers; and (2) establishing cooperative agreements between State and local fire and emergency services and Federal facilities in their region relating to the provision of fire and emergency services.(Sec. 107) Requires the Administrator to: (1) assess and report to Congress on the need for additional capabilities for Federal counterterrorism training of emergency response personnel.(Sec. 108) Earmarks funds for the Worcester Polytechnic Institute fire safety research program.(Sec. 109) Requires the Administrator to make available through the Internet home page of the U.S. Fire Administration a brief summary of the results and importance of any research grant or award of $50,000 made with funds authorized by this Act.(Sec. 110) Repeals provisions of the Act with respect to: (1) reports to Congress on the establishment and effectiveness of master plans for fire prevention and control; (2) reports to Congress on ways the Federal government may better assist the States and local jurisdictions in providing for more effective arson prevention, detection, and control; (3) a study of the effectiveness of smoke detectors, heat detectors, and sprinkler suppression; and (4) a study of firefighter safety.(Sec. 111) Requires the Administrator to review and report to specified congressional committees on the courses of instruction available at the National Fire Academy to ensure that they are up-to-date and complement, not duplicate, courses of instruction offered elsewhere.(Sec. 112) Repeals Federal law provisions that deem newly constructed multifamily property in New York City, New York, to have met certain of the Act's automatic sprinkler requirements if an equivalent safety level has been met.(Sec. 113) Amends Federal law with respect to the National Fallen Firefighters Foundation and its Board of Directors.Title II: Earthquake Hazards Reduction - Earthquake Hazards Reduction Authorization Act of 2000 - Amends the Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977 to authorize appropriations to the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) for earthquake hazards reduction for FY 2001 and 2003.(Sec. 202) Authorizes appropriations for FY 2001 and 2003 to the Secretary of the Interior for carrying out, through the Director of the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), responsibilities assigned under the Act, with specified amounts available for the Global Seismic Network and the Scientific Earthquake Studies Advisory Committee established by this Act. Makes specified amounts available for FY 2001 and 2003 for a related USGS grant program.Authorizes additional appropriations for FY 2001 and 2003 for a USGS program to develop a prototype real-time seismic warning system.Authorizes appropriations under the Act for FY 2001 and 2003 for National Science Foundation (NSF) engineering and geosciences research and for the National Institute of Standards and Technology.(Sec. 203) Repeals a provision regarding non-Federal cost sharing for supplemental funds.(Sec. 204) Requires the USGS Director to: (1) establish an Advanced National Seismic Research and Monitoring System to modernize, standardize, and stabilize the national, regional, and urban seismic monitoring systems in the United States into a coordinated system; and (2) transmit a five-year management plan for the System to the Congress. Authorizes additional appropriations for FY 2002 through 2006 for expansion and modernization, and for FY 2002 and 2003 for operations.(Sec. 205) Requires the NSF Director to establish the George E. Brown, Jr. Network for Earthquake Engineering Simulation that will upgrade, link, and integrate a system of geographically distributed experimental facilities for earthquake engineering testing of full-sized structures and their components and partial-scale physical models. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2001 through 2004.(Sec. 207) Requires the FEMA Director to report to the Congress on elements of the earthquake hazards reduction program that specifically address the needs of at-risk populations, including the elderly, persons with disabilities, non-English-speaking families, single-parent households, and the poor. Requires such report to make recommendations for additional legislative authority required to address such needs.(Sec. 208) Requires the FEMA Director's comprehensive earthquake education and public awareness program to include development of means of increasing public access to available locality-specific information that may assist the public in preparing for or responding to earthquakes.(Sec. 209) Includes communications infrastructure among the lifelines covered by the Act.(Sec. 210) Requires the USGS Director to establish a Scientific Earthquake Studies Advisory Committee.</summary>
</bill>
