<bill session="106" type="h" number="3008" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Elementary and Secondary School Library Media Resources, Training, and Advanced Technology Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide up-to-date school library media resources and well-trained, professionally certified school library media specialists for elementary schools and secondary schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400306"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="1999-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1999-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="2000-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1999-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2000-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2000-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="2000-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1999-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1999-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1262"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Curriculum planning"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Librarians"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="School administrators"/>
    <term name="School libraries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student activities"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/1999--Introduced.
Elementary and Secondary School Library Media Resources, Training, and Advanced Technology Assistance Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to establish a program to provide for elementary and secondary school library media resources, including mandatory State allotments for library media resources and discretionary grants for school library access during non-school hours.Directs the Secretary of Education to make such allotments to applicant State educational agencies (SEAs) according to a specified formula. Allows the SEA and the Secretary to reserve specified amounts for certain statewide and national activities, including information dissemination. Requires SEAs to make allocations to applicant local educational agencies (LEAs) that have: (1) the greatest need for school library media improvement; and (2) the highest percentages of poverty. Sets forth authorized uses of such funds by LEAs, including: (1) acquisition of resources, including books; (2) acquisition of advanced technology; (3) resource-sharing among schools and their library media centers and public and academic libraries; (4) professional development for school library media specialists; and (5) collaboration between such specialists and teachers and administrators. Sets forth accountability requirements for continuation of funding. Authorizes appropriations.Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to applicant LEAs to provide students with access to libraries in elementary schools and secondary schools during non-school hours, including the hours before and after school, weekends, and summer vacation periods. Requires that priority be given to LEAs that: (1) seek to provide activities that will increase reading skills and student achievement; (2) have effectively coordinated services and funding with entities involved in other Federal, State, and local efforts to provide programs and activities for students during non-school hours; and (3) have a high level of community support. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
