<bill session="104" type="h" number="2566" updated="2012-11-01T22:44:46-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-10-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Campaign Finance Reform bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bipartisan Clean Congress Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform the financing of Federal elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1996-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="1995-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="401547" joined="1996-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="401854" joined="1996-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="1996-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1996-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1995-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1996-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1995-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="1996-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1996-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400584" joined="1996-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1996-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1996-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="406082" joined="1995-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1996-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1996-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1996-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1996-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1996-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400607" joined="1996-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1996-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="409650" joined="1995-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1996-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="410887" joined="1996-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1996-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1996-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1996-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1996-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1996-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business and politics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional allowances"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Facsimile transmission"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor union finances"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Primaries"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Term limits"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>10/31/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: House of Representatives Election Spending Limits and Benefits Title II: Reduction of Special Interest Influence Subtitle A: Elimination of Political Action Committees From Federal Election Activities Subtitle B: Provisions Relating to Soft Money of Political Parties Subtitle C: Soft Money of Persons Other Than Political Parties Subtitle D: Contributions Subtitle E: Additional Prohibitions on Contributions Subtitle F: Independent Expenditures Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions Bipartisan Clean Congress Act of 1995 - Title I: House of Representatives Election Spending Limits and Benefits - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to make candidates for election to the House of Representatives eligible to receive benefits under this Act if they declare that they will not exceed expenditure or contribution limits. Sets forth expenditure limits of $600,000 by a candidate and authorized committees, allowing additional expenditures for runoffs and contested primaries. Provides for complying candidates running against noncomplying candidates. Entitles eligible candidates to receive certain broadcast media rates and reduced postage rates. Provides for Federal Election Commission certification of whether a candidate is eligible. Mandates repayment of benefits not used as required and civil penalties for excessive expenditures. (Sec. 102) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to: (1) modify broadcast media candidate rate requirements; and (2) regulate rates for eligible House candidates. Regulates preemption. Changes the circumstances in which a station license may be revoked for failure to allow candidate access. Conditions new licenses and renewal on agreement to abide by these provisions. (Sec. 103) Amends Federal law to require postal rates for third class mail sent by eligible House candidates to be the same as for qualified nonprofit organizations. (Sec. 104) Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to set contribution limits for eligible House candidates. (Sec. 105) Sets forth expenditure reporting requirements. Title II: Reduction of Special Interest Influence - Subtitle A: Elimination of Political Action Committees From Federal Election Activities - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit, notwithstanding any other provision of the Act, any person other than an individual or a political committee from making contributions, soliciting or receiving contributions, or making expenditures to influence a Federal office election. Defines "political committee" to mean: (1) a candidate's principal campaign committee; (2) any national, State, or district political party committee; (3) certain local political party committees; and (4) combinations of a candidate's and a party's committees. Removes provisions that currently include in the definition of "contribution or expenditure" the establishment, administration, and solicitation of contributions to a separate political fund by a corporation, labor organization, membership organization, cooperative, or corporation without capital stock. Modifies the circumstances in which a political committee that has supported more than one candidate may be designated as an authorized committee. Restricts the political committees that may be financed or controlled by any Federal office holder or candidate. Repeals provisions limiting multicandidate political committee contributions to candidates and their authorized political committees. (Sec. 202) Limits the aggregate amount of large contributions to congressional campaigns. (Sec. 203) Limits to $100 the aggregate contributions by a lobbyist with respect to any Federal office election. Subtitle B: Provisions Relating to Soft Money of Political Parties - Prohibits political party national committees and any entity established, financed, or controlled by them from soliciting or receiving contributions or spending funds not subject to this Act. Requires amounts spent by a political party committee that might affect a Federal election (including voter registration, get-out-the- vote activity, generic campaign activity, and communications that identify a Federal candidate) to be made from funds subject to this Act. Prohibits political party committees from soliciting funds for or making donations to any organization that is tax exempt under section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code. Prohibits any Federal office holder or candidate and their agents from soliciting or receiving funds: (1) in connection with a Federal election unless the funds are subject to this Act; or (2) to be spent in connection with a non-Federal election unless the funds are not in excess of amounts permitted to Federal candidates and committees under provisions of this Act and are not from sources prohibited by this Act for Federal elections. Prohibits Federal office holders or candidates from having certain relationships with or taking certain actions regarding any organization described in section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code. (Sec. 212) Imposes or modifies political committee reporting requirements. (Sec. 213) Removes the exclusion of office facility construction or purchase contributions from the definition of "contribution." Subtitle C: Soft Money of Persons Other Than Political Parties - Imposes reporting requirements on disbursements over $2,000 by a person other than a political party committee or a candidate. Subtitle D: Contributions - Revises requirements regarding contributions made through an intermediary or conduit. Subtitle E: Additional Prohibitions on Contributions - Requires that 60 percent of contributions to a congressional campaign from individuals come from individuals legally residing in the candidate's State. Subtitle F: Independent Expenditures - Revises the definition of "independent expenditure." Declares that any expenditure that contains express advocacy and does not qualify as an independent expenditure is a contribution. (Sec. 252) Imposes reporting requirements relating to independent expenditures. Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions - Modifies or creates requirements regarding: (1) the use of contributions for campaign vs. personal expenses; (2) campaign advertising disclosures regarding who paid for and authorized the advertising; (3) the filing of designations, statements, and reports in electronic form and by facsimile machine; (4) random audits and investigations; (5) the filing of certain reports for the election cycle rather than for the calendar year; (6) reporting and recordkeeping regarding personal or consulting service expenditures; (7) the use of candidates' names by authorized, unauthorized, and party committees; (8) the monthly filing of certain reports, "best efforts" by a treasurer to comply with requirements, and Commission waiver of requirements; (9) filing of statements of organization; (10) the Commission's authority to appear in actions related to its duties or powers; (11) exclusive Commission action on committee insolvency; (12) promulgation of regulations to prohibit devices or arrangements to undermine or evade certain provisions of the Act; (13) limiting Commission members to one term; (14) the authority of the Commission to seek injunctions; and (15) administrative and judicial procedures. (Sec. 316) Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991 to replace House of Representatives mass mailings provisions with provisions establishing an Official Mass Mailing Allowance for Members of the House of Representatives. Modifies Member mail allowance requirements and prohibits certain transfers from other Member accounts. (Sec. 318) Declares that it is the intent of the Congress that any funds realized by provisions of this Act establishing the Mass Mailing Allowance shall be designated to pay for benefits provided by provisions of this Act relating to postal rates for third class mail sent by eligible House candidates. (Sec. 320) Provides for expedited and mandatory Supreme Court review of any appeal of any interlocutory order or final court action on the constitutionality of any provision of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
