<bill session="108" type="h" number="4373" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FERMI Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Furthering Education and Research through Mantis Improvements Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To preserve the preeminence of the United States in scientific research by improving the Visas Mantis security check program through a reduction of processing times and improvement in efficiency under such program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2004-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Border Security, and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Data transmission systems"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Foreign students"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2004--Introduced.
Furthering Education and Research through Mantis Improvements Act or FERMI Act - Requires the Secretary of State to: (1) provide consular officers with improved guidance regarding the operational structure and requirements of the Visas Mantis security check program (which protects against illegal transfers of sensitive technology); and (2) provide greater specificity in the Technology Alert List used under the program. Requires the Secretary and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to make fully interoperable the data systems used under the program. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on progress toward implementing these provisions. Establishes a three-year validity period for Visas Mantis security checks and revalidations. Permits revalidations in the United States. Allows multiple entries on a nonimmigrant visa for which a security check is required. Makes security checks valid across changes in nonimmigrant classifications. Creates an exception for national security concerns as determined by the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to submit annual reports on the Visas Mantis program to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
