<bill session="104" type="h" number="4168" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-10-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helium Privatization Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Helium Privatization Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Helium Act to authorize the Secretary to enter into agreements with private parties for the recovery and disposal of helium on Federal lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400083"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T14:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T14:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11268-11273" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T14:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-09-26T14:27:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T14:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-09-28" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11669" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1996-09-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-10-09">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-10-09" type="public" number="104-273">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-273.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3008"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biomedical engineering"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy transportation"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Gas storage"/>
    <term name="Girl Scouts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Helium"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Natural gas reserves"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/1996--Introduced.
Helium Privatization Act of 1996 - Amends the Helium Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) enter into agreements with private parties for the recovery and disposal of helium on Federal lands; (2) grant leasehold rights to such helium; (3) store and transport crude helium; and (4) maintain and operate existing crude helium storage at the Bureau of Mines Cliffside Field. Directs the Secretary to: (1) cease producing, refining, and marketing refined helium; and (2) dispose of all facilities, equipment, and Federal property interests relating to refined helium activities. Requires the Secretary to impose fees for helium storage, withdrawal, or transportation services. Prescribes guidelines for: (1) the purchase of helium by Federal agencies from certain private persons; and (2) the sale of crude helium by the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to make crude helium sales in amounts that will cause minimum market disruption. Mandates that proceeds from helium sales be paid to the Treasury. Instructs the Secretary to eliminate helium stockpiles by a prescribed deadline. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Texas Plains Girl Scout Council for consideration of one dollar specified lands in Potter County, Texas, reserving easements to the United States for pipeline rights-of-way. Directs the Secretary to: (1) enter into arrangements with the National Academy of Sciences to study and report to the Congress on whether disposal of helium reserves (including crude helium reserves) will have a substantial adverse effect upon U.S. scientific, technical, biomedical, or national security interests; (2) determine whether disposal of the helium reserve will have a substantial adverse effect on the U.S. helium industry, the U.S. helium market or such interests; and (3) if the Secretary determines that selling the crude helium reserves will have a substantial adverse effect on the industry, market, or such interests, make recommendations to the Congress, including proposed legislation, necessary to avoid such effects.</summary>
</bill>
