<bill session="104" type="h" number="1570" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Loan Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to reduce the level of participation by the Small Business Administration in certain loans guaranteed by the Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407669"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/3/1995--Introduced.
Small Business Loan Amendments Act of 1995 - Amends the Small Business Act (Act) to reduce the level of participation by the Small Business Administration (SBA) in loans guaranteed under the Act on a deferred basis to: (1) 70 percent of the balance of the financing outstanding, with respect to loans made under the Preferred Lenders Program; and (2) 75 percent of such balance, with respect to all other loans. Allows such percentages to be reduced upon request of the participating lender. Prohibits the SBA from using the percentage requested as a criterion for establishing priorities in approving guarantee requests. Limits the maximum interest rate under the Preferred Lenders Program to that charged to other loan guarantees under the Act. Increases the loan guarantee fee authorized to be charged by the SBA. Repeals provisions allowing participating lenders providing loans of less than $75,000 to retain a portion of the loan guarantee fee charged by the SBA.</summary>
</bill>
