<bill session="105" type="h" number="3334" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Royalty Enhancement Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide certainty for, reduce administrative and compliance burdens associated with, and streamline and improve the collection of royalties from Federal and outer continental shelf oil and gas leases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400404"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1998-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1998-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="1998-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="1998-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="1998-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1998-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400540" joined="1998-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-09">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Gas storage"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum storage"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/1998--Introduced.
Royalty Enhancement Act of 1998 - Declares that all royalty oil and royalty gas accruing to the United States under any oil and gas lease shall be taken in kind by the United States at the applicable delivery point for each lease premises. Sets forth rights, obligations, and responsibilities pertaining to such royalty oil and gas with respect to: (1) the United States; (2) the States; (3) the lessee; and (4) qualified marketing agents. Allocates costs responsibility and transporter charges between the lessee and the United States. Prescribes procedures for resolving royalty share imbalances between: (1) the amount of royalty oil or gas production taken by the United States from a lease premises during a calendar month; and (2) the amount of such production attributable to such lease premises for that month. Sets forth guidelines for transportation by truck, tanker, or barge for royalty oil or gas taken in kind from onshore or offshore lease premises for which there is no pipeline connection at the well. Exempts from coverage by this Act: (1) compensatory royalties; (2) minimum royalties; and (3) net profit share lease royalties prior to payout. Sets forth reporting requirements for lessees and qualified marketing agents. Empowers the Secretary of the Interior to audit their reports. Prescribes guidelines under which the Secretary shall direct qualified marketing agents to offer for sale to eligible small refiners an eligible small refiner portion, which is intended for processing, or trading for equivalent barrels for processing, in the eligible small refiner's refineries located in the United States, and not for resale in-kind or value. Instructs the Secretary to: (1) convene an eligible small refiner advisory panel to assist in developing policies and procedures to implement this Act; and (2) develop and implement procedures to ensure a fair and equitable opportunity for eligible small refiners to purchase royalty oil from the eligible small refiner portion. Amends the Mineral Leasing Act and the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to repeal existing royalty-in-kind authority. Declares that this Act does not: (1) affect the Deep Water Royalty Relief Act of 1995 or any other Federal law applicable to stripper or marginal production; or (2) apply to Indian lands.</summary>
</bill>
