<bill session="108" type="h" number="1954" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-04T17:19:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-04T17:19:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Armed Forces Naturalization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Armed Forces Naturalization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Armed Forces Naturalization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Naturalization and Family Protection for Military Members Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To revise the provisions of the Immigration and Nationality Act relating to naturalization through service in the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400202" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400212" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2003-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2003-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400384" joined="2003-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-05-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-05-19T19:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 108-111.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-05-19T19:58:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="57">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 57.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4899-4910" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1954.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T17:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4921" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-06-04T17:19:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="239" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 414 - 5 (Roll no. 239).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4899-4901" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-16">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Hatch with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="142">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 142.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Border Security, and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Marriage"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
    <term name="Widowers"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2003--Reported to Senate amended.
Naturalization and Family Protection for Military Members Act of 2003 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to naturalization through armed forces service during nonhostile periods to reduce the required qualifying service from three years to two. Prohibits imposition of naturalization application or certificate fees and related State documentation fees for armed forces members seeking to naturalize.Provides for overseas naturalization proceedings for members of the armed forces.Directs the Secretary of Defense to prescribe a policy that facilitates the opportunity for a member to finalize naturalization for which the member has applied.(Sec. 3) Qualifies the Selective Reserve of the Ready Reserve for such naturalization benefits.(Sec. 4) Retains the immediate relative status for the alien spouse (until remarriage), child, or parent of a U.S. citizen who served honorably in active duty status and died from injury or disease incurred in or aggravated by combat. Requires petition filing within two years of such death.Permits child or parent petitions for immigrant status in instances where the armed forces member had not filed prior to death.States that an application for status adjustment by the alien spouse, child, or parent of an alien member who was granted service-related posthumous citizenship may be adjudicated as if the death had not occurred. Requires application filing prior to such death.Treats the spouse, child, or parent of a lawful permanent resident who was granted service-related posthumous citizenship as a valid petitioner for immediate family status. Requires petition filing within two years of such death.Permits such aliens to apply for permanent resident status adjustment.Waives public charge inadmissibility grounds for such spouses, children, or parents. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to waive on an individual basis inadmissibility provisions concerning aliens present without admission or parole, lacking documentation, or unlawfully present, if the alien establishes exceptional and extremely unusual hardship to the alien or the alien's spouse, parent, or child who is a U.S. citizen or lawful permanent resident alien.(Sec. 5) Provides that a request for the granting of posthumous citizenship to a member of the armed forces who died from an active service-related injury or disease incurred during a period of military hostilities may be filed: (1) upon locating the next-of-kin, and if so requested by the next-of-kin, by the Secretary of Defense (or designee) with the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services in the Department of Homeland Security immediately upon the death of that person; or (2) by the next-of-kin. (Current law provides for such filing only by the next-of-kin or other representative.) Requires the Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services to approve a request for posthumous citizenship filed by the next-of-kin if: (1) the request is filed within two years after the later of enactment of this section or the date of the person's death, whichever is later; (2) the request is accompanied by a duly authenticated certificate from the executive department under which the person served attesting to the person's honorable service and service-related death; and (3) the Director finds that the person satisfied certain enlistment location or post-enlistment status requirements. (Current law provides for approval by the Attorney General within two years after the later of March 6, 1990, or the person's death.) States that the Director (currently the Attorney General) shall send the documentation of posthumous citizenship to the next-of-kin.(Sec. 6) Makes this Act effective as if enacted on September 11, 2001.</summary>
</bill>
