<bill session="105" type="h" number="2171" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protection of Student Athletes Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit athlete agents from soliciting representation of student athletes, and to establish requirements for contracts between athlete agents and student athletes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400116"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="College sports"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/1997--Introduced.
Protection of Student Athletes Act of 1997 - Prohibits athlete agents from initiating contact to solicit representation of student athletes who are subject to the rules and regulations of the National Collegiate Athletic Association, the National Association for Intercollegiate Athletics, or the National Junior College Athletic Association. Requires suspension of any agent, upon conviction for such an offense for the first time, from representing any student athlete who attends the college or university in which the student athlete who was the subject of agent-initiated contact is enrolled. Requires suspension of any agent, upon conviction of any subsequent offense, from representing any student athlete, and makes that agent guilty of a Class C felony and subject to a fine under specified Federal law. Establishes requirements for contracts between athlete agents and student athletes, including the specific wording of a warning to student-athletes about risks of loss of eligibility and other disciplinary actions.</summary>
</bill>
