<bill session="104" type="hr" number="260" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-09T18:01:00-05:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-11-09T18:01:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving a requirement of clause 4(b) of rule XI with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400107"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-11-09T18:00:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-330, by Mr. Diaz-Balart.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-11-09T18:01:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="116">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 116.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-12-06T11:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Dreier moved to table the measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-06T11:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Dreier asked unanimous consent that the resolution be laid on the table. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-06T11:48:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to table the measure Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14039" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/1995--Introduced.
Waives provisions of rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives that require a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to resolutions reported by such Committee on November 13, 1995, to provide for the consideration or disposition of a bill or joint resolution making further continuing appropriations for FY 1996 or increasing or waiving (for a temporary period or otherwise) the public debt limit, including any amendment, conference report, or any amendment from conference in disagreement thereon. Provides that this Act shall not apply to resolutions providing for consideration or disposition of reconciliation bills.</summary>
</bill>
