<bill session="108" type="h" number="4265" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that when a company makes a charitable donation of equipment, the company is generally not liable for harm later caused by that equipment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400159"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate philanthropy"/>
    <term name="Electronics"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Machinery"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Office equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2004--Introduced.
Protects business entities from civil liability under Federal and State law for any injury or death resulting from: (1) the use of equipment donated to nonprofit organizations by such entities; (2) the authorized use of facilities made available to nonprofit organizations by such entities where the use occurs outside the scope of business; or (3) the authorized operation of aircraft or motor vehicles loaned to nonprofit organizations by such entities for use outside the scope of business. Creates an exception for injuries or death resulting from a business entity's gross negligence or intentional misconduct. Preempts inconsistent State laws unless such laws provide additional protection for business entities or the State elects not to be covered by this Act. Makes the provisions of this Act inapplicable to civil actions in State court where all parties are citizens of the State and the State has opted out of coverage by such election.</summary>
</bill>
