<bill session="106" type="h" number="3709" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-10T16:01:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-05-10T16:01:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Internet Tax Freedom bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Internet Tax Moratorium bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Internet Nondiscrimination Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Internet Nondiscrimination Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Internet Nondiscrimination Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make permanent the moratorium enacted by the Internet Tax Freedom Act as it applies to new, multiple, and discriminatory taxes on the Internet.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To extend for 5 years the moratorium enacted by the Internet Tax Freedom Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400577" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400135" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400605" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2000-02-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-02">
      <text>Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-05-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 8.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-05-08T18:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 106-609.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-05-08T18:50:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="332">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 332.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-05-09T20:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 496 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3709 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 496 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFUNDED MANDATE POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Conyers raised a point of order, pursuant to Sec. 425 of the Congressional Budget Act, against consideration of the bill. Mr. Conyers stated that the bill imposed an unfunded intergovernmental mandate in excess of $50 million. The Chair subsequently held that Mr. Conyers had met the threshhold required under the rule and the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the point of order. At the end of debate, the Chair will put the question on the consideration of the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T11:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 496.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2787-2821" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T11:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3709 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. The time for amendment under the five-minute rule is limited to two hours.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T11:15:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 496 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T11:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John E. Sununu to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T11:15:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3709.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the Chabot amendment to the Delahunt amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 496, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of agreeing to the Chabot amendment and to the Delahunt amendment, as amended or not, until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the Istook amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. A recorded vote was demanded and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 496, further proceedings were postponed until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that proceedings would now resume on the amendments debated earlier and on which recorded votes had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3709.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T15:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T15:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2801" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Conyers moved to recommit with instructions to Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House is debating the motion for ten minutes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 177 - 250 (Roll no. 158).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-05-10T16:01:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="159" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 352 - 75 (Roll no. 159).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T16:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-10T16:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-05-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="556">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 556.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="496"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2028"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2036"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental tax relations"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax auditing"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h678"/>
    <amendment number="h679"/>
    <amendment number="h680"/>
    <amendment number="h681"/>
    <amendment number="s3281"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/10/2000--Passed House amended.
Internet Nondiscrimination Act of 2000 - Amends the Internet Tax Freedom Act to prohibit, until October 21, 2006, a State or political subdivision from imposing: (1) taxes on Internet access, including such taxes generally imposed and actually enforced prior to October 21, 1998; and (2) multiple or discriminatory taxes on electronic commerce.Expresses the sense of the Congress that a State tax relating to electronic commerce, to avoid being multiple or discriminatory, should include, among other things: (1) a centralized, one-stop, multi-State registration system for sellers; (2) uniform definitions for goods or services that might be included in the tax base; (3) uniform and simple rules for attributing transactions to particular taxing jurisdictions; (4) uniform procedures for the certification of software that sellers rely on to determine non-multiple and non-discriminatory taxes and taxability; and (5) consistent electronic filing and remittance methods.</summary>
</bill>
