<bill session="104" type="h" number="19" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Trade in Financial Services Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage foreign countries to accord national treatment to United States banking, securities, and insurance organizations that operate or seek to operate in those countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1995-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1995-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Bank mergers"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="EEC countries"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Fair Trade in Financial Services Act of 1995 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury (the President in the case of insurance organizations) to identify foreign countries that may be denying national treatment to U.S. banking and securities organizations and determine whether such possible denial may be having a significant adverse effect on them. Requires the Secretary and the President, when making such determinations, to: (1) consider specified factors; and (2) initiate negotiations (through the U.S. Trade Representative, in the President's case) with such foreign country to ensure that it accords national treatment to such U.S. organizations upon the determination of such possible denial. Authorizes the Secretary to recommend to the appropriate Federal regulatory agency that it suspend consideration of, or deny a request for, authorization filed by a person of a foreign country determined to have denied such national treatment. Authorizes the President to recommend similar action to the Secretary with respect to the registration of alien insurance organizations. Prohibits such sanctions with respect to any request for authorization filed by specified U.S. depository institutions, securities organizations, or alien insurance organizations which do business in the United States as of a specified date (reciprocal grandfather exemptions). Requires the Secretary (the President with respect to insurance organizations) to report annually to the Congress on foreign countries that deny national treatment to such U.S. organizations. Prohibits alien insurance organizations from engaging in insurance activities within the United States unless certain registration and related State requirements have been met.</summary>
</bill>
