<bill session="108" type="h" number="4167" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for the motor vehicle safety and information and cost savings programs of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration for fiscal years 2005 through 2007, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Automobile insurance"/>
    <term name="Automobile parts"/>
    <term name="Automobile repair"/>
    <term name="Automobile theft"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Driver education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Natural gas vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Safety appliances"/>
    <term name="School buses"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seat belts"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2004--Introduced.
Amends Federal transportation law to authorize appropriations for the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA). Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to participate and cooperate through various means in international activities to enhance motor vehicle and traffic safety. Prohibits a person from affixing a certification label to a motor vehicle or motor vehicle equipment item unless the person has either performed tests or documented the basis for certifying compliance with applicable safety standards. Applies certain defect and motor vehicle safety noncompliance notification requirements to original motor vehicle equipment. Prohibits a dealer from selling a used motor vehicle for other than resale or leasing a used motor vehicle until the dealer informs the purchaser or lessee of any notification of a vehicle defect or noncompliance that has not been remedied and certain other requirements are met. Requires a motor vehicle manufacturer to establish an Internet-accessible record system that used motor vehicle dealers and the public may access, without charge, to determine whether a manufacturer's vehicle has been subject to any notification of a defect or noncompliance that has not been remedied. Requires a person who owns or leases a school bus or motor vehicle used to transport passengers for compensation, and who receives notice of a defect or noncompliance, from operating the vehicle until the defect or noncompliance is remedied. Prohibits a Federal motor vehicle standard from requiring or allowing a manufacturer to comply with it by using a safety belt interlock designed to prevent starting or operating a motor vehicle if the occupant is not using a safety belt. Authorizes the Secretary to expend a specified amount per year to conduct a safety research initiative for alternative fuel vehicles and research into vehicle-based driver assistance technologies. Authorizes appropriations for the NHTSA to carry out certain motor vehicle information and cost savings requirements. Increases civil penalties for persons who violate the prohibition against tampering with motor vehicle odometers.</summary>
</bill>
