<bill session="106" type="h" number="1930" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prisoner Web Site Disclosure Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require the operator of a World Wide Web site that offers to provide communication with any prisoner to disclose on the site the crime for which the prisoner is incarcerated and the release date for the prisoner.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400244"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/1999--Introduced.
Prisoner Web Site Disclosure Act of 1999 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit a person from offering, by means of the World Wide Web, to provide any communication with an incarcerated individual unless such offer also contains notice, clearly and conspicuously, of: (1) the crime(s) for which such individual is incarcerated; and (2) the earliest date on which such individual may be released. Makes such prohibition inapplicable to telecommunications carriers and other telecommunications service providers. Provides civil penalties. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to make widely available information designed to inform the public regarding the above prohibition, and to make such information available on the World Wide Web site of the FCC and in such other manners as determined appropriate.</summary>
</bill>
