<bill session="105" type="h" number="1785" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 31, United States Code, to provide an automatic continuing appropriation for the United States Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/1997--Introduced.
Provides for an automatic continuing appropriation for the U.S. Government whenever a regular appropriation bill or continuing resolution for a fiscal year does not become law prior to the beginning of such fiscal year. Appropriates such sums as may be necessary to continue any project or activity for which funds were provided in the preceding fiscal year: (1) in the amount provided in the corresponding regular appropriation Act or continuing resolution for such preceding fiscal year; or (2) if such corresponding appropriation bill or continuing resolution did not become law, then as provided by this Act. Sets forth the terms and conditions relating to such continuing appropriations. Prohibits funding for any project or activity: (1) for which there is no authorization of appropriations for such fiscal year; or (2) during a fiscal year if any other provision of law makes an appropriation, makes funds available, grants continuation authority, or specifically prohibits funding or authority for such project or activity.</summary>
</bill>
