<bill session="105" type="h" number="1758" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-11T18:29:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-06-11T18:29:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">NATO Enlargement bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">European Security Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">European Security Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that the enlargement of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) proceeds in a manner consistent with United States interests, to strengthen relations between the United States and Russia, to preserve the prerogatives of the Congress with respect to certain arms control agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1997-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-03T21:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 159 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1757 and H.R. 1758. Providing for the consideration of H.R. 1757 in the Committee of the Whole, and consideration of H.R. 1758 in the House. The rule provides for the consideration of H. R. 1757 under an open rule and for consideration of H.R. 1758 under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate on each bill. After engrossment of H.R. 1758, the Clerk shall await disposition of H.R. 1758 and add the text of the latter bill as a new matter at the end of H.R. 1757. H.R. 1758 shall then be considered as having been laid on the table. A motion to recomit with or without instructions shall be in order regarding H.R. 1757. A motion to recommit shall be in order regarding H.R. 1758.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-04T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 159 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T17:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 159.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3707-3717" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T17:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1757 and H.R. 1758. Providing for the consideration of H.R. 1757 in the Committee of the Whole, and consideration of H.R. 1758 in the House. The rule provides for the consideration of H.R. 1757 under an open rule and for consideration of H.R. 1758 under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate on each bill. After engrossment of H.R. 1758, the Clerk shall await disposition of H.R. 1758 and add the text of the latter bill as a new matter at the end of H.R. 1757. H.R. 1758 shall then be considered as having been laid on the table. A motion to recommit with or without instructions shall be in order regarding H.R. 1757. A motion to recommit shall be in order regarding H.R. 1758.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T17:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Frank (MA) moved to recommit with instructions to International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee on International Relations reported the bill back to the House with an amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3717" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-06-11T18:29:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T18:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T18:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 159, the text of H.R. 1758 was appended to the engrossment of H.R. 1757.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T18:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Laid on the table. See H.R. 1757 for further action.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3717" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="159"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="1757"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Antimissile missiles"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms control negotiations"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missile defenses"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="CIS countries"/>
    <term name="Caucasus"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Central Europe"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Collective security agreements"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Conventional weapons"/>
    <term name="Defense burdensharing"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Eastern Europe"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estonia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intercontinental ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Latvia"/>
    <term name="Lithuania"/>
    <term name="Management information systems"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military construction operations"/>
    <term name="Military maneuvers"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military posture"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="NATO enlargement"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Romania"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Tactical nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treaty-making power"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h178"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/11/1997--Passed House amended.
European Security Act of 1997 - Designates Romania, Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania, provided they meet certain criteria, as eligible to receive assistance under the NATO Participation Act of 1994. (Sec. 3) Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) such countries are to be commended for their progress toward political and economic reform and meeting the guidelines for prospective NATO members; and (2) upon their complete satisfaction of all relevant criteria, such countries should be invited to become full NATO members at the earliest possible date. Makes funds under the NATO Participation Act of 1994 available to support the implementation of the Regional Airspace Initiative and the Partnership for Peace Information Management System. Extends through FY 1999 the Department of Defense's authority to transfer excess defense articles to countries eligible to participate in the Partnership for Peace and eligible for assistance under the Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989. (Sec. 4) Authorizes the President to approve on behalf of the United States the Document Agreed Among States Parties to the Treaty on Conventional Armed Forces in Europe dated November 19, 1990, adopted in Vienna, Austria, on May 31, 1996, concerning the resolution of issues related to the Conventional Armed Forces in Europe (CFE) Treaty flank zone. Expresses the sense of the Congress that any revisions to the Treaty on Conventional Armed Forces in Europe can enter into force only if specifically approved in a manner described under the Arms Control and Disarmament Act. Prohibits approval of any Treaty revisions that jeopardize U.S. security interests in Europe, or the effectiveness and flexibility of NATO as a defensive alliance, by: (1) extending rights or imposing responsibilities on new NATO members different from those applicable to current NATO members, including with respect to nuclear weapons deployment and the stationing of other NATO troops and equipment; (2) limiting NATO's ability to defend the territory of new NATO members by restricting defense infrastructure construction or limiting NATO's ability to deploy necessary reinforcements; (3) providing any international organization or any non-NATO country with authority to review, delay, veto, or otherwise impede deliberations and decisions of the North Atlantic Council or their implementation, including with respect to NATO force deployment or the admission of additional members to NATO; or (4) impeding the development of enhanced relations between NATO and other non-NATO European countries by, for example, recognizing spheres of influence in Europe. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary of Defense to carry out a program of cooperative ballistic missile defense-related projects with the Russian Federation. Urges the President to initiate a dialogue with the Russian Federation aimed at exploring the potential for mutual accommodation of outstanding issues between the two nations on matters relating to ballistic missile defense and the Anti-Ballistic Missile Treaty of 1972, including the possibility of developing a strategic relationship not based on mutual nuclear threats. (Sec. 6) Declares that an ABM-TMD (anti-ballistic missile-theater missile defense) demarcation agreement shall not be binding on the United States unless it is specifically approved in a manner described under the Arms Control and Disarmament Act. (Sec. 7) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the United States already pays more than a proportionate share of the costs of the common defense of Europe, and the European members of NATO should pay the bulk of the costs of NATO expansion which are incurred by existing NATO members.</summary>
</bill>
