<bill session="107" type="h" number="3357" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-11-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-11-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-11-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Terrorism Risk Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure the continued financial capacity of insurers to provide coverage for risks from terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="2001-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="2001-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2001-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="2001-11-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-11-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Ways and Means, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-28">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-28">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="3210"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Business insurance"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Capital formation"/>
    <term name="Casualty insurance"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Expropriation"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Property insurance"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Self-insurance"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation insurance"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/28/2001--Introduced.
Terrorism Risk Protection Act - Confers responsibility upon the Secretary of the Treasury (Secretary) to implement a financial assistance program for commercial property and casualty insurers when industry-wide insured losses from acts of terrorism exceed $1 billion.Expresses the sense of Congress that acts of terrorism resulting in insured losses greater than $100 billion would necessitate further action by the Congress to address such additional losses.Sets forth repayment mechanisms under the financial assistance plan which provide for: (1) an assessments schedule; and (2) a terrorism loss repayment surcharge plan based upon imposing a policyholder premium surcharge on commercial property and casualty insurance.Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC) should develop appropriate definitions for acts of terrorism and appropriate standards for making determinations regarding such acts; (2) each State should adopt those definitions and standards for purposes of regulating insurance coverage in that State; (3) the Secretary should advocate and promote the development of definitions and standards appropriate for purposes of this Act; and (4) after such consultation, the Secretary should adopt definitions for acts of terrorism and standards for determinations appropriate for this Act.Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the NAIC should develop appropriate guidelines for commercial insurers and pools regarding maintenance of reserves against the risks of acts of terrorism; and (B) each State should adopt such guidelines for purposes of regulating commercial insurers doing business in that State.Expresses the sense of Congress that the States should require that the price of terrorism insurance coverage, including the costs of any terrorism related assessments or surcharges under this Act, be separately disclosed.Declares that a Federal cause of action shall be the exclusive remedy if assessments or surcharges are required due to insured losses resulting from acts of terrorism. Limits damages in actions regarding insurance claims and attorneys' fees. Prohibits the award of punitive damages, or of non-economic damages in excess of the defendant's direct proportion of responsibility for the plaintiff's physical harm.Instructs the President to establish a commission to study and report to Congress on the potential effects of an act of terrorism on the life insurance industry in the United States and the markets served by such industry.</summary>
</bill>
