<bill session="104" type="h" number="857" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ticket Fee Disclosure Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the disclosure of service and other charges on tickets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1995-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="407899" joined="1995-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1995-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E294-295"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/1995--Introduced.
Ticket Fee Disclosure Act of 1995 - Prohibits any seller or reseller (including any ticket broker) of entertainment or sporting event tickets from failing to: (1) disclose to a purchaser of such a ticket, prior to purchase, any fee, charge, or assessment (other than a tax or other levy imposed pursuant to Federal, State, or local law) to be imposed in excess of the face amount of the ticket; and (2) have the amount of any such cost imprinted on the ticket or on a receipt evidencing any such ticket sale. Directs that such provision be enforced by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) under the Federal Trade Commission Act (FTCA). Treats any violation of such provision as a violation of a rule under the FTCA regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices. Authorizes State attorneys general to bring civil actions on behalf of their residents whenever they believe that the interests of such residents have been or are being threatened or adversely affected because of an act or practice in violation of such provision. Requires the FTC to study, and report to specified congressional committees on, the practices of persons involved in the sale and resale of entertainment and sporting event tickets.</summary>
</bill>
