<bill session="107" type="h" number="3683" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Play in Sports Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the National Institute of Standards and Technology to assist in the development of reliable and valid tests for banned performance-enhancing substances and to establish a research program on the long-term consequences of the use of such performance-enhancing substances.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400255"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Technology, and Standards.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Environment, Technology, and Standards" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and athletes"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Steroids"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/2002--Introduced.
Fair Play in Sport Act of 2002 - Directs the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), in consultation and cooperation with the United States Anti-Doping Agency, to: (1) establish a research program to develop and improve the reliability, validity, and cost-effectiveness of testing for performance-enhancing substances the use of which is prohibited in the Olympic Games; and (2) establish a research program to determine the long-term consequences of the use of such substances. Requires NIST to provide review and assessment assistance to the Agency with respect to the laboratory accreditation process and testing procedures delineated in the International Olympic Committee's Olympic Movement Anti-Doping Code.</summary>
</bill>
