<bill session="107" type="h" number="3558" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Species Protection and Conservation of the Environment Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Species Protection and Conservation of the Environment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect, conserve, and restore native fish, wildlife, and their natural habitats on Federal lands through cooperative, incentive-based grants to control, mitigate, and eradicate harmful nonnative species, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400331"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2001-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="2001-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-12-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2391-2392"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-14">
      <text>Joint Hearings held by the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans, by the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health, and by the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-14">
      <text>Joint Hearings held by the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health, by the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands, and by the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-14">
      <text>Joint Hearings held by the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands, by the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health, and by the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Received from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-512.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-06-18T14:08:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="307">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 307.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Exotic animals"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2002--Reported to House amended.
Species Protection and Conservation of the Environment Act - Establishes a program to control harmful nonnative species on Federal (and adjacent) land.(Sec. 4) Establishes the Aldo Leopold Native Heritage Grant Program which authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to make grants to eligible applicants, including State and local governments, interstate or regional agencies, or private persons, for qualified control projects to control and monitor harmful nonnative species on land or in water. Requires such projects to be conducted in partnership with a Federal agency and on adjacent lands, both Federal and non-Federal, in such a way as to prevent the future reintroduction or dispersal of harmful nonnative species. Requires the Secretary to consider the extent to which a project: (1) addresses the operational backlog of the National Wildlife Refuge System; (2) encourages intergovernmental and public- private cooperation; (3) aids the conservation of endangered species; and (4) includes pilot testing or a demonstration of an innovative technology.Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to States for assessment projects which address priorities for the restoration, management, or enhancement of native fish or wildlife and their natural habitats and processes through the control of harmful nonnative species.Requires the Secretary to consult with the National Invasive Species Council and its advisory board.States that grants shall be for up to two years for a control project, with a possibility of renewal, and for up to five years for a monitoring and maintenance plan. Requires grants to be balanced both geographically and according to the size of the projects.Limits the Federal share of costs of control projects on non-Federal lands to 75 percent (100 percent for Federal lands). Increases such share to 85 percent to cover innovative technology costs.Requires the Council to develop: (1) requirements for the monitoring and maintenance of a control project; and (2) a control project database which includes project techniques and monitoring data.Requires control project grantees to report annually to the Secretary on: (1) the number of acres of native fish and wildlife habitat restored, protected, or enhanced, including a description of the partnerships; (2) an estimate of the long-term success of varying conservation techniques used; (3) the environmental soundness of the projects; and (4) specific methods and techniques used.Directs the Secretary to report biennially to the appropriate congressional committees.Requires the participation of a non-Federal interest who will monitor and maintain the control project before a grant may be made for a control project on Federal lands.(Sec. 5) Authorizes the Secretary, at the request of a Governor, to financially assist a rapid response to outbreaks of harmful nonnative species when rapid eradication or control is: (1) necessary to protect native fish, wildlife, or their habitats; (2) technically feasible; and (3) minimally disruptive to the ecosystem. Requires the same monitoring and reporting as is required of control project grantees.(Sec. 7) Authorizes appropriations for FY 2003 through 2008, limiting administrative costs.</summary>
</bill>
