<bill session="104" type="h" number="2511" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-04T15:06:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-06-04T15:06:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Anticounterfeiting Consumer Protection Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Anticounterfeiting Consumer Protection Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To control and prevent commercial counterfeiting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401587" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404142" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="405317" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1996-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="407899" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="1995-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1994"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-03-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-05-06T13:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 104-556.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-05-06T13:38:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="270">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 270.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-04T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Moorhead moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-04T14:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5776-5780" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-04T14:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-06-04T15:06:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-06-04T15:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-04T15:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Laid on the table. See S. 1136 for further action.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="104" type="s" number="1136"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1136"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Copyright infringement"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Phonorecords"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Receiving stolen goods"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/1996--Passed House amended.
Anticounterfeiting Consumer Protection Act of 1996 - Makes the following (counterfeiting offenses) predicate offenses under the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act: (1) trafficking in counterfeit labels for phonorecords, computer programs or computer program documentation or packaging and copies of motion pictures or other audiovisual works; (2) criminal copyright infringement; (3) unauthorized fixation of and trafficking in sound recordings and music videos of live music performances; (4) trafficking in goods or services bearing counterfeit marks; and (5) interstate transportation of stolen property. (Sec. 4) Amends the Federal criminal code to extend to computer programs and computer program documentation and packaging existing prohibitions and penalties applicable to trafficking in counterfeit labels affixed or designed to be affixed to phonorecords or copies of a motion picture or other audiovisual work. (Sec. 5) Requires the Attorney General to include in a report to the Congress, on a district by district basis, an accounting of all actions taken by the Department of Justice that involve counterfeiting offenses. (Sec. 6) Amends the Lanham Act to: (1) require the court to order the seizure of an aircraft, vehicle, or vessel used in connection with a violation of such Act; and (2) permit the plaintiff, in a case involving the use of a counterfeit mark in connection with the sale, offering for sale, or distribution of goods or services, to recover, instead of actual damages and profits, an award of statutory damages, as specified. (Sec. 8) Repeals a provision allowing forfeited articles that are excluded from importation under Federal copyright law to be refunded to the country of export whenever it is shown that the importer had no reasonable grounds for believing that his or her acts constituted a violation of law. (Sec. 9) Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to: (1) direct the Secretary of the Treasury, after forfeiture of merchandise bearing a counterfeit American trademark, to destroy the merchandise; or (2) alternatively, authorize the Secretary to obliterate the trademark where feasible and dispose of the goods seized as specified if the merchandise is not unsafe or a hazard to health and the Secretary has the consent of the trademark owner. (Sec. 10) Establishes civil penalties for aiding and abetting the importation for sale or public distribution of merchandise that is seized for bearing a counterfeit American trademark. Sets limits on fines for first and subsequent seizures, based on the value that the merchandise would have had if it were genuine. Specifies that the imposition of such fine shall be within the discretion of the Customs Service and in addition to any other civil or criminal penalty or other remedy authorized by law. (Sec. 11) Provides for the public disclosure of aircraft manifests. (Sec. 12) Directs the Secretary to require that entry documentation contain information necessary to determine whether the imported merchandise bears an infringing trademark. (Sec. 13) Includes within the definition of "contraband": (1) a counterfeit label for a phonorecord, computer program or its documentation or packaging, or motion picture or other audiovisual work; (2) a phonorecord or copy that criminally infringes a copyright; (3) a prohibited unauthorized fixation of a sound recording or music video of a live musical performance; or (4) any good bearing a counterfeit mark.</summary>
</bill>
