<bill session="107" type="h" number="4836" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Safe Medications Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish policies for any requirement by the Department of Veterans Affairs that veterans be required to split their medications as a cost-saving measure.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2002--Introduced.
Veterans Safe Medications Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to prescribe a policy for use by health care providers and pharmacies of the Department of Veterans Affairs of the practice of prescribing or dispensing tablet medication in a form that requires tablet splitting by the patient. Mandates that such policy shall allow tablet splitting only if: (1) a health care professional has determined that the patient has the mental and physical ability to use a tablet splitter; (2) the tablets are in a form referred to as "scored"; (3) the tablets are not sustained-release; (4) the tablets are intended to be taken every 48 hours or more frequently; and (5) an effective tablet splitter has been provided to the patient.Directs the Secretary to require that any adverse events directly attributable to tablet splitting be reported to the Under Secretary of Health on a monthly basis. Requires the Under Secretary to establish a national formulary of medications that have been approved for tablet splitting.</summary>
</bill>
