<bill session="106" type="h" number="1183" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-08">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fastener Quality Act Amendments Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Fastener Quality Act Amendments Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Fastener Quality Act Amendments Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Fastener Quality Act Amendments Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fastener Quality Act to strengthen the protection against the sale of mismarked, misrepresented, and counterfeit fasteners and eliminate unnecessary requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400577" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1999-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400592" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="1999-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-29T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 106-121, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-29T16:35:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than April 29, 1999.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-29T16:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-04-29T16:39:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="64">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 64.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11T14:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2935-2941" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11T14:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1183.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-05-11T14:39:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2935-2937" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11T14:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1999-05-25" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5978" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1999-05-25">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1999-06-08">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1999-06-08" type="public" number="106-34">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-34.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Aircraft construction"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal negligence"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Industrial standards"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Product counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="Quality control"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Test facilities"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/1999--Passed House amended.
Fastener Quality Act Amendments Act of 1999 - Amends the Fastener Quality Act to define "accredited laboratory" to mean a fastener testing facility used to perform end-of-line testing required by a consensus standard to verify that a lot of fasteners conforms to the grade identification marking called for in the consensus standard to which they have been manufactured, and which meet certain requirements. Defines "consensus standard" to mean the provisions of a document that describes fastener characteristics published by a consensus standards organization or a Federal agency, and does not include a proprietary standard. (Sec. 3) Revises the definition of "fastener" to apply to fasteners only, not to components or products which can contain fasteners. Excludes from the definition (and coverage of the Act) any items: (1) sold in packages containing no more than 100 of any one screw, nut, bolt, stud, or washer; (2) produced to proprietary standards developed by private companies that use fasteners in the manufacture, assembly, or service of their products, and develop fastener standards under the company's name; (3) specifically manufactured for use on an aircraft if the quality and suitability of those fasteners for that use has been approved by the Federal Aviation Administration or by a foreign airworthiness authority; or (4) manufactured in accordance with a fastener quality assurance system meeting International Organization for Standardization (ISO) Standard 9000 and other specified criteria. (Sec. 4) Makes it unlawful for a manufacturer or distributor, in conjunction with a sale or offer for sale of a fastener from a single lot, to knowingly misrepresent or falsify: (1) the record of conformance for the lot of fasteners; (2) the identification, characteristics, properties, mechanical or performance marks, chemistry, or strength of the lot of such fasteners; or (3) the manufacturer's insignia. Requires that mandatory end-of-line testing, in the case of fasteners manufactured solely to a consensus standard, be conducted by an accredited laboratory. (Sec. 5) Revises requirements for manufacturers' insignia on certain fasteners to require manufacturers to comply with insignia recordation requirements, unless the specifications provide otherwise. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to arbitrate civil penalties before a case is referred to the Attorney General. Repeals criminal penalties for negligent failure to maintain required fastener records. Directs the Secretary to establish a hotline system to facilitate the reporting of alleged violations of this Act and to investigate credible allegations reported through such system and report them to the Attorney General. (Sec. 7) Requires fastener manufacturers and importers to: (1) retain the record of conformance for fasteners for five years, on paper or in photographic or electronic format; and (2) make available upon the request of a distributor who has purchased a fastener (or a person who has purchased a fastener for use in the production of a commercial product) information in the record of conformance. Repeals the requirement that importers, private label distributors, and persons who make significant alterations to fasteners, as well as manufacturers, also retain all inspection, testing, and certification records for five years. (Sec. 10) Authorizes any person publishing a document setting forth guidance or requirements for the certification of manufacturing systems as fastener quality assurance systems by an accredited third party (or for the approval of accreditation bodies to accredit such third parties), or for the accreditation of laboratories (or for the approval of accreditation bodies to accredit such laboratories), to petition the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to approve the document, if it provides equal or greater rigor and reliability as compared to ISO-IEC Guide 62, 61, 25, or 58, as appropriate. Requires the Director, in addition to any other voluntary laboratory accreditation programs that may be established by private sector persons, to establish a National Voluntary Laboratory Accreditation Program for the accreditation of such laboratories. Requires an accreditation body accrediting third parties who certify manufacturing systems as fastener quality assurance systems, or accrediting laboratories, to affirm to the Director that they meet the requirements of ISO-IEC Guide 61 or 58, respectively. (Sec. 12) Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress on any changes in industry practice resulting from enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
