<bill session="108" type="hr" number="227" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-09T11:20:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-05-09T11:20:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide additional tax incentives to encourage economic growth.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-08T22:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 108-95, by Mr. Reynolds.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-08T22:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for debate in the House equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Ways and Means. The amendment recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill (H.Rept. 108-94) shall be considered as adopted. The rule waives all points of order against the bill, as amended, and against its consideration. Finally, the rule provides one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-05-08T22:01:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="38">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 38.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-05-09T09:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H3864-3902" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-09T09:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 227.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-09T11:12:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 203 (Roll no. 178).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2003-05-09T11:20:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="179" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 220 - 203 (Roll no. 179).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H3864" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-05-09T11:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="h" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2003--Passed House without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced in the House on May 8, 2003. The summary of that version is repeated here).Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 2 (providing additional tax incentives to encourage economic growth).</summary>
</bill>
