<bill session="108" type="h" number="5123" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Major Regulation Cost Review Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require agencies to review all major rules within 10 years after issuance, including a cost-benefit analysis using a standard government-wide methodology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2004-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400304" joined="2004-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and the Census.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO20" subcommittee="Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and the Census" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2004--Introduced.
Major Regulation Cost Review Act of 2004 - Amends Federal civil service law to require each Federal agency to publish in the Federal Register a plan, which may be amended at any time by publishing a revision, for the periodic review of all the major rules issued by the agency. Requires that the plan provide for review within five years after publication as a final rule, with a five year extension permitted. Directs the agency, in reviewing major rules, to consider: (1) the continued need for the rule; (2) the nature of complaints or comments received from the public concerning the rule; (3) the complexity of the rule; (4) the extent to which the rule overlaps, duplicates, or conflicts with other Federal rules, and with State and local governmental rules; and (5) the length of time since the rule has been evaluated or the degree to which technology, economic conditions, or other factors have changed in the area affected by the rule. Requires that: (1) the review include a cost-benefit analysis of the rule, including an identification and consideration of a range of less costly regulatory alternatives; and (2) each year each agency publish a list of the major rules which are to be reviewed and which are to be included in the accounting statement and associated report submitted to Congress by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget. Makes conforming changes to the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2001.</summary>
</bill>
