<bill session="106" type="h" number="2782" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Seniors Prescription Insurance Coverage Equity (SPICE) Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to assure access of Medicare beneficiaries to prescription drug coverage through the SPICE drug benefit program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="1999-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1999-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1480"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug utilization"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Medigap"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tobacco exports"/>
    <term name="Tobacco tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
Seniors Prescription Insurance Coverage Equity (SPICE) Act of 1999 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to add a new part D (SPICE Drug Benefit Program) (SPICE program) (redesigning the current Medicare part D (Miscellaneous Provisions) as Medicare part E (Miscellaneous Provisions) to establish a voluntary SPICE program, administered by the SPICE Board which also operates a Seniors Prescription Insurance Coverage Equity Office established within the Department of Health and Human Services, under which all individuals entitled to Medicare part A (Hospital Insurance) benefits and enrolled in Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) shall be provided access to coverage of outpatient prescription drugs that meet specified requirements. Grants such access via either enrollment in a Medicare+Choice (Medicare part C) plan, enrollment in a SPICE Medicare supplemental policy, or enrollment in a group health plan, all as defined by this Act. Provides for described financial assistance for covered beneficiaries for them to obtain enrollment coverage, with such assistance varying depending upon beneficiary income.Vests the Board with outreach and other specified duties, such as establishing procedures for enrollment and enhanced financial assistance with regard to eligible Medicare beneficiaries and the SPICE program, and conducting certain ongoing studies, as well as a study and report to Congress on permitting an alternative outpatient prescription drug benefit package under Medicare supplemental health insurance policies (Medigap) provisions.Outlines requirements for the offering of SPICE program coverage, which include prohibiting pre-existing condition exclusions with respect to coverage and allowing use of reasonable cost containment methods.Establishes in the Treasury the SPICE Trust Fund, consisting in part of amounts from the taxes imposed on tobacco and tobacco-related products and from the on-budget surplus, to be available only for expenditures to carry out the SPICE program. Makes appropriations and authorizes appropriations.Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 to include with Medigap policy comparison information for Medigap policies, information on the SPICE program for purposes of State grant application plans for State-wide health insurance, counseling, and assistance grants.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a variety of excise taxes on specified tobacco and tobacco-related products, as well as with regard to the manufacture or the importation of roll-your-own tobacco, and to make modifications to certain tobacco excise tax provisions, such as placing a restriction on importation of previously exported tobacco products.</summary>
</bill>
