<bill session="106" type="h" number="3997" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Money Return Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve systems for the delivery of dividends, interest, and other valuable property rights to lost security holders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400434"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400590" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="2000-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Responsibilities of the Securities and Exchange Commission Title II: United States Money Return Commission Money Return Act of 2000 - Title I: Responsibilities of the Securities and Exchange Commission - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to mandate that registered issuers of securities exercise due diligence in delivering dividends, interest, and other valuable property rights to their owners.Requires the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to extend the application of regulations governing the obligation of transfer agents to search for lost security holders to: (1) paying agents, including the obligation to use database searches; and (2) security holders who became lost security holders before a specified date. Prescribes notification procedures.Directs the SEC to establish a database accessible from the Internet with a listing of lost security holders and the issuers or paying agents obligated to deliver them their dividends, interest, and other valuable property rights.Requires that issuers or paying agents hold in trust the amounts to which security holders are entitled, including any accrued interest. Sets forth implementation guidelines.Title II: United States Money Return Commission - Establishes the United States Money Return Commission to: (1) collect and publish on the Internet and other media information on all money held by the United States that is owed to any person; (2) establish procedures for the use of state-of-the-art technology to restore such moneys to their rightful owners without charge; and (3) present an annual status report to the President.</summary>
</bill>
