<bill session="106" type="h" number="2051" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Transportation to investigate and hold public hearings in response to petitions claiming unreasonably high air fares or inadequate air carrier competition at airports.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airline rates"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/1999--Introduced.
Amends Federal aviation law to require the Secretary of Transportation to investigate and hold a public hearing with respect to each petition by the sponsor of a commercial service airport (or by the attorney general of a State on behalf of one or more persons, including governmental entities, with respect to an airport) claiming that fares for air transportation at an airport are unreasonably high, or that competition between air carriers at the airport is inadequate. Directs the Secretary to: (1) issue written findings in response to the issues raised in the petition; and (2) report to Congress the results of the investigations, if any. Directs the Secretary to review the marketing practices of air carriers that may inhibit the availability of quality, affordable air transportation services to commercial service airports. Requires the Secretary, if it is determined that one or more marketing practices of air carriers inhibit such services, to issue regulations addressing such practices.</summary>
</bill>
