<bill session="104" type="h" number="2715" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-24T13:35:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-04-24T13:35:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Paperwork Elimination Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Paperwork Elimination Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, popularly known as the Paperwork Reduction Act, to minimize the burden of Federal paperwork demands upon small businesses, educational and nonprofit institutions, Federal contractors, State and local governments, and other persons through the sponsorship and use of alternative information technologies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410887"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="402524" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407669" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="410067" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1996-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="411997" joined="1995-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Programs.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on Government Programs Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-03-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-04-16T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 104-520, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-23T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 409 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2715 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Providing for consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Smalll Business now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 409 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 409.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3749-3754" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2715 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 409 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Gene Taylor to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T12:38:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2715.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-04-24T13:35:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="130" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 418 - 0 (Roll no. 130).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO01" subcommittee="National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSSM15" subcommittee="Government Programs" name="House Small Business"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="409"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Appropriate technology"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Information policy"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h995"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/24/1996--Passed House amended.
Paperwork Elimination Act of 1996 - Amends the Paperwork Reduction Act to require the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to: (1) provide direction and oversee the use of information technology, including alternative information technologies to substitute for paper; (2) specifically promote the optional use of electronic information technology as such an alternative; and (3) provide within a required information resources strategic management plan a description of progress in providing for the use of electronic information as a substitute for paper. Requires each Federal agency to: (1) ensure that each information collection provides for the optional use of electronic maintenance, submission, or disclosure of information; (2) use alternative information technologies to reduce burden and improve data quality, agency efficiency, and responsiveness to the public; and (3) publish a description of how respondents may electronically maintain the information to be collected. Requires the Director to report to the Congress on the extent to which Federal agencies reduced the collection of information burden on small businesses and other persons through the use of electronic maintenance, submission, or disclosure of information as a substitute for paper maintenance, submission, or disclosure.</summary>
</bill>
