<bill session="107" type="h" number="1151" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Improve Voting Process bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Voting Opportunity Through Technology and Education Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Federal Election Commission to issue voluntary standards to promote the accessibility and effective use of voting systems, voting equipment, and polling places, to make grants to assist States in complying with such standards and carrying out other activities to promote accessibility in voting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2001-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2001-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2001-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2001-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1038"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in politics"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
    <term name="Voting of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Voting of the elderly"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2001--Introduced.
Voting Opportunity Through Technology and Education Act of 2001 - Directs the Office of Election Administration of the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to: (1) develop and publish revisions to the most recent version of voting system standards issued by FEC; and (2) expand the scope of such standards to include voluntary standards to promote for all individuals the accessibility of polling places and the effective use of voting systems and equipment that provide the opportunity for casting a secure and secret ballot.Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to direct the Office to serve as a clearinghouse of information on accessibility of voting systems and equipment and polling places for the elderly and individuals with disabilities.Provides that, after the issuance of the revised voting system standards by the Office, the FEC shall make grants to eligible States to: (1) bring voting systems and equipment, polling places, and voter registration facilities in the State into compliance with such revised standards; and (2) carry out other activities to promote the accessibility of voting systems and equipment, polling places, and voter registration facilities for the elderly and individuals with disabilities.Amends the Voting Accessibility for the Elderly and Handicapped Act to: (1) ensure that no citizen is denied the right to vote because the citizen is elderly or has a disability; and (2) restore certain reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
