<bill session="106" type="h" number="1965" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Asthma Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Education with increased authority with respect to asthma programs, and to provide for increased funding for such programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1999-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2000-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Asthma"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary school students"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection groups"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/1999--Introduced.
Asthma Act - Authorizes appropriations to the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute for FY 2000 through 2004 to expand the National Asthma Education and Prevention Program. Directs the coordinating committee for such Program to report to Congress: (1) a determination of the scope of asthma problems in the United States; (2) an identification of all Federal programs that carry out asthma-related activities; and (3) recommendations for strengthening and better coordinating Federal asthma-related activities. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to collaborate with the States to expand the scope of activities: (1) for determining the incidence and prevalence of asthma; and (2) carried out to prevent its health consequences. Directs the Secretary to conduct local asthma surveillance activities to collect data on the prevalence and severity of asthma and the quality of asthma management. Authorizes appropriations to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for such activities. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to nonprofit private entities to carry out outreach activities in applicant communities which provide: (1) information and education on asthma; and (2) referrals to health programs of public and private nonprofit entities that provide asthma-related services, including services for low- income individuals. Gives grant priorities to communities disproportionately affected by asthma or underserved by such health programs and in which a significant number of low-income individuals reside. Authorizes appropriations for the grant program. Directs the Secretary to encourage the States to carry out activities to assist children with respect to asthma, in accordance with Institute guidelines. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants for such purpose to those States with a State plan under title XXI (Children's Health Insurance) of the Social Security Act which provides for such activities, with a matching funds requirement of 50 percent of the Federal funds provided. Directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance to States to develop plans that will provide for such activities. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to local educational agencies to carry out, in communities with a significant number of low-income or underserved individuals, a program in elementary and secondary schools of such communities for conducting asthma-related activities for children who attend such schools. Authorizes appropriations. Expresses the sense of Congress that hospitals and managed care plans should undertake certain efforts to increase asthma-related education and training, asthma information and data, and asthma clinical practice guidelines. Expresses the sense of Congress that all Federal, State, and local asthma-related activities should: (1) promote the guidelines and other recommendations of the Public Health Service on asthma diagnosis and management; and (2) be designed in consultation with national and local organizations representing the medical, educational, and environmental communities, as well as advocates representing those affected by asthma.</summary>
</bill>
