<bill session="105" type="h" number="2967" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Insurance Consumer's Bill of Rights Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act and other laws to assure the rights of enrollees under managed care plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, Ways and Means, and Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Gynecology"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Obstetricians"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Physician-patient privilege"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Health Insurance Bill of Rights Title II: Application of Bill of Rights Under Various Laws Health Insurance Consumer's Bill of Rights Act of 1997 - Title I: Health Insurance Bill of Rights - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require a managed care group health plan (and a health insurer offering group coverage) to: (1) have a sufficient number and mix of primary care practitioners and specialists throughout the service area; (2) provide specialty care access, standing referrals, access to nonparticipating providers, and access without referrals to professionals trained in obstetrics and gynecology (allowing a professional trained in obstetrics and gynecology to be designated as a primary care practitioner); (3) not (if emergency services are covered) require prior authorization for services for emergencies (defined from the perspective of a prudent layperson); (4) not deny participation in, deny or limit coverage, or discriminate against a qualified enrollee (with a life-threatening or serious illness for which no standard treatment is effective) for participation in clinical trials; (5) provide coverage continuity when coverage is terminated; (6) not restrict medical communications between a health professional and the professional's patient; (7) disclose (if prescription drugs are covered but limited to a formulary) to enrollees the nature of the restrictions and make restriction exceptions when medically necessary or appropriate; (8) comply with certain utilization review requirements, including regarding a complaint and appeals process; (9) have an ongoing quality improvement program; (10) not discriminate on specified bases, including disability, genetic makeup, health status, payer source, or anticipated need for services; (11) ensure confidentiality; (12) provide enrollees and prospective enrollees with a prospectus containing specified information, including qualitative and quantitative information; and (13) not limit the manner in which particular covered services are delivered if medically necessary or appropriate. Title II: Application of Bill of Rights under Various Laws - Requires health insurers to comply with title I of this Act regarding group and individual coverage. Allows States to establish requirements at least as stringent on insurers as the requirements of title I of this Act. Amends the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 to provide for coordination by the Secretaries of the Treasury, Health and Human Services, and Labor regarding regulations, rulings, and interpretations concerning health insurance provisions of the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Internal Revenue Code. (Sec. 202) Amends ERISA to require group health plans (and insurers offering group coverage) to comply with title I of this Act. Allows States to establish requirements at least as stringent on insurers as the requirements of title I of this Act. (Sec. 204) Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require each Medicare+Choice organization offering a Medicare+Choice plan described in specified provisions to comply with title I of this Act, except when Medicare requirements are more protective of enrollees. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to allow Medicaid managed care organizations to not comply with Public Health Service Act health insurance requirements when those requirements are less protective of enrollees than Medicaid. Amends Federal law relating to the Federal Employees' Health Benefits Program to require plans offered under that Program to comply with title I of this Act, except when the Program's requirements are more protective of enrollees.</summary>
</bill>
