<bill session="106" type="h" number="3373" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-12-06">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Leif Ericson Millennium Commemorative Coin Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Lewis and Clark Expedition Bicentennial Commemorative Coin Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">United States Capitol Visitor Center Commemorative Coin Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Leif Ericson Millennium Commemorative Coin Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Lewis and Clark Expedition Bicentennial Commemorative Coin Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">United States Capitol Visitor Center Commemorative Coin Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in conjunction with the minting of coins by the Republic of Iceland in commemoration of the millennium of the discovery of the New World by Lief Ericson.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T17:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Leach moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T17:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12056-12059" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T17:49:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3373.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-11-16T17:58:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12056-12058" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T17:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1999-11-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14922-14923" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1999-11-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1999-12-06">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1999-12-06" type="public" number="106-126">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-126.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="31"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="1033"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Copper"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Iceland"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Platinum"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Silver"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="West (U.S.)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Leif Ericson Millennium Commemorative Coin Title II: Capitol Visitor Center Commemorative Coin Title III: Lewis and Clark Expedition Commemorative Coin Title I: Leif Ericson Millennium Commemorative Coin - Leif Ericson Millennium Commemorative Coin Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to mint and issue one-dollar silver coins, in conjunction with the simultaneous minting and issuance of commemorative coins by the Republic of Iceland, in commemoration of the millennium of the discovery of the New World by Leif Ericson.Mandates that all coin surcharges be paid to the Leifur Eiriksson Foundation for the purpose of funding student exchanges between the United States and Iceland.Title II: Capitol Visitor Center Commemorative Coin - United States Capitol Visitor Center Commemorative Coin Act of 1999 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to issue ten-dollar bimetallic coins, one-dollar silver coins, half-dollar clad coins, and if the Secretary determines that the minting and issuance of bimetallic coins is not feasible, five-dollar gold coins emblematic of the first meeting of the United States Congress in the U.S. Capitol Building.Mandates that all surcharges received from the coin sales be deposited in the Capitol Preservation Fund and made available to the U.S. Capitol Preservation Commission to aid in the construction, maintenance, and preservation of a Capitol Visitor Center.Title III: Lewis and Clark Expedition Commemorative Coin - Lewis and Clark Expedition Bicentennial Commemorative Coin Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to mint and issue one-dollar coins emblematic of the expedition of Lewis and Clark.Allocates surcharges from coin sales between the National Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Council and the National Park Service for activities associated with the bicentennial commemoration of the expedition.</summary>
</bill>
