<bill session="104" type="h" number="2052" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Population Stabilization and Reproductive Health Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to establish and strengthen policies and programs for the early stabilization of world population through the global expansion of reproductive choice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401310"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1995-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-07-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1456-1457"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity"/>
    <term name="Birth control"/>
    <term name="Breast feeding"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Childbirth"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contraceptives"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Deficiency diseases"/>
    <term name="Demography"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Female circumcision"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Human behavior"/>
    <term name="Human fertility"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Hunger"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Income statistics"/>
    <term name="Infant mortality"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Marriage"/>
    <term name="Maternal and infant welfare"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Poor women"/>
    <term name="Population growth"/>
    <term name="Population policy"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Reproduction"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Rights of women"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in education"/>
    <term name="Sex education"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sterilization (Birth control)"/>
    <term name="Sustainable agriculture"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in politics"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/1995--Introduced.
International Population Stabilization and Reproductive Health Act - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to set forth population assistance authorities and requirements. (Sec. 2) Makes such assistance available to a country that: (1) accounts for a significant portion of the world's annual population increment; (2) has significant unmet needs for fertility regulation and requires foreign assistance to sustain quality family planning services; or (3) demonstrates a strong policy commitment to population stabilization through the expansion of reproductive choice. Prohibits nongovernmental and multilateral organizations from being subjected to requirements which are more restrictive than those applicable to foreign governments for such assistance. Makes funds available for: (1) the United Nations Population Fund if it agrees to prohibit the use of funds for coerced abortion or involuntary sterilization; and (2) the Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training to further international cooperation in the development of fertility regulation technology. (Sec. 3) Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 4) Declares the sense of the Congress that the multilateral development banks should increase their annual support for specified population activities to at least $1 billion by December 31, 2000. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to report annually to the Congress on: (1) resources made available by multilateral development banks for population activities; (2) any specified actions taken by such banks to encourage increased resources if such resources total less than $1 billion; and (3) the progress made by such banks in meeting the objectives of the population activities. (Sec. 5) Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress on preparations for U.S. participation in the 1995 World Conference on Women. (Sec. 6) Makes development assistance available on a priority basis for countries which have agreed to address specific education, literacy, and health issues. Authorizes the President to establish a grant program, to be known as the Safe Motherhood Initiative, to improve the access of girls and women to reproductive health care services. Earmarks amounts of development and economic assistance for programs in support of increasing primary and secondary school enrollment and equalizing levels of male and female enrollment. Authorizes appropriations for the Child Survival Fund, the Safe Motherhood Initiative, and for research on, and treatment and control of, acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) in developing countries. (Sec. 8) Provides for certain actions to support the United Nations Forward Looking Strategies for the Advancement of Women and the United Nations Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination Against Women.</summary>
</bill>
