<bill session="104" type="hj" number="60" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States relating to a Federal balanced budget.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408839"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-24">
      <text>For Further Action See H.J.Res.1.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hj" number="1"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Deficit financing"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/1995--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Prohibits total outlays from exceeding total receipts, unless a three-fifths vote of both Houses authorizes a specific excess. Declares that total receipts include all receipts of the United States except those derived from borrowing or retirement trust funds. Declares that total outlays include all outlays except those for retirement trust funds or repayment of debt principal. Directs the President to submit a balanced budget. Waives these provisions when a declaration of war is in effect. Requires roll call votes in the House and Senate under this amendment. Makes this amendment effective the second fiscal year after its ratification. Declares that if there is a Federal budget deficit for the first fiscal year beginning after its ratification, then during the next five fiscal years, the annual budget deficit may not exceed specified percentums of that budget deficit for each of those years.</summary>
</bill>
