<bill session="113" type="h" number="697" updated="2013-07-17T15:53:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Three Kids Mine Remediation and Reclamation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Three Kids Mine Remediation and Reclamation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the conveyance of certain Federal land in Clark County, Nevada, for the environmental remediation and reclamation of the Three Kids Mine Project Site, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412446"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412559" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2013-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-137.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-08T15:05:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="99">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 99.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2013--Introduced.
Three Kids Mine Remediation and Reclamation Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Henderson Redevelopment Agency of the city of Henderson, Nevada, the Three Kids Mine Federal Land (the parcel or parcels of federal land consisting of approximately 948 specified acres) for the environmental remediation and reclamation of the Three Kids Mine Project Site. Directs the Secretary to administratively adjust the fair market value of the Three Kids Mine Federal Land based on the reasonable approximate assessment, remediation, and reclamation costs for the Three Kids Mine Project Area. Requires the Henderson Redevelopment Agency to pay the fair market value, if any for the Three Kids Mine Federal Land. Adjusts the boundary of the River Mountains Area of Critical Environmental Concern. Releases the United States, upon making the conveyance, from any and all liabilities or claims of any kind or nature arising from the presence, release, or threat of release of any hazardous substance or mining related materials at the Three Kids Mine Project Site. Makes the provisions of the Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1998 inapplicable to land conveyed under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
