<bill session="104" type="h" number="51" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">New Columbia Admission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the admission of the State of New Columbia into the Union.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1995-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Presidential messages"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Statehood (American politics)"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: State of New Columbia Subtitle A: Procedures for Admission Subtitle B: Description of New Columbia Territory Subtitle C: General Provisions Relating to Laws of New Columbia Title II: Responsibilities and Interests of Federal Government Title III: General Provisions New Columbia Admission Act - Title I: State of New Columbia - Subtitle A: Procedures for Admission - Sets forth procedures for admission into the United States of the State of New Columbia. Requires the Mayor of the District of Columbia to: (1) submit to the eligible voters propositions for statehood and adoption of a State Constitution; and (2) issue a proclamation for the first elections to the Congress of two Senators and one Representative of New Columbia. Requires the President, upon adoption of such propositions and certification of such elections, to issue a proclamation announcing the results and admitting New Columbia into the Union. Provides for conversion of District government offices to State offices. Subtitle B: Description of New Columbia Territory - Provides that New Columbia shall consist of all territory of the District as of the date of enactment of this Act, excluding land within specified metes and bounds that shall remain the District of Columbia and that shall include the principal Federal monuments, the White House, the Capitol Building, the Supreme Court Building, the Federal executive, legislative, and judicial office buildings located adjacent to the Mall and the Capitol Building, and certain military property. Subtitle C: General Provisions Relating to Laws of New Columbia - Prohibits New Columbia from imposing taxes on Federal property except as provided by the Congress. Maintains the applicability to New Columbia of current District laws and continues pending judicial proceedings. Title II: Responsibilities and Interests of Federal Government - Maintains: (1) the District of Columbia as the seat of the Federal Government; and (2) the Federal Government's authority over military lands and specified other property. Provides for Federal payments in lieu of taxes to New Columbia. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to take a scenic easement in the space above all lots within New Columbia. Requires each State that is the last place an individual resided before residing in the District of Columbia to permit such individual to vote in Federal elections by absentee ballot. Sets forth a rule for expedited consideration of a joint resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution to repeal the 23d amendment (provides for the appointment of electors for President and Vice President for the District). Title III: General Provisions - Establishes a Statehood Transition Commission to advise the President, the Congress, the District, and, after admission, New Columbia on procedures for an orderly transition to statehood during the first two years of New Columbia's existence. Directs the Commission to make recommendations regarding: (1) continued applicability of current Federal laws to the District; (2) the amount of the annual payment in lieu of taxes to New Columbia; and (3) the incarceration of individuals convicted of crimes in New Columbia and a plan for closing the Lorton Correctional Complex, Virginia, by 2010.</summary>
</bill>
