<bill session="106" type="h" number="3022" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rest of the Truth in Telephone Billing Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to improve the disclosure of information concerning telephone charges, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2036-2037"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Telephone rates"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1999--Introduced.
Rest of the Truth in Telephone Billing Act of 1999 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct a telecommunications carrier that is required to contribute to, or is assessed for, any universal service support mechanism, fund, tax, or program to identify on each subscriber's bill: (1) the identity of such mechanism, fund, tax, or program, as well as the governmental authority whose rules require or authorize the contribution or assessment; (2) the identity of any governmental mechanism, fund, tax, or program from which the subscriber receives a subsidy, as well as the governmental authority whose rules require or authorize the subsidy; (3) the basis for such contribution or assessment; (4) the dollar amount that is being attributed to and collected from such subscriber for such mechanism, fund, tax, or program; and (5) the average amount per month by which the subscriber's service is reduced by any identified subsidy.</summary>
</bill>
