<bill session="105" type="h" number="2579" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAFE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safety Advancement for Employees Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to further improve the safety and health of working environments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400568" joined="1998-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1998-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1998-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1997-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400583" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1998-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="1998-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400547" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="1998-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1997-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1998-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1997-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1997-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400353" joined="1998-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="410136" joined="1997-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1997-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1997-09-30" withdrawn="1997-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism treatment"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and employment"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial accidents"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Labor-management committees"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Management consultants"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Urinalysis"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/1997--Introduced.
Safety Advancement for Employees Act of 1977 - SAFE Act - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSHA) to authorize employers to establish employer and employee safety and health participation committees. States that such committees shall not constitute labor organizations for purposes of the National Labor Relations Act or the Railway Labor Act. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish a special advisory committee, with expertise in workplace safety and health, to advise on the establishment and implementation of a third party consultation services program. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to establish a third party consultation services program that certifies individuals to provide consultation services to help employers identify and correct safety and health hazards in the workplace. Provides for: (1) a registry of certified consultants; (2) disciplinary actions against consultants for malfeasance; (3) scope and guidelines for such consultative services; and (4) access to records. Exempts any employer receiving a declaration of OSHA compliance from a certified consultant from assessment of certain civil penalties for two years after receipt of such declaration, except in specified circumstances. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary, before issuing a final OSHA standard, to submit for review the draft final standard and a copy of the administrative record to the National Academy of Sciences (NAS). Directs NAS to appoint an independent Scientific Review Committee to review the draft final standard and the scientific literature, and make written recommendations to the Secretary. (Sec. 7) Requires certain Federal personnel responsible for enforcing OSHA to: (1) meet specified eligibility requirements; and (2) receive professional education and training at least every five years if they carry out inspections or investigations. (Sec. 8) Revises inspection procedures. Prohibits the Secretary from establishing any quotas for subordinates within the Occupational Safety and Health Administration with respect to number of inspections conducted, citations issued, or penalties collected. (Sec. 9) Establishes the use of alternative safe methods as an affirmative defense for employers. Establishes a civil penalty for employee violations of specified OSHA requirements. (Sec. 10) Reduces the types of violations of posting or paperwork requirements for which an employer may be assessed a civil penalty. (Sec. 11) Revises factors which the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission is required to consider in assessing civil penalties. (Sec. 12) Directs the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with States for State consultation services to employers concerning the provision of safe and healthful working conditions. Directs the Secretary to carry out a two-year pilot program in three States to provide small businesses, upon request, for a nominal fee, with expedited consultation services on safe and healthful working conditions. Requires the Secretary, before issuing a citation to an employer for a violation found during a consultation, to permit the employer to carry out corrective measures. (Sec. 13) Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) cooperative agreements to encourage the establishment of comprehensive safety and health management systems with specified features; and (2) a voluntary protection program with specified features to encourage the achievement of excellence in both the technical and managerial protection of employees from occupational hazards. (Sec. 14) Authorizes employers to establish alcohol and substance abuse testing programs in accordance with specified Federal guidelines.</summary>
</bill>
