<bill session="105" type="h" number="201" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financial Institution and Real Estate (FIRE) Relief Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax incentives for the economic recovery of areas affected by the loss of employment in the financial institution and real estate sectors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406284"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E57"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Burglary protection"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Urban economic development"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Financial Institution and Real Estate (FIRE) Relief Act of 1997 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow the Secretary of the Treasury to designate from among the areas nominated for designation, three nominated areas as economic recovery areas. Limits the period during which a designation may be made. Provides for an economic recovery area employment credit to any employer for any taxable year in the amount of 20 percent of the qualified area wages paid. Limits the amount of qualified area wages which may be taken into account for a calendar year to only the first $15,000 of wages respecting each qualified area employee. Sets forth provisions providing for coordination with the targeted jobs credit and the empowerment zone employment credit. Provides for a reduction in the maximum capital gains tax of ten percent for a taxpayer other than a corporation and 17 percent for a corporation on: (1) any qualified area stock; (2) any qualified area business property; and (3) any qualified area partnership interest, held for more than five years as of the date of sale or exchange. Sets forth provisions concerning substantial improvements made to qualified area business property in an economic recovery area. Provides for the treatment of pass-thru entities, the transfer of a qualified area investment, and expensing of equipment and leasehold equipment. Increases by 100 percent the amount of any deduction allowable for any security expenses. Revises provisions relating to the maximum capital gains tax rate for taxpayers other than corporations and corporations.</summary>
</bill>
