<bill session="106" type="h" number="1555" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-12-03">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Central Intelligence Authorization bill</title>
    <title type="popular">FY99 Intelligence Authorization bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Intelligence Authorization bill, FY2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Energy Sensitive Country Foreign Visitors Moratorium Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2000 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-06T19:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goss asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent) have until midnight on May 7 to file a report on H.R. 1555. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select)"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-07T17:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent). H. Rept. 106-130, Part I. Filed late, pursuant to previous special order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-07">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Armed Services for a period ending not later than May 11, 1999 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(c), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-11T17:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-05-11T17:55:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="74">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 74.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-12T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 167 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1555 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Permanent Committee on Intelligence now printed in the bill. No amendment to this amendment shall be in order except those printed in the Congressional Record designated for that purpose. Each amendment may be offered only by the Member who caused it to be printed or his designee and shall be considered as read. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T11:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 167 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T11:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 167.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3112-3141" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3121" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3121" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3121" label=" text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3130" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3130-3131" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3137-3138" label="text of Title VI as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T11:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1555 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Permanent Committee on Intelligence now printed in the bill. No amendment to this amendment shall be in order except those printed in the Congressional Record designated for that purpose. Each amendment may be offered only by the Member who caused it to be printed or his designee and shall be considered as read. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T11:10:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 167 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T11:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steven C. LaTourette to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T11:10:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1555.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T12:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is proceeding with debate on the amendment offered by Mr. Traficant.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T12:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is proceeding with debate on the amendment offered by Mr. Sweeney.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is proceeding with debate on the amendment offered by Mr. Hinchey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T12:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is proceeding with debate on the amendment offered by Mr. Barr.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T12:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is proceeding with debate on the amendment offered by Mr. Sanders.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Sanders, as amended, and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sanders objected to the voice vote pending the absence of a quorum. the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment, and the point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T13:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is proceeding with debate on the amendment offered by Ms. Waters.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is proceeding with debate on the amendment offered by Mr. Engels.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINSIHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinshed business is the request for a recorded vote on the Sanders amendment, as amended, that was postponed earlier today.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T13:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1555.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T13:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T13:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-05-13T13:59:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1555.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-05-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="119">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 119.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-07-16">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8707" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-16">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8707" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-16">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8707" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to proceed invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 99-0. Record Vote No: 212.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8825" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Motion to proceed considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8818-8824" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8852-8862, S8864-8868" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Amendment SP 1258 proposed by Senator Kyl.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Amendment SP 1259 proposed by Senator Coverdell.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-20">
      <text>Amendment SP 1259 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8906-8931, S8933-8939" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1260 proposed by Senator Bingaman to Amendment SP 1258.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1260 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1261 proposed by Senator Levin to Amendment SP 1258.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1262 proposed by Senator Bingaman to Amendment SP 1258.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1262 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1261 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 44-54. Record Vote No: 215.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1263 proposed by Senator Domenici to Amendment SP 1258.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1263 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1264 proposed by Senator Moynihan.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1265 proposed by Senator Moynihan.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1264 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1265 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1266 proposed by Senator Kerrey to Amendment SP 1258.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1267 proposed by Senator Kerrey for Senator Feinstein to Amendment SP 1258.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1266 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1267 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1268 proposed by Senator Levin to Amendment SP 1258.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1268 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1269 proposed by Senator Bryan.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Proposed amendment SP 1269 withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1258 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 96-1. Record Vote No: 216.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1270 proposed by Senator Shelby.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Amendment SP 1270 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1999-07-21" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8933-8939" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment asks for a conference, appoints conferees Shelby; Chafee; Lugar; Dewine; Kyl; Inhofe; Hatch; Roberts; Allard; Kerrey; Bryan; Graham; Kerry; Baucus; Robb; Lautenberg; Levin from the Select Committee on Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21">
      <text>Senate appointed conferee Warner from the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goss asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8939" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8523" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence for consideration of the House bill, and the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Goss, Lewis (CA), McCollum, Castle, Boehlert, Bass, Gibbons, LaHood, Wilson, Dixon, Pelosi, Bishop, Sisisky, Condit, Roemer, and Hastings (FL).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Armed Services for consideration of defense tactical intelligence and related activities: Spence, Stump, and Andrews.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-05T12:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gutknecht asked unanimous consent that managers on the part of the House have until midnight on Nov. 5 to file a conference report on H.R. 1555. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-05">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-05T20:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 106-457 filed. Filed late, pursuant to previous special order.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11630-11638" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement and official papers held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08T23:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 364 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 1555 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-09T10:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Dreier asked unanimous consent that it be in order at any time to consider the conference report to accompany H.R. 1555; that all points of order against the conference report and against its consideration be waived; that the conference report be considered as read when called up; and that H. Res. 364 be laid on the table. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-09T15:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Goss brought up conference report H. Rept. 106-457 by previously agreed to special order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-09T15:56:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-09T16:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on the conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="1999-11-09T16:48:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11755-11762" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-09T16:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-09">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1999-11-19" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1999-11-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-23">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1999-12-03">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1999-12-03" type="public" number="106-120">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-120.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="167"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="364"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1009"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1009"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Albanians"/>
    <term name="Alien property"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Assassination"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Balance of payments"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Business intelligence"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Chile"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communist parties"/>
    <term name="Communists"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Confidential funding (Federal budgets)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Covert operations"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Espionage"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fissionable materials"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Information leaking"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Intelligence community staff"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International banking"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Kosovo"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military communications"/>
    <term name="Military intelligence"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Military weapons"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Missing in action"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear warships"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Party affiliation"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Political leadership"/>
    <term name="Political science"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Reconnaissance satellites"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Serbia"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Underground movements"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Vietnamese Conflict"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
    <term name="Yugoslavia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h86"/>
    <amendment number="h87"/>
    <amendment number="h88"/>
    <amendment number="h89"/>
    <amendment number="h90"/>
    <amendment number="h91"/>
    <amendment number="h92"/>
    <amendment number="h93"/>
    <amendment number="h94"/>
    <amendment number="h95"/>
    <amendment number="s1255"/>
    <amendment number="s1256"/>
    <amendment number="s1257"/>
    <amendment number="s1258"/>
    <amendment number="s1259"/>
    <amendment number="s1260"/>
    <amendment number="s1261"/>
    <amendment number="s1262"/>
    <amendment number="s1263"/>
    <amendment number="s1264"/>
    <amendment number="s1265"/>
    <amendment number="s1266"/>
    <amendment number="s1267"/>
    <amendment number="s1268"/>
    <amendment number="s1269"/>
    <amendment number="s1270"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/5/1999--Conference report filed in House.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Intelligence Activities Title II: Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System Title III: General Provisions Title IV: Central Intelligence Agency Title V: Department of Defense Intelligence Activities Title VI: Foreign Counterintelligence and International Terrorism Investigations Title VII: National Commission for the Review of the National Reconnaissance Office Title VIII: International Narcotics Trafficking Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000 - Title I: Intelligence Activities - Authorizes appropriations for FY 2000 for the conduct of intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the: (1) Central Intelligence Agency (CIA); (2) Department of Defense; (3) Defense Intelligence Agency; (4) National Security Agency (NSA); (5) Departments of the Army, Navy, and Air Force; (6) Departments of State, the Treasury, and Energy; (7) Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); (8) National Reconnaissance Office (NRO); and (9) National Imagery and Mapping Agency (NIMA).(Sec. 102) Specifies that the amounts authorized to be appropriated and the authorized personnel ceilings as of September 30, 2000, for such activities are those specified in the classified Schedule of Authorizations, which shall be made available to the Senate and House Appropriations Committees and the President.(Sec. 103) Allows the Director of Central Intelligence (DCI), with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, to authorize employment of civilian personnel in excess of the number authorized for FY 2000 when the DCI determines that such action is necessary to the performance of important intelligence functions, subject to specified limitations. Requires notification of the Senate and House Intelligence Committees whenever such authority is exercised.(Sec. 104) Authorizes appropriations for the Intelligence Community Management Account of the DCI for FY 2000. Authorizes full-time personnel for elements within such Account as of September 30, 2000. Provides for the reimbursement of any U.S. officer or employee, or member of the armed forces, who is detailed to such staff.Earmarks funds authorized under this Act for the National Drug Intelligence Center. Requires a transfer of funds from the DCI to the Attorney General (AG) to operate the Center.(Sec. 105) Increases amounts authorized to be appropriated under the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 by the amount by which appropriations pursuant to such authorization were increased by the 1999 Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act and designated as emergency funding.Title II: Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System - Authorizes appropriations for FY 2000 for the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability Fund.Title III: General Provisions - Permits appropriations authorized by this Act for salary, pay, retirement, and other benefits for Federal employees to be increased by such additional amounts as may be necessary for increases in such compensation or benefits authorized by law.(Sec. 302) Specifies that the authorization of appropriations by this Act shall not be deemed to constitute authority for the conduct of any intelligence activity which is not otherwise authorized by the Constitution or laws of the United States.(Sec. 303) Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to prohibit a diplomatic intelligence support center from being established, operated, or maintained without prior approval of the DCI. Allows the DCI to approve such center only when required to provide necessary intelligence support in furtherance of U.S. national security interests. Prohibits amounts appropriated for intelligence-related activities from being obligated for such center that is not so approved.(Sec. 304) Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to: (1) include retired officers and employees within provisions concerning the identity protection of intelligence community officers and employees; (2) require any prison term imposed for violation of such protection requirements to be consecutive to any other imprisonment sentence; and (3) permit authorized Federal investigative agencies to access computers used by Federal employees in the performance of government duties.(Sec. 306) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to allow the naturalization of a person affiliated with a Communist or similar party if such person: (1) is otherwise eligible; (2) is within a proscribed category solely because of past membership in, or affiliation with, such party or organization; (3) does not fall within any other excluded category; and (4) is determined by the DCI to have made a contribution to the U.S. national security or national intelligence mission.(Sec. 308) Requires the DCI to review for declassification: (1) a specified national intelligence estimate concerning Vietnamese cooperation with the POW-MIA issue; and (2) an assessment of such estimate by the U.S. Chairman of the Vietnam War Working Group. Provides limitations. Requires review completion within 30 days after enactment of this Act.(Sec. 309) Requires the DCI, the NSA Director, and the AG to jointly prepare, and the NSA Director to submit to the appropriate congressional committees, a report describing the legal standards employed by elements of the intelligence community in conducting signals intelligence activities, including electronic surveillance.(Sec. 310) Requires the DCI to report to Congress describing the effects of espionage against the United States on U.S. trade secrets, patents, and technology development.(Sec. 311) Requires the DCI to report to the appropriate congressional committees describing all activities of intelligence community officers, covert agents, and employees with respect to the following events in the Republic of Chile: (1) the assassination of President Allende in 1973; (2) the succession of General Pinochet to such presidency; and (3) human rights violations committed by officers or agents of former President Pinochet.(Sec. 312) Directs the DCI to report to the appropriate congressional committees on the organized resistance in Kosovo known as the Kosova Liberation Army.(Sec. 313) Requires any intelligence community employee having knowledge that an intelligence employee, agent, or asset is involved in the illegal manufacture, purchase, sale, transport, or distribution of drugs to report such knowledge to an appropriate official.(Sec. 314) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the systematic declassification of records of permanent historical value is in the public interest and that management of the classification and declassification of such records by executive agencies requires comprehensive reform and additional resources; and (2) the DCI should continue to direct that elements of the intelligence community should competitively award contracts in a manner that maximizes the procurement of products properly designated as having been made in the United States.Title IV: Central Intelligence Agency - Amends the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 to: (1) extend to nonappropriated fund entities or instrumentalities associated or affiliated with the CIA the provision of items and services under the CIA central services program; (2) provide for additional deposits into the Central Services Working Capital Fund; and (3) extend such program through March 31, 2002.(Sec. 402) Amends the Central Intelligence Agency Voluntary Separation Pay Act to extend such Act through FY 2002.Title V: Department of Defense Intelligence Activities - Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to authorize the NIMA Director to exempt NIMA operational files from provisions of the Freedom of Information Act which require publication, disclosure, search, or review. Outlines exceptions, including for investigatory purposes by specified congressional committees and Federal entities. Provides for judicial review whenever any person who has requested NIMA records alleges that such records have been improperly withheld. Requires ex parte, in camera court examination whenever records authorized by executive order to be kept secret for national defense or foreign relations purposes are requested for production. Provides exceptions to such judicial review. Requires the NIMA Director and the DCI, at least once every ten years, to examine any exemptions currently in force to determine whether they should be removed. Provides for judicial review of NIMA's alleged failure to conduct such examinations.(Sec. 502) Amends the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1996 to extend through FY 2001 funding for infrastructure and quality of life improvements at the Menwith Hill and Bad Aibling Stations.Title VI: Foreign Counterintelligence and International Terrorism Investigations - Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to include within the definition of "agent of a foreign power" for purposes of coverage under such Act a person who knowingly enters the United States under a false or fraudulent identity for or on behalf of a foreign power or, while in the United States, knowingly assumes a false or fraudulent identity for or on behalf of a foreign power.(Sec. 602) Amends the Counterintelligence and Security Enhancements Act of 1994 to require the FBI to pass on to the appropriate Federal agency information obtained by the FBI concerning the possible disclosure of classified information by an individual within that agency. (Currently, the FBI must pass on such information only after receiving a report from the head of such agency concerning the possibility of such disclosure.)Title VII: National Commission For the Review of the National Reconnaissance Office - Establishes the National Commission for the Review of the National Reconnaissance Office to review and report to the intelligence committees, the DCI, and the Secretary of Defense on the current organization, practices, and authorities of the NRO, particularly with respect to: (1) roles and missions; (2) organizational structure; (3) technical skills; (4) contractor relationships; (5) use of commercial imagery; (6) acquisition of launch vehicles, launch services, and launch infrastructure, and mission assurance; (7) acquisition authorities; and (8) relationship with other Federal agencies and departments. Requires the DCI and Secretary of Defense to each submit to the intelligence committees an assessment of such final report. Provides Commission funding from appropriations authorized for the NRO under this Act.Title VIII: International Narcotics Trafficking - Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, the AG, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, and the DCI to consult and provide the appropriate and necessary information to enable the President to submit annually to specified congressional committees a report: (1) identifying publicly the foreign persons appropriate for sanctions pursuant to this title; and (2) detailing publicly the President's intent to impose sanctions upon such significant foreign narcotics traffickers (traffickers). Requires a classified annual report to the intelligence committees on the status of such sanctions. Requires exclusion from such reports of: (1) information the disclosure of which the DCI determines could compromise a U.S. intelligence operation, activity, source, or method; and (2) the names of any person that the AG determines could compromise the identity of a confidential source, jeopardize the integrity or success of an ongoing criminal investigation or prosecution, endanger the life or physical safety of any person, or cause substantial harm to physical property. Requires notification to the intelligence committees of such excluded information or names.Authorizes the President to waive the application of a sanction authorized by this title with respect to a trafficker when such application would significantly harm U.S. national security (requiring notification to specified congressional committees of such determination). Authorizes the President to add or delete designated traffickers in subsequent reports (requiring appropriate congressional notification).(Sec. 805) Subjects a trafficker identified by the President to any and all sanctions authorized by this title until revoked or waived. Blocks all U.S. property and interests which are owned or controlled by: (1) any trafficker; (2) any foreign person that the Secretary of the Treasury designates as materially assisting the international narcotics trafficking activities of a trafficker; (3) any foreign person that such Secretary designates as owned, controlled, or directed by a trafficker; and (4) any foreign person that such Secretary designates as playing a significant role in international narcotics trafficking.Prohibits certain transactions or dealings with such traffickers by U.S. persons. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to implement this title. Provides that determinations, findings, and designations made under this Act shall not be subject to judicial review.(Sec. 806) Authorizes the Secretary, to carry out this title, to: (1) investigate, regulate, or prohibit transactions in foreign exchange, currency, or securities and transfers of credit or payments by banking institutions involving foreign interests; (2) investigate, block, or regulate transactions involving foreign interests; and (3) impose record keeping and reporting requirements.(Sec. 807) Provides criminal and civil penalties for the willful violation of this title.(Sec. 809) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to deny or suspend admission into the United States for such traffickers, persons who have aided, abetted, or acted in collusion with such traffickers, or spouses or children of such traffickers who receive a financial or other benefit from illegal activities of such trafficker while knowing that the benefit was the product of the illegal activity.(Sec. 810) Establishes the Judicial Review Commission on Foreign Asset Control to review and report to specified congressional committees on the current judicial, regulatory, and administrative authorities relating to the blocking of assets of foreign persons by the U.S. Government and the remedies available to U.S. persons affected by the blocking of such assets.</summary>
</bill>
