<bill session="105" type="hj" number="129" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to protect the rights of crime victims.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administration of criminal justice"/>
    <term name="Bail"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional powers"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Pleas (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Speedy trial"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/1998--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Grants each victim of a crime of violence the right: (1) to reasonable notice of, and not to be excluded from, all public proceedings relating to the crime; (2) to be heard, if present, and to submit a statement, at all public proceedings to determine a release from custody, an acceptance of a negotiated plea, or a sentence; (3) to the foregoing rights at a parole proceeding that is not public, to the extent such rights are afforded to the convicted offender; (4) to reasonable notice of a release or escape from custody relating to the crime; (5) to consideration for the victim's interest in a trial free from unreasonable delay; (6) to a restitution order from the convicted offender; (7) to consideration for the victim's safety in determining any release from custody; and (8) to reasonable notice of such rights. Provides that: (1) only the victim or the victim's representative shall have standing to assert such rights; and (2) such rights shall apply in all Federal proceedings.</summary>
</bill>
