<bill session="105" type="h" number="914" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-16">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Cost of Higher Education Review Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make certain technical corrections in the Higher Education Act of 1965 relating to graduation data disclosures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1997-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-03-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E365"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-03-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-03-11T14:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 105-14.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-03-11T14:32:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="11">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 11.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-03-11T16:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McKeon moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-11T16:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H846-847" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-11T16:20:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-03-11T16:24:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-03-11T16:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Senate Committee on Labor and Human Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3300-3301" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 46 proposed by Senator Frist for Senator Jeffords.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Amendment SP 46 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1997-04-16" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-04-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-13T15:41:00-04:00">
      <text>House agreed to Senate amendment with amendments pursuant to H. Res. 145.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2541-2546" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hr" number="145"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hr" number="145"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Class size"/>
    <term name="College administration"/>
    <term name="College administrators"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="College graduates"/>
    <term name="College teachers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal mandates"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fiscal policy"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Impact aid"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Service academies"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State aid to education"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Teachers' tenure"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s46"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/13/1997--House agreed to Senate amendment with amendment.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Technical Amendments Title I: Cost of Higher Education Review Title I: Technical Amendments - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to make certain technical corrections relating to graduation rates data disclosures. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to extend from January 1, 1998, to January 1, 1999, the deadline for a final report by the Secretary of Education on a national assessment of programs assisted under ESEA title I, Helping Disadvantaged Children Meet High Standards. Directs the Secretary to deem Kansas and New Mexico as having timely submitted certain written notices of intent to consider specified impact aid payments under ESEA in providing State aid to local educational agencies (LEAs) for school year 1997-1998. Authorizes the Secretary to require these States to submit appropriate additional information, which shall be considered part of such notice. Provides that no eligible LEA shall receive less than 85 percent of the FY 1996 amount in a specified hold-harmless impact aid payment for each of FY 1997 through 2000. Revises requirements for the Secretary's use of data in providing additional assistance for heavily impacted LEAs, to specify that the student and revenue data used be expenditure data. Repeals the requirement that the Secretary use the most recent data available adjusted to the fiscal year in question. Amends ESEA with respect to Federal impact aid payments to prescribe priorities for payments (in excess of FY 1996 payments) to an LEA that: (1) received an impact payment in FY 1996; (2) serves a school district in which at least 60 percent of the real property is federally owned, including all or a portion of a U.S. military academy; and (3) whose per-pupil revenue from local sources for current expenditures is not less than the revenue for the preceding fiscal year. Title II: Cost of Higher Education Review - Cost of Higher Education Review Act of 1997 - Establishes a National Commission on the Cost of Higher Education to study and make recommendations to the President and the Congress regarding: (1) the increase in tuition compared with other commodities and services; (2) innovative methods of reducing or stabilizing tuition; (3) the impact on tuition of specified trends in college and university costs, student financial aid, and government mandates and fiscal policies; (4) mechanisms for a more timely and widespread distribution of data on tuition trends and other costs of operating colleges and universities; and (5) the adequacy of existing Federal and State financial aid programs in meeting the costs of attending colleges and universities. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
