<bill congress="107" type="hr" number="1009" updated="2012-10-31T13:27:18-05:00">
  <status datetime="2002-04-15">REPORTED</status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Business Checking Freedom Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Business Checking Freedom Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal the prohibition on the payment of interest on demand deposits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor state="PA" title="Rep" thomas_id="1594" district="15" name="Toomey, Patrick J."/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor name="Bereuter, Doug" district="1" title="Rep" state="NE" sponsored_at="2001-03-19" thomas_id="80"/>
    <cosponsor name="Capito, Shelley Moore" district="2" title="Rep" state="WV" sponsored_at="2001-03-13" thomas_id="1676"/>
    <cosponsor name="Carson, Julia" district="10" title="Rep" state="IN" sponsored_at="2001-12-13" thomas_id="1473"/>
    <cosponsor name="Gonzalez, Charles A." district="20" title="Rep" state="TX" sponsored_at="2001-03-13" thomas_id="1555"/>
    <cosponsor name="Hooley, Darlene" district="5" title="Rep" state="OR" sponsored_at="2001-03-13" thomas_id="1491"/>
    <cosponsor name="Kanjorski, Paul E." district="11" title="Rep" state="PA" sponsored_at="2001-03-13" thomas_id="615"/>
    <cosponsor name="Kelly, Sue W." district="19" title="Rep" state="NY" sponsored_at="2002-04-09" thomas_id="624"/>
    <cosponsor name="Ney, Robert W." district="18" title="Rep" state="OH" sponsored_at="2001-03-13" thomas_id="862"/>
    <cosponsor name="Roukema, Marge" district="5" title="Rep" state="NJ" sponsored_at="2001-03-13" thomas_id="990"/>
    <cosponsor name="Royce, Edward R." district="39" title="Rep" state="CA" sponsored_at="2001-03-19" thomas_id="998"/>
    <cosponsor name="Shays, Christopher" district="4" title="Rep" state="CT" sponsored_at="2001-03-14" thomas_id="1048"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <referral datetime="2001-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </referral>
    <referral datetime="2001-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
    </referral>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-28">
      <text>The committee laid the measure on the table by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T15:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Toomey moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T15:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1107-1111" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T15:22:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1009.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2002-04-09T15:40:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1107-1108" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09T15:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-12">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-04-15">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 344.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Automated teller machines"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Bank reserves"/>
    <term name="Checking accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance charges"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="NOW accounts"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary date="2002-04-09" status="Passed House amended.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;(There is 1 &lt;a href=&quot;/cgi-bin/bdquery/z?d107:HR01009:@@@D&amp;summ1&amp;&quot;&gt;other summary&lt;/a&gt;)">Business Checking Freedom Act of 2002 - Amends the Federal Reserve Act, the Home Owners' Loan Act, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to repeal the prohibition against the payment of interest on demand deposits. Makes such repeal effective two years from the date of enactment.(Sec. 3) Authorizes interest-bearing transaction accounts for businesses, permitting up to 24 transfers per month (or any greater number the Federal Reserve Board (Board) may determine) to another account of the owner in the same institution.(Sec. 4) Authorizes the payment of interest by a Federal reserve bank at least quarterly on balances maintained there on behalf of a depository institution.Revises the requirements for the annual survey of bank fees and services by the Board to specify the inclusion of: (1) checking and other transaction accounts; (2) negotiable order of withdrawal and savings accounts; (3) automated teller machine transactions; and (4) other electronic transactions. Establishes minimum survey requirements for each such account or transaction area. Requires such survey to address minimum balance requirements as well as fees.Amends the Truth in Lending Act (and Consumer Credit Protection Act) to revise the requirements for the semiannual survey of credit card price and availability information to specify the inclusion of certain information, including finance charges, annual percentage rates, and various fees.Requires the Board to report annually to Congress on the results of both surveys.Amends the Riegle-Neal Interstate Banking and Branching Efficiency Act of 1994 to repeal the termination date for and so continue the annual survey by the Board of certain retail banking services (and associated fees) provided by insured depository institutions.(Sec. 5) Amends the Federal Reserve Act to revise the ratio of reserves a depository institution must maintain against its transaction accounts, permitting a ratio of zero.(Sec. 6) Directs the Federal reserve banks in FY 2002 through 2006 to transfer to the Board for transfer to the Secretary of the Treasury, for deposit in the general fund, additional surplus funds equal to the net cost of their interest payments to depository institutions.(Sec. 7) Provides a rule of construction for escrow accounts maintained at a depository institution in connection with a real estate transaction. Declares that the institution's absorption of expenses or forbearance in charging a fee or other benefit should not be treated as the payment or receipt of interest.</summary>
</bill>
