<bill session="108" type="h" number="5369" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area Natural Gas Pipeline Enlargement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to allow the Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation to increase the diameter of a natural gas pipeline located in the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400372"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="2909"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/2004--Introduced.
Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area Natural Gas Pipeline Enlargement Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to grant the Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation an easement to enlarge the diameter of a specified pipeline from 14 inches to not more than 20 inches, consistent with the recreational values and protection of the resources of the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area in Pennsylvania. Authorizes the Superintendent of the Recreation Area to issue a permit to the Corporation for the use of the Recreation Area for temporary construction and staging areas required for the construction of the enlarged pipeline. Requires the Corporation to comply with all requirements for certification by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission that are necessary to permit the increase in pipeline size. Prohibits the Secretary from granting additional increases in the diameter of, or easements for, the pipeline within the boundary of the Recreation Area after the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
