<bill session="106" type="hc" number="219" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress regarding the preservation of full and open competition for contracts for the transportation of United States military cargo between the United States and the Republic of Iceland.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400142"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Military Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="sc" number="65"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Iceland"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military transportation"/>
    <term name="Treaty-making power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/2/1999--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should ensure that full and open competition continues in the selection of companies to transport U.S. military cargo between the United States and Iceland in accordance with the Treaty Between the United States of America and the Republic of Iceland to Facilitate Their Defense Relationship and Related Memorandum of Understanding in Implementation of the Treaty, signed September 24, 1986.Declares that neither the Secretary of State nor any other official of the United States should, without the advice and consent of the Senate, seek to amend, interpret, or alter the administration of the treaty or memorandum of understanding in any manner (through limitations on eligibility or otherwise) that: (1) would preclude companies qualified to conduct business under the laws of the United States or the Republic of Iceland from submitting offers for, being awarded, or performing such a transportation contract; or (2) would otherwise defeat the purpose of enhancing competition among United States-flag carriers or among Icelandic shipping companies under the treaty or memorandum.</summary>
</bill>
