<bill session="108" type="h" number="4030" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-04-21T12:56:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-04-21T12:56:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Medal for Outstanding Contributions in Math and Science Education Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Congressional Medal for Outstanding Contributions in Math and Science Education Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Congressional Medal for Outstanding Contributions in Math and Science Education Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Congressional Medal for Outstanding Contributions in Math and Science Education program to recognize private entities for their outstanding contributions to elementary and secondary science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2004-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-03-31">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01T17:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Boehlert asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Science, Space and Technology have until 5:00 p.m. on April 14 to file a report on H.R. 4030. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-20T18:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 108-465.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-04-20T18:51:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="269">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 269.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (MI) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2209-2211" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4030.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21T10:55:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21T12:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2224-2225" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-04-21T12:56:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="122" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 411 - 7 (Roll no. 122).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2209" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Research" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Career education"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Corporate philanthropy"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Standard of living"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2004--Passed House amended.
Congressional Medal for Outstanding Contributions in Math and Science Education Act of 2004 - (Sec. 3) Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to establish a Congressional Medal for Outstanding Contributions in Math and Science Education program. (Sec. 4) Requires the Director to annually name as finalists for medals up to: (1) 20 private entities with more than 500 employees; and (2) 20 private entities with 500 or fewer employees. Requires the Director to annually award medals from among such finalists up to: (1) five private entities with more than 500 employees; and (2) five private entities with 500 or fewer employees. Requires the Director to distribute information about the Medal recipients in a timely and efficient manner (including through the use of a searchable online database) to schools, institutions of higher education, educators, parents, administrators, policy-makers, researchers, public and private entities, and the general public. Allows any entity that is a finalist or receives a medal under this section to use such information for advertising and other publicity purposes. (Sec. 5) Limits eligibility for such a medal to private entities that have: (1) whether alone or in partnership with for-profit or nonprofit entities, assisted students, teachers, administrators, or other support staff to improve student achievement in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics in a school or community; and (2) been involved in such activities in a sustained manner for at least two years with at least one elementary or secondary school. (Sec. 6) Requires the Director to establish a system for accepting applications from entities seeking to be considered for a medal under this Act. Directs that applications include at least two letters of support, which: (1) may come from teachers, professional support staff, administrators, professional or business organizations, local, county, or State Departments of Education, or any other category of persons as designated by the Director; and (2) shall describe the reasons the entity deserves the medal. (Sec. 7) Requires the Director, in selecting entities to receive medals under this Act, to give priority consideration to evidence of improved achievement in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics by students, including improved achievement by women, minorities, and persons with disabilities. Directs the Director to also consider evidence of: (1) innovative approaches to increase interest in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics by students, including women, minorities, and persons with disabilities, one measure of which may be an increase in the number of students enrolled in advanced courses related to such fields; (2) employee interaction with students or teachers to support and improve science, technology, engineering, and mathematics learning; (3) success in positively influencing student attitudes and promoting education and career opportunities in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics; (4) successful outreach to students, parents, and the community regarding the importance of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education to the Nation's prosperity, job creation, and standard of living, as well as future earning potential for the individual; and (5) strong and sustained commitment to the students and schools. (Sec. 8) Amends the Science and Engineering Equal Opportunities Act to change the deadline for submission to Congress of the NSF report on women and minorities in science and engineering from even-numbered to odd-numbered years. (Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations to NSF.</summary>
</bill>
