<bill session="104" type="h" number="400" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-30">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Anaktuvuk Pass Land Exchange and Wilderness Redesignation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Anaktuvuk Pass Land Exchange and Wilderness Redesignation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Anaktuvuk Pass Land Exchange and Wilderness Redesignation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Sterling Forest Protection Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the exchange of lands within Gates of the Arctic National Park and Preserve, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E15-16"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-17">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-01-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 40 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27T13:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 104-8.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-01-27T13:59:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="3">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 3.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31T19:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 52 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 400 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-01T16:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 52 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-01T16:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 52.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1016-1019" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-01T16:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 400 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-01T16:56:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 52 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-01T16:56:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable J. Dennis Hastert to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-01T16:57:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-01T17:08:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 400.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-01T17:08:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-02-01T17:30:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="84" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 427 - 0, 1 Present (Roll no. 84).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-02-01T17:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Parks, Preservation and Recreation.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-03-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-03-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources incorporated provisions of related measures S. 536 in reported measure.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Murkowski with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 104-44.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-04-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="67">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 67.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-06-30">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9592-9595" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 1489 proposed by Senator Dole for Senator Murkowski.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 1489 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-30">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1995-06-30" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-30T10:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 554, papers are returned to the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Parks, Historic Preservation, and Recreation" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="52"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hr" number="554"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hr" number="554"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="536"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="536"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="719"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="All terrain vehicles"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Forests"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Interstate commissions"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Natural gas reserves"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1489"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/30/1995--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Anaktuvuk Pass Land Exchange and Wilderness Redesignation Title II: Alaska Peninsula Subsurface Consolidation Title III: Sterling Forest Anaktuvuk Pass Land Exchange and Wilderness Redesignation Act of 1995 - Title I: Anaktuvuk Pass Land Exchange and Wilderness Redesignation - Ratifies and confirms the agreement between the United States, the Arctic Slope Regional Corporation, the Nunamiut Corporation, and the city of Anaktuvuk Pass executed on December 17, 1992. Requires the lands acquired by the United States pursuant to such Agreement to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior as part of the Gates of the Arctic National Park and Preserve. Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act to provide for the addition and the rescission of lands within the Gates of the Arctic Wilderness. Provides for the addition of lands within the Noatak National Preserve and Noatak Wilderness. Title II: Alaska Peninsula Subsurface Consolidation - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to value the rights granted to Koniag, Incorporated, pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to receive title to the oil and gas rights and other interests in the subsurface estate of specified public lands in Alaska (selection rights) which Koniag possesses within the boundaries of Aniakchak National Monument and Preserve, Alaska Peninsula National Wildlife Refuge, and Becharof National Wildlife Refuge. Specifies that the value of such rights shall be equal to the fair market value of: (1) the oil and gas interests in the lands that are the subject of the selection rights; and (2) in the case of the lands for which Koniag is to receive the entire subsurface estate, the subsurface estate of the lands that are the subject of such rights. Directs the Secretary and Koniag to meet to select a qualified appraiser to conduct an appraisal of the selection rights in conformity with the standards of the Appraisal Foundation of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) submission of the appraisal report; (2) determination of the value of the selection rights; and (3) an alternative determination of value if Koniag disagrees with the value determined by the Secretary. Prohibits the average value per acre of the selection rights from being less than the value utilizing the risk adjusted discount cash flow methodology or more than $300. Directs the Secretary: (1) to enter into negotiations for an agreement to exchange Federal lands in Alaska for the selection rights; and (2) if, after ten years after the enactment of this Act such exchanges to acquire all of the selection rights have not been concluded, to conclude exchanges for the remaining rights for such Federal property identified by Koniag that is available for transfer to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary under any provision of law and, at the time of the proposed transfer to Koniag, is not generating receipts to the Government above $1 million per year. Exempts such property from the geographic limitations of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act and allows it to be retained by the Secretary solely for transferring purposes to Koniag to complete the exchange. Gives Koniag the option of declining to proceed with the exchange and identifying other property or paying the difference in value between the property and the selection rights if the value of the identified property is in excess of the value of the remaining selection rights. Title III: Sterling Forest - Sterling Forest Protection Act of 1995 - Establishes the Sterling Forest Reserve, New York, upon certification by the Palisades Interstate Park Commission to the Secretary of the Interior that the Commission has acquired sufficient lands or interests therein to constitute a manageable unit. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) Reserve boundaries; (2) the transfer of funds to the Commission for land acquisition; and (3) conditions of funding (including provision for specified conservation easements and that funds may be transferred to the Commission only to the extent that they are matched from funds contributed by non-Federal sources). Directs the Commission to: (1) manage the lands acquired within the Reserve in a manner consistent with the Commission's authorities and the protection of significant watershed, wildlife, and recreational resources within the New York-New Jersey highlands region; and (2) prepare a general management plan for the Reserve, to be submitted to the Secretary for approval. Authorizes appropriations. Limits the amount that may be transferred to the Commission for the acquisition of lands and interests in land within the Reserve.</summary>
</bill>
