<bill session="104" type="h" number="1391" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 4358(c) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 to permit medicare select policies to be offered in all States on an extended basis.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400567" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1995-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1995-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="1995-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-04">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.483.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="483"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 to permit Medicare select policies to be offered in all States, at State option, for an extended period of eight-and-a-half (instead of only three-and-a-half) years beginning with 1992. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) conduct a study that compares the health care costs, quality of care, and access to services under Medicare select policies with those under other Medicare supplemental policies; and (2) determine during 1999 whether the amendments made by this Act shall remain in effect beyond such extended period. Declares that such amendments shall remain in effect beyond the extended period unless the Secretary determines, based on the study, that as a result of such amendments: (1) there have been no savings in premium costs to select enrollees as compared to their enrollment in Medicare supplemental policies with comparable coverage which are not Medicare select policies; (2) there have been significant additional expenditures under the Medicare program; or (3) access to and quality of care have been significantly diminished.</summary>
</bill>
