<bill session="108" type="h" number="1291" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State High Risk Pool Drug Assistance Program Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to include State high risk pool insurance programs in the list of covered entities that receive reductions in the prices charged for prescription drugs under the prescription drug pricing agreements under section 340B of that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400092" joined="2003-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2003-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E453"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2003--Introduced.
State High Risk Pool Drug Assistance Program Act of 2003 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to add to the definition of a covered entity for purposes of the limitation on prices of drugs purchased by such entities. Includes as a covered entity a State-operated qualified high risk pool that provides for premium rates and covered benefits for such coverage consistent with standards included in the National Association of Insurance Commissioners Model Health Plan for Uninsurable Individuals. Directs the Secretary to include certain conditions in regulations implementing this Act, including that: (1) pharmacies that fill prescriptions for eligible individuals may bill the administrator or pharmacy benefit manager of the pool; (2) the pool shall maintain records of an eligible individual's health care claims; and (3) individuals shall receive health care services from contracted network providers. States that the pool shall serve individuals who would be eligible as a covered entity but for level of income, though that it shall not be limited to such individuals.</summary>
</bill>
