<bill session="106" type="h" number="1996" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Children's Lead SAFE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Children's Lead Screening Accountability For Early-Intervention Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that children enrolled in Medicaid and other Federal means-tested programs at highest risk for lead poisoning are identified and treated, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="1999-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1999-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="1999-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1122-1123"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1120"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Head Start programs"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicaid managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/1999--Introduced.
Children's Lead Screening Accountability For Early-Intervention Act of 1999 or Children's Lead SAFE Act- Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require State Medicaid plans to provide for reporting to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) of the number of children who: (1) are under age three and enrolled in the State plan; and (2) have received a blood lead screening test.Requires each contract between the State and an entity responsible for provision of medical assistance under the State plan to provide for: (1) compliance with mandatory blood lead screening requirements consistent with prevailing guidelines of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) for such screening; and (2) coverage of qualified lead treatment services. Allows reimbursement for qualified lead treatment services for children with elevated blood lead levels. Provides for enhanced Federal matching contributions for an information retrieval system that determines whether a child is enrolled under a State plan and whether an enrolled child has received mandatory early and periodic screening, diagnostic, and treatment services.Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 and the Head Start Act to mandate blood lead poisoning screening tests for an infant or child to be eligible to participate in either the special supplemental food program for women, infants, and children (WIC) or early Head Start and Head Start programs.Amends SSA title XXI (Children's Health Insurance Program) (CHIP) to mandate CHIP coverage for blood lead poisoning screening tests for children Amends the Public Health Service Act and SSA title V (Maternal and Child Health Services) with regard to grants for lead poisoning related activities. Authorizes appropriations.Imposes specified requirements on the CDC Director, including that the Director offer various assistance to the States with regard to children and lead poisoning. Authorizes appropriations.Outlines provisions for training and congressional reports with regard to HHS' Health Resources and Services Administration and childhood lead poisoning and blood lead screening tests.Mandates a CDC bonus program to improve the blood lead screening rates of States for children under age three enrolled in Medicaid. Details program particulars. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
