<bill session="108" type="h" number="1132" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Home At Last Tax Credit Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit to promote homeownership among low-income individuals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400201"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2003-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2003-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2003-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2003-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2003-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2003-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2003-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2003-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2003-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2003-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Mortgage banks"/>
    <term name="Mortgage interest rates"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2003--Introduced.
Home at Last Tax Credit of 2003 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a credit to promote homeownership among low-income individuals purchasing homes in a census tract targeted for reinvestment and redevelopment by the Department of Housing and Urban Development.Provides that the dollar amount of home at last tax credits received by each qualified State shall be equal to the population of the State multiplied by 40 cents, multiplied by 10, plus the unused home at last tax credit dollar amount of the state for the preceding calendar year or years. Provides for a cost-of-living adjustment.Defines a "qualified home at last loan" as a first mortgage single-family residential loan funded by a qualified lender to finance the purchase or construction or purchase and construction of a residence by a qualified borrower (meeting residence and income requirements) which has a lower-than-market interest rate as a result of a lender rate "buydown", but only if the loan, among other things: (1) does not exceed 105 percent of the purchase price of the residence; and (2) results in a monthly housing expense-to-income ratio with respect to such residence of not more than 33 percent at the time of closing.Requires annual reports from each State housing finance agency which allocates any home at last tax credit amount to any qualified lender.Prohibits carryback of home at last tax credits before the effective date.</summary>
</bill>
