<bill session="104" type="h" number="2259" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-10-18T21:04:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-10-18T21:04:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To disapprove certain sentencing guideline amendments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 7 - 3.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-09-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 104-272.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-09-29T18:25:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="141">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 141.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-10-17T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 237 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2259 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. A specified amendment is in order. An amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of S. 1254, as passed by the Senate, shall be considered as adopted in the Committee of the Whole and in the House. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of further amendment. No further amendment shall be in order except the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, debatable for 1 hour and not subject to amendment. After passage of the bill, it shall be in order to take from the Sp eaker's table and consider the bill S. 1254. It shall be in order to move to strike all afte...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 237 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 237.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10263-10283" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2259 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. A specified amendment is in order. An amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of S. 1254, as passed by the Senate, shall be considered as adopted in the Committee of the Whole and in the House. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of further amendment. No further amendment shall be in order except the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, debatable for 1 hour and not subject to amendment. After passage of the bill, it shall be in order to take from the Sp eaker's table and consider the bill S. 1254. It shall be in order to move to strike all afte...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 237 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Doug Bereuter to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 237, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Conyers amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T20:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2259.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T20:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T20:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T20:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Watt (NC) moved to recommit with instructions to Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T20:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Watt (NC) motion to recommit the bill to the Committee on the Judiciary with instructions that the Committee report the bill back to the House forthwith with an amendment requiring the U.S. Sentencing Commission to report back to the Congress by March 1, 1996 new sentencing guidelines with respect to crack cocaine and money laundering.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T20:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T20:52:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 149 - 266 (Roll no. 724).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10283" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-10-18T21:04:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="725" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 332 - 83 (Roll no. 725).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T21:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T21:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Laid on the table. See S. 1254 for further action.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10284" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="237"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2063"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2073"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1254"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Cocaine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Crack (Drug)"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Pleas (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Weapons"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h877"/>
    <amendment number="h878"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/18/1995--Passed House amended.
Disapproves the U.S. Sentencing Commission's amendments to the Sentencing Guidelines relating to: (1) equalization of crack and cocaine powder quantities for trafficking and possession offenses; and (2) money laundering and transactions in property derived from unlawful activity. (Sec. 2) Directs the Sentencing Commission to submit to the Congress recommendations regarding changes to the statutes and Sentencing Guidelines governing sentences for unlawful manufacturing, importing, exporting, and trafficking of cocaine and like offenses. Requires the recommendations to reflect the following considerations: (1) the sentence for trafficking in crack cocaine should generally exceed that imposed for trafficking in a like quantity of powder cocaine; (2) high-level cocaine traffickers should generally receive longer sentences than low-level traffickers; (3) a defendant who knowingly traffics in powder cocaine that will be converted into crack cocaine prior to its distribution to individuals should be treated at sentencing as though the defendant had trafficked in crack cocaine; and (4) an enhanced sentence should generally be imposed on a defendant who, in the course of an offense, murders or causes serious bodily injury to an individual, uses a dangerous weapon or possesses a firearm, involves a juvenile, a pregnant woman, or an unusually vulnerable person, engages in a continuing criminal enterprise or commits other criminal offenses in order to facilitate drug trafficking activities, restrains a victim, traffics in cocaine within 500 feet of a school, obstructs justice, has a significant prior criminal record, or is an organizer or leader of drug trafficking activities involving five or more persons. Specifies that such recommendations shall propose revision of the drug quantity ratio of crack cocaine to powder cocaine under the relevant statutes and guidelines in a manner consistent with the ratios set for other drugs. Requires: (1) the Department of Justice (DOJ) to report to the House and Senate Judiciary Committees on the charging and plea practices of Federal prosecutors with respect to money laundering; and (2) the Sentencing Commission to submit to such committees comments on the DOJ report.</summary>
</bill>
