<bill session="104" type="h" number="4245" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tobacco Youth Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restrict the access of youth to tobacco products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404280"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Age (Law)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
    <term name="Smoking and youth"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="Vending machines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Introduced.
Tobacco Youth Access Act - Allows the use of vending machines to sell tobacco products only in an area or establishment to which individuals under 18 years old (or such higher age as a State has set) (minimum age) are denied access. Allows the sale or distribution of cigarettes only in a package of 20 cigarettes. Prohibits offering or distributing tobacco products for sampling except in an area or establishment to which individuals under the minimum age are denied access. Mandates signs in retail establishments indicating the tobacco product purchase minimum age and the proof of age requirements, which must include photo identification. Requires retailers and their employees to sign an annual certification of knowledge of the minimum age and to conduct all tobacco product sales face-to-face. Prohibits the distribution of tobacco products through the redemption of coupons or coins except in face-to-face transactions. Requires the termination of any block grant under provisions of the Public Health Service Act relating to substance abuse, tuberculosis, and acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) if a State does not restrict youth access to tobacco as prescribed in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
