<bill session="105" type="h" number="1830" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for claim maintenance fees and royalties on hardrock mining claims, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404375"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-16">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mineral industries"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/1997--Introduced.
Mandates annual claim maintenance fees of $100 per claim per calendar year (except shale claims subject to claim maintenance fees under the Energy Policy Act of 1992). Reduces such fees by the amount of the claim maintenance fees paid under the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993. Allows the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Minerals Management Service (MMS), to waive claim maintenance fees for claim holders that, with all related parties, held no more than ten claims on lands open to location. States that the claim interest of any co-owner who fails to contribute his portion of the claim maintenance fee shall become the property of the co-owners who have paid the required fee. Subjects the production of locatable minerals located under the general mining laws (including their concentrates and products) to a royalty payment of eight percent of the gross income. Prescribes guidelines for the duties of claim holders, operators, and transporters. Authorizes the Secretary to require by rule that transporters possess documentation showing the amount, origin, and intended destination of the locatable mineral, concentrate or product. Prescribes recordkeeping, reporting, and auditing requirements. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with the Secretary of Agriculture to implement this Act. Provides for: (1) interest and substantial underreporting assessments in cases of tardy or delinquent mining claim royalty payments; and (2) several and joint liability for royalty payments on all locatable minerals, concentrates, or products derived therefrom which are lost or wasted due to negligence or noncompliance with regulations. Directs the Secretary to adjust dollar amounts every ten years for changes in the purchasing power of the dollar.</summary>
</bill>
