<bill session="104" type="h" number="2172" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vancouver National Historic Reserve Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Vancouver National Historic Reserve, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406799" joined="1995-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-28">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.4236.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="4236"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="1127"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Columbia River development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="General aviation aircraft"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Private aviation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Waterfronts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/1995--Introduced.
Vancouver National Historic Reserve Act of 1995 - Establishes the Vancouver National Historic Reserve in the State of Washington. (Sec. 5) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary), acting through the Director of the National Park Service, and the Secretary of the Army to participate as members of the Vancouver National Historic Reserve Partnership to oversee the protection, enhancement, and development of the Reserve. Requires the Partnership to: (1) act as a forum for cooperation and coordination among the member agencies; (2) minimize staffing, development, and operational costs to each member agency; (3) promote the coordinated protection, use, and interpretation of the cultural, recreational, and educational resources of the Reserve; (4) identify additional opportunities for appropriate public use and enjoyment of the Reserve; and (5) develop and coordinate implementation of the management plan, including the Pearson Airpark economic viability and mitigation plan, and an interpretive plan for the Reserve pursuant to this Act. Requires the Partnership to: (1) be comprised of a representative of each of the National Park Service, the Historic Preservation Office of the State of Washington, the Department of the Army, the city of Vancouver, and the citizens of Washington State; and (2) prepare and submit to the Secretary for review and approval a cooperative agreement, prepared with public participation, to govern the operations of the Partnership. (Sec. 8) Requires the Partnership to: (1) develop and submit a management plan for the Reserve to the Secretary for review and approval; and (2) as appropriate, submit a revised plan to the Secretary upon evaluating the progress made in implementing the original one. Allows the Partnership to enter into a memorandum of agreement with a State, a political subdivision, or a private person or organization that, at a minimum, establishes procedures for providing notice to the Partnership of actions proposed by such entity that may affect implementation of the management plan. (Sec. 9) Permits general aviation at Pearson Airpark that is permitted to be conducted on National Park Service (NPS) property on the enactment of this Act to continue after the year 2002, provided that: (1) Pearson AirField and Air Museum shall be operated by the city of Vancouver; (2) Vancouver pays the NPS a fee of $1 per year for the continued use and occupancy of the Airpark on NPS property and the appraised fair market land rental value of the portion of such property that is used for development of the Pearson Airpark Historical Museum; (3) all nonhistoric, aviation-related facilities and equipment shall be removed by Vancouver from NPS property by April 6, 2003, except those necessary for navigation and safety; (4) Vancouver shall not be compensated for historic aviation-related facilities or equipment remaining on NPS property, but shall be liable and responsible for continued use and maintenance of such facilities and equipment; (5) approval of the Secretary is required for all improvements and additions to facilities or equipment of the Air Museum located on NPS property; (6) helicopters shall not be based at Pearson Airpark except as necessary to accommodate emergency, disaster, or national security needs; and (7) the number of airworthy aircraft based at the Airpark shall be determined under the Pearson economic plan. Requires the Partnership to prepare and include in the management plan an economic viability and mitigation plan for the Pearson Airpark. (Sec. 10) Authorizes the Secretary to provide financial and technical assistance in preparing, developing, and implementing the management plan. (Sec. 12) Authorizes appropriations. Limits the Federal share of the costs of Partnership activities in a fiscal year to 50 percent.</summary>
</bill>
