<bill session="104" type="h" number="2231" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Technology Export Review Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Export Administration Act of 1979 to require reviews of the commodity control list.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407772"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1662-1663"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Semiconductors"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1995--Introduced.
Technology Export Review Act - Amends the Export Administration Act of 1979 to direct the Secretary of Commerce to conduct periodic reviews of national security and foreign policy export controls on goods and technology in order to ensure that requirements for validated licenses to export are periodically removed as such items become obsolete with respect to the objectives of such controls. Requires the Secretary, if the review warrants, to: (1) eliminate the requirement for an export license for a particular good or technology; (2) make such item eligible for delivery under a distribution license or other license authorizing multiple exports; (3) eliminate a performance threshold upon which the license requirement for the item is based; or (4) increase the performance levels at which a license for such item is required, at which it is eligible for delivery under a distribution license, or at which special conditions or security safeguard plans are imposed as a condition of export. Requires the Secretary to: (1) identify mass-market products (any good or technology sold, licensed, or distributed as a discrete item which will have been distributed for end use outside the United States in a quantity exceeding 100,000 units over a 12-month period); and (2) propose the elimination of export controls on such an item to any group of countries which imposes similar controls on it cooperatively with the United States. Requires the export control treatment imposed under this Act upon semiconductor devices to be no more restrictive or burdensome to the exporter than controls imposed under such Act upon computer systems or telecommunications systems for which the semiconductor devices serve as components.</summary>
</bill>
