<bill session="108" type="h" number="4224" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require revisions to the Federal Acquisition Regulation to require executive agencies to seek commercial, volume, or other discounts for purchases made with the Governmentwide commercial purchase card, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2004-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2004--Introduced.
Requires that the Federal Acquisition Regulation be revised to require the head of each executive agency to: (1) seek commercial, volume, or other discounts for purchases made with Government-wide commercial purchase card; (2) use procurement mechanisms other than purchase cards, including contracts, as appropriate to maximize cost savings; and (3) systematically collect and analyze data on use of the Government-wide commercial purchase card, including by vendor, in sufficient detail to identify opportunities to achieve savings. Directs the Comptroller General to report to specified congressional committees regarding: (1) the status and content of revisions required by this Act and any resulting agency policies and procedures, including a determination of whether the information collected is sufficient to identify opportunities to achieve savings; and (2) executive branch progress in improving data collection on Government-wide commercial purchase card use and in seeking discounts or entering into agreements that provide for reduced prices, and savings achieved through the use of discounts or other procurement mechanisms. Requires the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy to direct the head of each executive agency to provide to the Comptroller General such information as necessary to implement such requirements.</summary>
</bill>
