<bill session="105" type="h" number="767" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:45-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common-Sense Campaign Finance Reform Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require candidates for election for the House of Representatives or the Senate to raise at least 65 percent of their contributions from individuals residing in the district or State involved, to limit the amount of contributions such candidates may accept from multicandidate political committees, and to prohibit individuals who are ineligible to register to vote in Federal elections from making contributions to candidates or political parties.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400225"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="1997-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1997-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="1997-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="1997-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H567-568)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H567-568"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>02/13/1997--Introduced.
Common Sense Campaign Finance Reform Act of 1997 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to limit the amount of contributions a candidate may accept from: (1) individuals not residing in the candidate's district; and (2) multicandidate political committees. Sets forth reporting requirements. Prohibits individuals not eligible to vote in Federal elections from making any contribution to any candidate for election to Federal office or to any political party.</summary>
</bill>
