<bill session="104" type="h" number="2977" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-12">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Administrative Dispute Resolution Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Administrative Dispute Resolution Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Administrative Dispute Resolution Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize alternative means of dispute resolution in the Federal administrative process, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An Act to reauthorize alternative means of dispute resolution in the Federal administrative process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400544"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="1996-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-03-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-05-29T20:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 104-597.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-05-29T20:13:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="297">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 297.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-04T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gekas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-04T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5786-5789" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-04T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-06-04T15:43:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-06-04T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-06-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="427">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 427.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-12">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6162" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-12">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 1224 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1996-06-12" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 1224 with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-06-12">
      <text>Senate insisted on its amendment, requested a conference.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6162" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-14">
      <text>Senate appointed conferees Stevens; Cohen; Grassley; Glenn; Levin by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-19T10:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hyde asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-19T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10607" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-19T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Hyde, Gekas, Flanagan, Conyers, and Reed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-19T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-25T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 104-841 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11108-11111" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.4194.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="4194"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="4194"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="1224"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="104" type="s" number="1224"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1224"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="104" type="s" number="1224"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative Conference of the U.S."/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government employees' life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government employees' political activities"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Position classification"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/1996--Conference report filed in House.
Administrative Dispute Resolution Act of 1996 - Amends the Administrative Dispute Resolution Act (ADRA) and other Federal law with regard to alternative means of dispute resolution (ADR) in the administrative process. (Sec. 2) Includes the use of ombuds and arbitration among ADR procedures, but excludes settlement negotiations. Repeals: (1) the current exclusion and permits parties to use ADR to resolve certain Federal employee-related disputes involving such matters as retirement, life or health insurance, and suspension or removal from duty, as well as prohibited personnel practices; and (2) a requirement that a procedure used be in lieu of an adjudication to come within the definition of ADR. (Sec. 3) Limits applicability of confidentiality requirements only to communications involved in the proceeding, and no longer, also, to any information concerning such communications. Provides that a dispute resolution communication generated by a neutral which may not be disclosed under such provisions is exempt from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act. (Sec. 4) Makes certain amendments under ADRA and the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947 to reflect the closure of the Administrative Conference of the United States. (Sec. 5) Authorizes a Federal agency to use the services and facilities of State, local, and tribal governments for ADR purposes. (Sec. 6) Amends the Contract Disputes Act of 1978 to: (1) require contractors using ADR procedures to resolve a claim against the Federal Government to comply with the same certification procedures applicable to any other claim subject to such Act; and (2) repeal its termination date. (Sec. 7) Provides for expedited hiring of neutrals in civilian and defense agency contracts for use in any part of an ADR process. Amends ADR law on neutrals to: (1) repeal requirements for the Government to establish professional standards for neutrals and maintain a roster of qualified neutrals; and (2) require the President to designate an agency or designate or establish an interagency committee to facilitate and encourage agency use of dispute resolution. Directs such agency or committee to encourage and facilitate agency use of ADR and develop procedures that permit agencies to obtain the services of neutrals on an expedited basis. (Sec. 8) Revises ADRA and other ADR law, with regard to judicial review of arbitration awards, to: (1) repeal the authority of Federal agency heads to vacate unilaterally any award issued pursuant to an arbitration proceeding; (2) require each arbitration agreement to specify a maximum award that may be issued by the arbitrator and allow it to specify other conditions limiting the range of possible outcomes; (3) prohibit an agency officer or employee from offering to use arbitration for the resolution of issues in controversy unless he or she has authority to enter into a settlement concerning the matter or is otherwise specifically authorized by the agency to consent to the use of arbitration; and (4) require the head of an agency, prior to using binding arbitration, to issue guidance on its appropriate use or when an agency officer or employee has authority to settle an issue in controversy through binding arbitration. (Sec. 9) Amends ADRA to repeal its termination date and provide for permanent authorization. (Sec. 10) Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 11) Repeals the reauthorization for the Administrative Conference under the Negotiated Rulemaking Act of 1990. Directs the President to designate an agency or designate or establish an interagency committee to facilitate and encourage agency use of negotiated rulemaking. Modifies Federal provisions regarding defense agency contracts and Federal contracts to provide for expedited hiring of conveners and facilitators for negotiated rulemaking. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to: (1) take action to expedite the establishment of negotiated rulemaking committees and committees established to resolve disputes under ADRA; and (2) submit recommendations to the Congress for any necessary legislative changes. (Sec. 12) Revises Federal judicial code provisions regarding the jurisdiction of the United States Court of Federal Claims. Grants such court jurisdiction to review the agency's decision pursuant to specified standards.</summary>
</bill>
