<bill session="106" type="hr" number="285" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the referendum in East Timor and calling on the Government of Indonesia and all other parties to the current civil unrest in East Timor to assist in any attempts to immediately terminate the paramilitary's campaign of violence and terror and comply with the overwhelming results of the August 30, 1999, popular consultation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1999-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="1999-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="1999-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1999-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="1999-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="1999-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="1999-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8003"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Annexation (International law)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="East Timor"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International banking"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Martial law"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="National self-determination"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Refugee policy"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations employees"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/1999--Introduced.
Commends the people of East Timor for their perseverance to cast their vote on the future status of East Timor in a democratic manner. Congratulates them on their exemplary participation in the August 30, 1999, popular consultation.Condemns: (1) the post-election violence carried out by paramilitary groups against United Nations (UN) personnel and the people of East Timor; and (2) the assaults upon refugees seeking protection in churches, the International Red Cross, and other places of sanctuary. Expresses concern about the imposition of martial law by Indonesia in East Timor.Calls for international action to address the humanitarian crisis in which thousands of refugees from East Timor are blocked from receiving food or medical care. Reaffirms U.S. concern for the human suffering inflicted on the East Timorese. Demands an immediate halt to the violence and a peaceful transition to independence for East Timor.Encourages: (1) efforts on behalf of the UN to put pressure on the Government of Indonesia to attempt to control, disarm, and disband the militias in East Timor; (2) efforts by the UN envoys in Indonesia to express the international community's outrage over the violence in East Timor and to make plain to the Indonesian Government its responsibility to restrain paramilitary forces and to restore order and respect for human rights in East Timor; and (3) increased U.S. support for an expanded UN mandate with respect to East Timor, and significantly more UN personnel, leading toward assumption of U.S. responsibility for administration and security in East Timor.Welcomes continued dialogue between UN Secretary General Kofi Annan and Indonesian authorities for further measures to restore law and order in East Timor.Calls upon: (1) the President to suspend all remaining military assistance to Indonesia until the paramilitaries in East Timor are controlled and to condition all future non-humanitarian assistance to Indonesia upon the ability and willingness of the Indonesian Government to control paramilitary and militia forces and to restore order and respect for human rights in East Timor; (2) international organizations, including the World Bank and the International Monetary Fund, to condition all future non- humanitarian assistance to Indonesia upon the ability and willingness of the Indonesian Government to control such forces and to restore order and respect for human rights; (3) the UN Security Council to offer assistance to the Indonesian Government; (4) the international community to play an active role in helping to resolve the internal conflict in East Timor by encouraging all sides to participate in the peace process; and (5) the UN Security Council, should it determine that the Indonesian Government is unable or unwilling to maintain order in East Timor, to authorize member states of the UN to protect the lives and human rights of East Timor refugees.</summary>
</bill>
