<bill session="106" type="h" number="5439" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Taxpaper Protection and Contractor Integrity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To end taxpayer support of Federal Government contractors against whom repeated civil judgements or criminal convictions for certain offenses have been entered.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="3185"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Embezzlement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Indictments"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Receiving stolen goods"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/2000--Introduced.
Taxpayer Protection and Contractor Integrity Act - Requires Federal contracting officers to require any potential contractor who has disclosed the existence of an indictment, charge, conviction, or civil judgment under the Federal Acquisition Regulation to submit information regarding the number of such convictions or civil judgments, the nature of the offenses, and whether any fines, penalties, or damages were assessed.Prohibits the award of a Federal contract for the procurement of property or services to any individual or entity against whom three or more convictions or civil judgments have been entered after this Act's enactment for: (1) fraud or a criminal offense in connection with obtaining or performing a Federal, State, or local government contract or subcontract; (2) violation of a Federal or State antitrust statute relating to the submission of contract offers; or (3) embezzlement, theft, forgery, bribery, falsification or destruction of records, making false statements, or receiving stolen property in connection with obtaining such a contract or subcontract.Terminates such prohibition three years after the most recent conviction or civil judgment, subject to specified requirements. Authorizes the President to waive such prohibition: (1) in the interests of national security; or (2) if the need for the property or services is of such an unusual and compelling urgency that the Federal Government would be seriously injured in the absence of a waiver.</summary>
</bill>
