<bill session="106" type="h" number="1526" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commercial Space Competitiveness Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote the international competitiveness of the United States commercial space industry, to ensure access to space for the Federal Government and the private sector, and to minimize the opportunities for the transfer to other nations of critical satellite technologies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400427"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="1999-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Ground support systems (Astronautics)"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Launch vehicles"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space commercialization"/>
    <term name="Space flight"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1999--Introduced.
Commercial Space Competitiveness Act of 1999 - Amends the Commercial Space Launch Act to revise the definition of "launch" to delete provisions limiting the definition to activities involved in the preparation of a launch vehicle or payload for launch only when they take place at a launch site in the United States. Requires, in the scheduling of launches at a U.S. Government launch site, that private sector launches be provided the greatest possible access to launch opportunities at the earliest possible dates. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to facilitate and encourage the acquisition by the private sector and State governments of Federal property and services, including utilities, for the support of commercial space launch efforts. Requires, at least 30 days before any property is acquired, for the head of an agency from which the property is to be acquired to provide public notice of the proposed acquisition.</summary>
</bill>
