<bill session="107" type="h" number="974" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-04-03T16:33:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-04-03T16:33:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Interest Checking Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Small Business Interest Checking Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Small Business Interest Checking Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the number of interaccount transfers which may be made from business accounts at depository institutions, to authorize the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to pay interest on reserves, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To repeal the prohibition on the payment of interest on demand deposits, to increase the number of interaccount transfers which may be made from business accounts at depository institutions, to authorize the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to pay interest on reserves, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400060" joined="2001-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2001-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2001-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-03-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-04-03T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 107-38.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-04-03T15:18:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="27">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 27.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-04-03T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Oxley moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-03T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1374-1379" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-03T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 974.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-04-03T16:33:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1374-1375" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-04-03T16:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-03T16:33:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="524"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Automated teller machines"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Bank reserves"/>
    <term name="Checking accounts"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money supply"/>
    <term name="NOW accounts"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2001--Passed House amended.
Small Business Interest Checking Act of 2001- Amends the Federal Reserve Act, the Home Owners' Loan Act, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to repeal the proscription against payment of interest on demand deposits.Authorizes certain depository institutions prohibited by State law from offering demand deposits to offer all owners of a interest- or dividend-paying deposit or account to make withdrawals by negotiable or transferable instruments for the purpose of making payments to third parties. Requires that such an institution either: (1) not engage in lending activities; or (2) not be an affiliate of a company or companies whose aggregate assets represent over ten percent of the institution's total assets.Amends Federal banking law governing interaccount transfers to provide that a depository institution may permit owners of certain interest- or dividend-paying accounts to make up to 24 transfers monthly for any purpose to their other accounts in the same institution.Amends the Federal Reserve Act to authorize a Federal reserve bank to pay interest at least quarterly (at a rate not to exceed the general level of short term interest rates) to a depository institution on any balance it maintains at the reserve bank.Repeals a specified restriction in order to authorize pass-through reserves for member banks (as well as non-member banks).Instructs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to obtain annually a prescribed survey of designated retail bank fees and services (including electronic and credit card fees), and report the results annually to Congress.Reformulates the mandatory depository institution reserve ratio to: (1) one that is not greater than three percent, and may be zero, (currently, a flat ratio of three percent) for transaction accounts of $25 million or less; and (2) reduce from eight percent to zero the minimum ratio for transaction accounts exceeding $25 million. (Thus authorizes zero reserve requirements for such accounts.)Requires the Federal Reserve banks to transfer certain surplus funds for deposit into the general fund of the Treasury equal to the estimated net cost of making the quarterly payments of interest mandated by this Act for FY 2002 through 2006.Prohibits such banks from replenishing surplus funds by the amount of any such transfers during that time period.</summary>
</bill>
