<bill session="108" type="h" number="3747" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wallowa Lake Dam Rehabilitation and Water Management Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Bureau of Reclamation to participate in the rehabilitation of the Wallowa Lake Dam in Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400419"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1355"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/28/2004--Introduced.
Wallowa Lake Dam Rehabilitation and Water Management Act of 2004 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation: (1) to provide funding to the Associated Ditch Companies, Incorporated, to plan, design, and construct facilities needed to implement the Wallowa Lake Dam Rehabilitation Program; and (2) in cooperation with tribal, State, and local governmental entities, to participate in the planning, design, and construction of facilities needed to implement the Wallowa Valley Water Management Plan. Limits the Federal share of the cost of activities authorized under this Act to 80 percent and prohibits the Federal Government from holding title to any facility rehabilitated or constructed under this Act. Permits only the Nez Perce Tribe to own and operate any facility located at the Dam for trapping and transportation of migratory adult salmon.</summary>
</bill>
