<bill session="104" type="h" number="968" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Early Childhood Education Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish comprehensive early childhood education programs, early childhood education staff development programs, model Federal Government early childhood education programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400554"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1995-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of Indians"/>
    <term name="Education of handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational surveys"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Migrant education"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Single-parent families"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Unemployed"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in education"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Working mothers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Comprehensive Early Childhood Education Programs Title II: Training, Technical Assistance, Planning, and Evaluation Title III: Model Federal Government Child Development Programs Title IV: Research and Demonstrations Title V: General Provisions Comprehensive Early Childhood Education Act of 1995 - Establishes and expands comprehensive early childhood education programs and services. (Sec. 4) Authorizes appropriations. Title I: Comprehensive Early Childhood Education Programs - Directs the Secretary of Education to provide financial assistance for early childhood education programs to prime sponsors and other public and private nonprofit agencies and organizations pursuant to approved plans and applications. (Sec. 102) Authorizes the Secretary to designate a State, locality, combination of localities, Indian tribe on a Federal or State reservation, or public or private nonprofit agency or organization as a prime sponsor if it meets certain requirements and has its plan approved. (Sec. 103) Requires each designated prime sponsor to establish and maintain an Early Childhood Education Council. (Sec. 104) Sets forth requirements for comprehensive early childhood education plans. (Sec. 106) Authorizes special grants to States for various purposes. (Sec. 108) Requires reports on possible use of public facilities for child development programs. (Sec. 109) Provides for Federal share payments for programs, services, and activities. Title II: Training, Technical Assistance, Planning, and Evaluation - Authorizes the Secretary to make payments for preservice and inservice training for programs under this Act for employees, potential employees, and volunteers. (Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary to make technical assistance available to prime sponsors and project applicants for planning, developing, and implementing programs under this Act. (Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary to make an annual evaluation of Federal involvement in early childhood education activities. (Sec. 204) Directs the Secretary to: (1) appoint a Special Committee on Federal Standards for Early Childhood Education; and (2) promulgate Federal Standards for Early Childhood Education to be applicable to all programs assisted under this Act. (Sec. 205) Directs the Secretary to appoint a special committee to develop a uniform licensing code for early childhood education facilities. Title III: Model Federal Government Early Childhood Education Programs - Authorizes the Secretary to provide financial assistance to establish and operate model early childhood education programs for the children of Federal civilian employees. (Sec. 302) Provides for Federal share payments. Title IV: Research and Demonstrations - Directs the Secretary to: (1) carry out a program of early childhood development research and demonstration projects; and (2) coordinate all early childhood education research, training, and development within the Federal Government and, as feasible, by other agencies, organizations, and individuals. Requires representatives of specified Federal agencies to meet at least annually to coordinate child development and early childhood education and related activities. Title V: General Provisions - Defines "children" as individuals who have not reached age eight. (Sec. 502) Directs the Secretary to establish procedures to assure that adequate nutrition services will be provided in programs under this Act. Requires such services to make use of the Special Food Services Program for children. (Sec. 503) Sets forth special administrative (including nondiscrimination) provisions. Provides for withholding of grants and for public information.</summary>
</bill>
