<amendment session="107" chamber="h" number="416" updated="2013-07-17T08:15:54-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2356" sequence="2"/>
  <status datetime="2002-02-13T14:43:00-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="400293"/>
  <offered datetime="2002-02-13"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to ban soft money by political parties for Federal election activity; increase contribution limits for political parties and individuals; and define and regulate "express advocacy" communications.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute numbered 14 printed in the Congressional Record of February 12, 2002. to prohibit national and state parties from soliciting, receiving or spending soft money; to increase the aggregate limit an individual may contribute to candidates, parties and political action committees (PACs) from $25,000 to $30,000; to increases the limit on contributions from individuals and PACs to state parties to $10,000 per year; to require television and radio ads to include an audio statement by the candidate that clearly identifies the candidate and states the candidate's approval of the ad; the audio statement would also be required to contain a statement as to what organization is responsible for the content of the ad; to create an independent commission on campaign finance reform to study current law and recommend legislation to reform those laws; to make it illegal to to provide money to an individual as a means of encouraging him or her to vote; to prohibit the use of political fundraising and require national parties to reimburse the federal government for the use of Air Force One by the president, vice president or any head of an executive department for travel to a political fund raising event; to state that if any portion of the legislation is ruled unconstitutional, the remainder of the act and any adopted amendments to the act should remain intact; and to authorize any legal review of the act to go directly to the Supreme Court.Finally, the measure's provisions become effective 90 days after the bill is signed into law.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-02-13T13:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Ney.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H377-393" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H377-385" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2002-02-13T14:43:00-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="20">
      <text>On agreeing to the Ney amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 53 - 377 (Roll no. 20).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
