<bill session="107" type="h" number="3534" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-01T18:44:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-01T18:44:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cherokee, Choctaw, and Chickasaw Nations Claims Settlement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Cherokee, Choctaw, and Chickasaw Nations Claims Settlement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Cherokee, Choctaw, and Chickasaw Nations Claims Settlement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the settlement of certain land claims of Cherokee, Choctaw, and Chickasaw Nations to the Arkansas Riverbed in Oklahoma.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2002-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2001-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="2001-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400392" joined="2002-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400540" joined="2001-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-17">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Received from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-06-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-632.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-09-04T15:48:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="381">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 381.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6879-6883" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3534.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-10-01T18:44:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6880-6882" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-10-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="632">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 632.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Riparian rights"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2002--Passed House amended.
Cherokee, Choctaw, and Chickasaw Nations Claims Settlement Act - Declares that, pursuant to tribal resolutions and in exchange for the benefits conferred by this Act, the Cherokee, Choctaw, and Chickasaw Nations (Indian Nations) shall enter into a consent decree with the United States that extinguishes, upon payment of specified funds, all claims the Indian Nations have pending in the United States Court of Federal Claims in two specified cases against the United States. Describes the content of such cases as including the Indian Nations' interests in the Disclaimed Drybed Lands and the construction, maintenance and operation of the McClellan-Kerr Navigation Way on the Arkansas River, Oklahoma.Approves and ratifies transfers of interests in the Disclaimed Drybed Lands by parties other than the Indian Nations that have occurred in violation of the Trade and Intercourse Act, to the extent that such transfers are otherwise valid under law.Sets forth retained rights in related lands, minerals, and waterways.Entitles the United States to setoff against claims of the Indian Nations in the event the Court of Federal Claims does not enter into a consent decree as set forth in this Act.Exempts the United States and the Indian Nations from being made parties to any quiet title lawsuit or other lawsuit to determine ownership of or an interest in the Disclaimed Drybed lands after the execution of this Act.Requires that any lands above the high water mark of the Arkansas River that are declared surplus be taken into trust for the Indian Nation within whose boundary the land is located.Authorizes appropriations for the settlement of claims.Allocates claim settlement funds among the Indian Nations, depositing them in specified trust fund accounts. Makes such funds available for the acquisition of land, as specified. Provides for such funds' investment and the payment of attorney's fees, subject to specified limitations.</summary>
</bill>
