<bill session="106" type="h" number="675" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Beryllium Exposure Compensation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide jurisdiction and procedures for affording relief for injuries arising out of exposure to hazards involved in the mining and processing of beryllium.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="1999-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="1999-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="1999-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="1999-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Beryllium"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/1999--Introduced.
Beryllium Exposure Compensation Act - Provides jurisdiction and procedures for affording relief for injuries arising out of exposure to hazards involved in the mining and processing of beryllium. (Sec. 3) Establishes the Beryllium Exposure Compensation Trust Fund in the Treasury. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to administer the Fund. Requires amounts in the Fund to be: (1) invested in accordance with specified law; and (2) available only for disbursement by the Attorney General (AG) under this Act. Terminates the Fund after 30 years. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 4) Requires an eligible beryllium worker to receive $100,000 if the AG determines that the claim filed by or on behalf of that individual meets certain requirements for payment. Makes individuals eligible if they: (1) were employed at a beryllium industry site; (2) were exposed to significant beryllium hazards in the course of such employment; and (3) after such exposure developed a condition known to be related to beryllium exposure. (Sec. 5) Directs the AG to establish: (1) procedures for claims submission and payment, including documentation of individual employment and exposure, as well as written medical documentation of the development of a related condition; and (2) guidelines for claims determination, in consultation with other specified Federal officials. Sets forth claims payment requirements, including provisions for: (1) payments to, and claims by, survivors; and (2) treatment of payments under other laws. Requires the AG to complete each claim determination within 12 months after the claim is filed. (Sec. 11) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to report to Congress by the end of FY 2003 on the incidence of beryllium-related illness among workers employed at beryllium industry sites. (Sec. 12) Provides for budget Act compliance.</summary>
</bill>
