<bill session="104" type="h" number="2024" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-13">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mercury-Containing and Rechargeable Battery Management Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Mercury-Containing Battery Management Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Rechargeable Battery Recycling Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Mercury-Containing and Rechargeable Battery Management Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Mercury-Containing Battery Management Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Rechargeable Battery Recycling Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Mercury-Containing and Rechargeable Battery Management Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Mercury-Containing Battery Management Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Rechargeable Battery Recycling Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To phase out the use of mercury in batteries and provide for the efficient and cost-effective collection and recycling or proper disposal of used nickel cadmium batteries, small sealed lead-acid batteries, and certain other batteries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406431"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1995-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="1995-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="1995-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1996-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1995-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="1995-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="404068" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1996-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404296" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1996-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1995-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400169" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="406799" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="408553" joined="1995-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1995-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409618" joined="1995-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1995-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1995-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1995-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1995-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1996-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411550" joined="1996-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-04-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-04-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-23T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Commerce. H. Rept. 104-530.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-04-23T13:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="260">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 260.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-04-23T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Oxley moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-23T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3671-3679" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-23T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-04-23T15:24:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-04-23T15:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-04-25" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4265-4266" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1996-04-25">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1996-04-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-05-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-05-13">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-05-13" type="public" number="104-142">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-142.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="619"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Battery recycling"/>
    <term name="Cadmium"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compost"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer goods"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Electric batteries"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Manganese"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="Nickel"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Zinc"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/1996--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Rechargeable Battery Recycling Act Title II: Mercury-Containing Battery Management Act Mercury-Containing and Rechargeable Battery Management Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a program to provide information on the proper handling and disposal of used regulated batteries and rechargeable consumer products with nonremovable batteries. Defines a "regulated battery" as a rechargeable battery that contains a cadmium or lead electrode or contains other electrode chemistries and is the subject of a specified determination by the Administrator. Establishes civil penalties for violations of this Act. Prohibits enforcement actions for the sale or offering for sale or promotional purposes to the final consumer of an unmodified battery or product that is purchased ready for final sale, except with respect to an importer who has knowledge of the chemical contents of the battery when such contents make the sale or offering of the battery unlawful under title II of this Act. Sets forth recordkeeping requirements and establishes access authorities for the Administrator. Authorizes appropriations. Title I: Rechargeable Battery Recycling Act - Rechargeable Battery Recycling Act - Prohibits any person from selling for use in the United States a regulated battery or a rechargeable consumer product ready for retail sale and manufactured on or after 12 months after this Act's enactment date unless the labeling requirements of this Act are met and the battery is easily removable from the product or is sold separately. Sets forth labeling requirements, including that the label contain a statement that the battery must be recycled or disposed of properly. Authorizes the Administrator, upon determining that other rechargeable batteries having electrode chemistries different from regulated batteries are toxic and may cause substantial harm if discarded for land disposal or incineration, to promulgate requirements for: (1) labeling such batteries and related products; and (2) easy removability of regulated batteries from rechargeable consumer products designed to contain such batteries. Provides for exemptions from this Act's requirements under certain conditions. Subjects the collection, storage, or transportation of used rechargeable batteries, certain batteries excluded from the definition of "rechargeable battery" under this Act, mercury-containing batteries, and used rechargeable consumer products containing rechargeable batteries that are easily removable, notwithstanding State or local laws, to certain EPA regulations promulgated on May 11, 1995, regarding management of hazardous wastes known as "universal" waste, except that: (1) States may implement such requirements if they are identical and the State provides enforcement; (2) the requirements of regulations (and equivalent State provisions) regarding rulemaking petitions, additional regulation of spent lead-acid batteries that are being reclaimed, and procedures for case-by-case regulation of such batteries shall not apply; and (3) these requirements shall not apply to any lead-acid battery managed under the reclamation regulations or equivalent State provisions. Subjects persons who fail to comply with these requirements to enforcement under applicable provisions of the Solid Waste Disposal Act. Title II: Mercury-Containing Battery Management Act - Mercury-Containing Battery Management Act - Prohibits the sale or offering for sale or promotional purposes of: (1) alkaline-manganese batteries manufactured on or after the date of enactment of this Act with a mercury content that was intentionally introduced (limits the content in alkaline-manganese button cells to 25 milligrams of mercury per button cell); (2) zinc carbon batteries manufactured on or after the date of enactment of this Act that contain mercury that was intentionally introduced; (3) button cell mercuric-oxide batteries for use in the United States on or after the date of enactment of this Act; and (4) any mercuric-oxide battery on or after the date of enactment of this Act unless the manufacturer identifies a collection site that has all required Federal, State, and local government approvals, to which persons may send such batteries for recycling or disposal and informs its purchasers of such site and of a telephone number to get information about sending such batteries for recycling or disposal. Authorizes the Administrator, upon the petition of a person that proposes a new use for a battery technology or the use of a battery described in this title in a new product, to exempt such new use or product from this title if there exist safeguards to ensure that the battery or product will not be disposed of in an incinerator, composting facility, or landfill (other than a facility regulated under subtitle C of the Solid Waste Disposal Act).</summary>
</bill>
