<bill session="106" type="h" number="4210" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-25T18:39:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-07-25T18:39:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preparedness Against Terrorism Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Preparedness Against Terrorism Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide for improved Federal efforts to prepare for and respond to terrorist attacks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400569" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2000-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="2000-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2000-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2000-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2000-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2000-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2000-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2000-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2000-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="2000-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2000-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2000-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2000-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="2000-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400592" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2000-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2000-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2000-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2000-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400609" joined="2000-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400610" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="2000-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="2000-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight, Investigations and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-25">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-13T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 106-731.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-13T16:22:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="413">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 413.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T17:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Fowler moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T17:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H6886-6893" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T17:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4210.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-07-25T18:39:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H6886-6889" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW11" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Droughts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal budget process"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2000--Passed House amended.
Preparedness Against Terrorism Act of 2000 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (the Act) to include snow droughts, acts of terrorism or other catastrophic events within its definition of "major disaster" for purposes of authorized disaster relief.(Sec. 4) Requires the President (current law authorizes the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA Director)) to be responsible for carrying out Federal emergency preparedness plans and programs. Includes as a covered hazard a domestic terrorist attack involving a weapon of mass destruction.(Sec. 6) Requires the President to ensure that Federal response plans and programs are adequate to respond to the consequences of terrorism directed against a target in the United States, including weapons of mass destruction. Includes the development of equipment, clothing, and facilities within authorized preparedness measures.(Sec. 7) Repeals provisions of the Act which: (1) allow State preparedness funds to be used to prepare for hazards and for providing emergency assistance in response to hazards; and (2) require the FEMA Director to establish emergency preparedness security regulations.(Sec. 9) Establishes the President's Council on Domestic Preparedness to, among other things: (1) establish Federal policies, objectives, and priorities for enhancing the capabilities of State and local emergency preparedness and response personnel in early detection and warning of and response to all domestic terrorist attacks, including those involving weapons of mass destruction; (2) publish a Domestic Terrorism Preparedness Plan and annual strategy for carrying out such Plan; (3) provide for the creation of a State and local advisory group for the Council; (4) establish voluntary guidelines for State and local preparedness programs; (5) coordinate and oversee the implementation of such Federal policies, objectives, and priorities; and (6) make recommendations to the heads of appropriate Federal departments and agencies with regard to implementation of the Plan. Requires the Plan and annual strategy to be transmitted to Congress. Requires any part of a Plan or strategy involving classified information to be presented separately to Congress.Requires the Council, in developing the Plan, to designate an entity to assess the risk of terrorist attacks against transportation facilities, personnel, and passengers. Requires the Council to monitor Plan implementation, including conducting program and performance audits and evaluations.Requires each Federal program manager and department or agency head with responsibilities under the Plan, by specified dates, to transmit to the Council for each fiscal year recommended resource allocations for Plan programs and activities. Requires the Council to recommend for such fiscal years resource allocations with respect to annual strategies, and submit such recommendations to the relevant departments and agencies and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget. Requires the head of a Federal department or agency to consult with the Council before enhancing the capabilities of State and local emergency preparedness and response personnel with respect to terrorist attacks.Requires the Council to establish voluntary minimum guidelines for preparedness programs in order to provide guidance in the development and implementation of such programs.Authorizes the Council to attend meetings of the National Security Council pertaining to domestic terrorist attack preparedness matters, subject to the direction of the President.Requires the Council to have an Executive Director appointed by the President.Requires cooperation with the Council from each Federal department and agency with responsibilities under the Plan.Authorizes appropriations for FY 2001 through 2005.</summary>
</bill>
