<bill session="105" type="h" number="3784" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care for Working Families Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide health benefits for workers and their families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, Ways and Means, Government Reform and Oversight, and National Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House National Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="1969"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/1998--Introduced.
Health Care for Working Families Act - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (FLSA) to establish a new title II, Health Benefits for Employees and Their Families. Requires each large employer to: (1) offer to each of its employees the opportunity to enroll in a qualifying health benefit plan that provides coverage for the employee and the employee's family; (2) contribute to the cost of such plan; and (3) withhold the employee share of the plan premium from the employee's wages. Defines a large employer as one that employed an average of at least 50 full-time employees on business days during the preceding calendar year and employs at least 50 employees on the first day of the plan year. Considers contract workers as employees for such purposes. Defines a qualifying health benefit plan as one that: (1) provides benefits for health care items and services that are actuarially equivalent or greater in value than those offered as of January 1, 1998, under the Blue Cross-Blue Shield (BC-BS) Standard Plan provided under the Federal Employees Health Benefit Program (FEHBP); and (2) meets applicable requirements under the Public Health Service Act. Sets the minimum required contribution by an employer at the same portion of the total premium as the Federal Government pays for such BC-BS Standard Plan under FEHBP. Sets forth a formula for determining such minimum employer contribution with respect to part- time workers who work less than 30 hours per week; but requires no employer contribution for employees working less than ten hours per week. Requires any employee covered under a Federal health insurance program (including Medicare, Medicaid, FEHBP, and the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services) to accept an employer's offer of health insurance coverage and agree to payroll withholdings, or request the Federal health insurance program to pay the employee share of the premium. Exempts from this requirement: (1) an employee otherwise covered under an employment-based qualified health benefit plan; or (2) a family member of a non-electing employee, where the family member is otherwise covered under an employment-based qualified health benefit plan. Sets forth requirements relating to timing of coverage and withholding, enforcement, and preemption. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require a health insurance issuer that offers employee health insurance coverage to an employer to ensure that such coverage complies with requirements of title II of FLSA.</summary>
</bill>
