<bill session="106" type="hc" number="301" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress that the United States, in concert with the international community, should enact transaction taxes on short-term, cross-border foreign exchange transactions to deter speculation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2000-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2000-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2000-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-11">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-11">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Currency devaluation"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange futures"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2000--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the United States should show leadership by enacting, in concert with the international community, transaction taxes on short-term, cross- border foreign exchange transactions to deter speculation and that the adoption of such Tobin- style taxes should be done in coordination with a large number of nations, in a fully transparent and accountable manner, with the revenue dedicated to urgent global needs; (2) the United States should build support for and advocate this position at the World Bank and the International Monetary Fund, as well as within other regional and international organizations; and (3) this should not be done in isolation of other initiatives for reform of global finance and the United States should continue to explore other options with the international community.</summary>
</bill>
