<bill session="107" type="h" number="3633" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oklahoma City Victims Compensation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide compensation for the United States citizens or legal permanent residents who were victims of the bombing of the Murrah Federal Building in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma on April 19, 1995, on the same basis as compensation is provided to victims of the terrorist-related aircraft crashes on September 11, 2001.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400611"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2002--Introduced.
Oklahoma City Victims Compensation Act - Establishes a program to provide compensation to any individual (or relatives of a deceased individual) who was physically injured or killed as a result of the bombing of the Murrah Federal Building in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, on April 19, 1995.Directs the Attorney General, acting through the Special Master appointed under the September 11th Victim Compensation Fund of 2001, to administer the program, requiring determinations of claims within 120 days and payment within 20 days of determination. States that such determinations are final and not subject to judicial review.Limits claims to one per injured person or decedent and excludes claimants from pursuing civil action for damages, as specified.Grants the United States the right of subrogation with respect to any claim paid by the United States under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
