<bill congress="106" type="hconres" number="288" updated="2012-10-31T13:25:33-05:00">
  <status datetime="2000-03-22">REFERRED</status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the importance of families and children in the United States and expressing support for the goals and ideas of National Family Day.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor state="PA" title="Rep" thomas_id="1594" district="15" name="Toomey, Patrick J."/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor name="Roemer, Tim" district="3" title="Rep" state="IN" sponsored_at="2000-03-16" thomas_id="976"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <referral datetime="2000-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </referral>
    <action datetime="2000-03-21T14:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodling moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-21T14:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1129-1132" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-21T14:07:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 288.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-21T14:29:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-21T19:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1138-1139" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2000-03-21T19:29:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 392 - 0 (Roll no. 56).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1129" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-03-21T19:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <referral datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </referral>
  </actions>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Special days"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary date="2000-03-16" status="Introduced">Recognizes the importance of children and families to the future of the United States. Expresses support for the goals and ideas of National Family Day as established by KidsPeace. Encourages the people of the United States to participate in local and national activities honoring National Family Day. Believes that families who communicate and spend time together create stronger families which give kids peace.</summary>
</bill>
