<bill session="105" type="hc" number="280" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the development and implementation of a comprehensive energy conservation plan for the United States Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="1998-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1998-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1998-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1998-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1998-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1998-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1998-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1998-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409954" joined="1998-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="1998-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1998-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1998-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Buildings and Economic Development.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW08" subcommittee="Public Buildings and Economic Development" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
    <term name="Congressional office operations"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy consumption"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/1998--Introduced.
Requires the Architect of the Capitol to: (1) develop and implement a cost-effective energy conservation strategy for all facilities administered by Congress to achieve 20 percent reduction in energy consumption compared to FY 1991 within seven years after adoption of this resolution; (2) submit to the Congress a comprehensive energy conservation and management plan, including life cycle costs methods to determine the cost-effectiveness of proposed energy efficiency projects; (3) submit a request for necessary appropriations; (4) report annually to the Congress on congressional energy management and conservation programs; (5) perform energy surveys of all congressional buildings and attendant updates; (6) use such surveys to determine the cost and payback period of energy and water conservation measures likely to achieve requisite energy consumption levels; and (7) install energy and water conservation measures that will achieve the requirements through previously determined life cycle cost methods and procedures. Authorizes the Architect to: (1) contract with nongovernmental entities and employ private sector capital to finance energy conservation projects and achieve energy consumption targets; (2) develop innovative contracting methods to attract private sector funding for the installation of energy-efficient and renewable energy technology; and (3) participate in the Department of Energy's Financing Renewable Energy and Efficiency (FREE Savings) contracts program for Federal Government facilities. Directs the Architect to produce information packages and guides for each Member and employing authority of the Congress that detail simple, cost-effective methods to save energy.</summary>
</bill>
