<bill session="107" type="h" number="2047" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-26">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patent and Trademark Office Authorization Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Patent and Trademark Office Authorization Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Patent and Trademark Office Authorization Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Patent and Trademark Office Authorization Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for the United States Patent and Trademark Office for fiscal year 2002, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2001-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2001-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2001-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2001-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-06-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1002"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-14">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-07-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-08-02T18:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 107-190.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-08-02T18:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="112">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 112.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-11-06T14:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-06T14:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7728-7730" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-06T14:06:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2047.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-11-06T14:11:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7728-7729" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-11-06T14:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6174-6175" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2002-06-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-06-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-03">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.2215.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="740"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="2215"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="1754"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4113"/>
    <amendment number="s4115"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/26/2002--Passed Senate amended.
Patent and Trademark Office Authorization Act of 2002 - Authorizes appropriations to the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office for salaries and expenses for FY 2003 through 2008 in an amount equal to all patent and trademark fees estimated by the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) to be collected in each such fiscal year.(Sec. 2) Requires the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and the Director of the Office (Director), by February 15 of each fiscal year, to report an estimate of all fees to be collected in the next fiscal year to the chairman and ranking member of specified congressional committees.(Sec. 3) Requires the Director, by December 1, 2004, to complete the development of an electronic system for the filing and processing of patent and trademark applications that: (1) is user friendly; and (2) includes the necessary infrastructure to allow examiners and applicants to send all communications electronically, and the Office to process, maintain, and search electronically the contents and history of each application. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2003 and 2004 for development of such system.(Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary, in each of the five calendar years following the enactment of this Act, to report to specified congressional committees on the progress made in implementing the 21st Century Strategic Plan issued on June 3, 2002, and on any amendments made to it.(Sec. 5) Amends Federal patent law to provide that previous citation by or to, or consideration by the Office of, a patent or printed publication does not preclude the existence of a substantial new question of patentability in patent reexamination proceedings.(Sec. 6) Revises requirements for appeals in inter partes reexamination proceedings to allow a third-party requester to appeal to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, or be a party to any appeal taken by the patent owner, with respect to any final decision favorable to the patentability of any original or proposed amended or new claim of the patent.Allows a third-party requester to appeal a decision of the Board of Patent Appeals and Interferences.Provides that a third-party requester in an inter partes reexamination proceeding dissatisfied with the final decision in an appeal to the Board may appeal the decision only to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.</summary>
</bill>
