<bill session="104" type="h" number="1498" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Reserve Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modernize the Federal Reserve System, to provide for a Federal Open Market Advisory Committee, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404996"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1995-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1995-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1995-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="1995-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E874-876"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services. a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="663"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank reserves"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal budget process"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Open market operations"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/1995--Introduced.
Federal Reserve Reform Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Reserve Act to abolish the current Federal Open Market Committee, on which the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (the Board) sits, and replace it with a Federal Open Market Advisory Committee, on which the Board does not sit, which shall advise the Board on the conduct of open-market operations. Requires the Board to meet and consult with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers during specified periods. Revises the term of the Chairman of the Board to expire on January 31 of the first calendar year beginning after the end of the term of the President who appointed the Chairman. Provides for performance of the duties of Chairman and Vice Chairman in the event of absence, unavailability, or vacancy. Mandates that each Board-adopted change in the intermediate targets for monetary policy be disclosed to the public upon its date of adoption. Amends Federal law to: (1) instruct the Comptroller General to audit written communications by members of the Board or officers or employees of the Federal Reserve System with respect to financial transactions; and (2) mandate an annual transmittal to the President and the Congress of all estimated receipts and proposed expenditures of the Board and all Federal Reserve banks for the current year and the next two succeeding years.</summary>
</bill>
