<bill session="104" type="h" number="1557" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY96-98, Arts and Humanities</title>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY96-98, Inst. for Museum Services</title>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY96-98, Nat'l. Endowment for the Arts</title>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY96-98, Nat'l. Endowment for the Humanities</title>
    <title type="popular">Institute for Museum Services FY96-98 Authorization bill</title>
    <title type="popular">National Endowment for the Arts FY96-98 Authorization bill</title>
    <title type="popular">National Endowment for the Humanities FY96-98 Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Arts, Humanities, and Museum Services Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Arts, Humanities, and Museum Services Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 1996, 1997, 1998 for the National Endowment for the Arts, the National Endowment for the Humanities, and the Institute for Museum Services; and to repeal the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965 effective October 1, 1998.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1995-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1995-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-05-10">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 2.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-06-29T22:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Economic and Educational. H. Rept. 104-170.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-06-29T22:49:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="81">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 81.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="856"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/1995--Reported to House amended.
Arts, Humanities, and Museum Services Amendments of 1995 - Amends the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965 (NFAHA) and the Museum Services Act to revise and reauthorize programs under them. Repeals NFAHA as of October 1, 1998. (Sec. 2) Declares that the encouragement and support of national progress and scholarship in the arts and the humanities is primarily a matter for private and local initiative. (Sec. 3) Revises NFAHA provisions for the National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) to modify NEA authority. Eliminates a program of contracts, grants, or loans to artistic groups and individuals for certain projects and productions, with particular regard for traditionally underrepresented ones. (Sec. 4) Revises NFAHA provisions relating to the National Council on the Arts. (Sec. 5) Revises NFAHA provisions for the National Endowment for the Humanities (NHA) to modify NHA authority. Eliminates certain humanities assistance programs, including ones with regard to traditionally underrepresented scholars and institutions. Eliminates certain annual awards programs. (Sec. 6) Revises NFAHA provisions relating to the National Council on the Humanities. Declares that the NEH Chairperson has final authority to approve each application for financial assistance. (Sec. 7) Revises NFAHA administrative provisions. Prohibits panels from recommending approval of applications for assistance for artistic projects or productions determined to be obscene. (Sec. 8) Extends through FY 1998 the authorization of appropriations to carry out NFAHA, including funds for: (1) certain program grants and other assistance by the NEA and the NEH; (2) matching non-Federal funds received; and (3) administration of NEA and NEH programs. Sets limitations on total appropriations authorized for the NEA and the NEH. (Sec. 9) Amends the Museum Services Act (MSA) to extend through FY 1998 the authorization of appropriations, including funds for: (1) grants to museums to increase and improve services; and (2) functions of the Institute of Museum Services (which is within the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities). (Sec. 10) Revises NFAHA provisions for the Federal Council on the Arts and the Humanities to provide that one such Council member shall be designated by the Secretary of State (rather than by the Director of the U.S. Information Agency). Repeals MSA provisions for assessment of needs of small, emerging, minority, and rural museums. (Sec. 11) Repeals NFAHA as of October 1, 1998. (Sec. 12) Makes conforming amendments to various Federal laws to reflect the repeal of NFAHA.</summary>
</bill>
