<bill session="104" type="h" number="4138" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-10-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hydrogen Future Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the hydrogen research, development, and demonstration programs of the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1996-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1680"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T17:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walker moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T17:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11337-11340" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T17:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-09-26T17:22:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T17:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-09-28" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11667" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1996-09-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-10-09">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-10-09" type="public" number="104-271">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-271.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="655"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="655"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Gas storage"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen as fuel"/>
    <term name="Industrial research"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Photovoltaic power systems"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists in government"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Hydrogen Title II: Fuel Cells Title III: DOE Scientific and Technical Program Quality Hydrogen Future Act of 1996 - Title I: Hydrogen - Amends the Spark M. Matsunaga Hydrogen Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 1990 to replace its mandate for a comprehensive five-year program management plan for hydrogen research with a mandate that the Secretary of Energy conduct a research and development program relating to hydrogen production, storage, transportation, and use, with the goal of enabling the private sector to demonstrate the technical feasibility of using hydrogen for industrial, residential, transportation, and utility applications. Requires a detailed progress report to the Congress, including recommendations of the Hydrogen Technical Advisory Panel. (Sec. 103) Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to repeal the mandate for a renewable hydrogen energy program, effective October 1, 1998. (Sec. 104) Amends the Spark M. Matsunaga Hydrogen Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 1990 to direct the Secretary to require a commitment from non-Federal sources of at least 50 percent of demonstration costs. (Sec. 105) Directs the Secretary to foster the exchange of generic, nonproprietary information and technology, developed pursuant to the Act, among industry, academia, and the Federal Government to help the United States economy attain the economic benefits of the relevant information and technology. (Sec. 106) Authorizes appropriations for FY 1996 through 2001. Title II: Fuel Cells - Instructs the Secretary to solicit proposals for projects to prove the feasibility of integrating fuel cells with: (1) photovoltaic systems for hydrogen production; or (2) systems for hydrogen production from solid waste via gasification or steam reforming. Mandates proposal evaluation on a competitive basis using peer review. Prescribes proposal review guidelines. (Sec. 202) Authorizes appropriations for FY 1997 and 1998, to remain available until September 30, 1999. Title III: DOE Scientific and Technical Program Quality - Authorizes the Secretary to appoint scientific, technical, and professional personnel on leave of absence from academic, industrial, or research institutions to work for DOE for a limited term, or on a temporary basis. Sets forth compensation guidelines.</summary>
</bill>
