<bill session="105" type="h" number="2636" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the acceptance of an application for payments for fiscal year 1996 under the Impact Aid program from the Maconaquah School Corporation, Bunker Hill, Indiana, and to provide that data included in that application be used for purposes of determining payments for fiscal year 1997 under a related Department of Defense assistance program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on National Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-08">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-08">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Military Readiness" name="House National Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Impact aid"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/1997--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Education to accept, as if timely received, an application from the Maconaquah School Corporation, Bunker Hill, Indiana, for payments for FY 1996 under the Impact Aid program of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Directs the Secretary of Defense to treat any data included in such application and approved by the Secretary of Education as data be used for purposes of determining such School Corporation's eligibility for FY 1997 payments, and the amount of such payments, under a related Department of Defense assistance program of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1993.</summary>
</bill>
