<bill session="106" type="hr" number="660" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To commend President Clinton for supporting the efforts of former South African President Nelson Mandela to bring peace to Burundi.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400237"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="2000-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2000-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2000-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2000-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2000-10-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armistices"/>
    <term name="Belgium"/>
    <term name="Burundi"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Clinton Administration"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Refugee policy"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Rwanda"/>
    <term name="South Africa"/>
    <term name="Tanzania"/>
    <term name="Uganda"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/27/2000--Introduced.
Recognizes and commends the Hutu and Tutsi leaders of the people of Burundi for demonstrating their desire for peace by signing the power sharing agreement.Encourages: (1) Major Pierre Buyoya's government and rebel leaders to continue the cease-fire agreement negotiations begun September 20, 2000; and (2) the United States, French, and Belgian Governments, and other Western nations, to remain engaged in Burundi through a cease-fire and final negotiated peace settlement.Commends: (1) the Presidents of Uganda, Rwanda, and Tanzania for their presence in Nairobi and their commitment to help their neighbor to bring an end to the violence; (2) the Government of Tanzania for hosting 800,000 Burundian refugees; (3) former South African President, Nelson Mandela, for forging the power sharing agreement; and (4) President Clinton for his contributions in encouraging peace in Burundi.Urges: (1) the United States and the international community to continue their efforts to assist the encamped refugees; (2) all parties to remain constructively engaged in the peace process and to make rapid progress to bring into effect a peaceful and lasting solution to the crisis; and (3) the U.S. Government and the international community to continue to work with all parties to ensure a lasting peace that will end the conflict in Burundi.</summary>
</bill>
