<bill session="104" type="h" number="2647" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to terminate the tax subsidies for large producers of ethanol used as a fuel.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400584" joined="1996-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400510" joined="1995-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407838" joined="1995-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1995-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Alcohol"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alcohol tax"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy tax credits"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to terminate the credit for large producers of ethanol used as a fuel after 1997. Disallows the credit for alcohol used to produce any ether. Exempts from tax liquids sold for use or used in an off-highway business use. Repeals the reduced rate on ethanol fuel produced from natural gas. Provides for the tax treatment of fuel alcohol in the same manner as other motor fuels. Repeals the reduced rates on alcohol fuels. Exempts partially, in the case of methanol or ethanol, the rate of tax determined under the Highway Trust Fund financing rate. Imposes a floor stock tax on fuel alcohol held by any individual on a specified date and makes such individual liable for such tax. Exempts fuel alcohol held by any individual for any use to the extent a credit or refund of the tax imposed under current law is allowed. Prohibits the imposition of tax on fuel alcohol held in the tank of a motor vehicle or motorboat and for certain amounts of fuel.</summary>
</bill>
