<bill session="104" type="hc" number="131" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-01-05">PASSED:CONCURRENTRES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Establishing procedures making the transmission of the continuing resolution (H.J. Res. 134) to the President contingent upon the submission by the President of a 7-year balanced budget using updated economic and technical assumptions of the Congressional Budget Office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400590"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05T14:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 336 Reported to House. Providing for the disposition of the Senate amendment to H.J. Res. 134 in the House. Upon adoption of this resolution the House shall be considered to have taken from the Spearker's table the joint resolution H.J. Res. 134, with the Senate amendment thereto, and to have concurred in the Senate amendment with an amendment consisting of the text printed in the report accompanying this resolution. The House shall also be considered to have adopted H. Con. Res. 131.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05T18:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 336 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05T18:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 336, H. Con. Res. 131 is considered passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:CONCURRENTRES" datetime="1996-01-05" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Received in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S86, S88-89" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="336"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hr" number="336"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hj" number="134"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Economic forecasting"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/1996--Introduced.
Prohibits the Committee on House Oversight from presenting to the President H.J. Res. 134 (continuing appropriations) until the Speaker of the House notifies such Committee that: (1) the President has submitted to the Congress a plan to achieve a balanced budget by FY 2002; and (2) the Director of the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) has certified that the plan achieves a balanced budget based on CBO economic and technical assumptions.</summary>
</bill>
