<bill session="106" type="h" number="2834" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to clarify State and local authority to regulate the placement, construction, and modification of broadcast transmission and telecommunications facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="Antennas"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Electromagnetic waves"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Microwaves"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/1999--Introduced.
Amends the Communications Act of 1934 (the Act) to repeal a provision which prohibits a State or local government from regulating the placement, construction, and modification of personal wireless service facilities on the basis of environmental effects of radio frequency emissions to the extent that such facilities comply with Federal Communications Commission (FCC) regulations concerning such emissions. Requires, in an action in which a person is seeking to place, construct, or modify a telecommunications facility, that such person bear the burden of proof as to the necessity of such placement, construction, or modification. Prohibits the FCC from adopting as a final rule a specified proposed rule which preempts State and local authority over the placement of broadcast transmission facilities. States that no provision of the Act may be interpreted to: (1) authorize any person or entity to place, construct, or modify telecommunications facilities in a manner inconsistent with State or local law if alternative technology is capable of delivering the broadcast or telecommunications signals without the use of a tower; or (2) prohibit a State or local government from requiring the production of safety and interference studies with respect to such facilities.</summary>
</bill>
