<bill session="104" type="h" number="1708" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Mortgage Insurance Corporation Charter Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Federal Mortgage Insurance Corporation as a wholly owned Government corporation to provide full mortgage insurance and provide for the development of credit enhancement products for mortgages for single family homes of low- and moderate-income homebuyers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400429"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="401587" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400549" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1996-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="402524" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1996-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404296" joined="1996-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="404332" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="1996-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="405317" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1995-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="1996-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1996-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="408364" joined="1995-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1996-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="409633" joined="1995-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="409718" joined="1995-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1996-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="410636" joined="1995-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1995-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1116"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Capital formation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Organization of Corporation Title II: Business of Corporation Title III: Provisions Relating to Government National Mortgage Association and Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight Title IV: FHA Improvements Federal Mortgage Insurance Corporation Charter Act - Title I: Organization of Corporation - Establishes the Federal Mortgage Insurance Corporation (the Corporation) as a tax-exempt, self-supporting, wholly owned Government corporation to promote the single family housing market through expanded opportunities for full mortgage insurance and housing credit. (Sec. 104) Charges the Director of the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight (OFHEO) with regulatory supervision over the financial safety and soundness of the Corporation. Requires the Corporation to submit an annual budget and business plan to OFHEO. (Sec. 109) Places the Corporation within the purview of the Inspector General of the Department of Housing and Urban Development. Requires the Corporation to establish an annual business plan for review by the Congress and the President. (Sec. 112) Directs the Comptroller General to report to the President and the Congress on the impact upon the Corporation of statutory limitations and safety and soundness requirements. (Sec. 113) Authorizes appropriations in an amount each fiscal year equal to the amount of net income from Corporation operations. Title II: Business of Corporation - Limits Corporation authority to provide mortgage insurance or credit enhancement to property that is a one- to four-family dwelling located in the United States. (Sec. 202) Prescribes guidelines for the Corporation to implement a mortgage insurance program under the same statutory limitations applicable to family dwellings carried out by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development. Prescribes guidelines under which the Secretary shall transfer to the Corporation all assets and obligations relating to the mortgage insurance program for family dwellings. Sets a termination date for the Secretary's mortgage insurance authority. (Sec. 203) Authorizes the Corporation to: (1) provide full mortgage insurance for family dwellings that is not subject to the National Housing Act strictures; and (2) engage in any other method of enhancing credit for mortgages involving family dwellings. (Sec. 204) Subjects the Corporation to certain limitations on business activity. Title III: Provisions Relating to Government National Mortgage Association and Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight - Amends the National Housing Act to make technical changes reflecting the provisions of this Act. (Sec. 302) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to provide for the supervision and regulation of the Corporation. Vests the OFHEO Director with exclusive supervisory and regulatory authority over the safety and soundness of the Corporation, including a mandate to review any proposed new business activity to determine any potential for undercapitalization. Sets forth the Director's supervisory and enforcement parameters. Title IV: FHA Improvements - Amends the National Housing Act to: (1) modify the mortgage insurance eligibility formula for family dwellings; and (2) prescribe guidelines under which the Secretary may delegate the authority to insure mortgages for family dwellings to a mortgagee.</summary>
</bill>
