<bill session="104" type="h" number="3486" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To dispose of certain Federal properties at Dutch John, Utah, assist local government in the interim delivery of basic services to the Dutch John community, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408364"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1996-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Church property"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community facilities"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local officials and employees"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/1996--Introduced.
Provides for the transfer or disposal of certain Federal properties at Dutch John, Utah. (Sec. 4) Transfers lands designated for Federal retention from the jurisdiction of the Department of Agriculture to the Bureau of Reclamation and the Department of the Interior and removes them from inclusion in the Ashley National Forest and the Flaming Gorge National Recreational Area. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) to transfer to the Secretary of Agriculture jurisdiction over Federal improvements to be used by the Forest Service. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to survey or resurvey all or portions of the Dutch John Community as necessary to accurately describe parcels identified for transfer among agencies, for Federal disposal, or for retention by the United States, and to facilitate future recordation of title. (Sec. 6) Declares that the Dutch John Community Plan will be recognized by the Bureau of Reclamation and the Forest Service as an indication of potential future land use, and that the Bureau and Forest Service will cooperate with Daggett County in assuring that disposal processes are consistent with that plan and this Act. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to: (1) conduct appraisals to determine fair market value of those properties designated for disposal, subject to specified guidelines; (2) dispose of specified properties identified for disposal without regard to law governing patenting; and (3) assure reasonable and prudent maintenance and proper care of property to be disposed until title has passed. (Sec. 10) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) conduct threatened and endangered species clearances and other environmental reviews, identify sensitive resources, and (if necessary) formulate mitigation strategies; and (2) prior to transfer and disposal of any lands upon which are found cultural resources which may be eligible for recordation in the National Register of Historic Places, prepare a Memorandum of Agreement, for review and approval by the Utah Office of Historical Preservation and the National Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, setting forth a strategy for clearance or protection of cultural resources on affected lands. (Sec. 11) Directs the Secretary to provide training and transitional operating assistance to personnel designated by Daggett County as successors to the Secretary's operators of those infrastructure systems and facilities designated for disposal. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
