<bill session="106" type="h" number="441" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-12">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nursing Relief for Disadvantaged Areas Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Nursing Relief for Disadvantaged Areas Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Nursing Relief for Disadvantaged Areas Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to the requirements for the admission of nonimmigrant nurses who will practice in health professional shortage areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="1999-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-12T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 106-135.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-05-12T12:53:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="75">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 75.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogan moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3474-3478" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 441.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-05-24T15:15:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3474-3476" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-05-24T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-06-24">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-06-24">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Reported to Senate by Senator Hatch without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-06-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="168">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 168.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-10-22">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13604-13605" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 2326 proposed by Senator Roberts for Senator Lott.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 2326 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 2327 proposed by Senator Roberts for Senator Hatch.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-22">
      <text>Amendment SP 2327 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1999-10-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-10-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T16:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T16:02:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the Senate amendment to H.R. 441.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1999-11-02T16:17:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11321-11324" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T16:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-02">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1999-11-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1999-11-12">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1999-11-12" type="public" number="106-95">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-95.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="455"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executives"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign-trained physicians"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospital personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Management consultants"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Physical therapy"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2326"/>
    <amendment number="s2327"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/22/1999--Passed Senate amended.
Nursing Relief for Disadvantaged Areas Act of 1999 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish a four-year nonimmigrant (H-1C visa) classification for nonimmigrant registered nurses in health professional shortage areas.Requires that an alien: (1) have a full foreign nursing license or has received U.S. nursing education; (2) have passed an appropriate examination or is a licensed nurse in the State of intended employment; and (3) be fully eligible to begin work in the petitioning facility.Requires the facility to file an employment attestation with the Department of Labor with respect to such alien (or aliens) evidencing that: (1) similarly employed nurse's wages and conditions will not be adversely affected; (2) the alien's wages will be the same as other similarly employed nurses; (3) steps are being taken to recruit U.S. nurses (as set forth by this Act); (4) no labor dispute is involved; (5) no more than one-third of the facility's registered nurses will be H-1C aliens; (6) employment will not be performed at a facility other than the petitioning facility; and (7) notice of the petition for such alien nurses has been filed with the bargaining unit or other representative of the facility's registered nurses.Directs the Secretary of Labor to: (1) compile a public list of petitioning facilities; (2) establish a process for complaint receipt, investigation, and disposition (including civil monetary penalties) against a noncomplying facility; and (3) impose an attestation filing fee of up to $250.Limits: (1) aggregate fiscal year H-1C entrants to 500; and (2) fiscal year entrants in any one State to 25 and 50 in States with less or more than nine million inhabitants, respectively. Defines "facility" as a hospital: (1) in a health shortage area; (2) with at least 190 acute care beds; and (3) with at least 35 percent and 28 percent of its patients being Medicare and Medicaid patients, respectively.Repeals the nonimmigrant nursing program (H-1A visa).(Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to recommend: (1) an alternative to the H-1C program as a permanent remedy to the registered nurse shortage; and (2) a more effective program enforcement system.(Sec. 4) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to exempt certain nurses and physical therapists from foreign health care worker certification requirements.(Sec. 5) Authorizes the Attorney General to waive the job offer requirement for an alien in the professions holding an advanced degree or of exceptional ability if in the national interest. Directs the Attorney General to grant such a waiver for an alien physician to work in a health care shortage area or at a Veterans facility if a Federal or State agency has previously determined such physician's work to be in the public interest (Prohibits such a physician to be issued a permanent resident visa or to adjust to permanent resident status before completing five years of such qualifying employment.)(Sec. 6) Considers an accounting or management consulting service entity organized outside the United States to be an affiliate of certain U.S.- organized accounting or management consulting service entities if it markets its services under the same internationally recognized name through the same worldwide coordinating organization of which the U.S. entity is a member. (Thus permitting L-visa intra-company transfers of alien executives and employees.)</summary>
</bill>
