<bill session="106" type="h" number="370" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">No Frills Prison Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to prevent luxurious conditions in prisons.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="1999-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Boxing"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric appliances"/>
    <term name="Exercise"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Microcomputers"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Musical instruments"/>
    <term name="Physical education and training"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Prison administration"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Publishers and publishing"/>
    <term name="Punishment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/1999--Introduced.
No Frills Prison Act - Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to require a State, to be eligible for truth in sentencing incentive grants, to demonstrate that it: (1) provides living conditions and opportunities within its prisons that are not more luxurious than those that the average prisoner would have experienced if not incarcerated; (2) does not provide to any such prisoner specified benefits or privileges, including earned good time credits, less than 40 hours a week of work that either offsets or reduces the expenses of keeping the prisoner or provides resources toward restitution of victims, unmonitored phone calls (with exceptions), in-cell television viewing, possession of pornographic materials, instruction or training equipment for any martial art or bodybuilding or weightlifting equipment, or dress or hygiene other than as is uniform or standard in the prison; and (3) does not provide, for a prisoner serving a sentence for a crime of violence which resulted in serious bodily injury to another, housing other than in separate cell blocks intended for violent prisoners, less than nine hours a day of physical labor (with exceptions), any release from the prison for any purpose unless under physical or mechanical restraint, any viewing of television, any inter-prison travel for competitive sports, more than one hour a day spent in sports or exercise, or possession of personal property exceeding 75 pounds in total weight or that cannot be stowed in a standard size U.S. military issue duffel bag. Directs the Attorney General to establish similar conditions in the Federal prison system.</summary>
</bill>
