<bill session="108" type="h" number="1950" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-16T13:05:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-07-16T13:05:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">State Department FY2004-2005 Authorizations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2004 and 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Defense Trade and Security Assistance Reform Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2004 and 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Global Internet Freedom Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">International Free Media Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Missile Threat Reduction Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">United States International Leadership Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Millennium Challenge Account, Peace Corps Expansion, and Foreign Relations Authorization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Access for Afghan Women Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Defense Trade and Security Assistance Reform Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2004 and 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Global Internet Freedom Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">International Free Media Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Israeli-Palestinian Peace Enhancement Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Millennium Challenge Account Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Missile Threat Reduction Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Peace Corps Expansion Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">United States International Leadership Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for the Department of State for the fiscal years 2004 and 2005, to authorize appropriations under the Arms Export Control Act and the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 for security assistance for fiscal years 2004 and 2005, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To establish the Millennium Challenge Account to provide increased support for certain developing countries; to authorize the expansion of the Peace Corps; to authorize appropriations for the Department of State for fiscal years 2004 and 2005; and to authorize appropriations under the Arms Export Control Act and the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 for security assistance for fiscal years 2004 and 2005.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2003-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2003-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-05-08">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 42 - 3.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. DeLay asked unanimous consent that the Committee on International Relations have until midnight on May 16 to file a report on H.R. 1950. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-16T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on 108-105, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-16">
      <text>Referred jointly and sequentially to the House Committee on Armed Services for a period ending not later than June 13, 2003 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1 of rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-16">
      <text>Referred jointly and sequentially to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce for a period ending not later than June 13, 2003 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1 of rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-16">
      <text>Referred jointly and sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than June 13, 2003 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1 of rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 16, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Energy and Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 16, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09T19:51:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 16, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T10:21:00-04:00">
      <text>PERMISSION TO FILE REPORT - Mr. Pence asked unanimous consent to file a supplemental report from the Committee on International Relations to accompany the bill H.R. 1950, the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2004 and 2005.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12T10:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on International Relations, H. Rept. 108-105, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-16T20:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-16T20:19:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 11, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-16T20:19:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Energy and Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 11, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-30T14:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Armed Services. H. Rept. 108-105, Part III.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-07-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported Without Recommendation (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-07-11T18:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 108-105, Part IV.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-07-11T18:07:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="105">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 105.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-07-14T23:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 316 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1950 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. Provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on International Relations now printed in the bill modified by the amendments recommended by the Committees on Armed Services and Energy and Commerce also printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment and shall be considered as read. Waives all points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substitute as modified. Specified amendments are in order. Makes in order only those amendments printed in H.Rept. 108-206 and en bloc amendments as described in section 2. Provides that amendments shall be considered only in ...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 316 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 316.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6725-6824" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6733-6765" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1950 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. Provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on International Relations now printed in the bill modified by the amendments recommended by the Committees on Armed Services and Energy and Commerce also printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment and shall be considered as read. Waives all points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substitute as modified. Specified amendments are in order. Makes in order only those amendments printed in H.Rept. 108-206 and en bloc amendments as described in section 2. Provides that amendments shall be considered only in ...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 316 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jack Quinn to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1950.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Smith (NJ) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T14:17:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith (NJ) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Crowley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T14:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Hyde amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kennedy (MN) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T14:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kolbe amendment, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kolbe amendment, as modified, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Kolbe demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kolbe amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T15:12:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Paul amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Paul amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Lantos demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the King (IA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the King (IA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. King (IA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tauscher amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Tauscher amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Tauscher demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T16:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Menendez amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T16:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Weldon (PA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Hyde en bloc amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T16:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hostettler amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Hostettler amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Menendez demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rangel amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sherman amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McKeon amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waters amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1950 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T12:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6892-6903" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1950.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T12:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-07-16T13:05:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="369" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 382 - 42 (Roll no. 369).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T13:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T13:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16T13:06:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1950.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-07-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="211">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 211.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="316"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2673"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2800"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="925"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="925"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Aerospace industries"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Artillery"/>
    <term name="Artists"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting Board of Governors"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Capital cities"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Censorship"/>
    <term name="Central Americans"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="East Timor"/>
    <term name="Eastern Europe"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Expropriation"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Former Soviet states"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Haiti compilation"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Islamic countries"/>
    <term name="Islamic fundamentalism"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Journalism"/>
    <term name="Journalistic ethics"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Kazakhstan"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Kyrgyzstan"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Latin Americans"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Leadership"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mexicans"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military airlift"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Minesweeping"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in government"/>
    <term name="Missing children"/>
    <term name="Mozambique"/>
    <term name="Muslims"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nepal"/>
    <term name="New Zealand"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Opium"/>
    <term name="Ordnance"/>
    <term name="Paramilitary forces"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Patrol ships"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Racial violence"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Rain forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Reporters and reporting"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
    <term name="Tajikistan"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Textbooks"/>
    <term name="Thailand"/>
    <term name="Tibet"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Turkmenistan"/>
    <term name="Uganda"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Uzbekistan"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
    <term name="West Bank"/>
    <term name="Whaling"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h235"/>
    <amendment number="h236"/>
    <amendment number="h237"/>
    <amendment number="h238"/>
    <amendment number="h239"/>
    <amendment number="h240"/>
    <amendment number="h241"/>
    <amendment number="h242"/>
    <amendment number="h243"/>
    <amendment number="h244"/>
    <amendment number="h245"/>
    <amendment number="h246"/>
    <amendment number="h247"/>
    <amendment number="h248"/>
    <amendment number="h249"/>
    <amendment number="h250"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/5/2003--Introduced.
Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2004 and 2005 - Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2004 and 2005 - Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 and 2005 for: (1) the Department of State; and (2) U.S. international broadcasting activities. Sets forth certain Department of State authorities and activities, including: (1) diplomatic and consular activities; and (2) educational and cultural activities. Sets forth certain requirements with respect to: (1) the organization and personnel of the Department of State; (2) international organizations; and (3) U.S. international broadcasting activities. United States International Leadership Act of 2003 - Establishes a caucus of democratic countries that will help advance U.S. interests at international organizations and multilateral institutions. Global Internet Freedom Act of 2003 - Establishes within the Broadcasting Board of Governors an Office of Global Internet Freedom to develop and implement a comprehensive global strategy to combat state-sponsored and state-directed Internet jamming and persecution of those who use the Internet. Amends the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994 to establish the United States International Broadcasting Agency as an independent agency of the executive branch (effectively abolishing the the Broadcasting Board of Governors and the International Broadcasting Bureau). International Free Media Act of 2003 - Establishes within the Department of State a Coordinator for International Free Media to coordinate U.S. government policies, programs, and projects that promote international press freedoms and free media. Sets forth provisions with respect to: (1) certain reporting requirements; and (2) human rights violations in certain countries. Defense Trade and Security Assistance Reform Act of 2003 - Amends the Arms Export Control Act to set forth requirements: (1) prohibiting a foreign country from transferring U.S. defense articles and services to a terrorist-supporting country; (2) authorizing the President to control the transfer of defense articles (other than firearms) and defense services to foreign persons within the United States; (3) urging establishment of new license exemptions with respect to the export of defense articles and services only after careful coordination with appropriate U.S. law enforcement agencies; (4) developing mechanisms to identify in connection with the export licensing process persons who have been convicted of violating laws relating to the financing of terrorism; and (5) prohibiting the sale or transfer to the military, police, or intelligence services of a foreign country in which the United States has imposed an arms embargo. Sets forth requirements imposing stringent controls on all items on the Missile Technology Control Regime (MTCR) Annex. Authorizes appropriations under the Arms Export Control Act, the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, and the Security Assistance Act of 2000 with respect to foreign military sales and financing, international military education and training (IMET), security assistance for Israel and Egypt, demining and related activities, the Cooperative Development Program, maritime interdiction patrol boats for Mozambique, East Timor, democracy-building efforts in Cuba, the Congo Basin Forest Partnership (CBFP) program, combating piracy of U.S. copyrighted materials, and nonproliferation and disarmament activities. Missile Threat Reduction Act of 2003 - Amends the Arms Export Control Act to increase the duration of existing sanctions against foreign persons who violate U.S. export controls with respect to the transfer of missile equipment and technology on the MTCR Annex. Requires sanctions imposed under the Arms Export Control Act and the Export Adminsitration Act of 1979 to extend to governmental entities and other entities, including transactions involving third parties. Authorizes foreign assistance and technical assistance to countries that agree to destroy their ballistic missiles.</summary>
</bill>
