<bill session="106" type="h" number="4805" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Energy Security Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Federal Oil and Gas Lease Management Improvement Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Frontier Exploration and Development Incentives Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Marginal Well Preservation Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the energy security of the United States and decrease America's dependency on foreign oil sources to 50 percent by the year 2010 by enhancing the use of renewable energy resources, conserving energy resources, improving energy efficiencies, and increasing domestic energy supplies, mitigating the effect of increases in energy prices on the American consumer, including the poor and elderly, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400540"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400079" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400534" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2000-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Resources, Ways and Means, and Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air conditioning"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Capital formation"/>
    <term name="Caribou"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coal research"/>
    <term name="Coal-fired power plants"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Cogeneration of electric power and heat"/>
    <term name="Coke industry"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Condominium (Housing)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Cooperative housing"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Debt"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Dyes and dyeing"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy consumption"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Energy shortages"/>
    <term name="Energy storage"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Energy tax credits"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fixed price contracts"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Gas companies"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Natural gas reserves"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Nuclear research"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum engineering"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Petroleum storage"/>
    <term name="Photovoltaic power systems"/>
    <term name="Propane"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Renewable natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary recovery of gas"/>
    <term name="Secondary recovery of oil"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Solar equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Solar heating and cooling"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Sulphur dioxide"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Thermal power plants"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Waste reduction"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Energy Security Actions Required of the Secretary of Energy Title II: Amendments to Energy Policy and Conservation Act and Actions Affecting the Strategic Petroleum Reserve Title III: Provisions to Protect Consumers and Low Income Families and Encourage Energy Efficiencies Title IV: Provisions to Enhance the Use of Domestic Energy Resources Subtitle A: Hydroelectric Resources Subtitle B: Nuclear Resources Subtitle C: Development of National Spent Nuclear Fuel Strategy Subtitle D: Coal Resources Title V: Improvements to Federal Oil and Gas Lease Management Subtitle A: State Option to Regulate Oil and Gas Lease Operations on Federal Land Subtitle B: Use of Cost Savings from State Regulation Subtitle C: Streamlining and Cost Reduction Subtitle D: Federal Royalty Certainty Subtitle E: Royalty Reinvestment in America Title VI: Frontier Oil and Gas Exploration and Development Incentives Title VII: Tax Measures to Enhance Domestic Oil and Gas Production Subtitle A: Marginal Well Preservation Subtitle B: Independent Oil and Gas Producers Subtitle C: Other Provisions Title VIII: Tax Measures to Enhance the Use of Renewable Energy Sources, Improve Energy Efficiencies, Protect Consumers and Conversion to Clean Burning Fuels Title IX: Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act of 2000 Title X: Clean, Reliable, and Affordable Electricity Subtitle A: Accelerated Technology Research and Development Program for Advanced Clean Coal Technology for New and Existing Coal-Based Electric Generating Facilities Part 1: National Coal-Based Technology Development and Applications Program Part 2: Existing Plant Technology Applications Subtitle B: Credit for Emission Reductions and Efficiency Improvements in Existing Coal-Based Electricity Generation Facilities Subtitle C: Incentives for Early Commercial Applications of Advanced Clean Coal Technologies National Energy Security Act of 2000 - Title I: Energy Security Actions Required of the Secretary of Energy - Directs the Secretary of Energy (the Secretary) to report annually to the President and Congress on the progress the United States has made toward obtaining the goal of not more than 50 percent dependence on foreign oil sources by 2010.(Sec. 102) Sets a deadline for the Secretary to submit to the President a certain report of the National Petroleum Council, together with recommendations for administrative or legislative actions.(Sec. 103) Directs the Secretary to establish within the National Economic Council an Interagency Work Group on Natural Gas (the Group), whose function shall be to develop a strategy and comprehensive policy for the use of natural gas as an essential component of overall national objectives of energy security, economic growth, and environmental protection.Title II: Amendments to Energy Policy and Conservation Act and Actions Affecting the Strategic Petroleum Reserve - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (EPCA) to authorize drawdown and distribution of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) if: (1) the President concurs in the determination of the Secretary of Defense that it will not impair national security; and (2) the Secretary of Energy finds that it will not have an adverse effect on the domestic petroleum industry.(Sec. 201) Extends through FY 2003 the availability of FY 2000 appropriations for SPR authorities. Extends the expiration date for authorities related to domestic supply availability from March 31, 2000, to December 31, 2003.(Sec. 202) Extends from FY 1997 through 2003 the authorization of appropriations for the interagency working group that coordinates Federal programs affecting exports of renewable energy and energy efficiency products and services. Extends the expiration date for standby energy authorities from March 31, 2000, to December 31, 2003.(Sec. 203) Instructs the President to establish immediately an Interagency Panel on the Strategic Petroleum Study to study and report to the President and Congress regarding oil markets and estimated future fluctuations in the price, supply, and demand for crude oil, and to determine appropriate SPR capacity and use.Title III: Provisions to Protect Consumers and Low Income Families and Encourage Energy Efficiencies - Amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act to repeal: (1) the requirement that participating States share 25 percent of the cost of weatherization programs as a condition for receiving assistance grants; and (2) the mandate that forty percent of weatherization program funds be spent for weatherization program materials. Instructs the Secretary to establish energy audit procedures and techniques. Increases the financial assistance for labor and weatherization materials expenditures per dwelling unit. Includes among such weatherization materials heating and cooling modification costs, including replacement.(Sec. 301) Repeals the mandate for the Secretary to establish, pursuant to State application, a separate average per dwelling unit limitation.(Sec. 302) Amends the EPCA to direct the Secretary, upon State request, to provide information, technical assistance, and funding for specified actions (summer fill programs) to avoid severe seasonal price increases and supply shortages of kerosene, propane, and heating oil during summer months.(Sec. 303) Authorizes appropriations for an Energy Efficiency Science Initiative, managed by the Assistant Secretary for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, for grants for energy efficiency research.Title IV: Provisions to Enhance the Use of Domestic Energy Resources - Subtitle A: Hydroelectric Resources - Directs the Secretaries of the Interior and of the Army, respectively, to inventory all dams, impoundments, and other facilities under their jurisdiction and to report to Congress on the potential of such facilities to generate hydroelectric power and on actions planned to do so.(Sec. 402) Directs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to report to Congress on expedited hydroelectric licensing procedures.Subtitle B: Nuclear Resources - Directs the Chairman of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to report to Congress on: (1) domestic nuclear power generation and production; and (2) the potential for increasing nuclear generating capacity and production as part of the domestic energy mix.Subtitle C: Development of a National Spent Nuclear Fuel Strategy - Establishes an Office of Spent Nuclear Fuel Research within the Office of Nuclear Energy Science and Technology of the Department of Energy, headed by an Associate Director, to implement an integrated research and development program on technologies for the treatment, recycling, and disposal of high-level nuclear radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel, under the general supervision of the Secretary. Confers upon the Secretary grant and contract making authority.Subtitle D: Coal Resources - Directs the Secretary to: (1) report to Congress on the potential for increased generation from existing coal-fired power plants; and (2) provide grants for refinement and demonstration of new technologies for the conversion of coal to liquids.Title V: Improvements to Federal Oil and Gas Lease Management - Federal Oil and Gas Lease Management Improvement Act of 2000 - Emphasizes that this Act does not give a State a property right or interest in any Federal lease or land.Subtitle A: State Option to Regulate Oil and Gas Lease Operation on Federal Land - Permits a State to notify either the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture (depending upon the appropriate jurisdiction) of its intent to accept authority for regulation of certain oil and gas lease operations on Federal land within such State. Declares an automatic transfer of regulatory authority over designated operations from the appropriate Secretary to the State effective 180 days following receipt of such notification. Bars a Federal agency from exercising authority formerly held by such Secretary with respect to oil and gas lease operations on Federal land.Subtitle B: Use of Cost Savings from State Regulation - Prescribes guidelines to compensate a State for the costs of implementing such transferred authority.Subtitle C: Streamlining and Cost Reduction - Bars the appropriate Secretary from recovering costs for applications and other documents relating to oil and gas leases.(Sec. 532) Requires the Secretary to ensure: (1) timely issuance of Federal agency decisions respecting oil and gas leasing and operations on Federal land; and (2) that unwarranted denials and stays of lease issuance and unwarranted restrictions on lease operations are eliminated from the administration of oil and gas leasing on Federal land.(Sec. 535) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to publish a national inventory of oil and gas reserves and potential resources underlying Federal land and the Outer Continental Shelf.Subtitle D: Federal Royalty Certainty - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act and the Mineral Leasing Act pertaining to oil and gas leases to reformulate the payment of their respective lease royalties. Exempts Indian lands from such reformulation.Subtitle E: Royalty Reinvestment in America - Directs the appropriate Secretary, whenever certain crude oil or natural gas prices dip below a specified level, to allow as a credit against the payment of Federal oil and gas production royalties, a specified percentage of expenditures made for capital exploration and development on Federal oil and gas leases.(Sec. 551) Prohibits capital expenditures made on Outer Continental Shelf leases from being credited against onshore Federal royalty obligations.(Sec. 552) Instructs the appropriate Secretary to reduce the royalty rate for marginal oil and gas production following prescribed guidelines whenever certain crude oil or natural gas prices dip below a specified level.(Sec. 553) Prescribes procedural guidelines under which any operator of an oil well leased under specified statutes may notify the Secretary of the Interior of suspension of operation and production at the well.Title VI: Frontier Oil and Gas Exploration and Development Incentives - Frontier Exploration and Development Incentives Act of 2000 - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act governing bidding procedures for oil and gas leases to set a certain net profit royalty share for oil and gas production in the Beaufort Sea and Chukchi Sea Planning Areas of Alaska.(Sec. 602) Requires the Secretary of the Interior to reduce any future royalty or rental obligation by a specified percentage after an oil and gas lease has been granted pursuant to the statutory bidding system.Title VII: Tax Measures to Enhance Domestic Oil and Gas Production - Subtitle A: Marginal Well Preservation - Marginal Well Preservation Act of 2000 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to specify a tax credit for marginal domestic oil and natural gas well production.(Sec. 703) Authorizes taxpayer election to expense geological and geophysical expenditures and to delay rental payments for domestic oil and gas wells.Subtitle B: Independent Oil and Gas Producers - Amends the IRC to: (1) set forth a five-year net operating loss carryback for losses attributable to operating mineral interests of independent oil and gas producers; (2) suspend through 2004 the limitation on the total amount of the depletion allowance to 65 percent of taxable income; and (3) suspend through 2006 the taxable income limit with respect to marginal production.Subtitle C: Other Provisions - Amends the IRC to: (1) repeal the mandate that certain approved terminals offer dyed diesel fuel and kerosene for nontaxable purposes; and (2) redefine qualified tertiary injectant expenses for purposes of the enhanced oil recovery credit.Title VIII: Tax Measures to Enhance the Use of Renewable Energy Sources, Improve Energy Efficiencies, Protect Consumers and Conversion to Clean Burning Fuels - Amends the IRC to: (1) set forth placed-in-service rules and special rules for biomass facilities; (2) deny renewable electricity production credit to electricity sold to utilities under certain contracts; (3) exclude from gross income as contributions to capital certain amounts received by electric energy, gas, or steam utilities; (4) extend the credit for electricity produced from steel cogeneration; (5) declare certain expense limitations on depreciable business assets inapplicable to a storage facility used in connection with home heating oil distribution; (6) establish a tax credit for certain percentages of residential solar energy photovoltaic and solar water heating property expenditures; and (7) allow an energy credit for 20 percent of the basis of certain fuel cell property and eight percent of the basis of combined heat and power system property placed in service during the taxable year for business uses.Title IX: Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act of 2000 - Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act of 2000 - Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to establish and implement a competitive oil and gas leasing program that will: (1) result in an environmentally sound program; (2) not result in significant adverse effects upon fish and wildlife; and (3) ensure the receipt of fair market value by the public for the mineral resources to be leased.(Sec. 903) Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act of 1980 to repeal the prohibition against production of oil and gas from the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, and any leasing or development leading to such production.States that Congress determines that the Coastal Plain oil and gas leasing program and activities authorized by this Act are compatible with the purposes for which the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge was established, and that no further findings or decisions are required to implement this determination.States this Act is the sole authority for Coastal Plain leasing, and that such Plain is considered "Federal land" for purposes of the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982.Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) designate up to a specified total of Coastal Plain acreage as "Special Areas" and close them to leasing if the Secretary determines that these Areas require special management and regulatory protection; and (2) permit leasing in those Special Areas by setting lease terms that limit or condition surface use and occupancy by lessees but permit the use of horizontal drilling technology from sites on leases located outside the designated Special Areas.Declares that this Act constitutes the Secretary's sole authority to close Coastal Plain lands to oil and gas leasing and to exploration, development, and production. Instructs the Secretary to convey the surface estate of specified lands to the Kaktovik Inupiat Corporation and to the Arctic Slope Regional Corporation in order to remove clouds on title and clarify land ownership patterns within the Coastal Plain.(Sec. 905) Declares that the Final Legislative Environmental Impact Statement on the Coastal Plain of April 1997 is adequate to satisfy the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.(Sec. 906) States that lands may be leased to any person qualified to obtain a lease for oil and gas deposits under the Mineral Leasing Act. Requires the Secretary to prescribe lease procedures.(Sec. 907) Authorizes the Secretary to grant to the highest responsible qualified bidder by sealed competitive cash bonus bid any Coastal Plain lands upon payment of such bonus and a royalty which shall not be less than a certain amount. Prescribes lease terms and conditions. Sets forth bonding requirements to ensure financial responsibility of lessee and avoid Federal liability.(Sec. 912) Directs the Secretary to grant rights-of-way and easements across the Coastal Plain for oil and gas transportation.(Sec. 913) Requires the Secretary to promulgate regulations to provide for: (1) biannual scheduled onsite inspections for compliance of Coastal Plain facilities with environmental or safety regulations; and (2) annual nonscheduled onsite inspections of such facilities.Title X: Clean, Reliable and Affordable Electricity - Subtitle A: Accelerated Technology Research and Development Program for Advanced Clean Coal Technology for New and Existing Coal-Based Electric Generating Facilities - Part 1: National Coal-Based Technology Development and Applications Program - Directs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) identify technology costs and associated performance goals that would permit continued cost-competitive use of coal for electricity generation, for chemical feedstocks, and for transportation fuel; and (2) implement research and development programs that include demonstration and commercial application of coal-based technologies. Authorizes appropriations.Part 2: Existing Plant Technology Applications - Directs the Secretary to: (1) conduct a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application to develop economically and environmentally acceptable advanced technologies for utilization within current electricity generation facilities using coal as the primary feedstock; (2) transmit a detailed plan to Congress; and (3) solicit proposals for demonstrations designed to achieve such technical milestones. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle B: Credit for Emission Reductions and Efficiency Improvements in Existing Coal-Based Electricity Generation Facilities - Amends the IRC to: (1) allow a tax credit for investment in a qualifying clean coal technology unit; and (2) set forth the formula for determining a tax credit for production from such a unit.(Sec. 1033) Provides for a debt repayment mechanism under which the owner of a qualified system of continuous emission control, or a qualified clean coal technology unit, may elect to have credits applied to the prepayment of any debt or obligation for investment in the retrofit, repowering, or replacement of existing coal-based generation with certain systems of continuous emission control and clean coal technology.Subtitle C: Incentives for Early Commercial Applications of Advanced Clean Coal Technologies - Sets forth: (1) a tax credit for investment in a qualifying advanced clean coal technology facility; and (2) a formula for determining a tax credit for production from such a facility. Provides for a debt repayment mechanism under which the owner of a such facility may elect to have such tax credits applied to prepayment of debt or obligations incurred under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936.</summary>
</bill>
