<bill session="108" type="h" number="2329" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Pathogen Surveillance Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for global pathogen surveillance and response.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400222"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2003-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2003-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2003-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2003-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4881"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="871"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Foreign students"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Geographic information systems"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific instruments and apparatus"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Syndromes"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication systems"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/2003--Introduced.
Global Pathogen Surveillance Act of 2003 - Requires that priority for U.S. assistance under this Act be given to eligible developing countries that permit personnel from the World Health Organization (WHO) and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDCP) to: (1) investigate outbreaks of infectious diseases on their territories; (2) provide early notification of disease outbreaks; and (3) provide pathogen surveillance data to appropriate U.S. agencies in addition to international health organizations. Prohibits any foreign national participating in programs under this Act from having access, during the course of such participation, to select agents that may be used as, or in, a biological weapon, except in a supervised and controlled setting. Establishes a program under which the Secretary of State may award fellowships to eligible nationals to pursue: (1) graduate courses of study leading to a master of public health degree with a concentration in epidemiology from an institution of higher education in the United States with a Center for Public Health Preparedness; or (2) advanced public health training in epidemiology to be carried out at the CDCP (or equivalent State facility), or other Federal facility (excluding the Department of Defense or United States National Laboratories), for a period of between six and 12 months. Allows each fellowship recipient also to study at the CDCP (or an equivalent facility) the diagnosis and containment of likely bioterrorism agents. Requires fellowship recipients to agree to return, upon completion of education or training, to their countries of nationality or last habitual residence (so long as it is an eligible developing country) and complete at least four years of employment in a public health position in the government or a nongovernmental, not-for-profit entity in that country or, with the Secretary's approval in an international health organization. Allows the Secretary, on a case-by-case basis, and if in the U.S. national interest, to provide for participation in the program of U.S. citizens who agree, upon completion of education or training, to work at least five years in a public health position in an eligible developing country or the WHO. Directs the Secretary to support short training courses in-country (not in the United States) to laboratory technicians and other public health personnel from eligible developing countries in: (1) laboratory techniques relating to the identification, diagnosis, and tracking of pathogens responsible for possible infectious disease outbreaks; and (2) techniques of syndrome surveillance reporting and rapid analysis of syndrome information using Geographic Information System (GIS) and other Internet-based tools. Authorizes the President to furnish assistance to eligible developing countries to purchase and maintain: (1) public health laboratory equipment necessary to collect, analyze, and identify expeditiously a broad array of pathogens, including mutant strains, which may cause disease outbreaks or may be used as a biological weapon; and (2) related communications equipment and information technology. Authorizes a Federal agency head, upon the request of a U.S. chief of diplomatic mission or an international health organization, and with the Secretary's concurrence, to assign to the respective U.S. mission or organization any public health officer or employee of the agency for the purpose of enhancing disease and pathogen surveillance efforts in developing countries. Directs the CDCP and the Department of Defense each to: (1) increase the number of personnel assigned to their respective laboratories located in eligible developing countries that conduct research and other activities with respect to infectious diseases; and (2) expand the operations of those laboratories, especially in the implementation of on-site training of foreign nationals and regional outreach efforts involving neighboring countries. Authorizes the President to provide assistance to: (1) enhance the surveillance and reporting capabilities for the WHO and existing regional health networks; and (2) develop new regional health networks. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish new country or regional Foreign Epidemiology Training Programs in eligible developing countries.</summary>
</bill>
