<bill session="107" type="h" number="3810" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Livestock Ownership Fairness Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit livestock packers from owning or feeding livestock intended for slaughter for more than 14 days before such slaughter, to prohibit excessive concentration resulting from mergers among certain purchasers, processors, and sellers of livestock, poultry, and basic agricultural commodities, to require the Attorney General to establish an Office of Special Counsel for Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2002-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2002-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2002-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock and Horticulture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Livestock and Horticulture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agribusiness"/>
    <term name="Agricultural industries"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economic concentration"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Livestock industry"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Meat packing industry"/>
    <term name="Monopolies"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Poultry industry"/>
    <term name="Predatory pricing"/>
    <term name="Produce trade"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2002--Introduced.
Livestock Ownership Fairness Act of 2002 - Amends the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 to prohibit livestock packers directly or through a subsidiary, from conspiring to, or owning or feeding livestock to such an extent that the producer no longer materially participates in the management of the operation, with respect to livestock held for more than 14 days prior to slaughter. Exempts from such prohibition certain: (1) forward contracting arrangements under which the producer retains pre-delivery operational control of the livestock; (2) cooperatives that own, or feed livestock and provide such livestock for slaughter; or (3) certain small producer-owned or-controlled packers.Directs the Attorney General to establish in the Department of Justice an Office of Special Counsel for Agriculture to handle agricultural antitrust and related matters.Requires: (1) a person in the business of purchasing livestock, poultry, or a basic agricultural commodity for wholesale resale who files a premerger notice under the Clayton Act to file simultaneously a premerger notice with the Secretary of Agriculture; and (2) the Secretary to review the proposed merger and report to the Office of Special Counsel for Agriculture..</summary>
</bill>
