<bill session="106" type="h" number="1243" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-21T15:10:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-09-21T15:10:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Marine Sanctuaries Enhancement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Marine Sanctuaries Enhancement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Sanctuaries and Reserves Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the National Marine Sanctuaries Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400302" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1999-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-31">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-07-12T17:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-224.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-07-12T17:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="130">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 130.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21T14:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Saxton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21T14:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8410-8416" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21T14:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1243.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-09-21T15:10:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1482"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Marine biology"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/1999--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: National Marine Sanctuaries Title II: National Estuarine Reserves Sanctuaries and Reserves Act of 1999 - Title I: National Marine Sanctuaries - Amends the National Marine Sanctuaries Act to include in the definitions of: (1) "damages" the cost of curation and conservation of archaeological, historical, and cultural sanctuary resources and the cost of enforcement actions undertaken by the Secretary of Commerce for injury to a sanctuary resource; (2) "response costs" the costs related to the seizure, forfeiture, storage, or disposal arising from injury to sanctuary resources; and (3) "sanctuary resource" cultural and archaeological resources. (Sec. 104) Establishes the National Marine Sanctuary System and modifies sanctuary designation standards and procedures. Requires a Federal agency that takes an action other than an alternative recommended by the Secretary, if the action results in injury to a sanctuary resource, to prevent further damage and restore or replace the resource in a way approved by the Secretary. Prohibits, subject to exception, preparation of sanctuary designation documents without sufficient funding. (Sec. 106) Modifies the list of prohibited activities. (Sec. 107) Empowers enforcement officers to arrest a person for enforcement interference. Makes enforcement interference a criminal offense. Allows subpoenaing of electronic files. (Sec. 108) Requires the Secretary to conduct, support, and coordinate (currently, to conduct) research, monitoring, and education programs (currently, research, monitoring, evaluation, and education programs). Authorizes the Secretary to promote certain research and to develop interpretive facilities near any national marine sanctuary. Authorizes the establishment of facilities to promote sanctuaries and the purposes and policies of this title. (Sec. 109) Allows special use permittees to post bonds rather than securing general liability insurance. Requires permit fees to represent the fair market value of the sanctuary resource use (currently, of the sanctuary resource use and a reasonable return to the U.S. Government). Allows in-kind contributions in lieu of a fee or waiving or reducing the fee for nonprofit activities. Removes a requirement that permittees report annually on activities conducted and revenues derived from those activities. (Sec. 110) Authorizes: (1) the use of other governmental agencies' resources on a reimbursable or non-reimbursable basis; and (2) the Secretary to accept grants from Federal, State, and local governments, interstate agencies, foundations, and other persons to carry out the Act. (Sec. 111) Modifies venue requirements regarding civil actions by the Attorney General to recover response costs and damages regarding injury to sanctuary resources. Revises requirements regarding the use of recovered amounts. Imposes a three-year statute of limitations for recovery actions. (Sec. 112) Authorizes appropriations to carry out the Act and for construction projects at sanctuaries. (Sec. 113) Authorizes the establishment of one or more advisory councils to provide advice to (currently, to provide assistance to) the Secretary. (Sec. 114) Modifies requirements regarding the use of sanctuary program symbols. Title II: National Estuarine Reserves - Amends the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to declare it national policy to: (1) use Federal, State, and community partnerships developed through the National Estuarine Research Reserve System to improve the understanding, stewardship, and management of coastal areas; and (2) encourage the development, application, and transfer to local, State, and Federal resources managers of innovative coastal and estuarine resources management technologies and techniques that promote the long-term conservation of coastal and estuarine resources. (Sec. 202) Revises requirements for national estuarine reserve designation. Mandates: (1) development of guidelines for the conduct of System research, education, and resource stewardship (currently, System research); and (2) promotion and coordination of System use for research, education, and resource stewardship purposes (currently, for research purposes). Modifies amount limits regarding grants for acquiring lands and waters, operating reserves, constructing reserve facilities, and supporting research and monitoring. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into cooperative agreements or contracts with, or make grants to, any nonprofit organization to benefit a reserve, authorizing the organization to solicit donations to carry out projects; and (2) accept donations to carry out projects. (Sec. 203) Authorizes appropriations for Reserve System grants and for grants for construction and construction-related land acquisition at reserves.</summary>
</bill>
