<bill session="104" type="h" number="2482" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive One-Call Notification Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require States to consider adopting mandatory, comprehensive, statewide one-call notification systems to protect underground facilities from being damaged by any excavations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal negligence"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excavation"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Railroad maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Underground construction"/>
    <term name="Underground utility lines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/1995--Introduced.
Comprehensive One-Call Notification Act of 1995 - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to provide for the establishment of a nationwide toll-free telephone number to be used by State one-call notification systems to protect underground facilities from excavation damage. Requires each State to consider whether to adopt a comprehensive statewide one-call notification program containing all elements required under this Act. Outlines required elements of the program, including prior notification of any intended excavations and its application to all excavators and underground facility operators. Permits a State to elect not to require a person to contact the one-call notification system if the person owns or leases the property and operates all underground facilities at the excavation site. Provides penalties for violations of the requirements of a program, as well as enforcement procedures. Directs the Secretary to make grants to States (or to operators of State notification systems) which have elected to adopt or establish and maintain a notification system with all required elements. Allows grants for alternative programs if they are at least as protective of the public health and safety and environment as a State program under this Act. Directs the Secretary to: (1) coordinate the implementation of this Act with appropriate Federal agencies; (2) review and report to the Congress on the extent to which Department of Commerce programs and procedures could be used to achieve the purposes of this Act; (3) develop and make available to States a model State one-call notification program, with suggested elements; and (4) develop public service announcements and other materials to educate the public about one-call notification systems and the national phone number. Requires each State to provide an initial and annual status reports on progress made in implementing a State program. Allows States to implement more protective notification systems than that required under this Act. Expresses the sense of the Congress that equipment and products purchased with funds made available under this Act should be American-made. Requires notification of such preference to the recipients of assistance under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
