<bill session="106" type="h" number="2807" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SCHIP Improvement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to promote identification of children eligible for benefits under, and enrollment of children in, the Medicaid and State Children's Health Insurance programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1999-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2000-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1999-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1999-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1999-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1999-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="1999-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1999-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1999-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1999-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="1999-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2000-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1570"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/1999--Introduced.
SCHIP Improvement Act of 1999 - Amends the National School Lunch Act (NSLA) and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (CNA) to promote identification of children eligible for benefits under, and enrollment of children in, the Medicaid program and State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP) under titles XIX and XXI, respectively, of the Social Security Act.(Sec. 2) Amends NSLA to provide a limited waiver of a confidentiality requirement, for persons directly connected with the administration of a State plan for Medicaid or SCHIP, for the purpose of identifying children eligible for benefits under, and enrolling children in, any such plan. Makes such waiver applicable with respect to the agency from which the information would be obtained only if the State and the agency so elect.(Sec. 3) Amends CNA provisions for the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC program) to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary) to establish a demonstration project, in not more than 40 local agencies in not fewer than two States, under which costs of nutrition services and administration (under the WIC program) shall include the costs of identification of children eligible for benefits under, and enrollment of children in, State plans for Medicaid and SCHIP. Directs the Comptroller General to evaluate for Congress the costs associated with implementing such project, including Federal and State costs per child enrolled in such State plans.(Sec. 3(sic)) Amends NSLA to direct the Secretary to make grants to States to carry out State plans to involve eligible entities in the identification of children eligible for benefits under, and enrollment of children in, State plans for Medicaid and SCHIP. Provides that the following are eligible entities: (1) a school or school food authority participating in the school lunch program under NSLA; (2) an institution participating in the child and adult care food program under NSLA; (3) a local agency participating in the WIC program under CNA; or (4) any other nongovernmental social service provider. Includes the WIC demonstration project established under this Act among authorized uses of such grant funds. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to provide a specified amount of funds to the Secretary for each of FY 2000 through 2003. Entitles and directs the Secretary to accept such funds, without further Act of appropriation.</summary>
</bill>
