<bill session="108" type="h" number="2641" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to implement the Calfed Bay-Delta Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2003-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-07">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2828"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="1097"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental justice"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Land subsidence"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Oxygen"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pesticide pollution"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Selenium"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2003--Introduced.
Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act - Approves the August 28, 2000, Federal programmatic Record of Decision issued by specified Federal agencies and supported by the State of California as a framework for addressing Calfed Bay-Delta Program components. Authorizes the Secretary and the heads of such agencies to carry out Stage 1 activities (projects and programs planned for the first seven years) in the following categories if such activities have been subject to environmental review and approval under Federal and State law and have been certified by the California Bay-Delta Authority to be consistent with the Record of Decision and all applicable State and Federal law: water storage; conveyance; water use efficiency; water transfers; the Environmental Water account; integrated regional water management plans; ecosystem restoration; watersheds; water quality; levee stability; science; program management, oversight, and coordination; refuge water supplies; groundwater management. Prohibits the authorization of any Federal funds for a project under the Program for increasing water supply, water yield, water storage, or water conveyance that is intended for any agricultural, municipal and industrial, domestic, or hydroelectric power purposes unless a feasibility study is prepared, a report on findings is submitted, and the Secretary certifies that: (1) the study and report indicate that total project benefits will equal or exceed total project costs; (2) the beneficiaries have demonstrated a willingness and ability to pay for costs allocated to them under the beneficiaries pay principle; and (3) such beneficiaries are obligated to repay such costs. Requires the Federal agencies to: (1) coordinate their activities with specified California agencies; (2) cooperate with local and tribal governments and the public through a federally chartered advisory committee or other means; and (3) implement the Program using the best available scientific information and scientific review. Directs the Secretary: (1) to report monthly on the Authority's progress in achieving the water supply targets, environmental water account requirements, and water quality targets described in the Record and on any pending actions that may affect the Authority's ability to achieve those targets and requirements; (2) to report annually on Program implementation, expenditures, and accomplishments; (3) to certify in such annual report whether the Program is progressing in a balanced manner in advancing Program components (requires the Authority to prepare a revised implementation schedule to ensure balanced progress if balance is not certified); (4) to submit annual financial reports containing a detailed accounting of all Federal and State funds received and obligated under the Program and all projects to be carried out in the upcoming year; (5) prior to December 2004, to report to Congress on the Program's accomplishments, the specific steps remaining to be undertaken, the specific funding levels and sources to accomplish such steps, and recommendations necessary to accomplish Program goals and objectives. Requires: (1) the President's budget to include requests for an appropriate funding level for each Federal agency to carry out its Program responsibilities; and (2) the Office of Management and Budget to submit an interagency budget crosscut report displaying the budget proposed for each such agency for the Program. Prohibits the Federal share of the total cost of implementing Stage 1 from exceeding 33.3 percent.</summary>
</bill>
