<bill session="104" type="h" number="3596" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil Region National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of the Oil Region National Heritage Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402657"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1996-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1996-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1996-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1996-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/1996--Introduced.
Oil Region National Heritage Area Act - Designates the Oil Region National Heritage Area in Pennsylvania if, within 180 days, the Oil Heritage Region Corporation submits, and the Secretary of the Interior approves, a Compact for the Area (signed by the Governor of Pennsylvania) that defines the Area, describes anticipated programs, and includes information about the objectives and management of the Area. (Sec. 5) Establishes the Oil Region National Heritage Advisory Commission to serve in an advisory capacity to the Oil Heritage Region, Inc., the locally based private, nonprofit management Corporation which will oversee the development of the Oil Region National Heritage Park. (Sec. 8) Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) withdrawal of such designation; and (2) criteria for retention of such designation, including the presence of a cohesive assemblage of natural, historic, or cultural resources that represent distinctive aspects of American heritage worthy of conservation and that are best managed through public-private partnerships. (Sec. 10) Prohibits assistance or funding from being provided under this Act two years after the date of the Area's designation unless the Corporation submits a Management Plan to the Governor and the Secretary along with a certification of endorsement or disapproval by the Commission. (Sec. 11) Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance to Pennsylvania, its political subdivisions, or the Corporation regarding Plan revisions and implementation. Makes the Area eligible for technical and grant assistance available to other National Heritage Areas under any National Heritage Areas Program or similar program established by the Congress. (Sec. 12) Sets forth provisions regarding limitations on inclusion of and access to private property with respect to such Area. (Sec. 13) Prohibits the Secretary, as a condition of approving the Compact or the determination of eligibility for technical assistance under this Act, from requiring: (1) enactment or modification of land use restrictions; or (2) limitations on fishing, hunting, or trapping. Provides that neither the Secretary nor other Federal agencies may condition the receipt of other forms of assistance in connection with the National Heritage Area status of the Area on such limitations.</summary>
</bill>
