<bill session="108" type="h" number="2707" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-02-24T19:20:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-02-24T19:20:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Demonstration Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Assessment and Demonstration Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Assessment and Demonstration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture, acting through the U. S. Forest Service, to carry out a demonstration program to assess potential water savings through control of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive on forests and public lands administered by the Department of the Interior and the U. S. Forest Service.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To provide for an assessment of the extent of the invasion of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive on lands in the Western United States and efforts to date to control such invasion on public and private lands, including tribal lands, to establish a demonstration program to address the invasion of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400020" joined="2003-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400037" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2003-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2003-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400265" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400303" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400336" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2003-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400434" joined="2003-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-02-24T12:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-424, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-24T12:01:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Feb. 24, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-24T12:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-02-24T12:03:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="244">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 244.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-02-24T14:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Pearce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-24T14:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H520-523" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-24T14:21:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2707.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-24T14:40:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-24T19:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H529-530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-02-24T19:20:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="26" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 367 - 40 (Roll no. 26).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H520" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-02-24T19:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-06-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="605">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 605.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="1516"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Goats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Herbicides"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Integrated pest management"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Revegetation"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
    <term name="West (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/24/2004--Passed House amended.
Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Assessment and Demonstration Act - (Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of of Agriculture, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretaries) to assess the extent of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive invasion in the western United States (as defined by the 1902 Reclamation Act). Requires such assessment to include: (1) documentation of the quantity of water lost due to the infestation and of the quantity of water saved due to various control methods, including the portion of saved water that returns to surface water or groundwater supplies and at what rates; and (2) determination of the optimum control method for the various land types and land uses, of what conditions indicate the need to remove such growth and the optimal methods for disposal or use of such growth, and of the methods to prevent the regrowth and reintroduction of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive and to reestablish native species. Directs the Secretaries to prepare and submit to specified congressional committees (the congressional committees) a report containing the results of such assessment and identifying: (1) long-term management and funding strategies that could be implemented by Federal, State, tribal, and private land managers and owners on all land management types to address the invasion of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive; and (2) deficiencies or areas for further study and where actual field demonstrations would be useful in the control effort. Authorizes the Secretaries to make grants to institutions of higher education or nonprofit organizations (or both) with an established background and expertise in public policy issues associated with the control of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive in order to obtain technical experience, support, and recommendations related to the identification of the long-term management and funding strategies required to be included in such report. Limits each grant awarded to $250,000. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretaries, based on the assessment and report, to initiate a program of at least three demonstration projects in the western States designed to address deficiencies and areas for further study to address the invasion of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive, including the testing of additional control methods identified by such report. Allows the Secretaries to enter into an agreement with a western State to carry out a project and, if the Secretaries select a demonstration project for implementation in national Forest System lands, makes the Secretary of Agriculture responsible for implementation of such project. Requires projects to be designed with integrated methods and adaptive management strategies and carried out over time frames and spatial scales large enough to accomplish the goals laid out in the report. Provides that, before being carried out, the methods and strategies proposed for each project shall be subject to review by scientific experts, including non-Federal experts, selected by the Secretaries. Limits the total cost of each project to $7 million, including planning, design, implementation, revegetation, maintenance, and monitoring costs. Allows the Secretaries to accept, but not require, in cases of projects conducted on lands under the jurisdiction of either Secretary, funds or in-kind contributions, including State agency provided services. Limits the Federal share of the costs of any activity on private lands funded under a project to 75 percent of the activity's total cost. Requires projects to include: (1) documentation of the quantity of water saved due to various control methods, including the portion of water saved that returns to surface water or groundwater supplies and at what rates; and (2) optimal revegetative states to prevent regrowth and reintroduction of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive and to reestablish native species. Requires the Secretaries to submit to the congressional committees annual reports on such projects. (Sec. 4) Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect, or otherwise bias, use by the Secretaries of other statutory or administrative authorities to plan or conduct Salt Cedar or Russian Olive control and eradication. (Sec. 5) Authorizes appropriations to the Secretaries to: (1) conduct the assessment; (2) award the grants specified above; and (3) carry out the program of demonstration projects specified above.</summary>
</bill>
