<bill session="104" type="h" number="950" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Microenterprise and Asset Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title IV of the Social Security Act to remove the barriers and disincentives in the program of aid to families with dependent children that prevent recipients of such aid from moving toward self-sufficiency, and to provide for the establishment of demonstration projects designed to determine the social, psychological, and economic effects of providing to individuals with limited means an opportunity to accumulate assets, and the extent to which an asset-based welfare policy may be used to enable individuals with low income to achieve economic self-sufficiency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400538"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="403864" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1995-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1995-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Entitlements"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social science research"/>
    <term name="Socially handicapped"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Welfare reform"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Microenterprise and Asset Development Title II: Demonstration Projects Microenterprise and Asset Development Act - Title I: Microenterprise and Asset Development - Amends part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) (AFDC) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) to exclude from AFDC eligibility determinations certain income and resources that are to be used for education, training, and employability purposes. (Sec. 101) Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to report to the Congress on a revision of the AFDC limit on automobiles in order to increase the employability of AFDC recipients. (Sec. 102) Provides for State agency exclusion from AFDC eligibility determinations of certain resources related to microenterprise initiatives by AFDC recipients towards self-sufficiency. Requires State agencies to ensure that caseworkers advise AFDC recipients of the option for microenterprises. Provides for the inclusion of microenterprise training and activities in the JOBS program under SSA title IV part F (Job Opportunities and Basic Skills Training Program). Title II: Demonstration Projects - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a deduction for contributions made to an individual development account (IDA) by or on behalf of a qualified individual to pay qualified expenses of such individual. Limits such contributions to $2,000 per year. Defines qualified expenses as those for: (1) postsecondary educational expenses; (2) a first-home purchase; and (3) retirement. Allows such deduction in arriving at adjusted gross income. Declares that contributions to IDAs are not subject to the gift tax or the tax on prohibited transactions. (Sec. 203) Provides for the establishment of demonstration projects designed to determine: (1) the social, psychological, and economic effects of providing to individuals with limited means an opportunity to accumulate assets; and (2) the extent to which an asset-based welfare policy may be used to enable individuals with low income to achieve economic self-sufficiency. Requires each organization authorized to conduct a demonstration project to establish a Reserve Fund for use in a prescribed manner. Requires the Secretary to establish an oversight panel to: (1) develop guidelines for investment of Reserve Fund and IDA monies; (2) monitor project progress; and (3) make recommendations for projects not progressing adequately, and review their implementation. Makes an individual eligible for assistance under a demonstration project if such individual is a member of a household that meets: (1) the income test of not more than 200 percent of the poverty threshold; and (2) the net worth test of not more than $20,000. (Sec. 204) Requires the disregard by all means-tested Federal programs of funds in the IDAs of demonstration project participants.</summary>
</bill>
