<bill session="106" type="h" number="1940" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to clarify the tax treatment of Settlement Trusts established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1073"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/1999--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code with respect to the tax treatment of Settlement Trusts established under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act.Exempts from income taxation any such Settlement Trust electing coverage by this Act. Declares that for an electing trust: (1) no amount shall be includible in the gross income of a Settlement Trust beneficiary by reason of a contribution to the Settlement Trust during such taxable year; and (2) the ordinary requirements for taxation of trusts and beneficiaries shall not apply.Requires an electing trust to distribute at least 55 percent of its adjusted taxable income each taxable year. Imposes a tax on a trust, in the amount of the failure, if the distribution is insufficient.Includes in the beneficiary's gross income, as ordinary income, any distribution from an electing trust (only when the actual distribution is received). Provides that distributions from the trust will be taxable as ordinary income even if the distribution represents a return of capital. Requires tax withholding on trust distributions over a certain amount.</summary>
</bill>
