<bill session="105" type="h" number="3903" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Glacier Bay National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Glacier Bay National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Glacier Bay National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Glacier Bay National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Glacier Bay National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for an exchange of lands located near Gustavus, Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E884"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11T12:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-706, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11T12:18:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 11, 1998.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-11T12:25:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="401">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 401.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7750-7753" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-09-15T15:33:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15T15:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="579">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 579.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-02" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11368, S11379" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Senate vitiated previous passage.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12061" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12061" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Amendment SP 3794 proposed by Senator Jeffords for Senator Murkowski.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Amendment SP 3794 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1998-10-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T15:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-10T15:09:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10427" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-10">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-10-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-10-30" type="public" number="105-317">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-317.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="2109"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="2109"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3672"/>
    <amendment number="s3794"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/8/1998--Passed Senate amended.
Glacier Bay National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 1998 - Provides for: (1) an exchange of specified State lands in Alaska for specified Federal lands to be completed within six months after the issuance of a license to Gustavus Electric Company (GEC) by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) for the construction and operation of a hydroelectric project on such Federal lands; or (2) the exchange of other specified Alaska lands having a sufficiently equal value to satisfy State and Federal law within one year after such license is issued if the Secretary of the Interior and Alaska have not agreed on which lands Alaska will convey within such six-month period. Designates specified State lands and waters in Alaska as wilderness upon consummation of such exchange to ensure that this transaction maintains approximately the same amount of area of designated wilderness. Conditions such land exchange on: (1) FERC's having conducted economic and environmental analyses pursuant to the Federal Power Act (FPA), the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act that conclude that the construction and operation of a hydroelectric power project on such lands will not adversely impact the purposes and values of the Glacier Bay National Park and Preserve, will comply with the requirements of the National Historic Preservation Act, and can be accomplished in an economically feasible manner; (2) FERC holding at least one public meeting in Gustavus, Alaska, allowing its citizens to express their views on the proposed project; (3) FERC having determined, with the concurrence of the Secretary and Alaska, the minimum amount of land necessary to construct and operate the project; (4) GEC having been granted a FERC license that requires it to submit an acceptable financing plan to FERC before project construction commences; and (5) FERC approving such plan. Makes the FERC licensing process applicable to any application submitted by GEC to FERC for the right to construct and operate a hydropower project on specified Alaska lands. Authorizes FERC to accept and consider an application filed by GEC for construction and operation of such a project, notwithstanding FPA provisions, if submitted within three years after this Act's enactment. Provides for FERC to retain jurisdiction over any hydropower project constructed on such site. Sets forth additional provisions regarding issuance of a license for construction or operation of such a project. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to issue a special use permit to GEC to allow completion of the required analyses. Requires the Secretary to impose conditions in the permit as needed to protect the purposes and values of the Preserve. Requires the lands acquired from Alaska to be added to and administered as part of the National Park System, subject to valid existing rights. Continues the authorities and jurisdiction provided in this Act until expressly modified or repealed by the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
