<bill session="105" type="hr" number="239" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-24T14:41:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-09-24T14:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2267) making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1998, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23T21:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-264, by Mr. Dreier.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-23T21:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2267 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Bill is open to amendments. The amendment printed in Part 1 of the report accompanying this resolution shall be considered as having been adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole. Before consideration of any other amendment, it shall be in order to consider amendment No. 1 in part 2 of the report accompanying this resolution, which may amend portions of the bill not yet read. The amendments printed in part 2, with the exception of amendment No. 1, may only be offered at the appropriated point in the reading of the bill. All amendments shall be considered in the manner specified in the report. All points of order against amendment No. 2 in part 2 of the report shall be waived. Points of order against amendment Nos. 1 and 3 in par...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-09-23T21:28:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="95">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 95.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-09-24T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7755-7759" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-24T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-24T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1997-09-24T14:41:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-09-24T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="2267"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/1997--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 2267 (Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and related agencies appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
