<bill session="106" type="h" number="4744" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Truth in Regulating Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the General Accounting Office to report to Congress on economically significant rules of Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="2000-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="2000-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="2000-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="2000-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="2000-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-20T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 106-772.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-20T18:08:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="441">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 441.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO01" subcommittee="National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="4924"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2000--Introduced.
Truth in Regulating Act of 2000 - Provides that when a Federal agency publishes an economically significant rule, a chairman or ranking member of a committee of jurisdiction of either House of Congress may request the Comptroller General to review such rule. Defines "economically significant rule" to mean any proposed or final rule, including an interim or direct final rule, that may have an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more or adversely affect in a material way the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or State, local, or tribal governments or communities, or for which an agency has prepared an initial or final regulatory flexibility analysis.Requires the Comptroller General to submit a report on each rule reviewed, including an independent evaluation of: (1) the costs and benefits; (2) alternative approaches that could achieve the same goal more cost-effectively or that could provide greater net benefits, and if applicable, a brief explanation of any statutory reasons why such alternatives could not be adopted; (3) the regulatory impact analysis, federalism assessment, or other analysis or assessment prepared by the agency or required for the rule; and (4) the results of the evaluation and the implication of those results, including an evaluation of any changes from the proposed rule made by the agency in the final rule. Requires the Comptroller General to develop procedures for determining the priority and number of requests for review which give the highest priority to requests regarding a notice of proposed rulemaking and to requests regarding an interim final rulemaking.Authorizes appropriations for FY 2001 through 2003.Provides that this Act shall not apply to rules published after three years after its effective date.</summary>
</bill>
