<bill session="106" type="h" number="5387" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Railroad Retirement Reform Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a transition for railroad workers to the Social Security Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400382"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Locomotives"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Pollution taxes"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Underground petroleum tanks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/2000--Introduced.
Railroad Retirement Reform Act of 2000 - Amends the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974, title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA), the Internal Revenue Code (IRC), and the Railroad Retirement Solvency Act of 1983 and to outline provisions to restructure the railroad retirement system, with changes: (1) prohibiting the transfer of funds from the Social Security Equivalent Benefit Account to the Railroad Retirement Account or the Railroad Trust Fund, and restricting their use for paying for Social Security equivalent benefits and related administrative expenses; (2) transitioning to full Social Security coverage (with corresponding reductions in the railroad retirement benefit) and subjecting to employment taxes under the Federal Insurance Contributions Act (FICA taxes) any railroad employees who have performed service before January 1, 2002; (3) revising employer, employee representative, and employee tier 2 tax rates, tying the basis of their determination to the average account benefits ratio as defined in this Act; and (4) repealing the general fund subsidy to the Railroad Retirement Account.Directs the labor and management members of the Railroad Retirement Board to transmit a plan to the Secretary of Labor for a (private) multiemployer pension plan for individuals who would otherwise be covered by the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974.Amends IRC to: (1) repeal the 4.3-cent special motor fuel excise tax on railroads and inland waterway transportation; and (2) subject diesel fuel used in trains to the additional tax for the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
