<bill session="104" type="h" number="1307" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the New Bedford Whaling National Historical Park in New Bedford, Massachusetts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401547" joined="1995-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-03">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="608"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="608"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sailing ships"/>
    <term name="Whaling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/1995--Introduced.
Establishes the New Bedford Whaling National Historical Park in New Bedford, Massachusetts, to be administered as a unit of the national park system. Requires expenditures to consist of: (1) one dollar of Federal funds for each four dollars of non-Federal funds for cooperative agreements entered into under this Act; and (2) non-Federal funds matching Federal funds for visitor and interpretive facilities (other than operation and maintenance costs). Requires the Secretary of the Interior to submit to specified congressional committees and to implement a general management plan for the Park. Authorizes appropriations. Limits the amount that may be appropriated for visitor and interpretive facilities and directional and visitor orientation signage. Prohibits the use of appropriations authorized under this Act for operation or maintenance of the Schooner Ernestina and limits the amount of Federal funds that may be used annually for interpretive and educational programs for the Schooner Ernestina pursuant to cooperative grants under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
