<bill session="104" type="h" number="1390" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Childrens' Media Protection Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide means of limiting the exposure of children to violent programming on television, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405939"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="332"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Educational television"/>
    <term name="Electronic industries"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public television"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television and children"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Violence in television"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/1995--Introduced.
Childrens' Media Protection Act of 1995 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to: (1) prescribe rules for the rating of violence levels in television programming, including rules for the transmission of signals containing specifications for blocking violent programming; and (2) require television sets with picture screens of 13 inches or more to be equipped with blocking circuitry and enable viewers to block display of all programs with a common rating. Prohibits any person from shipping, manufacturing, assembling, or importing any television not so equipped. Requires performance standards for blocking technology. (Sec. 6) Directs the FCC to initiate a rulemaking proceeding to prescribe a prohibition on the broadcast on commercial television and any public telecommunications entities between six o'clock a.m. and ten o'clock p.m., inclusively, of programming that contains gratuitous violence. (Sec. 7) Directs the FCC, in granting an application for a television broadcast license, to impose conditions which ensure that the applicant complies with the standards for children's television programming as established under the Children's Television Act of 1990 and otherwise serves the educational and informational needs of children through its overall programming. Prohibits a cable franchise award or renewal unless the cable operator complies with such standards.</summary>
</bill>
