<bill session="106" type="h" number="2483" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Eastern Santa Clara Basin Water Quality Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers and in coordination with other Federal agency heads, to participate in the funding and implementation of a balanced, long-term solution to the problems of groundwater contamination, water supply, and reliability affecting the Eastern Santa Clara groundwater basin in California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="1999-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Groundwater pollution"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/1999--Introduced.
Eastern Santa Clara Basin Water Quality Act - Establishes in the Treasury an Eastern Santa Clara Basin Restoration Fund to be administered by the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, in cooperation with the city of Santa Clarita, California, the California Department of Toxic Substances Control, and the Castaic Lake Water Agency. Requires that the proceeds from such Fund be used for the design, construction, operation, and maintenance of water quality projects that: (1) are related to sites that are sources of perchlorates or any associated contaminants; (2) are located in Santa Clarita; and (3) potentially affect the Eastern Santa Clara groundwater basin. Authorizes appropriations for such Fund. Authorizes the Secretary to accept and administer in cooperation with Santa Clarita, the Department, and the Agency any funds which the State of California, local government agencies, or private entities may contribute to such Fund. Requires the Secretary to integrate the water projects with other Federal and State water projects in and around the Eastern Santa Clara groundwater basin. Prohibits counting any of the funds made available for such projects as part of the Federal share of any previously authorized Federal project or activity. Authorizes the Secretary, in cooperation with State and local government agencies, to participate in studies and other investigative activities and in the planning and design of projects that offer a long-term solution to groundwater contamination caused by perchlorates. Authorizes appropriations and provides that no less than $2 million per fiscal year of such appropriated amounts shall be for projects located in Santa Clarita conducted in cooperation with the Agency.</summary>
</bill>
