<bill session="105" type="h" number="141" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:26-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Select Commission to Advise on Reforming Elections Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Select Commission to Advise on Reforming Elections to issue recommendations for the reform of laws governing the financing of campaigns for election for Federal office, to establish expedited procedures for the consideration of legislation implementing the recommendations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1997-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="1997-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1997-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1997-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="1997-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1997-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Rules and Organization of the House.</text>
      <committee name="House Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSRU" name="House Rules"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" name="House Rules" subcommittee="Rules and Organization of the House"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Election law"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>01/07/1997--Introduced.
Select Commission to Advise on Reforming Elections Act - Establishes the Select Commission to Advise on Reforming Elections to study the laws relating to the financing of campaigns for Federal elections and to report and recommend legislation to reform those laws. (Sec. 6) Requires the Commission to submit a report to the President, the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives, and the majority and minority leaders of the Senate on its activities. Directs the Commission, as specified, to submit to the President, the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives, and the majority and minority leaders of the Senate, any recommendations for changes in campaign finance laws to which seven or more Commission members may agree. Prohibits the submission of recommendations by the Commission after July 15, 1998. (Sec. 7) Requires that when the Commission submits any recommendation for changes in campaign finance laws, those Commission members concurring in the recommendation shall include legislation to implement the recommendation. Provides for expedited congressional consideration of any legislation introduced which implements a recommendation of the Commission. (Sec. 8) Terminates the Commission after the later of: (1) the submission of its report; or (2) the submission of its recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
