<bill session="107" type="h" number="4791" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Weather Research Program Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for the United States Weather Research Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400119"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2002-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E891"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Technology, and Standards.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Environment, Technology, and Standards" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Computer simulation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood forecasting"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Hydrological forecasting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Meteorological research"/>
    <term name="Meteorological satellites"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Rain and rainfall"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Tornadoes"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2002--Introduced.
United States Weather Research Program Act of 2002 - States that the United States Weather Research Program's priorities shall be in the areas of: (1) hurricanes, to improve landfall location and hurricane strength forecasts; (2) heavy precipitation, to improve winter and rain storm forecasts; (3) floods, to improve flood forecasting and forecasting and warning systems for inland flooding related to tropical cyclones; (4) two-to-fourteen day forecasting, to improve weather predictions and warnings of high-impact weather events, to conduct the Hemispheric Observing System Research and Predictability Experiment (THORpex) to fill observational gaps in the Northern Hemisphere, and to test and evaluate advanced data assimilation techniques in global models; (5) societal and economic impacts, to identify methods of delivering weather information effectively, to recommend ways to improve weather communications, to assess impacts of adverse weather, to evaluate what weather information is most useful, and to perform research on such impacts; and (6) testing research concepts at Program-sponsored test bed centers, to enable technology transfer to operational meteorologists.Directs the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to develop and annually update, and NOAA's Administrator to report to Congress on, a five-year plan: (1) describing how Federal agencies can best team with universities and other research institutions; (2) identifying social, economic, and military needs and requirements for weather information; (3) outlining methods for disseminating information to user communities; and (4) describing best practices for transferring Program research results to forecasting operations.</summary>
</bill>
