<bill session="106" type="h" number="1799" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Sexual Trauma Treatment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to revise and improve the authorities of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs relating to the provision of counseling and treatment for sexual trauma experienced by veterans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400163"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E954"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E961-962"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled veterans"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Psychiatrists"/>
    <term name="Psychologists"/>
    <term name="Psychotherapy"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Rape victim services"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sexual harassment of women"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Stress (Psychology)"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women soldiers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/1999--Introduced.
Veterans Sexual Trauma Treatment Act - Makes permanent a program to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide counseling to veterans to overcome psychological trauma which resulted from a physical assault or battery of a sexual nature, or from sexual harassment, which occurred during active miliary service (under current law the program authorizing such counseling expires in 2001). Allows such program to include appropriate treatment. Requires a Department of Veterans Affairs mental health professional (currently, the Secretary) to determine when such counseling and treatment is necessary. Requires the dissemination of information concerning the availability of such services to affected veterans. Includes as eligible for such care and services certain current and former reserve personnel. Directs the Secretary to: (1) complete the design and updating of public service announcements and other appropriate means of communication concerning the availability of such services and to submit to the congressional veterans' committees examples of such communications; and (2) report to such committees on program implementation. Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Defense to report jointly to the congressional veterans' and defense committees describing their collaborative efforts to ensure that military personnel are informed upon their separation from service about sexual trauma counseling and treatment programs available through the Department.</summary>
</bill>
