<bill session="106" type="h" number="2823" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 to provide for the retention and administration of Oil Shale Reserve Numbered 2 by the Secretary of Energy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOE.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Military Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/1999--Introduced.
Amends the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 to direct the Secretary of Energy to administer Oil Share Reserve Number 2. Requires the Secretary to enter into: (1) a cooperative management and resource assessment agreement with the Ute Indian Tribe of the Uintah and Ouray Reservation for the management, administration, and development of the Reserve; and (2) an oil and gas lease with such Tribe to explore, prospect, conserve, develop, use, operate, market, and sell the petroleum of such Reserve. Allows the Secretary to enter into agreements with such Tribe with respect to minerals other than petroleum and other commodities. Provides funding. Waives requirements of presidential and congressional approval and consultation prior to contracting for an oil shale reserve with respect to the agreement, assessment, or administration required under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
