<bill session="108" type="h" number="1857" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Humanitarian Assistance to Combat HIV/AIDS in sub-Saharan Africa and the Caribbean and National Security Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize assistance to combat the growing HIV/AIDS problem in countries in sub-Saharan Africa and the Caribbean.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E794"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Africans"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Italy"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2003--Introduced.
Humanitarian Assistance to Combat HIV/AIDS in sub-Saharan Africa and the Caribbean and National Security Act of 2003 - Declares the sense of Congress that: (1) effectively addressing the HIV/AIDS problem in countries in sub-Saharan Africa and the Caribbean is a moral issue of the greatest magnitude and is in the national security interest of the United States; and (2) the President should enter into direct talks with the governments of other member countries of the G-8 and member countries of the European Union to increase the amount of financial support to combat the HIV/AIDS pandemic in sub-Saharan Africa and the Caribbean. Authorizes the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to award grants to nongovernmental organizations (NGOs) for the prevention, treatment, and control of HIV/AIDS in countries in sub-Saharan Africa and Caribbean countries, including treatment, medical care, and support services to HIV-infected parents and their children. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, should provide appropriate medical and technical expertise to the Administrator and recipient governments. Authorizes the Secretary of State, in conjunction with the Secretary of HHS, to appoint to the country team in each U.S. embassy in sub-Saharan Africa and the Caribbean a health officer to advise the U.S. Ambassador and assist in coordination of the effort to combat HIV/AIDS with local governments.</summary>
</bill>
