<bill session="104" type="hr" number="391" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-28T12:25:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-03-28T12:25:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3136) to provide for enactment of the Senior Citizens' Right to Work Act of 1996, the Line Item Veto Act, and the Small Business Growth and Fairness Act of 1996, and to provide for a permanent increase in the public debt limit.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27T21:02:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-500, by Mr. Solomon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27T21:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3136 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the House without intervention of any point of order, except those arising under sec. 425(a) of the Congressional Budget Act. Specified amendments are in order. Upon adoption of this resolution, the amendments specified in the report accompanying this resolution shall be considered as having been adopted. A further amendment, if offered by the chairman of the Committee on Ways and Means shall be in order without intervention of any point of order, except those arising under sec. 425(a) of the Budget Act, debatable for 10 minutes. If, before March 30, 1996, the House has received a message informing it that the Senate has adopted the conference report to accompany the bill S. 4, the...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-03-27T21:02:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="200">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 200.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28T10:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2972-2986" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28T10:43:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the resolution and on the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28T12:16:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question on the amendment and Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 232 - 180 (Roll no. 97).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-03-28T12:25:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="98" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 232 - 177 (Roll no. 98).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="3136"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="4"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="4"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Line item veto"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h984"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/28/1996--Passed House amended.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 3136 (social security earnings limit, line item veto, regulatory analysis, and public debt increase). Provides that if, before March 30, 1996, the House of Representatives receives a message that the Senate has adopted the conference report for S. 4 (line item veto): (1) the Clerk of the House, in the enrollment of H.R. 3136, shall strike title II (line item veto); and (2) the House shall be considered to have adopted that conference report.</summary>
</bill>
