<bill session="105" type="hr" number="508" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-30T17:42:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-07-30T17:42:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4276) making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1999, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-07-22T21:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-641, by Mr. Linder.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-22T21:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4276 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The amendments printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution may be offered only by a Member designated in the report and only at the appropriate point in the reading of the bill, shall be considered read, shall be debatable for the time specified, shall not be subject to amendment and shall not be subject to a demand for a division of the question. All points of order against the amendments printed in the report are waived. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-07-22T21:17:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="231">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 231.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-07-30T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6781-6790" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-30T16:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-30T17:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-07-30T17:42:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-07-30T17:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="4276"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/1998--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 4276 (Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and related agencies appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
