<bill session="106" type="h" number="4737" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Secrets Safety Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Nuclear Secrets Safety Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require an inventory of documents and devices containing Restricted Data at the national security laboratories of the Department of Energy, to improve security procedures for access to the vaults containing Restricted Data at those laboratories, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="2000-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="2000-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2000-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2000-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="2000-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-12-15T17:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Armed Services. H. Rept. 106-1035, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-12-15T17:10:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="597">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 597.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="Polygraphs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2000--Introduced.
Nuclear Secrets Safety Act - Directs the Secretary of Energy to report to specified congressional committees an inventory of each document or device at each national security laboratory that contains Restricted Data.Amends the National Nuclear Security Administration Act, with respect to procedures for ensuring that any individual is not permitted access to any classified area of a laboratory vault containing Restricted Data, to require such procedures, at a minimum, to provide that an individual shall not have access to any such vault unless, before each access, the individual's identity is verified by an attendant through direct visual observation.Requires the counterintelligence program at each such laboratory to include a polygraph program for individuals with access to any vault containing Restricted Data. Requires each such individual to undergo a polygraph examination within one year after having access to any such vault, in particular within 30 days after first access (or within 120 days after enactment of this Act, if first access occurred on or before enactment).Requires the Administrator for Nuclear Security to ensure that the combination of each lock to each laboratory vault containing Restricted Data is changed not later than 30 days after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
