<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="359" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:47-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="961" sequence="4"/>
  <status datetime="1995-05-10T20:30:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="407772"/>
  <offered datetime="1995-05-10"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to strike language that would remove the requirement that EPA first list a pollutant before it or a State may allow a permit-holder to comply with Best Practicable Control Technology or water quality standards in lieu of Best Available Technology; strike language that would authorize EPA or States to modify effluent limitations in permits for coal remining, even if the operations exceed State water quality standards or the receiving waters did not meet water quality standards prior to remining and the applicant submits a plan citing specific measures that will be used to improve existing water quality; strike language that would stipulate that a coal remining operation that started prior to the adoption of new regulatory standards is deemed to be in compliance as long as post-mining discharges are the same or better than before mining commenced, and remining was conducted under a Surface Mining Control and Reclamation permit; strike language that would provide flexibility for permit holders to undertake innovative pollution prevention measures; and strike language that would revise the standards and procedures for determining water quality standards on a State and Federal level, but retain language providing for a review of such proposed revisions by the Administration.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment (printed as amendment No. 33 in the Congressional Record of May 9) to delete several provisions in Title III of the bill that would: 1. Eliminate the current requirement that EPA first list a pollutant before it or a state may allow a permit-holder to comply with Best Practical Control Technology or water quality standards in lieu of Best Available Technology; 2. authorize the EPA or states to modify effluent limitations in permits for coal remining even if the operations exceed state water quality standards under certain circumstances; 3. stipulate that coal remining operations which began operation prior to the adoption of new standards should be considered to be in compliance; 4. provide flexibility for permit-holders to undertake innovative pollution prevention measures; 5. revise the standards and procedures for determining water quality standards.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10T19:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Mineta.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1995-05-10T20:30:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="313">
      <text>On agreeing to the Mineta amendment (A004) Failed by recorded vote: 166 - 260 (Roll no. 313).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
