<bill session="106" type="h" number="798" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Resources 2000 Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the permanent protection of the resources of the United States in the year 2000 and beyond.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="1999-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="1999-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="1999-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1999-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="1999-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="1999-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="1999-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1999-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400181" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="1999-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="1999-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="1999-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1999-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400508" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="1999-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400281" joined="1999-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400519" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1999-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1999-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="1999-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1999-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400383" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="1999-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1999-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400613" joined="1999-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1999-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="1999-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1999-06-07" withdrawn="1999-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-02-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E256-257"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-23">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-23">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-09">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities, Resource Conservation and Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-10">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG23" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Resource Conservation and Credit" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="3245"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="3245"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="446"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Demography"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered animals"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental degradation"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Estuarine ecology"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Farmland protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mollusks"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Shellfish fisheries"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports facilities"/>
    <term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Swimming"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Urban life"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/23/1999--Introduced.
Resources 2000 Act - Reduces according to a specified formula the amount of qualified Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) revenues that shall be deposited for a limited fiscal year into the Land and Water Conservation Fund, the Historic Preservation Fund, or any other fund or account established by this Act.(Sec. 6) Limits the amount available for administrative expenses to two percent.(Sec. 7) Requires off-budget treatment of the receipts and disbursements of funds under this Act.Title I: Land and Water Conservation Fund Revitalization - Amends the Land and Water Conservation Act of 1965 to extend indefinitely the period for: (1) depositing amounts into the Land and Water Conservation Fund (currently, such period ends September 30, 2015); and (2) under specified conditions, annual authorization of appropriations to the Fund in certain amounts for FY 1977 through 1978 and each succeeding fiscal year.(Sec. 103) Makes $900 million available each fiscal year for obligation or expenditure without further appropriation, to be allocated as follows: (1) 50 percent for Federal purposes; and (2) 50 percent for State grants.(Sec. 105) Removes the "outdoor recreation" limitation on the use of financial assistance to States to carry out planning, land acquisition, and development projects for land and water conservation purposes.(Sec. 106) Revises the formula used to allocate amounts made available for State purposes from the Fund each fiscal year, including distributing one-third of such funds among the several States under a competitive grant program.(Sec. 107) Revises the requirement that a State have a comprehensive statewide outdoor recreation plan as a prerequisite to consideration by the Secretary of the Interior of financial assistance for acquisition or development projects. Allows a State, in order to reduce costly repetitive planning efforts, to use for such a plan a current State comprehensive outdoor recreation plan, a State recreation plan, or a State action agenda under criteria developed by the Secretary.(Sec. 108) Removes the restriction on providing financial assistance to States for incidental costs relating to land and water acquisition.Permits local funding and a limited percentage of the amount of State allocated funds in any one year to be used for sheltered facilities for swimming pools and ice skating rinks in areas where the Secretary determines a need to enhance public safety.(Sec. 109) Requires the Secretary to approve, subject to certain conditions, the conversion of property (other than for public outdoor recreation use) acquired or developed with assistance under the Act only if the State demonstrates that no prudent or feasible alternative exists. Exempts from such requirement conversion of property that is no longer viable as an outdoor conservation or recreation facility due to changes in demographics, or that must be abandoned because of environmental contamination which endangers public health and safety.Title II: Urban Park and Recreation Recovery Program Amendments - Amends the Urban Park and Recreation Recovery Act of 1978 to provide for the development of new recreation areas and facilities (including the acquisition of lands for such development) under the urban park and recreation recovery program.(Sec. 205) Revises requirements for: (1) Federal assistance grant eligibility; (2) matching grants to local governments for rehabilitation, development, and innovation purposes; (3) local park and recreation recovery action programs; (4) State action incentives; and (5) conversion of recreation property for any other purpose other than public recreation purposes.(Sec. 210) Establishes in the Treasury the Urban Park and Recreation Recovery Fund. Specifies the amount to be deposited into the Fund each fiscal year out of qualified OCS revenues, which shall be available, without further appropriation, until expended.Sets forth limitations on annual State grants under this Act and grant and program administration.(Sec. 211) Repeals sunset provisions and congressional reporting requirements with respect to: (1) the impact of the urban park and recreation recovery program; and (2) the annual achievements of the innovation grant program.Title III: Historic Preservation Fund - Amends the National Historic Preservation Act to specify the amount to be deposited into the Historic Preservation Fund each fiscal year after FY 1998 out of qualified OCS revenues, which shall remain available, without further appropriation, and until expended, only to carry out the purposes of such Act.(Sec. 301) Requires at least one half of the funds obligated or expended each fiscal year under this Act to be used for preservation projects on historic properties (giving priority to the preservation of endangered historic properties).Title IV: Farmland, Ranchland, Open Space, and Forestland Protection - Establishes in the Treasury the Farmland, Ranchland, Open Space, and Forestland Protection Fund.(Sec. 403) Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to use specified amounts from the Fund for the farmland protection and forest legacy programs.Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to use specified amounts from the Fund for the ranchland protection program.(Sec. 404) Amends the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 with respect to the farmland protection program to: (1) specify that the program shall be a matching grant program carried out through eligible entities such as State and local government, Indian tribes, and nonprofit conservation organizations; (2) eliminate acreage limitations; and (3) increase the existing funding cap, revising it from a total program cap to a fiscal year cap.(Sec. 405) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a ranchland protection program similar to the farmland protection program.Title V: Federal and Indian Lands Restoration Fund - Establishes the Federal and Indians Lands Restoration Fund which shall be used as a dedicated source of funding for a coordinated program on Federal and Indian lands to restore degraded lands, protect resources that are threatened with degradation, and protect public health and safety. Deposits $250 million of qualified Outer Continental Shelf revenues received by the United States each fiscal year into the Fund and allocates: (1) 60 percent to the Secretary of the Interior for lands within the National Park System, National Wildlife Refuge System, and public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management; (2) 30 percent to the Secretary of Agriculture for lands within the National Forest System; and (3) ten percent to the Secretary of the Interior for competitive grants to Indian tribes under this Act.Requires the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) each establish priority lists for the use of funds which give priority to projects based upon the protection of significant resources, the severity of damages or threats to resources, and the protection of public health or safety; and (2) jointly establish a coordinated program for tracking the progress of activities carried out and determining the extent to which demonstrable results are being achieved.Title VI: Living Marine Resources Conservation, Restoration, and Management Assistance - Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to use amounts from the Living Marine Resources Conservation Fund for allocation to a coastal State with a Living Marine Resources Conservation Plan to reimburse the State for the costs of developing, implementing, and revising such a plan. Sets forth plan requirements.Establishes the Living Marine Resources Conservation Fund. Provides for the deposit in such fund of specified amounts received by the United States as qualified Outer Continental Shelf revenues. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants from such fund for the conservation, restoration, or management of living marine resources. Sets forth criteria for grant approval.Defines "living marine resources" as indigenous fin fish, anadromous fish, mollusks, crustaceans, and all other forms of marine animal and plant life, including marine mammals and birds, that inhabit marine or brackish waters of the United States during all or part of their life cycle.Title VII: Funding for State Native Fish and Wildlife Conservation and Restoration - Amends the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Act of 1980 to revise the purposes and applicability of such Act so as to: (1) provide for promoting conservation of native (currently, nongame) fish and wildlife; and (2) preserving biological diversity by maintaining natural assemblages of native fish and wildlife. Replaces the definition of "fish and wildlife" and "nongame fish and wildlife" with a definition of "native fish and wildlife" as a fish, animal, or plant species that: (1) historically occurred or occurs in an ecosystem, other than as a result of an introduction, and lives in an unconfined state; and (2) does not include any population of a domesticated species that has reverted to a feral existence.(Sec. 703) Requires State conservation plans to promote balanced and diverse assemblages of native fish and wildlife.(Sec. 704) Repeals the provision specifying that conservation actions set forth in a conservation plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior shall be eligible for reimbursement as fish and wildlife projects.(Sec. 705) Makes amendments relating to the reimbursement of State costs for the development, revision, and implementation of conservation plans to: (1) extend eligibility for reimbursement of costs incurred by States for developing conservation plans through FY 2010, and for implementing conservation plans through FY 2005; (2) repeal specified reimbursement requirements; (3) prohibit paying reimbursement to any State for any cost incurred in implementing an approved conservation plan or action to the extent that more than 50 (currently ten) percent of such costs in any such year are accounted for by inkind contributions; and (4) prohibit the amount of reimbursement paid to any State for any fiscal year after FY 2010 from exceeding 75 percent of the cost of implementing and revising the plan during the fiscal year.(Sec. 706) Establishes the Native Fish and Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Fund into which the following amounts received as qualified Outer Continental Shelf revenues shall be deposited: (1) $100 million for each of FY 2000 and 2001; (2) $200 million for each of FY 2002 through 2004; and (3) $350 million for FY 2005 and each proceeding fiscal year. Makes up to the amount stated for a fiscal year available to the Secretary of the Interior for that fiscal year to reimburse States for conservation plans and actions.Title VIII: Endangered and Threatened Species Recovery - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce to use amounts in the Endangered and Threatened Species Recovery Fund to provide financial assistance to persons for development and implementation of Endangered and Threatened Species Recovery Agreements. Requires either Secretary to give priority to the development and implementation of Agreements that: (1) implement actions identified under recovery plans approved by the Secretary; (2) have the greatest potential for contributing to the recovery of an endangered or threatened species; and (3) require use of the assistance on land owned by a small landowner or on a family farm by the owner or operator.Prohibits the Secretary from providing financial assistance for any action that is required by a permit issued under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 or that is otherwise required under Federal law.(Sec. 803) Authorizes the Secretary to enter into such Agreements and sets forth Agreement requirements, including: (1) requiring activities not otherwise mandated by law that contribute to species recovery; and (2) specifying species recovery goals. Requires the Secretary to review Agreements for compliance with such requirements, propose necessary revisions, approve Agreements in compliance, periodically monitor the implementation of each Agreement, and disburse financial assistance to implement the Agreement.(Sec. 804) Establishes the Endangered and Threatened Species Recovery Fund in the Treasury and requires $100 million to be deposited into the Fund each fiscal year from amounts received as qualified Outer Continental Shelf revenues.</summary>
</bill>
