<bill session="104" type="h" number="4174" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fallen Timbers Battlefield, Fort Meigs, and Fort Miamis National Historical Site Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Fallen Timbers Battlefield, Fort Meigs, and Fort Miamis National Historical Site in the State of Ohio.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1996-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="2122"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military parks"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/1996--Introduced.
Fallen Timbers Battlefield, Fort Meigs, and Fort Miamis National Historical Site Act - Establishes the Fallen Timbers Battlefield, Fort Meigs, and Fort Miamis National Historical Site in Ohio. Withdraws the Site from such designation if the Secretary of the Interior determines and notifies the Congress that: (1) its use, condition, or development is incompatible with the purposes of this Act; or (2) its management entity has not made reasonable and appropriate progress in preparing or implementing the Stewardship Plan for the Site. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) provide technical assistance regarding such Plan and its implementation to Ohio, such State's political subdivision, nonprofit organization, or any other person on a request by the management entity; and (2) assist in the Plan's development. Prohibits: (1) as a condition of such technical assistance, the Secretary from requiring any recipient to enact or modify land use restrictions; (2) the Secretary or any other Federal agency from making a limitation on fishing, hunting, or trapping a condition of the determination of eligibility for, or receipt of, assistance under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
