<bill session="106" type="h" number="2450" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Railroad Safety Reform Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform the safety practices of the railroad industry, to prevent railroad fatalities, injuries, and hazardous materials releases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="1999-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Ground Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW10" subcommittee="Ground Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism treatment"/>
    <term name="Automation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contractors"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fuel storage"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Highspeed trains"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Locomotives"/>
    <term name="Management audit"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Radio"/>
    <term name="Railroad commuting traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad equipment"/>
    <term name="Railroad finance"/>
    <term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
    <term name="Railroad maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad rolling stock"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seniority in employment"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sleep disorders"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic signs and signals"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Vandalism"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Employee Fatigue Title II: Protection of Employees and Witnesses Title III: Grade Crossing Safety Title IV: Passenger Service Safety Standards Title V: Safety Rulemaking and Enforcement Title VI: Miscellaneous Provisions Railroad Safety Reform Act of 1999 - Title I: Employee Fatigue - Amends Federal transportation law to revise the hours of duty limitations with respect to train employees (including determining when an employee is on or off duty). Declares that a railroad carrier shall not be held responsible for violating such requirements in the case of a dually employed employee if none of the railroad carrier's managers, supervisors, officers, and agents had actual knowledge of the employee's work schedule for another employer. Makes similar changes with respect to signal employees and dispatching service employees and power directors.(Sec. 105) Revises certain sleeping quarters limitations with respect to train employees (including signal employees), and for any individuals employed to maintain the right of way of a railroad carrier, to require such carrier and its managers, supervisors, officers, and agents to provide, among other things, a separate bedroom for each employee or individual.(Sec. 106) Requires each Class I and Class II railroad carrier, each railroad carrier providing intercity rail passenger transportation, and each railroad carrier providing commuter rail passenger transportation, to submit to the Secretary of Transportation a fatigue management plan designed to reduce: (1) fatigue experienced by railroad employees or its independent contractors; and (2) the likelihood of accidents and injuries caused by such fatigue. Provides a waiver for the submission of such plan.(Sec. 108) Prohibits, except in a specified emergency, a railroad carrier and its managers, supervisors, officers, and agents from requiring a transport vehicle driver to remain or go on duty: (1) unless such driver has at least eight consecutive hours off duty, during which such driver receives no communication from such carrier and its managers, supervisors, officers, and agents, during the prior 24 hours; (2) for a period in excess of ten consecutive hours; (3) unless such driver has received notice at least eight hours before going on duty; and (4) unless such driver has had at least one period of at least 24 consecutive hours off duty in the past seven days.(Sec. 110) Authorizes a railroad carrier and its managers, supervisors, officers, and agents to require a train employee to work a split shift only if the split shift begins between 12:01 a.m. and 11:59 a.m. and ends before 2:00 a.m. on the day following the day on which the shift begins.(Sec. 111) Prohibits a railroad carrier and its managers, supervisors, officers, and agents from requiring an employee to report for duty to begin an eight-hour shift which begins at a time that is more than four hours earlier or more than six hours later than the time of day when that employee, within the previous 72 hours, began a prior eight-hour shift (rotating shift). Directs the Secretary to report to Congress the results of a study regarding: (1) the effect of rotating shifts on employee fatigue; and (2) alternative methods of preventing fatigue due to such shifts.(Sec. 112) Directs the Railroad Safety Advisory Committee to convene a working group to consider what legislative changes might be appropriate with respect to hours of service. Requires the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration to report to Congress on the Committee's recommendations with respect to such changes.Title II: Protection of Employees and Witnesses - Revises certain employee protection requirements prohibiting a railroad carrier from discharging or discriminating against an employee also to prohibit such carrier from threatening, intimidating, or disciplining for, or preventing an employee from (among other things): (1) notifying, or attempting to notify, the carrier of a work-related personal injury or illness; (2) cooperating with a safety investigation; (3) furnishing information to any party as to the facts relating to any accident resulting in injury or death or damage to property occurring in connection with railroad transportation; (4) accurately reporting hours of duty or dual employment status; or (5) reporting a hazardous condition or refusing to work when confronted by a hazardous condition. Sets forth both civil and criminal penalties for violations of the requirements under this Act.(Sec. 201) Sets forth certain requirements with respect to the exclusion of an individual from employment by a railroad carrier as a safety-critical employee.(Sec. 203) Requires a railroad carrier to have an annual audit of the process by which it reports accidents.(Sec. 204) Makes it unlawful for any person to knowingly interfere with, obstruct, or hamper a railroad safety investigation, or knowingly or intentionally use intimidation, harassment, or threats to influence the testimony of any person or prevent a person from attending such investigation. Sets forth both civil and criminal penalties for violations of this Act.Title III: Grade Crossing Safety - Revises grade crossing safety requirements to require each railroad carrier to: (1) establish a toll-free telephone service to receive calls reporting malfunctions of safety equipment, or disabled vehicles blocking railroad tracks, at grade crossings; (2) notify trains operating near a grade crossing of the malfunction or disabled vehicle and contact appropriate public safety officials; and (3) ensure placement of signs at each grade crossing displaying the toll-free telephone information.(Sec. 302) Directs the Secretary to review current local, State, and Federal laws regarding violations of grade crossing signals. Directs the Secretary to develop and make available to State and local governments model State legislation providing for civil or criminal penalties, or both, for violations of grade crossing signals.Title IV: Passenger Service Safety Standards - Requires all passenger railroad cars to have emergency windows after January 1, 2002.(Sec. 402) Sets forth requirements for: (1) passenger railroad signals; and (2) internal and compartmentalized fuel tanks on passenger locomotives.Title V: Safety Rulemaking and Enforcement - Amends Federal transportation law with respect to railroad safety to direct the Secretary to convene an annual conference to determine the most important actions needed to improve railroad safety, and report the results to Congress.(Sec. 503) Directs the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) to report monthly to specified congressional committees on the status of FRA's safety-related rulemakings and reports.(Sec. 504) Sets forth requirements with respect to the rulemaking process of rules proposed by the Railroad Safety Advisory Committee.(Sec. 505) Declares that certain railroad power brake safety rules proposed on September 16, 1994, shall take effect as final rules one year after enactment of this Act if before that time the Secretary has not issued all final regulations required by specified law.(Sec. 506) Directs the Secretary to initiate a rulemaking to ensure the safety of operators of railroad cranes and other hoisting equipment, and of railroad employees working in the vicinity of cranes and other hoisting equipment.(Sec. 508) Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations addressing noise emissions from high-speed rail systems (including magnetic levitation systems) when operating at speeds greater than 150 miles per hour.(Sec. 509) Directs the Secretary to issue rules requiring that no track inspection shall be conducted from a vehicle traveling at a speed of more than 15 miles per hour.(Sec. 510) Authorizes officers, employees, or agents of the Secretary to monitor railroad radio communications for purposes of conducting any rulemaking, accident investigations, and acquiring general information as to railroad operations as it relates to railroad safety. Prohibits the use of information obtained from such monitoring as evidence for the assessment or collection of civil penalties or for implementation of other enforcement activities, except that it may be used as background for further investigation which might lead to the discovery of other useful evidence.(Sec. 511) Expands the Secretary's emergency authority to order restrictions and prohibitions to include instances of unsafe conditions involving significant harm to the environment.(Sec. 512) Requires fees imposed on railroad carriers to cover the costs of providing an additional 400 railroad safety inspectors.Title VI: Miscellaneous Provisions - Directs the Federal Transit Administrator to consult with the Federal Railroad Administrator concerning relevant safety issues when making a grant or loan to a commuter railroad to help eliminate or correct an unsafe condition that may cause a serious hazard of death or injury.(Sec. 602) Provides for the adjustment of civil penalties for inflation with respect to railroad safety violations committed under Federal railroad safety law.(Sec. 603) Requires certification of other safety-related railroad personnel in addition to locomotive engineers.(Sec. 604) Sets forth requirements with respect to: (1) transport motor vehicle inspections; and (2) railroad employee seniority rights.</summary>
</bill>
