<bill session="105" type="h" number="4598" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the sanctity of contracts and leases entered into by surface patent holders with respect to coalbed methane gas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400088"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-09-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1763"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="2500"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coal reserves"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/1998--Introduced.
Declares that the United States shall not deem as an infringement upon its ownership rights certain existing Federal contracts and leases covering land conveyed by the United States that in turn convey to surface patent holders any rights to coalbed methane gas exploration, extraction, sales, or production. Declares this Act applicable only to land with respect to which the United States owns coal reserved to it in a patent issued under specified Federal law. States that this Act does not: (1) apply to any tribally-owned or State-owned interest in coal or land; or (2) limit the right of any person who entered into a contract or lease for federally-owned coal before, on or after the date of enactment of this Act to mine and remove such coal, and to release coalbed methane without liability to surface patent holders with rights to explore for, extract, sell, or produce coalbed methane.</summary>
</bill>
