<bill session="108" type="h" number="3233" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Identity Theft Notification and Credit Restoration Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require financial institutions and financial service providers to notify customers of the unauthorized use of personal information, to amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require fraud alerts to be included in consumer credit files in such cases, and to provide customers with enhanced access to credit reports in such cases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400163"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2003--Introduced.
Identity Theft Notification and Credit Restoration Act of 2003 - Amends the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act to require a financial institution to promptly notify the following entities whenever a breach of personal information has occurred at such institution: (1) each customer affected by such breach; (2) certain consumer reporting agencies; and (3) appropriate law enforcement agencies. Requires any person that maintains personal information for or on behalf of a financial institution to promptly notify the institution of any case in which such customer information has been breached. Prescribes notification procedures. Authorizes a customer injured by a violation of this Act to institute a civil action to recover damages. Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require a consumer reporting agency to include a fraud alert in a consumer file: (1) upon notification by financial institution; and (2) upon consumer request. Requires a consumer reporting agency to ensure that each person procuring credit information with respect to a consumer is made aware of the existence of a fraud alert in the consumer's file, regardless of whether a full credit report, credit score, or summary report is requested. Mandates no-cost consumer access to credit reports and scores once during each calendar year and once every three months during the one-year period beginning on the date on which a fraud alert is included in the consumer file. Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate implementing regulations.</summary>
</bill>
