<bill session="108" type="h" number="4281" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-13T16:26:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-13T16:26:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Small Business Medical Care bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to improve access and choice for entrepreneurs with small businesses with respect to medical care for their employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400206"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400053" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400212" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400265" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2004-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E761"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-11T20:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 638 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4279, H.R. 4280 and H.R. 4281. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-12T12:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 638 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13T13:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 638.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2951-2960, CR 5/14/2004 H2967-2986" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13T13:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4279, H.R. 4280 and H.R. 4281. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13T13:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 4281.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to House Resolution 638 the House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Kind amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. McCarthy (NY) moved to recommit with instructions to Education and the Workforce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/14/2004 H2984-2986" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 5/14/2004 H2984" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the McCarthy (NY) motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13T16:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/14/2004 H2983" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 196 - 218 (Roll no. 173).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-05-13T16:26:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="174" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 252 - 162, 1 Present (Roll no. 174).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2951-2957" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13T16:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13T16:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 638, H.R. 4281 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="hr" number="638"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="638"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="hr" number="638"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="660"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="660"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="4275"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="4279"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="545"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care fraud"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance agents"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Professional associations"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trade associations"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h525"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/13/2004--Passed House without amendment.
Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2004 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for establishment and governance of association health plans (AHPs), which are group health plans whose sponsors are trade, industry, professional, chamber of commerce, or similar business associations, and which meet certain ERISA certification requirements. (Thus, through ERISA preemption of State laws, certified AHPs are exempted from State regulation of health insurance providers, including State consumer protection laws and State requirements for health care benefits to be offered by such entities, with certain exceptions.) (Sec. 2) Establishes rules governing AHPs, including requirements relating to certification, sponsors and boards of trustees, participation and coverage, nondiscrimination, plan documents, contribution rates, benefit options, applications for certification, notice of voluntary termination, corrective actions, and mandatory termination. Requires AHPs which provide health benefits in addition to health insurance coverage to maintain certain reserves and comply with other solvency requirements. Directs the Secretary of Labor to apply for appointment, and carry out specified duties, as trustee of any insolvent AHPs which provide health benefits in addition to health insurance coverage. Allows a State to impose a contribution tax on any AHP commencing operations in such State after the enactment of this Act. Sets forth limits on such tax, including reduction by the amount of any tax or assessment otherwise imposed by the State on specified other insurance related items maintained by the AHP. Requires AHPs to include in their summary plan descriptions, in connection with each benefit option, a description of the form of any solvency or guarantee fund protection secured under ERISA or applicable State law. Allows a certified AHP to exist in a State regardless of any State law that would preclude it. Preempts State requirements for benefits to be offered by AHPs; but allows a State in which an AHP is domiciled to require the domiciled AHP to cover particular types of diseases and conditions. Allows health insurance issuers to offer coverage of the same policy type offered in connection with a particular AHP to eligible employers, regardless of whether such employers are members of the particular association and regardless of State law. Deems health insurance coverage policy forms filed and approved in a particular State in connection with an insurer's offering under an AHP as approved in any other State in which such coverage is offered when the insurer provides a complete filing in the same form and manner to the authority in the other State. Makes inapplicable to certified AHPs certain current ERISA provisions which allow State regulation of multiple employer welfare arrangements (MEWAs). Revises ERISA preemption rules to permit State regulation of self-insured MEWAs providing medical care which do not elect to meet the certification requirements for AHPs. Directs the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees by January 1, 2009, on the effect, if any, AHPs have had on the number of uninsured individuals. (Sec. 3) Revises requirements for treatment of single employer arrangements. Allows two or more trades or businesses to be deemed a single employer if they are in the same control group offering medical care benefits, under specified conditions. (Sec. 4) Provides for enforcement of AHP requirements, including criminal penalties for certain willful misrepresentations, issuance of cease and desist orders, and the responsibility of AHP boards of trustees for certain claims procedures. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary, regarding the exercise of authority, to consult only with the recognized primary domicile State for an AHP. (Sec. 6) Provides for transitional and other rules relating to treatment of certain existing health benefit programs.</summary>
</bill>
