<bill session="106" type="h" number="368" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Schools Internet Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the installation of a system for filtering or blocking matter on the Internet on computers in schools and libraries with Internet access, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400530" joined="1999-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="School boards"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/1999--Introduced.
Safe Schools Internet Act of 1999 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit universal telecommunications services from being provided to any elementary or secondary school unless its administrator has certified to the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) that it has selected and installed a system for computers with Internet access which filters or blocks matters deemed inappropriate for minors. Prohibits such service with respect to a library having Internet access unless it certifies that it employs such a filtering or blocking system on one or more of its computers. Requires a library to notify the FCC within ten days after changing or terminating such a system. Requires the determination of what shall be considered inappropriate for minors to be made by the appropriate school, school board, library, or other responsible authority, without Federal interference.</summary>
</bill>
