<bill session="104" type="h" number="3616" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Self-Sufficiency Standard Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Job Training Partnership Act to provide for the establishment of standards to ensure long-term economic self-sufficiency for participants in adult training programs carried out under part A of title II of that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economic security"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Graphs and charts"/>
    <term name="Hard-core unemployed"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Wage surveys"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/1996--Introduced.
Self-Sufficiency Standard Act - Amends the Job Training Partnership Act to establish economic self-sufficiency standards for disadvantaged adult training programs, according to a formula to be developed by the Secretary of Labor, and local economic self-sufficiency tables to be developed by service delivery areas. Prohibits incentive grants to service delivery areas that do not have in effect, after two years, an approved local economic self-sufficiency standards table. Requires inclusion of such a table and related reports in the job training plan and in the Governor's coordination and special services plan. Directs the Secretary to make up to six grants in each of three fiscal years to States for demonstration and exemplary programs to increase the number of participants in disadvantaged adult training programs who are trained and placed in jobs that yield long-term economic self-sufficiency in accordance with the local economic self-sufficiency tables.</summary>
</bill>
