<bill session="105" type="h" number="392" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Economic Growth Incentive Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for economic growth by reducing income taxes for most Americans, by encouraging the purchase of American-made products, and by extending transportation-related spending, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Government Reform and Oversight, Banking and Financial Services, and Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-09">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-09">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-09">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-09">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Bank reserves"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Ferries"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Highspeed ground transportation"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Highway use tax"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="Scenic byways"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/9/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Reduction in Individual Income Taxes Title II: Incentive for Purchase of American-Made Property Title III: Surface Transportation Programs Title IV: Relief from Credit Crunch Title V: Cap on Federal Employment Title VI: Reduction in Federal Overhead Expenses Economic Growth Incentive Act of 1997 - Title I: Reduction in Individual Income Taxes - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reduce individual income taxes. Title II: Incentive for Purchase of American-Made Property - Allows an itemized deduction for State and local general sales taxes imposed on the retail sale of American-made property. Title III: Surface Transportation Programs - Amends the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to repeal the obligation ceiling for Federal-aid highways and highway safety construction programs. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1998 through 2000 for: (1) highway programs; (2) donor State bonus amounts; (3) apportionment adjustments; (4) set asides for interstate discretionary projects; (5) the discretionary bridge program; (6) national high-speed ground transportation programs; (7) the highway timber bridge program; (8) highway use tax evasion projects; (9) the scenic byways program; (10) construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities; (11) certain highway safety programs; (12) Federal Transit Act authorizations; and (13) the motor carrier safety grant program. Removes the highway safety obligation ceilings. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend the authority to make expenditures from the Highway Trust Fund until September 30, 2000. Title IV: Relief from Credit Crunch - Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the current "credit crunch" should be eased by making it easier for businesses and individuals to obtain loans and leases; and (2) State banking authorities and the appropriate Federal banking agencies should more sensibly apply the requirements on loan loss reserves so as not to punish or restrain responsible borrowers. Title V: Cap on Federal Employment - Prohibits the number of Federal employees from exceeding such number on the date of enactment of this Act. Rescinds all unobligated amounts that were appropriated before such date to pay the salary, wages, or benefits for a position not filled on that date. Title VI: Reduction in Federal Overhead Expenses - Rescinds ten percent of all unobligated amounts that were appropriated before the date of enactment of this Act to pay overhead expenses of any Federal agency. Reduces authorizations for any fiscal year to pay overhead expenses of any Federal agency by ten percent.</summary>
</bill>
