<bill session="106" type="h" number="3611" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Interest Checking Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the number of interaccount transfers which may be made from business accounts at depository institutions, to require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to pay interest on certain reserves, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400213"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Bank reserves"/>
    <term name="Checking accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money supply"/>
    <term name="NOW accounts"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2000--Introduced.
Small Business Interest Checking Act of 2000 - Amends Federal banking law governing interaccount transfers to provide that a depository institution may permit owners of certain interest or dividend paying accounts to make up to 24 transfers monthly for any purpose to their other accounts in the same institution.Amends the Federal Reserve Act to require a Federal reserve bank to pay interest at least quarterly (at a rate not to exceed the general level of short term interest rates) to a depository institution on any balance it maintains at the reserve bank to meet reserve requirements.Authorizes the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to prescribe implementing regulations.Reformulates the mandatory depository institution reserve ratio to: (1) one that is not greater than three percent, and may be zero, (currently, a flat ratio of three percent) for transaction accounts of $25 million or less; and (2) reduce from eight percent to zero the minimum ratio for transaction accounts exceeding $25 million. (Thus authorizes the Federal Reserve Board to set zero reserve requirements for such accounts.)</summary>
</bill>
