<bill session="105" type="h" number="537" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Background Security Records Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the law popularly known as the Presidential Records Act of 1978 and the law popularly known as Privacy Act, to ensure that Federal Bureau of Investigation records containing sensitive background security information that are provided to the White House are properly protected for privacy and security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Security, International Affairs and Criminal Justice.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO06" subcommittee="National Security, International Affairs and Criminal Justice" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential records"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="White House (Washington, D.C.)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/1997--Introduced.
Background Security Records Act of 1997 - Amends the Presidential Records Act of 1978 to direct that any record provided by the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to the White House for providing background security information on any individual shall: (1) not be a presidential record; and (2) upon the conclusion of a President's term of office or upon conclusion of the last term, shall be returned to the FBI, subject to an exception. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to maintain and periodically provide to the President and the FBI Director accurate lists of individuals who are employed in or detailed to the White House. Amends the Privacy Act to require that any record provided by the FBI to the White House for providing background security information on an individual shall be maintained at the White House as an FBI record. Prohibits disclosure of a record containing sensitive background information on an individual by the FBI to the White House, except as specified.</summary>
</bill>
