<bill session="108" type="h" number="4670" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of a Center for Scientific and Technical Assessment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2004-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2004-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2004-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2004-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5139"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-12-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2168-2169"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2004--Introduced.
Establishes: (1) a Center for Scientific and Technical Assessment to provide timely advice to Congress on scientific and technical aspects of public policy issues, administered by a Director; and (2) a Technical Assessment Board to provide guidance to the Director to ensure that the Center provides timely and useful responses to congressional requests. Authorizes the Director to appoint, with the approval of the Comptroller General, a Deputy Director. Prohibits the Director and Deputy Director from engaging in any other business, vocation, or employment, or (except with the Comptroller General's approval) holding any office in, or acting in any capacity for, any organization, agency, or institution with which the Center makes any contract or other arrangement under this Act. Permits: (1) any Member of Congress to make requests to the Board that the Center conduct an investigation and report to the requester, within a specified time period, on any matter relating to scientific and technical assessment (and sets priorities for requests); and (2) the Director to establish an advisory panel as necessary to support each technical assessment report. Requires each report to be subject to peer review before delivery to the committee or Member requesting it. Provides for public release of unclassified reports, subject to a delay of up to two weeks at the request of the Board or a Member.</summary>
</bill>
