<bill session="107" type="h" number="5319" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Reduce Wildfire Risk bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Forests Reform Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Healthy Forests and Wildfire Risk Reduction Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the capacity of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to expeditiously address wildfire prone conditions on National Forest System lands and other public lands that threaten communities, watersheds, and other at-risk landscapes through the establishment of expedited environmental analysis procedures under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, to establish a predecisional administrative review process for the Forest Service, to expand fire management contracting authorities, to authorize appropriations for hazardous fuels reduction projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400265"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2002-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2002-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2002-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="2002-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2002-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400305" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2002-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2002-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400398" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2002-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2002-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2002-09-04" withdrawn="2002-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-05">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-10-08">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-10-31T11:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-770, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-31T11:31:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 22, 2002.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Management audit"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tree diseases"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Weed control"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/31/2002--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Healthy Forests and Wildfire Risk Reduction Act of 2002 - (Sec.5) States that this Act shall apply only with respect to a hazardous fuels reduction project undertaken by the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior on National Forest System or Bureau of Land Management lands, respectively, if such Federal lands: (1) are located in the wildland-urban interface; (2) are located in risk proximity to a municipal water supply system; (3) are other at-risk Federal lands; or (4) contain threatened and endangered species habitat. Limits fiscal year acreage to two million acres.Excludes: (1) National Wilderness Preservation System lands; (2) Federal lands where vegetation removal is prohibited; and (3) Wilderness Study Areas.(Sec. 6) Reserves at least 70 percent of hazardous fuels reduction program funds for each of FY 2003 through 2005 for projects on Federal lands in the wilderness-urban interface. Gives priority to projects that would provide the greatest protection to human lives and property.(Sec. 7) Permits the Secretary concerned to implement a fuel reduction program without the full environmental review of alternatives required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, unless the project entails construction of a new permanent system road. Provides for public notice and hearings.(Sec. 8) Sets forth a Forest Service administrative appeals process under which: (1) appellants would have ten days to give notice of their intent to appeal, and 15 days to file an appeal; (2) the Forest Service would have 25 days to decide on the merits of the appeal; and (3) appeals review officers would have the discretionary authority to sign a new decision document at the end of the appeals process which would be considered the final agency decision.(Sec.9) Provides judicial review only in the Federal district court with jurisdiction over the proposed project's location. Requires: (1) plaintiffs to file causes of action within 15 days of publication of notice of final agency action, after which the Secretary concerned shall stay the project until completion of judicial review; and (2) Federal district courts to decide the merits of an action within 60 days, with extensions under specified circumstances.(Sec. 10) Requires General Accounting Office audits of this Act's implementation.(Sec. 11) Authorizes through September 30, 2005: (1) the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into not more than 15 stewardship and end result contracts for hazardous fuels reduction projects; and (2) the Secretary of the Interior to enter into not more than 26 such projects, other than revested Oregon and California Railroad and reconveyed Coos Bay Wagon Road grant lands.(Sec. 12) States that the processes established by this Act shall be available through September 30, 2005.(Sec. 13) States that this Act shall not be construed to affect: (1) litigation involving the Roadless Area Conservation Rule; or (2) the authority of the Secretaries to implement hazardous fuel reduction projects under other available authorities on any Federal lands.(Sec. 14) States that the Secretary concerned shall complete hazardous fuels reduction projects on Federal lands consistent with the implementation plan for the ``Collaborative 10-year Strategy for Reducing Wildland Fire Risks to Communities and the Environment,'' (dated May 2002).(Sec. 15) Directs the Secretaries to jointly establish an independent monitoring panel.(Sec. 16) Authorizes related appropriations for: (1) National Forest System lands; and (2) Bureau of Land Management lands.</summary>
</bill>
