<bill session="104" type="hr" number="252" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-01T15:31:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-11-01T15:31:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2546) making appropriations for the government of the District of Columbia and other activities chargeable in whole or in part against the revenues of said District for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31T18:53:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-302, by Mr. Linder.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31T18:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2546 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. Before consideration of any other amendment, it shall be in order without intervention of any point of order to consider the amendment printed in the report accompanying this resolution, debatable for 10 minutes and not subject to amendment. If the amendment is adopted, the bill, as amended, shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment. The bill shall be considered as read through page 58, line 4, and all points of order for failure to comply with clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI shall be waived. Debate on each further amendment to the bill, and any amendments thereto shall be limited to 30 minutes. It shall be in order without intervention of any point o...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-10-31T18:53:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="110">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 110.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01T14:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11618-11627" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01T14:11:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01T15:11:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-11-01T15:31:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="757" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 181 (Roll no. 757).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01T15:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="2546"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/31/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the modified open rule for the consideration of H.R. 2546 (District of Columbia appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
