<bill session="106" type="h" number="1148" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Reserve Board Abolition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To abolish the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal reserve banks, to repeal the Federal Reserve Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Central banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/1999--Introduced.
Federal Reserve Board Abolition Act - Abolishes the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and each Federal reserve bank.Repeals the Federal Reserve Act.Sets forth administrative provisions regarding the winding up of affairs of the Board and banks.Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to liquidate all Board and bank assets so as to achieve as expeditious a liquidation as may be practical while maximizing the return to the Treasury.Transfers the net proceeds of liquidation to the Treasury after satisfying all claims against the Board and banks accepted by the OMB Director and redeeming bank stock.Abolishes all outstanding liabilities of the Board and banks at the time such entities are abolished, including any liability for retirement and other benefits for former Board and bank officers and employees, and makes such liabilities payable from amounts deposited in the Treasury general fund.</summary>
</bill>
