<bill session="108" type="h" number="3907" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Transportation to transfer to the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration a certain percentage of apportionments of funds made available from the Highway Trust Fund from States that do not enact laws to prohibit driving under the influence of an illegal drug, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400324"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-04">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2004--Introduced.
Sets forth the duties of the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA), including to: (1) advise and coordinate with other Federal agencies on how to address the problem of driving under the influence of an illegal drug; (2) conduct research on the prevention, detection, and prosecution of driving under such influence; and (3) report annually to Congress on the extent of the problem in each State, including a description of the progress each State has made in addressing such problem. Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to transfer to the Administrator increasing percentages of funds otherwise apportioned to a State out of the Highway Trust Fund from any State that does not enact laws to prohibit driving under the influence of an illegal drug. Requires transferred funds to be used to carry out NHTSA duties. Requires the Secretary, if any funds are transferred to the Administrator, to transfer to the Administrator also a calculated amount of obligation authority distributed for the fiscal year to the State for Federal-aid highways and highway safety construction programs.</summary>
</bill>
