<bill session="104" type="h" number="2762" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require additional research prior to the promulgation of a standard for sulfate under the Safe Drinking Water Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1996-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Carcinogens"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/1995--Introduced.
Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control, prior to promulgating a national primary drinking water regulation for sulfate, to jointly conduct additional research to establish a reliable dose-response relationship for the adverse health effects that may result from exposure to sulfate in drinking water. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) consideration of health effects that may be experienced by groups within the general population, such as infants and travelers, that are potentially at greater risk; (2) the conduct of research in consultation with interested States and based on the best available, peer-reviewed science and supporting studies; and (3) notice, time, and rulemaking requirements for promulgating such standard.</summary>
</bill>
