<bill session="105" type="h" number="2605" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-06T23:16:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-11-06T23:16:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Communist China Subsidy bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Communist China Subsidy Reduction Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Communist China Subsidy Reduction Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the United States to oppose the making of concessional loans by international financial institutions to any entity in the People's Republic of China.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06T21:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 302.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10159-10169" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06T21:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2358, H.R. 2232, H.R. 2195, H. Res. 188 and H.R. 967. Providing for the sequential consideration in the House of the following measures: H.R. 2358, H.R. 2232, H.R. 2195, H. Res. 188, H.R. 967, H.R. 2570, H.R. 2386, H.R. 2605, and H.R. 2647. One hour of general debate is provided for each measure. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06T21:23:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06T22:30:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06T22:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Taylor (MS) moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10167-10168" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06T22:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Solomon raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Solomon asked unanimous consent that the amendment proposed by Mr. Taylor (MS) was not germane to the bill and was, therefore, in violation of the rules of the House. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06T22:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Taylor (MS) moved to appeal the ruling of the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06T22:57:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to appeal the ruling of the Chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 192 (Roll no. 604).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10168" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-11-06T23:16:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="605" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 354 - 59 (Roll no. 605).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06T23:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on East Asian and Pacific Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSFR02" subcommittee="East Asian and Pacific Affairs" name="Senate Foreign Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hr" number="302"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Birth control"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="International agricultural cooperation"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nonviolence"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Public demonstrations"/>
    <term name="Publishers and publishing"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific exchanges"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Trials"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h470"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/6/1997--Passed House amended.
Communist China Subsidy Reduction Act of 1997 - Amends the International Financial Institutions Act to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. Executive Directors at each international financial institution to vote to oppose the provision of concessional loans (with highly subsidized interest rates, grace periods for repayment of five years or more, and maturities of 20 years or more) to China, any Chinese citizen or national, or any Chinese entity. (Sec. 4) Expresses the sense of the Congress that U.S. nationals conducting industrial cooperation projects in China should adhere to certain principles, including: (1) suspending the use of any merchandise that they have reason to believe was produced by convict or forced labor, and refusing to use forced labor in their projects; (2) seeking to ensure that political or religious views, sex, ethnic or national background, or association with dissidents will not prohibit hiring, lead to harassment, demotion, or dismissal, or otherwise affect the employment status of an individual employed in the industrial cooperation project; (3) ensuring that methods of production used in the projects do not pose unnecessary danger to workers and the surrounding neighborhoods and environment; (4) striving to establish private business enterprises when involved in a project with the Government of China; (5) discouraging any military presence on the premises of the project; (6) promoting freedom of association and assembly among employees; (7) providing the Department of State with information relevant to its efforts to collect information on prisoners for purposes of the Prisoner Information Registry; (8) discouraging or preventing compulsory political indoctrination programs from taking place on project premises; (9) promoting freedom of expression of all kinds; and (10) preventing harassment of workers who decide freely the number and spacing of their children, and prohibiting compulsory population control activities on the premises of the project. Directs the Secretary of State to forward a copy of these principles to the member nations of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, and encourage them to promote similar principles. Directs each U.S. national conducting an industrial cooperation project in China to register with the Secretary and indicate whether they agree to implement such principles. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to give preference to U.S. nationals who have adopted such principles when selecting participants for trade missions to China. (Sec. 5) Directs U.S. agencies that engage in educational, cultural, scientific, agricultural, military, legal, political, and artistic exchanges to initiate and expand such exchange programs with regard to China. Expresses the sense of the Congress that a federally chartered not-for-profit organization should be established to fund exchanges between the United States and China through private donations.</summary>
</bill>
