<bill session="105" type="h" number="3109" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-09T12:20:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-09-09T12:20:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Thomas Cole National Historic Site Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Thomas Cole National Historic Site Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Thomas Cole National Historic Site in the State of New York, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-09T12:00:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="394">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 394.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-09T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-695.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-09T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-09T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7435-7437" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-09T12:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-09-09T12:20:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-09-09T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-09T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Artists"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Painting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/1998--Passed House amended.
Thomas Cole National Historic Site Act - Establishes the Thomas Cole National Historic Site in New York State as an affiliated area of the National Park System. Provides that the Greene County Historical Society, Greene County, New York, shall continue to own, manage, and operate the Site. Directs the Society to administer the Site in accordance with this Act and all laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with: (1) the Society to preserve the House and other structures at the Site and to assist with education programs and research and interpretation of the House and associated landscapes; and (2) New York, the Society, the Thomas Cole Foundation, and other public and private entities to facilitate public understanding and enjoyment of the lives and works of the Hudson River artists through assistance to develop, present, and fund art exhibits, resident artist programs, and other appropriate activities related to the preservation, interpretation, and use of the Site. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire: (1) personal property associated with, and appropriate for, the interpretation of the Site; and (2) works of art associated with Thomas Cole and other Hudson River artists for the purpose of display at the Site. Directs the Secretary to develop and submit to specified congressional committees a general management plan for the Site, including recommendations for regional wayside exhibits. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
