<bill session="105" type="h" number="3666" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Nutrition and WIC Reauthorization Amendments of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to provide children with increased access to food and nutrition assistance, to simplify program operations and improve program management, to extend certain authorities contained in such Acts through fiscal year 2002, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="1998-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1998-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1998-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1998-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1998-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="406284" joined="1998-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1998-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1998-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1998-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1998-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1998-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E584"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Breast feeding"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dairy products"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Dietary fat"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled children"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic benefits transfers"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to disability services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Food handling"/>
    <term name="Food poisoning"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Food service"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Grocery trade"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Homeless children"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infant formulas"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legumes"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and the aged"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare fraud"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Amendments to the National School Lunch Act Title II: Amendments to the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 Title III: Amendments to the Commodity Distribution Reform Act and WIC Amendments of 1987 Child Nutrition and WIC Reauthorization Amendments of 1998 - Title I: Amendments to the National School Lunch Act - Amends the National School Lunch Act (NSLA) with respect to direct expenditures for agricultural commodities and other foods to repeal requirements for: (1) interim sources of funds pending supplemental appropriations; and (2) State matching funds for such interim funds and for cash donations in lieu of commodity donations. (Sec. 102) Allows State agencies to retain up to one-half of any program funds recovered during State-conducted audits or reviews of school food authorities, institutions, and service institutions participating in food assistance programs authorized under NSLA and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (CNA). Requires State agencies to use such funds for otherwise allowable program costs to improve management operations of such programs within the State, including by providing funds to school food authorities, institutions, and service institutions participating in such programs. (Sec. 103) Repeals a prohibition against requiring a State to match Federal funds for meals in private schools if the State educational agency is prohibited by law from disbursing State appropriated funds to private schools. Sunsets the Secretary of Agriculture's authority to disburse NSLA program funds to schools directly at the end of FY 2000. Requires the Secretary to provide training and technical assistance to State agencies which assume program administration from the Secretary on or before October 1, 2000. (Sec. 104) Requires all schools participating in the National School Lunch Program (lunch program) under NLSA or the School Breakfast Program (breakfast program) under CNA in which meals are prepared on site to obtain inspections twice during each school year that indicate food service operations meet State or local health and safety standards. (Sec. 105) Repeals the Secretary's authority, acting through the Administrator of the Food and Nutrition Service or through the Extension Service, to award grants for food and nutrition demonstration projects. Requires schools participating in the lunch program or breakfast program to make every effort to establish meal service periods that provide children adequate time to fully consume their meals in an environment conducive to eating. (Sec. 106) Directs the Secretary to require that schools in the contiguous United States purchase for the lunch program and breakfast program, whenever possible, only food products that are produced in the United States. (Sec. 107) Revises the NLSA summer food service program to apply to suppers and supplements the Secretary's authority to establish adjustments to reimbursement rates in the States of Alaska and Hawaii, and in specified territories, to reflect differences in costs from those in all other States. Revises the eligibility criteria for private nonprofit institutions under the summer food service program to increase from five to 25 the number of sites they may operate. Repeals certain summer food service program requirements relating to: (1) a March 1st deadline for indication of interest; (2) restrictions on meal contracting; and (3) vendor registration. Extends through FY 2002 the authorization of appropriations for the NLSA summer food service program. (Sec. 108) Reauthorizes through FY 2002 the NSLA commodity distribution program, which may use Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) and other specified funds to purchase agricultural commodities for use in programs under NLSA, CNA, and the Older Americans Act of 1965. (Sec. 109) Revises NLSA child and adult care food program requirements for licensing and alternate approval for schools and outside school hours child care. Reinstates categorical eligibility, under the NLSA child care food program, for participants in the Even Start program of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. (Extends such eligibility through FY 2002; it had ended with FY 1997.) Revises conditions for child and adult care program participation by institutions moving toward compliance with the requirement for tax exempt status. Repeals a notification requirement for incomplete applications. Requires State agencies, at least once every two years, to provide notification of child and adult care program availability, participation requirements, and application procedures to each nonparticipating institution or family or group day care home that is located in a needy area within the State, and has Federal, State, or local licensing or approval or receives funds under Social Security Act block grants to States for social services. Repeals the requirement that a participating State provide sufficient training, technical assistance, and monitoring to facilitate effective program operation. Repeals the Secretary's mandate to make funds available each fiscal year for State audits of participating institutions in the child care food program. Directs the Secretary to provide State agencies with increased levels of training and technical assistance for their management and oversight of the child and adult care program. Allows institutions that provide care to at-risk school children during after-school hours, weekends, or holidays during the regular school year to participate in the child care food program. Defines as at-risk any children who: (1) are age 12 through 18; and (2) live in a geographical area served by a school enrolling elementary students in which at least 50 percent of the total number of children enrolled are certified eligible to receive free or reduced price school meals under NSLA or CNA. Allows such institutions to claim reimbursements, at the free supplement rate, only for: (1) supplements served without charge to at-risk school children during after-school hours, weekends, or holidays during the regular school year; and (2) one supplement per child per day. Directs the Secretary to provide State agencies with information concerning the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC program) under CNA. Requires State agencies to ensure that each participating child care center (other than institutions providing care to school children outside of school hours) receives certain WIC program informational materials and updates, and provides such information to parents of enrolled children annually. Repeals specified termination dates to grant permanent authorization to demonstration projects for child care food program qualification of private for-profit organizations providing nonresidential day care services. (Sec. 110) Allows emergency shelter homeless programs to participate in the child and adult care food program. Allows shelters to claim reimbursements, at the free supplement rate, only for: (1) supplements served without charge to resident children through age 12; and (2) not more than three meals or two meals and a supplement per child per day. (Sec. 111) Repeals authority for certain demonstration projects involving: (1) meals and supplements outside of school hours; (2) fortified fluid milk; (3) fruits, vegetables, legumes, cereals, and grain-based products; (4) low-fat dairy products and lean meat and poultry products; and (5) reduced paperwork and application requirements and increased participation. (Sec. 112) Extends through FY 2002 the authorization of appropriations for training and technical assistance under the child and adult care food program. (Sec. 113) Extends through FY 1999 authority to fund the food service management institute, including mandatory and discretionary activities. (Sec. 114) Extends through FY 2002 the authorization of appropriations for compliance and accountability activities under the child and adult care food program. (Sec. 115) Extends through FY 1999 authority to fund an information clearinghouse for nongovernmental groups on food assistance and self-help activities for low-income individuals and communities. Makes the Secretary's authority to contract for such a clearinghouse discretionary rather than mandatory. Waives competition requirements for a contract with any organization that has performed satisfactorily under a previous clearinghouse contract. (Sec. 116) Repeals the requirement that the Secretary provide guidance and grant assistance to eligible entities for accommodating special dietary needs of individuals with disabilities who participate in covered programs under NSLA and CNA. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out accommodation activities, including guidance, technical assistance, training, and grants for State agencies and eligible entities. Title II: Amendments to the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 - Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (CNA) to Sunsets the Secretary of Agriculture's authority to disburse CNA program funds to schools directly at the end of FY 2000. Requires the Secretary to provide training and technical assistance to State agencies which assume program administration from the Secretary on or before October 1, 2000. (Sec. 202) Repeals specified requirements for reallocation of State administrative expense funds. Eliminates the ten percent limitation on the transfer of administrative expense funds under CNA and NSLA. Extends through FY 2002 the authorization of appropriations for State administrative expenses under CNA. (Sec. 203) Establishes additional program application requirements, involving physical presence, income documentation, and verification, for the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants and children (WIC program). Authorizes the Secretary to provide bulk quantities of WIC program nutrition education materials to State agencies administering the Commodity Supplemental Food Program under the Agriculture and Consumer Protection Act of 1973 at no cost to that program. Extends through FY 2002: (1) the authorization of appropriations for the WIC program and for the WIC farmers market nutrition program; and (2) requirements to use certain WIC funds for allocations to State agencies for costs of nutrition services and administration, and for program infrastructure and information, projects of regional or national significance, and breastfeeding promotion and support activities. Revises WIC program requirements relating to: (1) infant formula procurement; (2) spend-forward authority; (3) matching funds requirement; (3) ranking criteria for farmers market nutrition program State plans; and (4) disqualification of certain vendors convicted of trafficking or illegal sales. (Sec. 204) Authorizes appropriations in necessary amounts (currently gives a specified amount for each fiscal year) for FY 1999 through 2002 for the nutrition education and training program under CNA. Title III: Amendments to the Commodity Distribution Reform Act and WIC Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Commodity Distribution Reform Act and WIC Amendments of 1987 to revise provisions relating to applicability and customer acceptability information. (Sec. 302) Adds to such Act food distribution requirements relating to the Secretary of Agriculture's authority to: (1) transfer commodities between programs; (2) resolve claims; (3) use specified funds to make payment of costs associated with management of commodities which pose a health or safety hazard; and (4) accept commodities donated by Federal sources.</summary>
</bill>
