<bill session="107" type="hr" number="461" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-27T11:43:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-06-27T11:43:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5010) making appropriations for the Department of Defense for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T19:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 107-536, by Mrs. Myrick.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T19:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The rule waives clause 2 of rule XXI (prohibiting unauthorized or legislative provisions in an appropriations bill) against provisions in the bill. The rule authorizes the Chairman of the Committee of the Whole to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record. Upon adoption, it shall be order, any rule of the House to the contrary notwithstanding, to consider concurrent resolutions providing for adjournment of the House and Senate during the month of July.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-06-26T19:28:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="179">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 179.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-06-27T11:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4076-4079" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-27T11:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 461.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-27T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2002-06-27T11:43:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4076" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-06-27T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="107" type="h" number="5010"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2002--Reported to House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 5011 (FY 2003 Department of Defense appropriations).Makes it in order to consider concurrent resolutions providing for adjournment of the House of Representatives and Senate during July.</summary>
</bill>
