<bill session="107" type="h" number="5687" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal Land Conveyance Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain parcels of land acquired for the Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal features of the Oahe Unit, James Division, South Dakota, to the State of South Dakota for the purpose of mitigating lost wildlife habitat, on the condition that the current preferential leaseholders shall have an option to purchase the parcels, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public schools"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water supply engineering"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/16/2002--Introduced.
Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal Land Conveyance Act of 2002 - Deauthorizes the Blunt Reservoir feature of the Oahe Irrigation Project authorized as part of the Pick-Sloan Missouri River Basin Program.Allows preferential leaseholders (original landowners or descendants, or operators of the land at the time of purchase) of parcels of the Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal an option to purchase from the Commission of Schools and Public Lands of South Dakota the land they lease. Sets terms for such purchases. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey all preferential lease parcels not purchased by the leaseholder to the South Dakota Department of Game, Fish, and Parks, to be used for mitigating the wildlife habitat that was lost as a result of the development of the Pick-Sloan project.Directs the Secretary to convey to the Department the nonpreferential leased parcels and unleased parcels of the Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal, to be used for mitigating the wildlife habitat that was lost as a result of the development of the Pick-Sloan project.Requires the Governor of South Dakota, or a designee of the Governor (the "Governor"), to accept certain conditions of conveyance, including that: (1) the State receives the land conveyed in "as is" condition; (2) the State assumes responsibility for any liabilities accruing after the date of conveyance as a result of ownership, operation or maintenance of such land; (3) the Federal Government retains all oil, gas, and mineral rights; (4) the property shall continue to be used for wildlife conservation; and (5) title shall revert to the United States if the land is needed for national defense purposes.Authorizes the Governor to allow a person to exchange other land in South Dakota for a nonpreferential lease parcel or unleased parcel at Blunt Reservoir or Pierre Canal.Permits the United States a perpetual easement for a water conveyance structure over, under, across, or through the Pierre Canal Feature.</summary>
</bill>
