<bill session="108" type="h" number="3631" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Television Viewer Privacy Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the collection, by interactive video-related service providers, of personally identifiable information regarding the viewing choices of subscribers to such services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400371"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2003--Introduced.
Television Viewer Privacy Act of 2003 - Prohibits an interactive video-related service provider (provider) from collecting, maintaining, or disclosing any personally identifiable viewing information (information) regarding a subscriber without the prior written or electronic consent of such subscriber, except: (1) to render or conduct a legitimate business activity related to the service provided; (2) pursuant to a court order authorizing disclosure to a governmental entity; or (3) to such subscriber. Requires, for such consent, that the subscriber be provided a separate statement that clearly and conspicuously informs the subscriber of: (1) the nature of the information collected and its intended use; (2) the nature, frequency, and purpose of any disclosure that may be made; (3) the period during which the information will be maintained by the provider; and (4) required limitations with respect to the collection, maintenance, and disclosure of such information by the provider and the methods by which such limitations may be enforced. Requires a provider to destroy any collected information as soon as it is no longer necessary. Provides for: (1) enforcement through the Federal Trade Commission or by the States; and (2) damages, including actual and punitive damages.</summary>
</bill>
