<bill session="104" type="h" number="3282" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Panama Canal Commission Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize expenditures for fiscal year 1997 for the operation and maintenance of the Panama Canal, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400569"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="1996-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on National Security, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" subcommittee="Postal Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Air travel"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Disability retirement"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Interoceanic canals"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Panama"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal Commission"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Prosthesis"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1996--Introduced.
Panama Canal Commission Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1997 - Authorizes the Panama Canal Commission to make expenditures as necessary for the operation, maintenance, improvement, and administration of the Panama Canal for FY 1997. Makes funds available for the purchase, and transportation to Panama, of passenger motor vehicles. Amends the Panama Canal Act of 1979 (the Act) to: (1) remove certain definitions and recommendations for legislation; (2) abolish the Office of the Ombudsman within the Commission; (3) revise provisions concerning the appointment, compensation, and duties of Commission employees; (4) make inapplicable to non-U.S.-citizen Commission employees certain Federal compensation, health, and retirement benefits; and (5) revise the travel and transportation expenses authorized for Commission employees. Directs the Commission (currently, the President and Federal agency heads, respectively) to establish a Panama Canal Employment System and Commission employment standards. Repeals provisions: (1) concerning the interim application of the Canal Zone Merit System and the authority for additional pay to employees recruited and retained for employment in the Canal Zone; (2) authorizing the purchase of artificial limbs and other appliances for Commission employees injured before September 7, 1916; (3) authorizing employee leave for jury or witness duty or services; (4) providing for the deposit of remaining Canal Zone Government funds; (5) requiring the Comptroller General to take into consideration, during Commission audits, certain conversion problems of the accounting system of the Panama Canal Company; (6) authorizing the Commission to adjust Canal Zone toll charges; (7) authorizing the President and the Commission to prescribe regulations concerning the operation and protection of the Panama Canal Zone; (8) applicable during a prior transition period; (9) authorizing appropriations for the disinterment, transportation, and reinterment in the United States of the remains of former Commission employees; and (10) providing for the compensation level of U.S. military personnel serving in a Commission position. Establishes a Central Examining Office to implement provisions relating to Commission employee recruitment, examination, and qualification standards. Provides for the applicability to the Commission of specified Federal laws. Revises provisions concerning: (1) the administration of disability benefits to former Commission employees; and (2) the establishment of, and deposit of funds into, the Panama Canal Revolving Fund. Authorizes the Commission to make direct purchase of printing and related services and to provide air transportation for Commission officials and employees. Requires: (1) the Commission to take possession and administer the funds of the Canal Zone postal service; and (2) Commission investigation of accident claims to include a hearing by the Commission's Board of Local Inspectors. Authorizes the Commission (currently, the President) to prescribe regulations governing the operation of the Canal and the navigation of adjacent waters.</summary>
</bill>
