<bill session="104" type="h" number="1954" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Park Scenic Overflight Concessions Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Park Service Concessions Policy Act to enable the Secretary of the Interior to authorize scenic commercial overflights at units of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409954"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1367"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-05">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, DOT.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Tourist trade"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/1995--Introduced.
National Park Scenic Overflight Concessions Act of 1995 - Amends the National Park Service Concessions Policy Act to prohibit a person from flying an individual for compensation over a National Park System (NPS) unit to view any portion of the unit unless the person has in effect a valid commercial air tour concession contract issued by the Secretary of the Interior. Requires the Secretary to publish guidelines applicable to commercial air tour flights over NPS units, providing for such flights where appropriate and restricting or prohibiting such flights where necessary. Authorizes the Secretary to amend the general management plan for any NPS unit to establish air concessions requirements, applicable to flights subject to the concession contract requirements of this Act, that: (1) document the degree to which commercial scenic overflights may affect the natural resources of the park unit concerned and the effects of such overflights on the park visitor's experience; and (2) propose measures necessary to protect park resources and the visitor's experience from the adverse effects of commercial scenic overflights. Imposes a fine and up to five years' imprisonment on any person who knowingly or willfully violates any requirement, rule, or regulation promulgated pursuant to this Act. Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), in cooperation with the Secretary, to develop: (1) standardized reporting systems for the documentation of low flying aircraft incidents in airspace over NPS units; and (2) training programs and instructional materials for National Park Service personnel to enable them to recognize and report such incidents. Requires the Administrator to amend FAA regulations to treat aircraft noise abatement at NPS units as in the public interest. Directs the Administrator and the Secretary to report jointly to the Congress on the progress made under this Act and other authority of law in mitigating the adverse effects of overflights at NPS units.</summary>
</bill>
