<bill session="106" type="h" number="795" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-18T14:30:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-10-18T14:30:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chippewa Cree Tribe of the Rocky Boy's Reservation Indian Reserved Water Rights Settlement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Chippewa Cree Tribe of the Rocky Boy's Reservation Indian Reserved Water Rights Settlement and Water Supply Enhancement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Chippewa Cree Tribe of the Rocky Boy's Reservation Indian Reserved Water Rights Settlement and Water Supply Enhancement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the settlement of the water rights claims of the Chippewa Cree Tribe of the Rocky Boy's Reservation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400587"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1999-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1999-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1999-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-02-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E258"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-10-12T20:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-374.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-10-12T20:22:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="217">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 217.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-10-18T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Doolittle moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-18T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10127-100131" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-18T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 795.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-10-18T14:30:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-10-18T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="438"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Droughts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Water allocation (Policy)"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water supply engineering"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/18/1999--Passed House amended.
Chippewa Cree Tribe of the Rocky Boy's Reservation Indian Reserved Water Rights Settlement and Water Supply Enhancement Act of 1999 - Provides that the Tribe, in exchange for benefits provided under this Act, shall not exercise its right to withdraw as a party to the Compact and shall release the United States from certain water rights claims and claims arising out of negotiation of the Compact and the settlement authorized by this Act. Entitles the United States to set off against any claim for damages by the Tribe certain funds transferred to it pursuant to this Act if such waiver and release do not become effective as set forth in this Act.Title I: Chippewa Cree Tribe of the Rocky Boy's Reservation Indian Reserved Water Rights Settlement - Approves and ratifies the Water Rights Compact entered into on April 14, 1997, by the Chippewa Cree Tribe of the Rocky Boy's Reservation and the State of Montana, as modified by this Act. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to execute and implement the Compact.Requires the United States, the Tribe, or the State of Montana to petition the Montana Water Court to enter and approve the proposed decree agreed to by such parties. Provides that if approval by the appropriate court does not become final within three years after the filing of the decree or the decree is approved but subsequently set aside: (1) the approval and ratification of the Compact by the United States shall be null and void; and (2) this Act shall be of no further force and effect.(Sec. 102) Directs the Secretary to administer and enforce the Tribal Water Right until the approval of a tribal water code by the Tribe. Satisfies any entitlement to Federal Indian reserved water of any tribal member solely from the water secured to the Tribe by the Compact.Authorizes the Tribe, subject to the Secretary's approval and Compact conditions, to enter into a service contract or other agreement providing for the temporary delivery, use, or transfer of water rights confirmed to the Tribe in the Compact.(Sec. 103) Directs the Secretary: (1) through the Bureau of Reclamation (Bureau), to plan, design, and construct specified water development projects on the Reservation; and (2) at the request of the Tribe, to enter into an agreement with the Tribe to carry out such activity through the Tribe's annual funding agreement entered into under the self- governance program under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act.(Sec. 104) Establishes the Chippewa Cree Indian Reserved Water Rights Settlement Trust Fund to fulfill the purposes of this Act, subject to certain restrictions on expenditures. Sets forth management and investment requirements, terms, and conditions.(Sec. 105) Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 106) Describes the State contribution to the settlement.Title II: Tiber Reservoir Allocation and Feasibility Studies Authorization - Requires the Secretary to allocate a specified amount of stored water to the Tribe without cost. Provides that such allocation shall be part of the Tribal Water Right and subject to the terms of this Act. Grants the Tribe the right to devote the water to any use within or outside the Reservation.(Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary, through the Bureau of Reclamation, to: (1) perform a municipal, rural, and industrial, domestic, and incidental drought relief feasibility study of water and related resources in North Central Montana to evaluate alternatives for a municipal, rural, and industrial supply for the Reservation; and (2) conduct a regional feasibility study to evaluate such water and related resources to determine the limitations on those resources and how those resources can best be managed to serve the needs of Montana's citizens. (Sec. 204) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
