<bill session="105" type="h" number="3461" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-11-13">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Hydroelectric Services Improvement Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Hydroelectric Services Improvement Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To approve a governing international fishery agreement between the United States and the Republic of Poland.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-12T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-12T16:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-12T16:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10594-10597" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-10-12T16:11:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-12T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-12T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-15T16:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Con. Res. 352, enrollment corrections have been made.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-21" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12943-12944" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-21">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-21">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1998-11-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-11-13">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-11-13" type="public" number="105-384">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-384.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hc" number="352"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hc" number="352"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Emblems"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Geodetic research"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hydrological forecasting"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Indian hunting and fishing rights"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International fishery management"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="North Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Ocean currents"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research ships"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Poland"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Shellfish fisheries"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tuna fisheries"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h930"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/13/1998--Public Law.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Governing International Fishery Agreement with Poland Title II: Miscellaneous Fisheries Provisions Title III: NOAA Hydrographic Services Title IV: Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Title I: Governing International Fishery Agreement with Poland - Approves the governing international fishery agreement, as contained in a presidential message to the Congress dated February 5, 1998, between the United States and the Republic of Poland. Title II: Miscellaneous Fisheries Provisions - Amends the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Act of 1995 to reauthorize the Act, add an annual congressional reporting requirement on the activities of the Fisheries Commission, the General Council, and the Scientific Council, and provide for allocating quotas under the Convention, among other changes. (Sec. 202) Reauthorizes the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975 through 2001. (Sec. 203) Authorizes the States of Washington, Oregon, and California (involved States) to adopt and enforce State laws and regulations governing fishing and processing in the adjacent exclusive economic zone in any Dungeness crab (Cancer magister) fishery for which there is no fishery management plan in effect under that Act. Sets forth requirements for State management of a Dungeness crab fishery. Prohibits enforcement of any State limited access system for such a fishery (except with regard to landings) against a vessel not registered under the State law but otherwise legally fishing in the adjacent exclusive economic zone. Permits vessels to harvest or process Dungeness crab in the exclusive economic zone adjacent to the involved State only as authorized by a permit issued by any of those States or pursuant to any tribal treaty rights to Dungeness crab pursuant to United States v. Washington. Preserves the authority of any State under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (except as expressly provided under this Act) to regulate fishing, fish processing, or landing of fish, except as expressly provided in this title. Terminates the authority of the involved States under this title with respect to a Dungeness crab fishery when a fishery management plan for the fishery under the Magnuson-Stevens Act becomes effective. Title III: NOAA Hydrographic Services - Hydrographic Services Improvement Act of 1998 - Sets forth the responsibilities and authorities of the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), including those regarding: (1) acquiring and disseminating hydrographic data; (2) promulgating hydrographic services standards; (3) ensuring comprehensive geographic coverage of hydrographic services; (4) maintaining a national hydrographic database; (5) providing hydrographic services in uniform, easily accessible formats; and (6) contracting for the acquisition of hydrographic data. (Sec. 304) Authorizes a quality assurance program, allowing certification of hydrographic products and use of a related emblem for certified products. Allows a fee for the certification and use. Establishes in the Treasury the Hydrographic Services Account, consisting of those fees, to be used for hydrographic services. Prohibits the Administrator from: (1) establishing any fee or other charge for the provision of any hydrographic service except as authorized by this title; and (2) increasing the amount of any fee or other charge for the provision of any hydrographic service except as authorized. (Sec. 305) Requires the Administrator and the Commandant of the Coast Guard to report to the Congress on implementation of real-time tide and current data systems in U.S. ports. Requires the Administrator to report to the Congress on a plan to ensure that Federal competence and expertise in hydrographic surveying will be maintained after the decommissioning of the three existing Administration hydrographic survey vessels. (Sec. 306) Authorizes appropriations to the Administrator for FY 1999 through 2001 for: (1) nautical mapping and charting; (2) hydrographic surveys; (3) geodetic functions; and (4) tide and current measurement functions. (Sec. 307) Amends the Coast and Geodetic Survey Commissioned Officers' Act of 1948 to: (1) set authorized levels of commissioned officers on NOAA's active list for FY 1999 through 2003, but allowing the Administrator to make certain reductions if appropriate; and (2) require a position to be appointed from the officers on such list serving in or above the grade of captain who shall be responsible for administration of the commissioned officers, and for oversight of the operation of NOAA's vessel fleet. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to terminate immediately the moratorium on new appointments of commissioned officers to the NOAA Corps. Title IV: Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative - Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act - Establishes the Northwest Straits Advisory Commission. (Sec. 404) Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to provide assistance for use in accordance with the Northwest Straits Citizen's Advisory Commission Report of August 20, 1998, and the priorities of the Commission, to: (1) collect marine resources data in the Northwest Straits (NS); (2) coordinate Federal, State, and local marine resources NS protection and restoration activities; and (3) carry out other activities identified in the Report as important to such protection and restoration.</summary>
</bill>
