<bill session="105" type="h" number="4129" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain parcels of land in the State of Washington from the Secretary of the Interior to the Secretary of Energy and to transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain parcels of land in the State of Washington from the Secretary of Energy to the Secretary of the Interior.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="1998-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-24">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-24">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOE, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/1998--Introduced.
Transfers administrative jurisdiction over specified lands in the State of Washington from: (1) the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management, to the Secretary of Energy; and (2) the Secretary of Energy to the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management. Withdraws such lands from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining and mineral leasing law. Sets forth: (1) reservations of such lands in connection with the Hanford project of the Department of Energy; and (2) authorities and disposal requirements under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 with respect to the lands transferred to the Secretary of Energy.</summary>
</bill>
