<bill session="108" type="h" number="4584" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Reorganize U.S. Intelligence Operations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Directing Community Integration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Security Act of 1947 to improve the organization and operation of the intelligence community, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400127" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400336" joined="2004-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Intelligence community staff"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military intelligence"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2004--Introduced.
Directing Community Integration Act - Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to require the Director of Central Intelligence (DCI) to serve as head of the U.S. intelligence community (IC) "acting through the Central Intelligence Agency" (CIA), while continuing to head the CIA and serve as principal adviser to the President for national security-related intelligence matters. (Currently, requires the DCI to serve as head of the IC, head of the CIA, and serve as principal adviser to the President for national security-related intelligence matters.) Eliminates the position of Deputy Director of Central Intelligence for Community Management. Creates eight associate directorships and five assistant directorships to assist the DCI with IC responsibilities and lists their duties. Gives certain directors overlapping CIA or cross-agency duties. Establishes the positions of General Counsel of the IC, Inspector General of the IC, and Executive Director of the CIA. Strikes a statutory provision that allows the National Security Council and the President to circumscribe the DCI's access to national security-related intelligence. Requires the DCI to prepare budgets of IC elements within the National Foreign Intelligence Program and to guide budget development for other IC elements. Removes time limits applicable to personnel transfers among IC elements. Makes the DCI responsible to the President for ensuring positive IC relationships with the intelligence or security services of foreign governments. Authorizes the DCI to exercise his or her CIA authority with respect to any IC element upon written request of the element head. Requires: (1) greater coordination between the Secretary of Defense and the DCI; and (2) the DCI's concurrence in additional agency appointments. Repeals the sunset provision applicable to limits on the establishment or operation of diplomatic intelligence support centers.</summary>
</bill>
