<bill session="107" type="h" number="5298" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Good People, Good Government Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for reform relating to Federal employee career development and benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil service system"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Manpower utilization"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in government"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in government"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2002--Introduced.
Good People, Good Government Act - Requires each executive agency to appoint or designate a Chief Human Capital Officer who shall assist in carrying out responsibilities with respect to: (1) selecting, developing, and managing a high-quality, productive workforce in accordance with merit system principles; and (2) implementing the rules and regulations and the laws governing the civil service within the agency.Requires the functions of such Officers to include: (1) setting the workforce development strategy of the agency; (2) assessing current workforce characteristics and future needs; (3) reviewing agency training and other human resources policies and programs; (4) developing and advocating a culture of continuous learning; (5) identifying best practices; and (6) applying methods for measuring intellectual capital.Establishes a Chief Human Capital Officers Council.Requires a study on the feasibility and desirability of developing human capital metrics for use by the Federal Government.Revises agency training programs to require: (1) their evaluation and modification; (2) the appointment or designation of a training officer; (3) establishment of a comprehensive program to provide training to employees to develop managers; and (4) manager training on unacceptable performance issues.Revises academic degree training criteria.Requires agencies to appoint or designate a recruitment officer.Increases the biweekly contribution payable by the Government for a Federal employee or annuitant enrolled in a Federal employee health insurance plan.Establishes alternative ranking and selection procedures for evaluating applicants for competitive service.</summary>
</bill>
