<bill session="108" type="h" number="988" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Escaped Prescribed Fire Emergency Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide compensation to individuals who are injured by an escaped prescribed fire and to amend the tort procedure provisions of title 28, United States Code, relating to claims for such fires, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Resources, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-17">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Border Security, and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2003--Introduced.
Escaped Prescribed Fire Emergency Assistance Act - Allows the head of any Federal land management agency, in the case of an escaped prescribed fire where there is partial or total loss of a primary residence, to authorize payment of reasonable emergency assistance for up to 30 days, with an additional 30 day extension in extenuating circumstances. States that such assistance shall not be construed as a waiver of rights under the Federal Tort Claims Act (FTCA). Authorizes such payments to be made from the Department of Agriculture's and the Department of the Interior's Wildfire Management Accounts.States that any action or decision taken respecting a prescribed fire shall not be considered to be the exercise of a discretionary function.Allows an individual with a claim before a Federal agency to amend it before final action is taken on it by the agency, or before the individual brings a civil action under FTCA against the United States, whichever may be later.Requires an agency to: (1) notify an individual whose claim fails to state a claim upon which the agency may take action under FTCA; and (2) attach to any claim form it distributes notice that the claim may be amended.</summary>
</bill>
