<bill session="106" type="h" number="4705" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Investment Recovery Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the recoupment of a portion of the Federal investment in research and development supporting the production and sale of pharmaceutical, biologic, or genetic products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2000-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Science, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1090"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Basic Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Basic Research" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Human genetics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2000--Introduced.
Public Investment Recovery Act of 2000 - Requires each transaction entered into by a Federal agency under which Federal support is provided for research and development which leads or may lead to the production and sale of a pharmaceutical, biologic, or genetic product to include provisions requiring that payments to recoup a portion of the agency's investment be paid annually to the Federal agency for deposit into a Public Investment Recovery Trust Fund established by this Act.Establishes a Public Investment Recovery Board to: (1) determine the total amount of profits for such a product; and (2) make calculations as required by this Act of the proportion of Federal support for research and development which lead to the production and sale of such a product. Prescribes a formula for determining the percentage of profits required to be paid.Provides for the expiration of payments on the expiration of the initial patent issued for such product.Allows: (1) not more than two percent of amounts in the Trust Fund to be used by the Food and Drug Administration or the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to support research and reports on the comparative efficiency and effectiveness of such products; (2) not more than 20 percent of amounts in the Trust Fund in the first five fiscal years after the enactment of this Act, and three percent in subsequent fiscal years, to be used to help pay the administrative expenses of carrying out this Act; and (3) not more than 20 percent of amounts in the Trust Fund to be used by NIH to support pharmaceutical, biologic, or genetic research and development, unless no Medicare prescription drug benefit has been enacted, in which case the remainder of the funds in such Fund may be used for a purpose authorized by this Act. Requires the remainder of such funds, if such a drug benefit has been enacted, to be used for the financing of such a benefit.</summary>
</bill>
