<bill session="106" type="h" number="2024" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Aviation Code-Share Safety Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require air carriers to conduct safety audits of foreign air carriers as a condition of approval of certain cooperative arrangements between the carriers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1999-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-06-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1138"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Management audit"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/1999--Introduced.
Aviation Code-Share Safety Act of 1999 - Amends Federal aviation law to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to approve a code-sharing arrangement (an arrangement whereby an air carrier's designator code is used to identify a flight operated by another carrier) between an air carrier providing air transportation of passengers and a foreign air carrier, only if: (1) the director of safety, director of operations, and director of maintenance for the air carrier each certify to the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration that an initial safety audit, (including an on- site inspection) of the foreign air carrier has been conducted under a safety audit program approved by the Administrator, and the foreign air carrier met the standards of the safety audit program; and (2) the air carrier agrees to conduct periodic safety audits (including on-site inspections) of the foreign air carrier in accordance with the safety audit program. Sets forth specified safety audit program requirements.</summary>
</bill>
