<bill session="107" type="h" number="2228" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Maritime Disaster Family Assistance Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program of assistance to families of passengers and crew members involved in maritime disasters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400159"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="2001-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="2001-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2002-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal advertising and soliciting"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2001--Introduced.
Maritime Disaster Family Assistance Act of 2001 - Amends Federal maritime law to direct the Secretary (of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, or the National Transportation Safety Board in certain instances), whenever notified of a maritime disaster within the United States involving a passenger vessel or fishing vessel operator that results in the death or disappearance of two or more individuals, to: (1) designate and publicize the name and phone number of an employee of the Coast Guard as a director of family support services to act as liaison between the operator and the families of the passengers involved in the disaster; and (2) designate an independent nonprofit organization for coordinating the emotional care and support of such families.Prohibits any person from impeding the Secretary (including the director of family support services), or a designated organization, in carrying out specified responsibilities or the ability of the families to have contact with one another.Prohibits unsolicited communications concerning a potential action for personal injury or wrongful death by an attorney or any potential party to the litigation to an individual (other than a vessel operator employee) injured in the maritime disaster, or to a relative, before the 45th day following the disaster.Prohibits a State from preventing a designated organizations' employees, agents, or volunteers from providing mental health and counseling services to the victims' families in the 30-day period beginning on the date of the disaster.</summary>
</bill>
