<bill session="104" type="hr" number="131" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To preserve the constitutional role of the House of Representatives to originate revenue measures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400106"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-05T23:27:00-04:00">
      <text>NOTICE OF INTENT - Mr. Deutsch announced his intention to offer the resolution for consideration as constituting a question of the privileges of the House with regard to certain provisions contained in the conference report on H.R. 831.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Deutsch rose to a question of the priviliges of the House and called for consideration of the resolution. The Chair ruled that the resolution did not raise a question of the privileges of the House and, therefore, was not a privileged resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Deutsch appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walker moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 230 - 192 (Roll no. 300).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Tax preferences"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/5/1995--Introduced.
Directs the Comptroller General to report to the House of Representatives the Comptroller General's opinion on whether the addition of a targeted tax benefit by the conferees to the conference report on H.R. 831 (amending the Internal Revenue Code to permanently extend the deduction for the health insurance costs of self-employed individuals and repealing the provision permitting nonrecognition of gain on sales and exchanges effectuating policies of the Federal Communications Commission) violates the requirement of the Constitution that all revenue measures originate in the House.</summary>
</bill>
