<bill session="108" type="hc" number="190" updated="2013-07-14T19:03:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-05T13:51:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-05T13:51:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a joint committee to review House and Senate rules, joint rules, and other matters assuring continuing representation and congressional operations for the American people.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2003-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400242" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400338" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2003-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T21:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Dreier asked unanimous consent That it be in order at any time without intervention of any point of order to consider H. Con. Res. 190; that it shall be considered as read for amendment; shall be debatable for one hour equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Rules; and the previous question shall be considered as ordered on the concurrent resolution to final adoption without intervening motion. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T21:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Rules. H. Rept. 108-141.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-06-04T21:31:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="58">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 58.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by a previous order of the House.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5005-5012" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T12:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated by a previous order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T13:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the concurrent resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-06-05T13:51:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5005" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and the House.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Technology and the House" name="House Rules"/>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional joint committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2003--Passed House without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on June 4, 2003. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Establishes a joint committee of the House of Representatives and the Senate (composed of 20 members) to study and review the procedures which should be adopted by the House, the Senate, and Congress to: (1) ensure congressional continuity and authority during times of crisis; (2) improve congressional procedures necessary for the enactment of measures affecting homeland security during such times; and (3) enhancing the ability of each chamber to cooperate effectively with the other body on major and consequential issues related to homeland security. Requires: (1) a majority vote of the members from each House before a recommendation by the committee can be made; and (2) any recommendation with respect to the rules and procedures of one House that only affects matters related solely to that House to only be made and voted on by members of that House and upon its adoption by a majority of such members, to be considered to have been adopted by the full committee as a recommendation of the joint committee. Requires an interim report to the Speaker of the House and the Majority Leader of the Senate by January 31, 2004, and a final report by May 31, 2004, of the results of such study and review.Terminates the committee by May 31, 2004.</summary>
</bill>
