<bill session="105" type="h" number="3261" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Privacy Protection Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to protect the integrity and confidentiality of Social Security account numbers issued under such title, and to prohibit the establishment in the Federal Government of any uniform national identifying number.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1998-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1998-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1998-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1998-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="1998-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1998-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E222-223"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/1998--Introduced.
Privacy Protection Act of 1997 (sic) - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code to prohibit any Federal, State, or local government agency or instrumentality from using a social security account number or any derivative as the means of identifying any individual, except for specified social security and tax purposes. Amends the Privacy Act of 1974 to prohibit any Federal, State, or local government agency or instrumentality from requesting an individual to disclose his social security account number on either a mandatory or a voluntary basis. Prohibits any two Federal agencies or instrumentalities from implementing the same identifying number with respect to any individual, except as authorized under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
