<bill session="108" type="h" number="3439" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">JTTF Enhancement Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote the sharing of personnel between Federal law enforcement agencies and other public law enforcement agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2003-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2213"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/4/2003--Introduced.
JTTF Enhancement Act of 2003 - Requires the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to carry out a program under which the Director maintains in appropriate U.S. regions and localities task forces of law enforcement agents to combat international terrorism. Directs that each task force be comprised of at least one FBI agent and selected Federal, State, and local law enforcement agents. Requires the Director to: (1) make available appropriate training to each participating agent; and (2) continue to reimburse the overtime pay for each participating State and local agent. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to increase the number of Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services agents available for the program. Amends the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 to authorize a program of detailing Central Intelligence Agency employees with State and local law enforcement agencies.Authorizes a detail program for State and local enforcement personnel to the Department of Justice.Directs the Attorney General to expand the Law Enforcement Support Center to ensure access for all Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies.</summary>
</bill>
