<bill session="106" type="h" number="28" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Quality Child Care for Federal Employees Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for greater access to child care services for Federal employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1999-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1999-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E13-14"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-20">
      <text>Re-referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-05-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 106-323, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 15, 1999.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-09-15T15:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="191">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 191.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Breast feeding"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Child care workers"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Mothers"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
Quality Child Care for Federal Employees Act - Directs the Administrator of General Services to: (1) establish health, safety, and facility standards and compliance requirements for child care in executive branch facilities;(2) issue regulations requiring any entity sponsoring a child care center to comply with certain accreditation standards; and (3) establish an interagency council to facilitate cooperation and sharing of best practices. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 4) Amends Federal law to revise conditions for the allotment of space for child care services for Federal employees in Federal buildings. Makes available child care and related services to children of Federal employees or on-site Federal contractors, or dependent children who live with such employees or contractors. (Currently space may be allotted for the provision of child care services to children of whom at least 50 percent have one parent or guardian who is a Federal employee.) Declares that the Administrator of General Services must confirm that at least 50 percent of aggregate enrollment in Federal child care centers governmentwide are children of Federal employees or on-site Federal contractors, or dependent children who live with such employees or contractors. States that, if enrollment at a center drops below the goal, the provider shall develop and implement a business plan with the sponsoring Federal agency to achieve the goal within a reasonable time frame. Authorizes an agency without a child care program, or the Administrator upon identifying a need for child care at a Federal agency, to enter into an agreement with an existing non-Federal, licensed, and accredited child care facility, or a planned facility that will become licensed and accredited. Permits an agency, upon the approval of the agency head, to conduct a pilot project for up to two years to test innovative approaches to providing more cost-effective alternative forms of child care assistance for Federal employees. Requires the Administrator to serve as an information clearinghouse for such pilot projects initiated by other agencies. Requires all existing and newly hired workers in any child care center located in federally owned or leased facilities to undergo a criminal history background check. Directs each agency head to require that each child care facility the agency first operates, or contracts for, at least one year after enactment of this Act provide reasonable accommodations for the needs of breast fed infants and their mothers.</summary>
</bill>
