<bill session="106" type="h" number="3685" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">USDA Civil Rights Resolution Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate the timely resolution of back-logged civil rights discrimination cases of the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400587"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2079"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Blacks in rural areas"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2000--Introduced.
USDA Civil Rights Resolution Act of 2000 - Amends the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 to provide that if a complainant seeks a determination by the Department of Agriculture on the merits of an eligible complaint (certain complaints related to alleged discrimination in violation of the Equal Credit Opportunity Act or commodity or disaster assistance programs) and the complaint is not resolved by the Department within 270 days of being investigated, the complainant may petition the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice to: (1) review the complaint; and (2) make recommendations to the Department of Agriculture to resolve the complaint. Requires the Department of Justice to conduct such review and make recommendations to resolve the complaint not later than 30 days after a petition is filed.Makes the right to review by the Department of Justice available to any complainant with a complaint that: (1) is not considered an eligible complaint under specified time criteria (eligible complaints were filed before July 1, 1997, and allege discrimination occurred between 1981 and 1996); and (2) is pending at the Office of Civil Rights of the Department of Agriculture on this Act's enactment date.Deems complainants to have exhausted administrative remedies after review is completed and authorizes the filing of actions after such time in a district court. Requires the tolling of any statute of limitations beginning on the date the complaint was filed at the Department of Agriculture and ending on date of completion of review by the Department of Justice.</summary>
</bill>
