<bill session="105" type="h" number="374" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sikes Act Improvement Amendments of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Act popularly known as the "Sikes Act" to enhance fish and wildlife conservation and natural resources management programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1997-01-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E17, E19"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on National Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Installations and Facilities.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-03">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-11">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Joint Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans and by the Subcommittee on Military Installations and Facilities.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-18">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.1119.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS04" subcommittee="Military Installations and Facilities" name="House National Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="1119"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sustainable forestry"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Sikes Act Improvement Amendments of 1997 - Amends the Act of September 15, 1960, commonly referred to as the Sikes Act, to direct (current law authorizes) the Secretary of Defense to carry out a program of wildlife, fish, and game conservation on each U.S. military installation. Requires an integrated natural resource management plan (plan) to be included in each program. Authorizes the Secretary to manage each military installation to provide: (1) for the conservation of fish and wildlife on such installation and sustained multipurpose uses of those resources; and (2) necessary or appropriate public access for those uses. Requires the plan to address the needs for fish and wildlife management, land management, forest management, and wildlife-oriented recreation. Requires an opportunity for public comment on each plan prepared. Requires the: (1) Secretaries of each military department to review and report to the Secretary on military installations under their jurisdiction for which a plan would be appropriate; and (2) Secretary to report to the Congress on such reviews. Sets a deadline for the establishment of such plans. Directs the Secretary to annually review the extent to which plans were prepared or in effect and implemented during the preceding year. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to report to specified congressional committees on funds expended on conservation activities conducted pursuant to such plans. Provides for the enforcement on military installations of all Federal laws relating to natural resources conservation on Federal lands. Requires the Secretary of each military department to ensure that sufficient numbers of trained natural resource management and law enforcement personnel are available and assigned to perform tasks necessary to ensure plan compliance. Entitles the Act of September 15, 1960, as the Sikes Act. Extends through FY 2000 the authorization of appropriations for natural resources conservation programs on military installations, as well as equivalent programs on other public lands.</summary>
</bill>
