<bill session="106" type="h" number="4358" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Omnibus District of Columbia Tax Incentive Recovery Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">District of Columbia $5,000 Homebuyer Credit Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">District of Columbia City-Wide Enterprise Zone Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">District of Columbia Economic Recovery Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">District of Columbia Nonresident Tax Credit Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to promote the economic recovery of the District of Columbia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-05-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E604-605"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Industrial development bonds"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Municipal taxation"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Imposition and Withholding of Nonresident Wage Tax Title II: Modifications to Enterprise Zone Benefits Available with Respect to the District of Columbia Title III: Limitation on Income Tax Imposed on Individuals Who Are Residents of the District of Columbia Title IV: First-Time Homebuyer Credit for District of Columbia Made Permanent Omnibus District of Columbia Tax Incentive Recovery Act of 2000 - Title I: Imposition and Withholding of Nonresident Wage Tax - District of Columbia Nonresident Tax Credit Act of 2000 - Subjects every nonresident individual employed in the District of Columbia to a tax equal to two percent of wages from employment in the District of Columbia and two percent of net earnings from self-employment in the District of Columbia, so long as there is a corresponding Federal credit, subject to exceptions. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish such a credit.Title II: Modifications to Enterprise Zone Benefits Available with Respect to the District of Columbia - District of Columbia City-Wide Enterprise Zone Act of 2000 - Designates the entire District of Columbia as the District of Columbia Enterprise Zone. Treats the entire District of Columbia as an empowerment zone.Title III: Limitation on Income Tax Imposed on Individuals Who Are Residents of the District of Columbia - District of Columbia Economic Recovery Act of 2000 - Prohibits the net tax income of District of Columbia residents from exceeding specified limits. Requires a study of the impact of such limits for District residents.Title IV: First-Time Homebuyer Credit for District of Columbia Made Permanent - District of Columbia $5,000 Homebuyer Credit Act of 2000 - Makes the first-time homebuyer credit for the District permanent.</summary>
</bill>
