<bill session="106" type="h" number="4331" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Patent Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the issuance of patents for the Generalized System of Preference (GSP) countries with a Letter of Agreement with the U.S. through a program establishing an International US\GSP Office in which the U.S. issues patents using U.S. standards that are valid under both U.S. and GSP law, to aid in creating captial for GSP countries through patents and innovation and to establish or enhance their patent system through U.S. expertise and training.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2000-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Patent agreements"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2000--Introduced.
International Patent Act of 2000 - Makes the United States Patent and Trademark Office (PTO) responsible for: (1) establishing at the PTO a special United States-Generalized System of Preference (US-GSP) country office for official notification of issuance of patents which have official status for both the U.S. and a specific GSP country law; (2) insuring that dual issuance of patents under the GSP country law be made according to U.S. standards and valid under U.S. law; and (3) insuring that all examination and search duties for the grant of U.S. letters patent and specific GSP country patents be performed by U.S. examiners who are U.S. citizens.Requires a trust fund of fifteen percent charged from fees, with a special handling fee, to be set aside in the name of a GSP country for its use in establishing or enhancing its patent system.Requires the United States, an examining and patent search country in compliance with the Patent Cooperation Treaty (PCT), to make PTO patent data base computer search facilities available, for a fee, in each GSP country.Directs the Small Business Administration to provide information to GSP countries on the steps required to create a small business based on a patent issued to an individual-small business under the US-GSP Patent Notification Office.Directs the Agency for International Development to develop a program to instruct GSP countries in the methods of structuring a patent system to enhance economic development, with the U.S. Dole-Bayh Act as a model illustrating the benefits accruing to universities from intellectual property.</summary>
</bill>
