<bill session="106" type="h" number="2743" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Farm and Ranch Emergency Assistance Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the financial situation of America's farmers and ranchers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400121"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400578" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1999-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400190" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400588" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400530" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400540" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1999-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities, Resource Conservation and Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock and Horticulture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Risk Management, Research and Specialty Crops.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG23" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Resource Conservation and Credit" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Livestock and Horticulture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG28" subcommittee="Risk Management, Research and Specialty Crops" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Fruit trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Import quotas"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Livestock industry"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Oilseeds"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Soybeans"/>
    <term name="Vegetable trade"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Market Loss Assistance for Contract Commodities Title II: Market Loss Assistance for Soybeans and Other Oilseeds Title III: Removal of Trade Sanctions Title IV: Temporary Removal of Limit on Loan Deficiency Payments and Marketing Loan Gains Title V: Upland Cotton Price Competitiveness Title VI: Market Loss Assistance for Livestock and Dairy Producers Title VII: Emergency Concessional Sales and Donations Title VIII: Conservation Reserve Title IX: Early Availability of AMTA Payments Title X: Crop Insurance Farm and Ranch Emergency Assistance Act of 1999 - Designates amounts made available by this Act as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Deficit Control Act of 1985. Title I: Market Loss Assistance for Contract Commodities - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to use specified amounts for 1999 contract commodity market loss assistance to producers under a production flexibility contract. Makes such assistance available in proportion to amounts received under a producer's flexibility contract. Title II: Market Loss Assistance For Soybeans and Other Oilseeds - Directs the Secretary to use specified amounts of Commodity Credit Corporation funds for 1999 market loss assistance to soybean and oilseed producers. Considers such assistance as payments for purposes of production flexibility contract limits. Title III: Removal of Trade Sanctions - Directs the Comptroller General to examine and report on specified aspects of trade sanctions. (Sec. 302) Prohibits the President from imposing unilateral agricultural or medical sanctions against a foreign government, with an exception for national security reasons. (Sec. 303) Directs the Secretary to make annual reports with respect to foreign sanctions and their effect on U.S. agricultural commodities. (Sec. 304) Directs the Secretary to expand agricultural export assistance to offset sanction-affected market losses. Title IV: Temporary Removal of Limit on Loan Deficiency Payments and Marketing Loan Gains - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to remove limits on marketing loan gains and loan deficiency payments for crop years 1999 and 2000. Title V: Upland Cotton Price Competitiveness - Amends the Agricultural Market Transition Act to: (1) reduce specified eligibility criteria with respect to upland cotton special marketing assistance; (2) make agricultural commodities pledged to the Corporation as loan collateral eligible for marketing certificate redemption; (3) eliminate related expenditure caps; and (4) revise special import quota provisions. Title VI: Market Loss Assistance for Livestock and Dairy Producers - Directs the Secretary to use specified Corporation funds to assist livestock and dairy producers. Title VII: Emergency Concessional Sales and Donations - Directs the Secretary to use specified Corporation funds for an emergency agricultural export concessional sales and donations program. Limits the amount of such funds available to assist fruit and vegetable producers. Title VIII: Conservation Reserve - Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary should enroll the fully authorized acreage in the conservation reserve program. Title IX: Early Availability of AMTA Payments - Amends the Agricultural Market Transition Act to authorize advance payments in full through FY 2002 under the production flexibility contract program. Title X: Crop Insurance - Directs the Secretary to use specified Corporation funds to assist producers in purchasing additional crop insurance for crop year 2000.</summary>
</bill>
