<bill session="106" type="h" number="2819" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Biomass Research and Development Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create an initiative for research and development into the utilization of biomass for fuel and industrial products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1999-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="1999-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1999-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1999-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1999-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2000-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="1999-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1999-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1999-10-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1821"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Risk Management, Research and Specialty Crops.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Basic Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Basic Research" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG28" subcommittee="Risk Management, Research and Specialty Crops" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Farm manure"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Feedstock"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grain"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Legumes"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development contracts"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Sugar"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/1999--Introduced.
Biomass Research and Development Act of 1999 - Directs the Secretaries of Energy and Agriculture (the Secretaries) to coordinate policies and procedures that promote research, development, and demonstration on the production of biobased products for ensuring full consideration of potential feed-stock resources for energy-efficient, economically competitive, and environmentally sound biobased products and assessing the environmental, economic, and social impact of the production of such products from biomass on a large scale.Requires the Secretaries to each designate a high-level officer as a point of contact from their respective Departments and provides for such points of contact to jointly: (1) assist in arranging interlaboratory, interagency, and site-specific supplemental agreements for research, development, and demonstration projects relating to biobased products; (2) administer the Biomass Research and Development Initiative (Initiative); and (3) respond in writing to each recommendation made by the Biomass Research and Development Technical Advisory Committee.(Sec. 5) Directs the Secretaries to establish a Biomass Research and Development Board to coordinate programs within and among the departments and agencies of the Federal Government to promote the use of biobased products by maximizing the benefits deriving from Federal grants, research and development agreements, and other assistance, and bringing coherence to Federal planning.(Sec. 6) Directs the Secretaries to establish a Biomass Research and Development Technical Advisory Committee (Advisory Committee) to advise the Secretaries concerning the technical focus and direction of requests for proposals issued under the Initiative and procedures for reviewing such proposals and facilitate consultations and partnerships among Federal agencies, the research community, agricultural and forestry producers, industry, consumers, and other interested groups to carry out program activities relating to the Initiative, and evaluate and perform strategic planning on such program activities. Requires the Advisory Committee to: (1) advise the points of contact respecting the Initiative and evaluate and make written recommendations to the Board to ensure that funds appropriated for the Initiative are distributed and used consistently for grants, contracts, and other financial assistance under this Act; (2) ensure that the points of contact are funding proposals that are selected on a competitive, peer-reviewed basis, as determined by an independent panel of scientific and technical peers; and (3) ensure that activities are carried out in accordance with this Act. Provides for the Advisory Committee to coordinate its activities with other Federal advisory committees working in related areas to avoid duplication of effort.(Sec. 7) Directs the Secretaries, acting through their respective points of contact and in consultation with the Board, to establish and carry out the Initiative under which competitively awarded grants, contracts, and other financial assistance are provided to, or entered into with, eligible entities to carry out research, development, and demonstration respecting biobased products. Specifies the purposes for which such grants, contracts, and other financial assistance shall be provided. Requires Federal agencies to issue regulations establishing procedures to ensure that no class of applicants has an unfair advantage in competing for an award.Requires the points of contact, after consultation with the Board, to: (1) publish annually a joint request for proposals for such grants, contracts, and other financial assistance; (2) provide a preference in such grants, contracts, and other financial assistance to consortia involving experts from multiple institutions and academic disciplines working on cross-cutting or integrative research, development, and demonstration challenges; and (3) require that such assistance be awarded competitively after the establishment of procedures that provide for scientific peer review by an independent panel of scientific and technical peers.Requires such grants, contracts, or other financial assistance to be used to conduct: (1) research and development in technologies or processes determined by the Advisory Committee to be consistent with the purposes specified under this Act; (2) research into the sustainability and long-term environmental impacts of the technologies or processes; (3) research into the economic viability (including the cost, net energy and comparative energy uses) of the technologies or processes; or (4) pilot projects of processes and technologies that lead to a better understanding of the energy or environmental impacts or performance characteristics of a biobased product. Prohibits the provision of such financial assistance for a demonstration project unless at least an equal amount of funding is obtained for such project from non-Federal sources.Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary of Energy to provide such administrative support and funds to the Board and the Advisory Committee as are necessary to enable them to carry out this Act. Declares that the Secretary of Agriculture and the heads of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the National Science Foundation, the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Department of the Interior may, and are encouraged to, provide such support and funds to the Board and the Advisory Committee.(Sec. 9) Requires the Secretaries to transmit to Congress specified initial and final reports.</summary>
</bill>
