<bill session="108" type="h" number="4882" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Controlled Substances Export Reform Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to provide authority to the Attorney General to authorize narcotic drugs in schedule I, II, III, or IV and nonnarcotic controlled substances in schedule I or II to be exported from the United States to a country for subsequent export from that country to another country, if certain conditions are met.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400320"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2004-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2004-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2004-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="2004-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="2004-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2004-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2004-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="2004-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="2004-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2004-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2004-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="2004-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1450"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="3028"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2004--Introduced.
Controlled Substances Export Reform Act of 2004 - Amends the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to authorize the Attorney General to allow any narcotic drug in schedule I, II, III, or IV or any non-narcotic controlled substance in schedule I or II (covered drug) to be exported from the United States to a country for subsequent export to another country if: (1) both the country to which the covered drug is exported from the United States (first country) and the country to which it is subsequently exported (second country) are parties to the Single Convention on Narcotic Drugs, 1961, and the Convention on Psychotropic Substances; (2) the first and second countries have each maintained an adequate system of drug import controls; (3) regarding the first country, the covered drug is consigned to a holder of such permits or licenses as required under that country's laws and a permit to import the drug has been issued; (4) regarding the second country, substantial evidence that the drug is to be consigned to a permit holder as required under that country's laws is furnished, a permit to import it is to be issued, there is an actual need for the drug, and it will not be re-exported; (5) within 30 days after export from the first country, the person who exported it from the United States certifies that re-export has occurred; and (6) the Attorney General has issued a permit to export the covered drug from the United States.</summary>
</bill>
