<bill session="104" type="h" number="292" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Price and Supply Information Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the collection and dissemination of information relating to the price and supply of home heating fuel, natural gas, and automotive fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400210"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Automobile fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Propane"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Energy Price and Supply Information Act of 1995 - Directs the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration of the Department of Energy to conduct and publish weekly surveys on a national, State, and PADD (Petroleum Administration Defense District) basis during each winter season with respect to: (1) home heating fuel; (2) natural gas; and (3) automotive fuel. Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish on such basis recommended adequate inventory levels for home heating fuel, natural gas, and automotive fuel. Requires the Secretary to: (1) notify the Congress, the President, and State energy offices before October 1 of each year whether such inventory levels will be met for the winter heating season; and (2) recommend legislative and administrative actions necessary to restore inadequate inventories if they fall below recommended levels. Requires the Secretary to study and report on the effect of interruptible natural gas contracts on the demand and supply of home heating fuel during the 1989-1990 winter heating season.</summary>
</bill>
