<bill session="104" type="hr" number="463" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-27T00:57:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-06-27T00:57:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of a joint resolution and a resolution relating to the People's Republic of China.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-06-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6847"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-06-25T23:59:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="247">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 247.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-25T23:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-636, by Mr. Solomon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-25T23:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 461 and H.J. Res. 182. Providing for the consideration in the House of H.J. Res. 182 with two hours of general debate. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration shall be waived. Pursuant to secs. 152 and 153 of the Trade Act of 1974, the previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motion. Secs. 152 and 153 of the Trade Act shall not apply to any other joint resolution disapproving the extension of most-favored-nation treatment to the People's Republic of China for the remainder of the 104th Congress. After disposition of the joint resolution, it shall be in order to consider in the House H. Res. 461, debatable for one hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-26T23:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6950-6954" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-26T23:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T00:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-06-27T00:57:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="6/26/1996 CR H6954-6963" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T00:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hr" number="461"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="hr" number="461"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="hj" number="182"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/1996--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.J. Res. 182 (most-favored-nation treatment for the People's Republic of China) and H. Res. 461 (human rights abuse, nuclear and chemical weapons proliferation, illegal weapons trading, military intimidation of Taiwan, and trade violations by the People's Republic of China).</summary>
</bill>
