<bill session="106" type="h" number="2407" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to establish certain requirements regarding the approval of facilities for the disposal of polychlorinated biphenyls, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400528"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Newspapers"/>
    <term name="Polychlorinated biphenyls"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/1999--Introduced.
Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from approving the construction of a facility for the disposal of polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs) unless the construction is in the public interest and the facility's design, location, and operation will protect public health and the environment. Allows any person to file a petition with a court of appeals for review of such approval. Applies to approval of a PCB disposal facility Solid Waste Disposal Act requirements of public notice and participation for issuance of a permit regarding a hazardous waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility. Prohibits approval of construction of a PCB disposal facility unless the owner or operator provides the Administrator (and the Administrator makes publicly available) a complete violations record.</summary>
</bill>
