<bill session="106" type="h" number="2744" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Home Health Equity Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to modify the interim payment system for home health services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400121"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400281" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="1999-10-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1310"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
Home Health Equity Act of 1999 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act and the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 to eliminate the 15 percent home health services payment reduction which would occur if the Secretary of Health and Human Services did not establish a prospective payment system (PPS) for such services as provided for in such Act.Provides for: (1) outlier payments to home health agencies (agencies) in spite of applicable per beneficiary payment limits when a provider demonstrates to the Secretary that an individual was furnished appropriate home health services at a reasonable cost that significantly exceeded such applicable per beneficiary limit because of certain conditions; and (2) recoupment of overpayments by the Secretary to agencies over a 36-month period as specified.Makes various Medicare amendments under reasonable cost provisions with regard to an increase in payment amounts to agencies with limits under the national average and an increase in the per visit limit for cost reporting periods beginning on or after October 1, 1999, with regard to the amount of payments that may be made under Medicare for services furnished by agencies.Eliminates timekeeping requirements under the prospective payment system for home health services.Provides for periodic interim payment for certain agencies under Medicare provisions regarding payment to service providers.Revises surety bond requirements for agencies.Excludes additional Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) costs from determination of the Medicare part B premium.</summary>
</bill>
