<bill session="105" type="h" number="1358" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Interstate Transportation of Municipal Solid Waste Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to permit a Governor to limit the disposal of out-of-State solid waste in the Governor's State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="404996" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1997-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1997-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400602" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400520" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="1997-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="463"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Groundwater pollution"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Landfill siting"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/1997--Introduced.
Interstate Transportation of Municipal Solid Waste Act of 1997 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize a State Governor, if requested by an affected local government, to prohibit the disposal of out-of-State municipal waste in any landfill or incinerator subject to the jurisdiction of the Governor or the local government. Exempts from a Governor's authority to prohibit the disposal of out-of-State waste: (1) landfills that received documented shipments of such waste in 1993 and are in compliance with State laws relating to design and location standards, leachate collection, groundwater monitoring, and financial assurance for closure and post-closure and corrective action; (2) proposed landfills that, prior to January 1, 1993, received an authorization as part of a host community agreement from the affected local government to receive municipal waste generated out-of-State and a State notice of decision to grant a construction permit; or (3) incinerators that received documented shipments of such waste during 1993 and are in compliance with performance standards under the Clean Air Act and State laws relating to facility design and operations. Permits Governors, without the request of affected local governments, to limit the quantity of out-of-State municipal waste received for disposal at landfills covered by exceptions under this Act as follows: (1) for each landfill, to an annual quantity equal to that received for disposal at the landfill during 1993; and (2) for the State, 95 percent of the quantity received by the State during the previous calendar year for 1997 through 2003 and 65 percent of the quantity received during 1993 for 2004 and succeeding years. Sets annual quantity limitations on the export of municipal solid waste by a State to landfills or incinerators in another State that are not covered by host community agreements or permits authorizing receipt. Prohibits discrimination against any particular landfill and against shipments of out-of-State waste on the basis of State of origin. Authorizes States to deny permits for the construction or operation of a new landfill or incinerator or a major modification of an existing landfill or incinerator if: (1) the State has approved a State or local comprehensive solid waste management plan developed under Federal or State law; and (2) the denial is based on the State's determination that there is not a local or regional need for the landfill or incinerator in the State. Allows States not exercising such permit denial authority to require that a permit issued for a new landfill or incinerator or an expansion include an annual limitation of not less than 20 percent on the total quantity of out-of-State municipal solid waste relative to the total waste received by the facility. Allows a facility with specific authorization to receive a specific quantity of out-of-State waste pursuant to a host community agreement entered into prior to enactment of this Act to receive that quantity, notwithstanding the foregoing State requirement.</summary>
</bill>
