<bill session="108" type="h" number="2889" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Atlantic Striped Bass Protection Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Commerce to conduct a study of existing and new fishery observer data to effectively map migratory patterns, delineate wintering areas and feeding grounds of Atlantic Striped Bass in the Mid-Atlantic exclusive economic zone, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2003-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2004-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="2004-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-08-08">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Fish kills"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2003--Introduced.
Atlantic Striped Bass Protection Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to study and report to Congress on data gathered by observers on fishing vessels to: (1) map migratory patterns, wintering areas, and feeding grounds of Atlantic Striped Bass in the waters of the Mid-Atlantic exclusive economic zone; and (2) identify and map locations in which deployed gear caught or discarded Atlantic Striped Bass in excess of ten percent of the target species landed on the same trip. Requires the Secretary, based on study findings, to promulgate regulations under the Atlantic Striped Bass Conservation Act that establish conservation and management measures to minimize the bycatch and mortality of bycatch of Atlantic Striped Bass caught in non-directed commercial fishing in the Mid-Atlantic exclusive economic zone. Requires such regulations to include temporary closure of any identified location in which there is a particularly high level of Atlantic Striped Bass in non-directed commercial fishing, under which the deployment of net, finfish trap, or longline gear by any vessel fishing under a Federal fishing permit shall be prohibited.</summary>
</bill>
