<bill session="106" type="h" number="4846" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-11-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Recording Preservation Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Recording Preservation Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">National Recording Preservation Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the National Recording Registry in the Library of Congress to maintain and preserve recordings that are culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">A bill to establish the National Recording Registry in the Library of Congress to maintain and preserve sound recordings and collections of sound recordings that are culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400549" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400202" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2000-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ney moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H6846-6851" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4846.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-07-25T14:47:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H6846-6849" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25T14:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="781">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 781.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-10-25">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10953" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-10-25" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-01T14:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11739" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-01T14:16:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendments Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11739" label="text as House disagree to Senate amendment"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-01T14:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-01">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House disagrees to Senate amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-01">
      <text>Senate receded from its amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S11501" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11501" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-11-01">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-11-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-11-09">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-11-09" type="public" number="106-474">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-474.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal incorporation"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Phonorecords"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4341"/>
    <amendment number="s4342"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/9/2000--Public Law.
National Recording Preservation Act of 2000 - Title I: Sound Recording Preservation by the library of Congress - Subtitle A: National Recording Registry - Requires the Librarian of congress to: (1) establish the National Recording Registry for the purpose of maintaining and preserving sound recordings that are culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant; (2) establish criteria and procedures under which sound recordings may be included in the Registry, except that no sound recording shall be eligible for such inclusion until ten years after its creation; (3) establish procedures for general public recommendations to the National Recording Preservation Board (established under this Act) regarding the inclusion of sound recordings in the Registry; and (4) determine which sound recordings meet the established criteria and select them for inclusion, up to a maximum of 25 sound recordings or groups of sound recordings each year.(Sec. 103) Requires the Librarian to provide a seal to indicate that a selected sound recording has been included in the Registry and is the Registry version of that recording. Requires the Librarian to establish guidelines for approval of the use of the seal. Specifies prohibited uses, as well as remedies for violation of such prohibitions, including a civil fine and injunctive relief.(Sec. 104) Requires copies of such sound recordings on the Registry received under this Act to be maintained in the Library of Congress as the National Recording Registry Collection of the Library of Congress. Limits preservation to only one copy of the same version or take of any recording. Requires the Librarian to provide for reasonable access to the sound recordings and other materials in the collection for scholarly and research purposes.Subtitle B: National Sound Recording Preservation Program - Requires the Librarian to: (1) implement a comprehensive national recording preservation program, in conjunction with other recording archivists, educators and historians, copyright owners, recording industry representatives, and others involved in activities related to recording preservation, and taking into account studies conducted by the Board; (2) use the National Audio-Visual Conservation Center of the Library at Culpeper, Virginia, to ensure proper storage of preserved sound recordings; and (3) carry out activities to make sound recordings more accessible for research and educational purposes, and to generate public awareness and support of the Registry and such program.Subtitle C: National Recording Preservation Board - Requires the Librarian to establish in the Library of Congress a National Recording Preservation Board to: (1) review nominations of sound recordings for inclusion in the Registry; and (2) advise the Librarian with respect to the inclusion and the preservation of these and other sound recordings that are culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant.(Sec. 124) Requires the Board to study and report on the current state of Library of Congress sound recording archiving, preservation, and restoration activities, taking into account the research and other activities carried out by or on behalf of the National Audio-Visual Conservation Center.Subtitle D: General Provisions - Authorizes appropriations.Title II: National Recording Preservation Foundation - Grants a Federal charter to the National Recording Preservation Foundation (a charitable and nonprofit corporation that is not a Federal Government agency or establishment).(Sec. 201) Authorizes the Librarian to: (1) provide, on a reimbursable basis, personnel, facilities, and other administrative services to the corporation; and (2) accept the services of the corporation and its directors, officers, and employees as volunteers in performing functions authorized under this Act, without compensation from the Library of Congress.Authorizes appropriations in an amount equal to private donations to the corporation, for reimbursement of the Library for such personnel, facilities, and other administrative services. Bars the use of such funds for the corporation's own administrative expenses, including salaries, travel, transportation, and overhead expenses.</summary>
</bill>
