<bill session="108" type="h" number="3511" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Video Programming Consumer Privacy Protection Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require vendors of multichannel services to protect the privacy of their customers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2325-2326"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication satellites"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Radio"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Television relay systems"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2003--Introduced.
Video Programming Consumer Privacy Protection Act of 2003 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require a multichannel service vendor (a multichannel video programming distributor or person that has access to video programming viewing information) (vendor), at the time of entering into a service agreement with a subscriber and at least once a year thereafter, to provide written notice to such subscriber concerning: (1) the nature of personally identifiable information (information) collected with respect to the subscriber; (2) the nature of any disclosure of such information; (3) the period during which such information will be maintained by the vendor; (4) the time and place at which the subscriber may have access to such information; and (5) limitations with regard to the vendor collection and disclosure of such information and the right of the subscriber to enforce such limitations. Prohibits any vendor from collecting or disclosing such information without the prior written or electronic consent of the subscriber, with certain business-related exceptions. Requires a vendor to provide subscriber access to all collected information, and to destroy information no longer necessary. Provides civil remedies for violations, including actual and punitive damages.</summary>
</bill>
