<bill session="107" type="hr" number="469" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the recent escalation within many participating states of the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe of anti-Semitic violence, as well as manifestations of xenophobia and discrimination directed against ethnic and religious minorities, is of grave concern and requires the highest attention of all OSCE governments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2002-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2002-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2002-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2002-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2002-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2002-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2002-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Antisemitism"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Gypsies"/>
    <term name="Hate crimes"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Jews"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Racism"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2002--Introduced.
Calls for the governments of all participating states of the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) to: (1) condemn racial and ethnic hatred, anti-Semitism, xenophobia, and discrimination, as well as religious and ideological persecution, and to make public statements recognizing violence against Jews and Jewish cultural sites as anti-Semitic; (2) decry the rationalizing of anti-Jewish attitudes and violence as merely a result of justified popular frustration with the conflict in the Middle East; (3) ensure effective local and national law enforcement, including thorough investigation and prosecution of criminal acts stemming from anti-Semitism, xenophobia, or discrimination; (4) protect individuals from acts of violence based on ethnic, linguistic, racial, or religious reasons; (5) ensure that laws and policies fully respect the rights of Roma and to promote antidiscrimination legislation to this effect; (6) ensure that minority religious communities are able to realize rights and benefits on the basis of full equality; and (7) cultivate an atmosphere of cooperation and reconciliation among the diverse parties affected by discrimination in Europe.Calls on executive branch officials and Members of Congress to raise such matters in their bilateral contacts with OSCE participating states and in appropriate multilateral fora, including OSCE's Permanent Council and the July 2002 Eleventh Annual Session of the OSCE Parliamentary Assembly.</summary>
</bill>
