<bill session="105" type="h" number="4260" updated="2012-11-01T22:49:19-05:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Pension Limitation and Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to limit the number of years a Member of Congress may participate in the Civil Service Retirement System or the Federal Employees' Retirement System, to deny Federal retirement benefits to any Member convicted of a felony, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410136"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Civil Service"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional pensions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Pardons"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>07/16/1998--Introduced.
Congressional Pension Limitation and Reform Act - Amends Federal civil service law to limit to 12 years (with certain exceptions) the number of years that a Member of Congress may participate in either the Civil Service Retirement System or the Federal Employees' Retirement System. Prohibits an individual or his or her survivor or beneficiary from being paid annuity or retired pay on the basis of the individual's creditable service if the individual is convicted of an act or ommission: (1) which is a felony under Federal or State law; (2) committed while the individual is a Member of Congress; (3) which occurs in connection with the individual's service as a Member of Congress; and (4) which occurs after the enactment of this Act. Applies the same prohibition to such an individual who: (1) is under indictment after the enactment of this Act for such offense; or (2) willfully remains outside the United States or its territories and possessions for more than one year with knowledge of the indictment or charge. Prohibits interest from being computed on an individual's refund of contributions and deposits paid toward annuity or retired pay if such individual was convicted of such an offense in this Act for the period after the conviction. Authorizes, under specified conditions, the restoration of such annuity or retired pay if the individual is pardoned by the Governor in the case of a felony under State law.</summary>
</bill>
