<bill session="105" type="h" number="2592" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-08-03T13:11:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-08-03T13:11:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Private Trustee Reform Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Private Trustee Reform Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 11 of the United States Code to provide private trustees the right to seek judicial review of United States trustee actions related to trustee expenses and trustee removal.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="408476" joined="1997-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1998-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="1998-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-07-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-07-31T15:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 105-663.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-07-31T15:46:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="370">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 370.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T13:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gekas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T13:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6901-6903" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T13:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-08-03T13:11:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Oversight and Courts.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Oversight and the Courts" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Expense accounts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/1998--Passed House amended.
Private Trustee Reform Act of 1998 - Amends the Federal judicial code to allow a United States trustee whose appointment to a panel or as a standing trustee is terminated or who ceases to be assigned to cases filed under title 11 of the United States Code (bankruptcy provisions) to obtain judicial review of the final agency decision by commencing an action in U.S. district court for the district in which the panel member or standing trustee resides, after exhausting all available administrative remedies which, if the trustee so elects, shall also include an administrative hearing on the record. Deems the trustee to have exhausted such remedies, unless the trustee elects to have an administrative hearing on the record, if the agency fails to make a final agency decision within 90 days after the trustee requests administrative remedies. Authorizes a standing trustee to obtain judicial review of final agency action to deny a claim of actual, necessary expenses by commencing an action in U.S. district court in the district where the individual resides. Directs the Attorney General to prescribe procedures to implement such provisions. Requires: (1) the district court, in conducting judicial review under this Act, to determine whether to retain the case or to refer the case to a bankruptcy judge in the district; (2) a bankruptcy judge to whom a case is referred to submit a recommendation for disposition to the district court based solely on a review of the administrative record before the agency; (3) a final order or judgment to be entered by the court after considering the bankruptcy judge's recommendation and after reviewing those matters to which any party has timely and specifically objected; and (4) the agency decision to be affirmed unless it is unreasonable and without cause based upon the administrative record before the agency. Grants the U.S. district courts jurisdiction to review final agency decisions and actions pursuant to this Act. Authorizes bankruptcy judges to submit recommendations to such courts.</summary>
</bill>
