<bill session="107" type="h" number="3121" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">High Plains Groundwater Resource Conservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To further continued economic viability in the communities on the High Plains by promoting sustainable groundwater management of the Ogallala Aquifer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2001-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2001-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-05">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Rural Development and Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Credit, Rural Development, and Research" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aquifers"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Dry farming"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Great Plains"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/2001--Introduced.
High Plains Groundwater Resource Conservation Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary), through the U.S. Geological Survey and in cooperation with the State Geologists of the High Plains Aquifer States (Colorado, Kansas, Nebraska, New Mexico, Oklahoma, South Dakota, Texas, and Wyoming), to develop and carry out a hydrogeologic mapping, modeling, and monitoring program for the High Plains Aquifer.Requires the Secretary to establish a High Plains Aquifer Coordination Council to: (1) ensure that mapping, modeling, and monitoring efforts relating to the Aquifer are in place to provide information on the water resources of the Aquifer, including sustainability; (2) facilitate coordination of Federal, State, and local programs relating to the groundwater resources of the Aquifer; (3) evaluate the effectiveness of Federal and State programs in addressing present and anticipated groundwater resources issues relating to the Aquifer; and (4) provide recommendations to the Secretary, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Governors of such States regarding programs, policies, and changes in Federal and State law to address such resources issues of the Aquifer.Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture in FY 2003 through 2012 to provide cost-share payments, incentive payments, and technical assistance to eligible producers (persons who are engaged in livestock or agricultural production) who enter into contracts with the Secretary through a High Plains Aquifer Ground Water Conservation Incentives Program. Directs the Commodity Credit Corporation to make available specified amounts in FY 2003 through 2012 to carry out such Program.Requires that lands eligible for the Environmental Conservation Acreage Reserve Program which would result in significant per acre savings of groundwater resources of the Aquifer if removed from agriculture production to be awarded 90 Program bid points, to be designated as groundwater conservation points, in addition to any other ratings such lands may receive.Requires such Secretary to prepare a report regarding the impacts of the commodity programs administered by the Department of Agriculture on the water resources of the Aquifer.Requires the Secretary to provide financial assistance to the eight High Plains Aquifer States to provide educational programs related to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
