<bill session="106" type="h" number="3186" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Telecommunications Merger Review Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restrict the authority of the Federal Communications Commission to review mergers and to impose conditions on licenses and other authorizations assigned or transferred in the course of mergers or other transactions subject to review by the Department of Justice or the Federal Trade Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1999-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-01">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-01">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1125"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Amateur radio stations"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/1999--Introduced.
Telecommunications Merger Review Act of 1999 - Amends the Clayton Act to repeal the authority of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to approve telecommunications industry mergers.Amends the Communications Act of 1934 (the Act) to mandate that the FCC has no authority to review a merger or other transaction (merger), or to impose any term or condition on the assignment or transfer of any license or other authorization (license) issued under the Act that is proposed to be assigned or transferred in the course of a merger, while that merger is subject to review by either the Department of Justice (DOJ) or the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). Empowers DOJ and FTC with primary authority to review mergers involving the proposed assignment or transfer of any license issued under the Act. Authorizes the FCC to file comments in any such proceeding.States that, if DOJ or FTC reviews a merger and issues either a written decision of approval or a written statement of nonintervention in such merger, then the FCC shall authorize the assignment or transfer of any license involved therein. Prohibits the FCC from imposing any other term or condition on the assignment or transfer of such license, or imposing any other obligation on any party to such merger.Prohibits the FCC from reviewing any application for assignment or transfer of a license issued under the Act in connection with a merger unless neither DOJ nor the FTC issues a decision or statement in connection with such merger. Requires the FCC to conclude any review so conducted within 60 days after DOJ or FTC issues such a decision or statement.</summary>
</bill>
