<bill session="104" type="h" number="2751" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Employee Separation Incentive and Reemployment Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide temporary authority for the payment of retirement and separation incentives, to provide reemployment assistance to Federal employees who are separated as a result of workforce reductions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400435"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="1996-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1996-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1996-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="1996-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1995-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1996-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1995-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1995-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1995-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1995-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1995-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11350"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Dismissal wage"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employment subsidies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government employees' life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Relocation of employees"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: General Provisions Title II: Voluntary Separation Incentives Title III: Reemployment Assistance Programs Title IV: Extension of Benefits Federal Employee Separation Incentive and Reemployment Assistance Act - Title I: General Provisions - Sets forth conditions for Federal employees to receive an incentive payment under this Act pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management. (Sec. 104) Authorizes the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts to make incentive payments available to individuals serving in the judicial branch. (Sec. 105) Exempts certain boards, commissions, councils, committees, or similar groups established to carry out certain activities under this Act from a specified proscription against interagency financing of groups which do not have a prior and specific statutory approval to receive financial support from more than one agency or instrumentality. Title II: Voluntary Separation Incentives - Sets forth parameters for Federal employee incentive payments which differ on the basis of one's eligibility for immediate retirement. Requires repayment of such incentive payments by retirees upon any subsequent Federal employment, unless repayment is waived by the appropriate authority. Amends the Federal Workforce Restructuring Act of 1994 to provide for employee backfill prevention. Title III: Reemployment Assistance Programs - Amends Federal civil service law to direct the Office of Management and Budget to establish a Government-wide priority placement program, and each agency to establish an agency-wide priority placement program for employees separated or scheduled to be separated from Federal employment by a reduction in force. (Sec. 302) Authorizes the head of an agency to: (1) pay retraining and relocation incentives according to prescribed guidelines in order to facilitate the reemployment by non-Federal employers of eligible employees who are separated from the agency; and (2) establish a job placement and counseling services program for current and former employees and their families. Title IV: Extension of Benefits - Amends Federal civil service law to provide for continuation of life and health insurance benefits for Federal employees separated from Federal employment under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
