<bill session="105" type="h" number="3849" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Internet Tax Freedom bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Internet Tax Freedom Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Internet Tax Freedom Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to establish a national policy against Federal and State regulation of Internet access and online services, and to exercise congressional jurisdiction over interstate and foreign commerce by establishing a moratorium on the imposition of exactions that would interfere with the free flow of commerce conducted over the Internet, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400139" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="411550" joined="1998-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-05-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 41 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-05T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Commerce. H. Rept. 105-570, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-05T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Ways and Means Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 19, 1998.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-05T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 19, 1998.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-05T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Rules Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 19, 1998.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-06-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-06-19T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 105-570, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-19T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Ways and Means Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 26, 1998.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-19T17:41:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Rules Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 26, 1998.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-25T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-25T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Rules discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-06-25T12:45:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="339">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 339.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-07-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1288"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="4105"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="442"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="442"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Internet service providers"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Price regulation"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Telephone rates"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/1998--Reported to House amended, Part II.
Internet Tax Freedom Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 (the Act) to prohibit the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) or any State commission from having regulatory authority or jurisdiction with respect to charges paid by subscribers for Internet access or online services (IAOs). Preserves FCC authority and the State commission's authority to: (1) implement the Telecommunications Act of 1996 or the amendments made by such Act; and (2) regulate common carriers that offer IAOs in conjunction with the provision of any telephone toll, telephone exchange, or exchange access services as such terms are defined in title I of the Act. (Sec. 3) Exempts IAOs providers from Federal regulatory fees. Requires the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to determine whether any direct or indirect Federal regulatory fees, other than the fees identified under the Act, are imposed on IAOs providers, and if so, make recommendations to the Congress regarding whether such fees should be modified or eliminated. (Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with appropriate congressional committees, to examine: (1) barriers imposed in foreign markets on U.S. providers of property, goods, services, or information engaged in electronic commerce and on U.S. providers of telecommunications services; (2) how the imposition of such barriers will affect U.S. consumers, the competitiveness of U.S. citizens providing property, goods, service, or information in foreign markets, and the growth and maturing of the Internet; and (3) what measures the Government should pursue to foster, promote, and develop electronic commerce in the United States and in foreign markets. Directs: (1) the Secretary to report to the President on the results of the examination; and (2) the President to review the report and submit to appropriate congressional committees such policy recommendations as the President deems necessary or expedient. (Sec. 5) Provides for the expedited congressional consideration of legislative recommendations. (Sec. 6) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the President should seek bilateral and multilateral agreements through various international organizations to require that the provision of IAOs be free from undue and discriminatory regulation by foreign governments and that electronic commercial transactions between United States and foreign providers of property, goods, services, and information be free from undue and discriminatory regulation, international tariffs, and discriminatory taxation.</summary>
</bill>
