<bill session="105" type="hc" number="237" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Voicing concern about the serious limitations on human rights and civil liberties in Belarus, including lack of compliance with Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) commitments, and urging the President to take these into consideration in his determination of most-favored-nation (MFN) status for Belarus.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1998-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1998-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1998-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1998-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1998-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1998-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1998-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Belarus"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/1998--Introduced.
Declares that the Congress: (1) voices its concern about the current limitations on human rights and civil liberties in Belarus, and calls upon its government to follow the principles embodied in the 1994 constitution and abide by its commitments under the Helsinki Final Act (including subsequent agreements of the Organization on Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) and other international commitments); (2) urges the Belarusian President to restore the rights of the Supreme Soviet; (3) urges the President, the Secretary of State, the U.S. Embassy in Miensk, and the U.S. missions to the United Nations and the OSCE to utilize every opportunity to encourage the Government of Belarus to respect its international human rights commitments, including OSCE principles and norms; (4) welcomes the work of the OSCE Advisory and Monitoring Group in assisting in the development of democratic institutions in Belarus; and (5) urges the President not to renew the extension of nondiscriminatory treatment (most-favored-nation treatment) to the products of Belarus if there is not sufficient improvement in its human rights record.</summary>
</bill>
