<bill session="106" type="h" number="5311" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Heather French Homeless Veterans Assistance Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve programs for homeless veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2000-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2000-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2000-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400600" joined="2000-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2000-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2000-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1611-1612"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism treatment"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congregate housing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuum of care"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug addiction"/>
    <term name="Drug addicts"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to substance abuse programs"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Homeless veterans"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing codes"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Interagency Council on the Homeless"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mentally ill"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Occupational therapy"/>
    <term name="Patient satisfaction"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Prefabricated buildings"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soldiers' homes"/>
    <term name="Terminally ill"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women veterans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2000--Introduced.
Heather French Homeless Veterans Assistance Act of 2000 - Declares as a national goal to end homelessness among veterans within a decade. Encourages all Federal, State, and local departments and agencies, quasi-governmental organizations, private and public sector entities, and individuals to work cooperatively toward such goal.(Sec. 4) Establishes within the Department of Veterans Affairs the Advisory Committee on Homeless Veterans to: (1) assemble and review information relating to homeless veterans; (2) provide an ongoing assessment of Department effectiveness in assisting such veterans; and (3) provide ongoing advice on the most appropriate means of providing such assistance. Requires the Committee to take into special account the needs of veterans who have served in a theater of combat operations. Requires annual reports from the Committee to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and from the Secretary to the congressional veterans' committees, on Department programs and activities relating to homeless veterans.(Sec. 5) Amends the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act to require the Interagency Council on the Homeless to meet no less often than annually (currently, at the discretion of the Council Chairperson).(Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to support the continuation within the Department of at least one center for evaluation to monitor the structure, process, and outcome of Department programs that address homeless veterans. Requires an annual report from the Secretary to Congress.(Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to designate specified care provided in, or sponsored or coordinated by, the Department as being within the "complex care" category within the Veterans Equitable Resource Allocation (VERA) system. Requires the Secretary to ensure that funds for any new program for homeless veterans carried out through a Department facility are designated, for the first three years of that program, as a special purpose program for which funds are not allocated through the VERA system.(Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary to carry out a program of grants to Department health care facilities to encourage the development of programs targeted at meeting the special needs of homeless veterans (age, substance abuse, post-traumatic stress disorder, terminally or mentally ill, or women). Requires the Secretary to conduct a study of the effectiveness of the grant program in meeting such needs. Provides funding from annual appropriations for Department medical care.(Sec. 9) Requires the Secretary to have appropriate officials of the Mental Health Service and the Readjustment Counseling Service of the Veterans Health Administration initiate a coordinated strategy for joint outreach to veterans at risk of homelessness, particularly those being discharged from institutions.(Sec. 10) Requires the Secretary to establish three Centers of Excellence in Integrated Mental Health Services Delivery at appropriate Department medical centers. Directs the Secretary to: (1) compare treatment outcomes for chronically mentally ill veterans at such centers with treatment outcomes provided through traditional consultation; and (2) report comparison results to Congress.(Sec. 11) Prescribes conditions under which outpatient dental services and the treatment of a dental condition or disability of a veteran shall be considered medically necessary, and therefore required to be furnished through the Department. Makes eligible for such care veterans who are: (1) enrolled under the Department's patient enrollment system; and (2) receiving care under one of a number of various departmental settings (domiciliary care, therapeutic residential or community residential care).(Sec. 12) Directs the Secretary to carry out the transitional housing grant program under the Homeless Veterans Comprehensive Service Programs Act of 1992 so as to ensure that there is at least one active transitional housing program in each State. Requires the Secretary to establish centers for the provision of comprehensive services to homeless veterans in at least each of the 20 largest metropolitan areas. Repeals a provision limiting the number of such programs. Requires the Secretary to ensure that opioid substitution therapy is available at each Department medical center. Extends through December 31, 2006, the authority of the Secretary to provide certain treatment and rehabilitation for seriously mentally ill and homeless veterans.(Sec. 13) Authorizes the Secretary to allow homeless veterans receiving care through vocational rehabilitation programs to participate in the compensated work therapy program, and to allow veterans in the latter program to be provided housing through the therapeutic residence program. Provides certain staffing requirements for homeless veterans programs within the Veterans Benefits Administration.(Sec. 14) Amends the Homeless Veterans Comprehensive Service Programs Act of 1992 to revise fire and safety standards required of facilities used for homeless veterans.(Sec. 15) Directs the Secretary to carry out a program of temporary assistance grants to homeless veterans. Makes eligible for such program veterans: (1) of a period of war or meeting certain minimum service requirements; (2) being or recently having been released from certain institutions, including a homeless shelter; (3) who are homeless immediately before the commencement of such assistance; and (4) who had less than marginal income (below poverty level) for the previous three months. Allows such assistance for no more than six months during any two-year period. Provides authorized grant amounts and requires assistance coordination with other Department benefits.(Sec. 16) Directs the Secretary to carry out a program to provide emergency housing grants to eligible veterans. Outlines eligibility requirements similar to the above program. Provides authorized grant amounts and allows a grant to an eligible veteran once during a 24-month period.(Sec. 17) Requires the Secretary to carry out a program to make technical assistance grants to nonprofit community-based groups for assistance in applying for grants to address problems of homeless veterans. Provides funding.(Sec. 18) Authorizes the Secretary to waive, with respect to homeless veterans, the requirement of the purchase of a lot under the Department's home loan program for manufactured housing.(Sec. 19) Extends through FY 2006 the authorization of appropriations for the homeless veterans reintegration program.</summary>
</bill>
