<bill session="104" type="h" number="4268" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Telemedicine and Medical Informatics Demonstration Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a project to demonstrate the application of telemedicine and medical informatics to improving the quality and cost-effectiveness in the delivery of health care serivces under the Medicare program and other health programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1996-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban problems"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Introduced.
Medicare Telemedicine and Medical Informatics Demonstration Act of 1996 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, through the Agency for Health Care Policy and Research, to make a grant to a consortium meeting specified criteria to provide for a project for the development and operation of telemedicine and medical informatics systems to demonstrate the application of high-capacity computing and advanced networks to the provision of health care to residents of medically underserved rural and inner-city areas. Requires the project to focus on Medicare beneficiaries and on improvements in primary care (and prevention of complications) for residents with diabetes (mellitus). Lists project objectives, which include improving patient access to and compliance with appropriate care guidelines for chronic diseases through direct telecommunications link with information networks in order to improve patient quality-of-life and reduce overall health care costs. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
