<bill session="104" type="h" number="20" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Risk Management Improvement and Derivatives Oversight Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Derivatives Dealer Self-Regulation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a framework to improve risk management techniques at financial institutions, including the prudential use of derivative products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Risk Management and Specialty Crops.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG24" subcommittee="Risk Management and Specialty Crops" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Bank management"/>
    <term name="Bank marketing"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Bank reserves"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Burglary"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Derivative securities"/>
    <term name="Embezzlement"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Extortion"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International banking"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Perjury"/>
    <term name="Professional associations"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Robbery"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Federal Derivatives Commission Title II: Supervisory Improvements Title III: Financial Institution Insolvency Reforms Title IV: Derivatives Dealer Self-Regulation Title V: Miscellaneous Risk Management Improvement and Derivatives Oversight Act of 1995 - Title I: Federal Derivatives Commission - Establishes the Federal Derivatives Commission to establish principles and standards to improve risk management techniques and the prudent use of derivative financial instruments by financial institutions. (Sec. 105) Directs the Commission to develop training programs in risk management techniques and derivatives activities for Federal and State regulatory personnel. (Sec. 108) Directs the Commission to establish a liaison committee to encourage the application of uniform examination standards by State and Federal supervisory agencies. (Sec. 110) Directs the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Federal Reserve Board) to encourage governments, central banks, and regulatory authorities of other countries to work toward adopting and maintaining certain supervisory and capital standards for financial institutions engaged in derivatives activities. (Sec. 111) Mandates that insured credit unions be supervised for purposes of derivatives activities by the National Credit Union Administration under standards no less stringent than those for Federal depository institutions. Title II: Supervisory Improvements - States that failure of an institution-affiliated party engaged in derivatives activities to have adequate technical expertise may be deemed by a Federal regulatory agency to constitute an unsafe or unsound banking practice. (Sec. 203) Amends the International Banking Act of 1978 to include as a prerequisite for approval of a foreign bank office in the United States that its derivatives activities are subject to comprehensive regulation in its home country. (Sec. 204) Mandates that the Federal financial institution regulatory agencies develop the means to obtain all necessary information relating to derivatives activities (or any class of derivative financial instruments) whenever an appropriate regulatory agency determines that the information is necessary as a result of adverse market conditions or other emergency situations. Title III: Financial Institution Insolvency Reforms - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and Federal bankruptcy law to include derivative financial instruments within the definition of "swap agreement" (thereby bringing such instruments within the parameters of their conservatorship and bankruptcy guidelines). (Sec. 302) Authorizes the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation to prescribe expanded recordkeeping requirements for qualified financial contracts (including market valuations) by insured depository institutions. Title IV: Derivatives Dealer Self-Regulation - Derivatives Dealer Self-Regulation Act of 1995 - Authorizes the Federal Reserve Board to mandate the establishment of a self-regulatory system for the supervision of derivatives dealers (a national derivatives association). Prescribes implementation guidelines. Mandates membership in such association as a prerequisite to any transaction by a derivatives dealer relating to a derivative financial instrument. Sets forth criminal penalties for violations of this Act. Authorizes the Board to: (1) modify association rules; (2) impose sanctions upon the association; and (3) expel members and remove its officers. Title V: Miscellaneous - Sets forth savings provisions.</summary>
</bill>
