<bill session="108" type="h" number="4504" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-05T16:26:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-05T16:26:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Orderly and Timely Interstate Placement of Foster Children Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Safe and Timely Interstate Placement of Foster Children Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve protections for children and to hold States accountable for the orderly and timely placement of children across State lines, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To improve protections for children and to hold States accountable for the safe and timely placement of children across State lines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400104"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400060" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="2004-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Herger moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8094-8100" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4504.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-10-05T16:26:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8094-8096" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05T16:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05T16:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="2779"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/2004--Passed House amended.
Safe and Timely Interstate Placement of Foster Children Act of 2004 - (Sec. 2) Expresses the sense of Congress that States should revise the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children. (Sec. 3) Amends the Social Security Act to require each State to: (1) have in effect procedures for orderly and timely placement of children, in foster care or for adoption, across State lines; and (2) complete home studies for such purpose within 60 days of another State's request. (Sec. 4) Requires each State to complete home studies for such child placement purposes within 60 days of another State's request. Expresses the sense of Congress that States should use private agencies to conduct home studies and give full faith and credit to other States' home study reports. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make incentive grants to States that complete timely interstate home studies. (Sec. 5) Revises requirements for completing background checks before placement approval and for checking of child abuse registries. Suspends and subsequently eliminates an opt-out provision. (Sec. 6) Allows access to the Federal parent locator service to courts in foster care or adoptive placement cases. (Sec. 7) Revises requirements relating to caseworker visits. (Sec. 8) Revises requirements relating to health and education records. (Sec. 9) Revises requirements relating to notice of proceedings. (Sec. 11) Provides for consideration of out-of-state placements in permanency hearings, case plans, and case reviews. (Sec. 14) Requires State plans for child welfare services to contain assurances that the State shall make use of cross-jurisdictional resources to facilitate timely adoptive or permanent placements for waiting children. Requires assurances that the State shall eliminate legal barriers to such use of interjurisdictional resources. Includes contracts for the purchase of services among the ways States are to use such resources. (Sec. 15) Directs the Comptroller General to study State performance of background checks for child placements.</summary>
</bill>
