<bill session="107" type="h" number="5138" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-22T17:09:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-07-22T17:09:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">True American Heroes Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">True American Heroes Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To posthumously award congressional gold medals to government workers and others who responded to the attacks on the World Trade Center and the Pentagon and perished and to people aboard United Airlines Flight 93 who helped resist the hijackers and caused the plane to crash, to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in commemoration of the Spirit of America, recognizing the tragic events of September 11, 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2002-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2002-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="2002-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2002-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2002-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="2002-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-22T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. King moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-22T16:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5021-5027" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-22T16:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5138.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-07-22T17:09:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5021-5023" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-07-22T17:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="3054"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional gold medals"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Flags"/>
    <term name="Flight crews"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Mayors"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Municipal officials"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Port authorities"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Silver"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2002--Passed House amended.
True American Heroes Act of 2002 - Title I: Medals for Responders and Resisters - (Sec. 101) Authorizes the award (posthumously) of congressional gold medals to the government workers and others who responded to the attacks on the World Trade Center in New York City and the Pentagon in Virginia and perished in the tragic events of September 11, 2001, and to the people aboard United Airlines Flight 93 who helped resist the hijackers on board and caused the plane to crash.Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to strike duplicates in gold of the gold medals for permanent display in named departments and duty stations. Authorizes the Secretary to strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medals at a price sufficient to cover the costs of the bronze medals and the cost of the gold medals.Title II: Spirit of America Commemorative Coins - (Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to mint and issue $50 dollar gold coins, one-dollar silver coins, and half-dollar clad coins emblematic of the tragic events that occurred at the Pentagon, in New York City, and in Pennsylvania, on September 11, 2001.(Sec. 206) Requires the sale of such coins to include a surcharge to cover the cost of the gold coins minted under this Act for presentment to the next of kin of those who died in the September 11, 2001, attacks, and any proceeds from such surcharges in excess of the cost of producing all coins to be: (1) used to cover the costs incurred in the production of the gold medals that have not been recovered from the sale of duplicate bronze medals minted under this Act; and (2) with respect to any amount remaining after payment of such costs, transferred to any fund for the victims of such attacks.</summary>
</bill>
