<bill session="106" type="hc" number="204" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Voicing concern about serious violations of human rights and fundamental freedoms in most states of Central Asia, including substantial noncompliance with their Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) commitments on democratization and the holding of free and fair elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1999-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2361-2362"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Constitutions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Kazakhstan"/>
    <term name="Kyrgyzstan"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Opposition (Political science)"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Tajikistan"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Turkmenistan"/>
    <term name="Uzbekistan"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/21/1999--Introduced.
Declares that Congress: (1) expresses concern about the tendency of Central Asian leaders to seek to remain in power indefinitely and their willingness to manipulate constitutions, elections, and legislative and judicial systems to do so; and (2) reminds the leaders of Central Asian states that elections cannot be free and fair unless all citizens can take part in the political process on an equal basis, without intimidation or fear of reprisal, and with confidence that their human rights and fundamental freedoms will be fully respected.Urges: (1) Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, and Uzbekistan to come into compliance with Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) commitments on human rights, democracy, and the rule of law, specifically the holding of free and fair elections that do not exclude genuine challengers, to permit independent and opposition parties and candidates to participate on an equal basis with representation in election commissions at all levels, and to allow domestic non-governmental and political party observers, as well as international observers; (2) Central Asian leaders to establish conditions for independent and opposition media to function without constraint, limitation, or fear of harassment, to repeal criminal laws which impose prison sentences for alleged defamation of the state or public officials, and to provide access to state media on an equal basis during election campaigns to independent and opposition parties and candidates; (3) the leaders of Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan to condemn and take effective steps to cease the systematic use of torture and other inhuman treatment by authorities against political opponents and others and to permit the registration of independent and opposition parties and candidates; and (4) Voice of America and Radio Liberty to expand broadcasting to Central Asia.Encourages the Administration to: (1) raise with the governments of other OSCE participating states the possible implications for OSCE participation of any participating state in the region that engages in clear, gross, and uncorrected violations of its OSCE commitments; and (2) seek formation of an OSCE Human Dimension Mission to Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan to investigate the human rights situation.</summary>
</bill>
