<bill session="105" type="h" number="957" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ethics Reform Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To abolish the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct in the House of Representatives, establish an Independent Commission on House Ethics, and provide for the transfer of the duties and functions of the Committee to the Independent Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1997-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1997-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="1997-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Termination of Committee on Standards of Official Conduct in the House of Representatives Title II: Establishment of Commission Title III: General Provisions Ethics Reform Act of 1997 - Title I: Termination of Committee on Standards of Official Conduct in the House of Representatives - Amends: (1) rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives to terminate the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct; (2) the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 to repeal provisions regarding that Committee; and (3) specified Rules and laws to replace references to the Committee with references to the Independent Commission on House Ethics established in title II. Title II: Establishment of Commission - Establishes within the legislative branch the Independent Commission on House Ethics. Prescribes as duties of the Commission: (1) recommending to the House appropriate administrative actions to establish or enforce standards of official conduct for Members, officers, and employees of the House; (2) investigating alleged violations of such standards and reporting its findings and recommendations to the House; (3) reporting to appropriate Federal or State authorities, with House approval, any substantial evidence of violations of law applicable to the performance of duties or the discharge of responsibilities by such persons; (4) considering requests of such persons for, and publishing, advisory opinions; and (5) providing information and guidance to such persons regarding standards of conduct. Sets forth procedural requirements for undertaking an investigation and disclosing results. Directs the Commission to establish an Office on Advice and Education to: (1) provide information and guidance to, and to conduct educational briefings for, such persons regarding standards of conduct; and (2) recommend to the Commission advisory opinions of general applicability. Title III: General Provisions - Requires investigations pending before the Committee on the day before the enactment of this Act to be continued by the Commission. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) publication in the Congressional Record of the Commission's reports to the House; and (2) House consideration of Commission recommendations for action.</summary>
</bill>
