<bill session="104" type="h" number="503" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Telecommunications Economic Opportunity Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require all providers of telecommunications services to establish and carry out plans for procurement from businesses owned by minorities and women, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402763"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E142-143"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Affirmative action programs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in the mass media industry"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination against women"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women in the mass media industry"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/13/1995--Introduced.
Telecommunications Economic Opportunity Act of 1995 - Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to require each provider of telecommunications services (provider) to submit annually a detailed and verifiable plan for increasing its procurement from businesses that are owned by minorities and women in all categories of procurement in which minorities are underrepresented. Requires each provider to report annually to the FCC regarding implementation of programs established under this Act. Directs the FCC to report annually to the Congress on the progress of activities undertaken by each provider. Directs the FCC to establish regulations for: (1) implementing programs under this Act; and (2) verifying and determining the eligibility of businesses owned by minorities and women. Requires each provider and its affiliates to develop and implement an outreach program to inform and recruit eligible businesses to apply for procurement contracts under this Act. Allows for the waiver of such requirements when their application to a provider results in undue hardship or unreasonable expense. Provides sanctions and remedies in the case of: (1) a business that falsely represents itself as a business owned by minorities or women; or (2) a provider which makes false representations in its annual report to the FCC or in its implementation of programs under this Act. Prohibits discrimination against eligible businesses attempting to procure contracts from telephone utilities. Authorizes civil actions by eligible businesses to enforce the provisions of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
