<bill session="107" type="hr" number="486" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to establish a discretionary spending ledger and a mandatory spending ledger.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400392"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400305" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2002-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400353" joined="2002-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-07-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1259"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/17/2002 H8027" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
      <reference ref="wrong version inadvertently printed on 10/10/2002 CR H7885-8028"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2002--Introduced.
Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to direct the chairman of the Budget Committee to maintain a Discretionary Spending Ledger, divided into entries corresponding to Appropriations Committee subcommittees. States that each entry will consist of the Deficit Reduction Safeguard Balance which may be credited with any reductions in new budget authority offered in an amendment to an appropriation bill.Requires such chairman to maintain a Mandatory Spending Ledger, divided into entries corresponding to the House Committees receiving budget allocations, excluding Appropriations. States that each entry will consist of the First Year Deficit Reduction Safeguard Balance and the Five Year Deficit Reduction Safeguard Balance which may be credited with applicable reductions in new budget authority offered in an amendment to a bill.Permits such reductions to be used to offset an increase in other new budget authority or remain within the applicable allocation.Prohibits the entry of a negative amount.Requires the chairman to maintain and make available to Members running tallies of the amendments adopted, reflecting increases and decreases of budget authority in bills as reported.</summary>
</bill>
