<bill session="104" type="h" number="639" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">West Virginia National Rivers Technical Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical amendments relating to three units of the National Park System in the State of West Virginia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400331"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.2292.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2292"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/23/1995--Introduced.
West Virginia National Rivers Technical Amendments Act of 1995 - Amends the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978 to: (1) direct the Secretary of the Interior to permit West Virginia to undertake fish stocking activities within the boundaries of the New River Gorge National River; and (2) make applicable to such national river provisions of the West Virginia National Interest River Conservation Act of 1987 allowing for cooperative agreements between the Secretary and such State for the maintenance and improvement of existing public roads and rights-of-way. Amends the West Virginia National Interest River Conservation Act of 1987 to defeat a boundary modification with respect to the Gauley River National Recreation Area in West Virginia if project construction at such Area is not commenced within the required time period or if the construction license is surrendered at any time. Requires the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees setting forth a plan to provide river access for noncommercial recreation users within such Area. Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to authorize the Secretary to enter into an agreement or acquire such lands as necessary to allow public access to the Bluestone River, West Virginia, and provide parking and related facilities near Eads Mill.</summary>
</bill>
