<bill session="107" type="h" number="3632" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Worker's Freedom of Choice Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that labor dues and fees are used only for collective bargaining purposes and exclusive representation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400394"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="2002-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor union finances"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Union dues"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2002--Introduced.
Worker's Freedom of Choice Act - Prohibits labor unions or employers subject to valid labor agreements from receiving, soliciting, or accepting payment of dues or fees not related to exclusive representation and core purposes, including collective bargaining, contract administration, and grievance adjustment (notwithstanding an exception under the National Labor Relations Act relating to union security agreements which require payment of union dues or fees as a condition of employment). Gives a right of civil action to employees who dispute the amount so collected by labor organizations. Requires employers to post notice of such prohibition against labor unions using dues or fees, which are collected as conditions of employment, for any activities not necessary to performing their duties of exclusive representation of employees in dealing with employers on labor-management issues (union duties).Amends the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 to require every labor union to attribute and report expenses by function classification, verified by independent audit, in enough detail to allow its members to determine whether such expenses were necessary to perform such union duties. Requires disclosure under such Act to employees required to pay any union dues or fees under a union security agreement as well as to union members.Prohibits labor union retaliation or coercion against any employee for exercising any right granted or protected by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
