<bill session="105" type="hc" number="336" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Condemning the Taliban regime and supporting a broad based government in Afghanistan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1989-1990"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Air travel"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation agreements"/>
    <term name="Christianity"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Islamic fundamentalism"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political refugees"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Shiites"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/1998--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives and the Senate that the United States should: (1) publicly condemn the Taliban regime for its reprehensible atrocities against human rights, in particular, womens' rights, its embrace of international terrorism, and its willing integration into a worldwide narcotics syndicate; (2) recognize that it will be better served by a comprehensive regional strategy that addresses Afghan issues rather than its current one that relies primarily on Pakistan; (3) explore its mutual interest with other countries of the region regarding the danger of the Taliban; (4) not grant diplomatic recognition to the Taliban or assist in any way its recognition in the United Nations but rather should support the inter-Afghan dialogue efforts to form a truly representative broad- based government; (5) work to initiate through the United Nations Security Council a ban on all international commercial air travel to and from Taliban controlled Afghanistan; (6) call on the Taliban regime to permit humanitarian supplies to be delivered without interference to all regions of Afghanistan; and (7) consider those Afghans, especially known friends of the United States, fleeing political persecution from the Taliban regime to be refugees eligible for consideration for asylum. Calls for: (1) the Department of Defense to conduct a vulnerability assessment of the Taliban regime; (2) the Department of State to urge the Islamic Republic of Pakistan to protect the rights of Christians and Shiite Muslims in Pakistan and to publish a special report to the Congress on the human rights situation in Pakistan, especially as it affects religious minorities; and (3) the Department of State to report to the Congress concerning whether the Taliban, which provides a safe haven for Osama bin Laden and other terrorist organizations as well as illicit drug monies which assist these terrorists, should be added to the list of designated foreign terrorist organizations.</summary>
</bill>
