<bill session="106" type="h" number="2590" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Older American's Protection From Violence Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Elder Abuse Identification and Referral Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Violence Against Women Act of 1994, the Family Violence Prevention and Services Act, the Older Americans Act of 1965, the Public Health Service Act, and the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 to ensure that older or disabled persons are protected from institutional, community, and domestic violence and sexual assault and to improve outreach efforts and other services available to older or disabled persons victimized by such violence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1999-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1999-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1999-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1999-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1999-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Commerce, and Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8592"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8629"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Clergy"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Continuum of care"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against the elderly"/>
    <term name="Curriculum planning"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elder abuse"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to disability services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to nursing education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the aged"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to the aged"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical students"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Older women"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Rape victim services"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senior centers"/>
    <term name="Social workers"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's shelters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Violence Against Women Act of 1994 Title II: Family Violence Prevention and Services Act Title III: Older Americans Act of 1965 Title IV: Public Health Service Act Title V: Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 Older American's Protection From Violence Act of 1999 - Title I: Violence Against Women Act of 1994 - Amends the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 to direct the Attorney General to: (1) make grants to law school clinical programs to fund inclusion of cases addressing issues of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation, including domestic violence and sexual assault against older or disabled individuals; and (2) develop curricula and training programs to assist prosecutors and Federal and State law enforcement personnel (including local courts) in recognizing, investigating, and prosecuting instances of such abuse.(Sec. 101) Authorizes appropriations.Title II: Family Violence Prevention and Services Act - Amends the Family Violence Prevention and Services Act to instruct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to include, within grants for State domestic violence coalitions, funds to develop outreach, support groups, and counseling targeted towards victims of elder domestic abuse.(Sec. 204) Expands the eligibility criteria for community initiative demonstration grants to include adult protective services entities.Title III: Older Americans Act of 1965 - Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to direct the Assistant Secretary for Aging to consider the importance of research about the sexual assault of women who are older or disabled individuals when establishing research priorities.(Sec. 304) Expands the scope of eligible demonstration projects to include domestic violence shelters and programs for elder and disabled individuals.(Sec. 305) Authorizes appropriations without fiscal year limitation to implement the ombudsman program and the elder abuse prevention program.(Sec. 306) Directs the Secretary to: (1) make grants to nonprofit private organizations to support local community initiatives to coordinate activities concerning intervention and prevention of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation, including domestic violence and sexual assault against older or disabled individuals; (2) develop and implement outreach programs for assisting older or disabled victims of such abuse; and (3) implement continuing education training programs for adult protective service workers, persons carrying out a State Long-Term Care Ombudsman program, health care providers, and community-based social service providers to improve recognition and treatment of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation, including domestic violence and sexual assault against older or disabled individuals.Title IV: Public Health Service Act - Elder Abuse Identification and Referral Act of 1998 (sic) - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary, in awarding grants or contracts to health professions entities under such Act, to give preference to an entity that has in effect a requirement that each student receiving a degree or certificate from such entity has had significant training as a provider of health care in the identification and referral of victims of elder abuse and neglect.Title V: Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 - Amends the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 to ensure that nothing in title XI of the Act shall preclude a financial institution, officer, employee, or agent from reporting suspected financial exploitation of an older or disabled individual to State, Federal, or local law enforcement authorities, or to government-regulated adult protective services entities. Protects such individuals from liability for such disclosures.</summary>
</bill>
