<bill session="108" type="h" number="2875" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish procedures for consideration of applications for award of the Purple Heart medal to veterans who were held as prisoners of war before April 25, 1962.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400209"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1613-1614"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Total Force.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS27" subcommittee="Total Force" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Ex-prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military medals, decorations, etc."/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2003--Introduced.
Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1996 to provide for the awarding of the Purple Heart to members held as prisoners of war before April 25, 1962, who were wounded while in captivity or who, while in captivity, were subjected to deprivation of food and medical treatment and to other forms of mistreatment. Requires the Secretary of the military department concerned to inform the former prisoner that historical information about the prison camp and other appropriate circumstances may be considered by the Secretary in evaluating an application for award of the Purple Heart and that the former prisoner may submit such information. Directs such Secretary to take into account the length of time that the award applicant was held in captivity to help determine whether the former prisoner was likely to have been wounded, starved, or denied medical treatment.</summary>
</bill>
