<bill session="106" type="h" number="5651" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To convey certain Federal lands to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400615"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military base conversion"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Naval bases"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2000--Introduced.
Conveys to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico the conservation zones on the western end of the Island of Vieques, Puerto Rico, designated for transfer or transferred to the Secretary of the Interior.Requires that: (1) the conveyed areas be managed for conservation purposes subject to a cooperative agreement between Puerto Rico and the Secretary; (2) areas adjacent to such areas be considered for inclusion under the agreement; and (3) such agreement be implemented in cooperation with the Puerto Rico Conservation Trust and other interested parties.Requires all conveyed lands to be managed to protect and preserve their natural resources.Permits amounts necessary to carry out the cooperative agreement to be made available to the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation to establish and manage an endowment for the management of such lands.</summary>
</bill>
