<bill session="106" type="h" number="5250" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Younger Americans Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide assistance to mobilize and support United States communities in carrying out youth development programs that assure that all youth have access to programs and services that build the competencies and character development needed to fully prepare the youth to become adults and effective citizens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="2000-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2000-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2000-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="2000-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2000-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="2000-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-09-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1556"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child mental health services"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community centers"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Ethics"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Recreation centers"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in social service"/>
    <term name="Youth"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Short Title; Policy; Findings; Definitions Title II: Coordination of National Youth Policy Title III: Grants for State and Community Programs Title IV: Training, Research, and Evaluation Younger Americans Act - Title I: Short Title; Policy; Findings; Definitions - Sets forth a national youth policy to assure that all youth have access to the full array of core resources, including: (1) ongoing relationships with caring adults; (2) safe places with structured activities in which to grow and learn; (3) services that promote healthy lifestyles, including those designed to improve physical and mental health; (4) opportunities to acquire marketable skills and competencies; and (5) opportunities for community service and civic participation.Title II: Coordination of National Youth Policy - Establishes in the Executive Office of the President: (1) the Office of National Youth Policy (the Office); (2) a Director of the Office; and (3) the Council on National Youth Policy within the Office. Authorizes appropriations.Title III: Grants for State and Community Programs - Authorizes appropriations for the Associate Commissioner of the Family and Youth Services Bureau of the Administration on Children, Youth, and Families in the Department of Health and Human Services to make block grant allotments to States for State and community programs for youth to assure access to the five core resources listed in the national youth policy. Provides for reservations of funds for Native American organizations, outlying areas, and Federal discretionary programs to respond to needs of youth in correctional and other out-of-home settings, high poverty areas, rural areas, and other high-risk situations.(Sec. 304) Sets forth requirements for State agencies, planning and mobilization areas, distribution of funds for State activities and local allocations, community boards and area agencies on youth, area plans, grants and contracts to eligible entities, and youth development program activities.Title IV: Training, Research, and Evaluation - Authorizes awarding of grants and contracts to eligible entities for specified evaluation, education and training, research, and dissemination activities.(Sec. 402) Directs the Associate Commissioner to: (1) develop and establish systems for evaluating activities under this Act, and for providing education and training of personnel of States, area agencies, and community boards to work with youth; and (2) conduct an independent biennial evaluation of the impact of programs assisted under this act and other initiatives to promote positive youth development.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
