<bill session="105" type="h" number="2696" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-18T10:41:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-03-18T10:41:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vessel Hull Design Protection Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Vessel Hull Design Protection Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Vessel Hull Design Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 17, United States Code, to provide for protection of certain original designs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="1997-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11T18:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 105-436.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-03-11T18:44:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="246">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 246.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-18T10:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Coble moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-18T10:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1243-1247" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-18T10:36:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-03-18T10:41:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-03-18T10:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-19">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.2281.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2281"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Copyright infringement"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Oaths"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Postal crimes"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="United States Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1998--Passed House amended.
Vessel Hull Design Protection Act - Amends Federal copyright law to provide for protection of original designs of vessel hulls which make a vessel attractive or distinctive in appearance to the purchasing or using public. Bars protection for designs that are: (1) not original; (2) staple or commonplace; (3) dictated solely by a utilitarian function of the article that embodies them; or (4) embodied in a useful article that was made public by the designer or owner more than one year before the date of application for registration. Provides for ten-year terms of protection. Sets forth marking and design notice requirements for protected designs. Bars recovery against persons who began undertakings leading to infringement before receiving notice. Places the burden of providing notice of protection on design owners. Grants owners of protected designs exclusive rights to make, have made, import, sell, or distribute for sale or for use in trade any useful article embodying protected designs. Makes it infringement to engage in such activities with respect to infringing articles without an owner's consent. Provides that it shall not be infringement to: (1) engage in certain activities with respect to protected designs without knowledge; or (2) reproduce a protected design solely for purposes of teaching, analyzing, or evaluating the appearance, concepts, or techniques embodied in the design or the functions of the useful article embodying the design. Places the burden of establishing a design's originality on the party alleging rights in a design. Provides that protection shall be lost if application for design registration is not made within two years after the date on which the design is first made public. Sets forth registration application requirements. Accords protection to designs with respect to which an application was filed by a U.S. owner in a foreign country on the date as filed if the U.S. application is filed within six months after the earliest date on which such foreign application was filed. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) determinations of registrations and procedures for cancelling registrations in cases where a party believes he or she may be damaged by registration; and (2) ownership and transfer of property rights of protected designs. Authorizes design owners to seek judicial review of final refusals of the Register of Copyrights to register designs. Permits the use of arbitration to resolve infringement disputes. Authorizes injunctive relief to prevent infringement. Provides for recovery of damages or the infringer's profits in infringement cases. Sets a three-year statute of limitations with respect to recovery for infringement. Authorizes the court to order or cancel registrations. Prescribes penalties for the filing of infringement actions with respect to fraudulently-obtained registrations or making false markings or representations. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury and the Postal Service to issue regulations for the enforcement of exclusive rights with respect to importation of protected designs. Subjects articles imported in violation of such rights to seizure and forfeiture. Terminates protection under this Act upon issuance of a design patent with respect to an original design. Grants the U.S. district courts jurisdiction over actions arising under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
