<bill session="104" type="h" number="3924" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Statistical Confidentiality Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide uniform safeguards for the confidentiality of information acquired for exclusively statistical purposes, and to improve the efficiency of Federal statistical programs and the quality of Federal statistics by permitting limited sharing of records for statistical purposes under strong safeguards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400506"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1996-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative responsibility"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Statistical services"/>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/1996--Introduced.
Statistical Confidentiality Act - Designates Federal Statistical Data Centers. Authorizes the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), after consultation with the head of an agency proposing a reorganization that eliminates, or substantially alters the missions or functions of, an agency or unit designated as a Statistical Data Center, to designate an agency or unit to serve as a successor statistical data center under the terms of this Act if certain criteria are met. Requires, among other things, that statistical data centers: (1) identify opportunities to eliminate duplication and otherwise reduce the reporting burden and cost imposed on the public by sharing information for exclusively statistical purposes; and (2) safeguard the confidentiality of identifiable information acquired for statistical purposes. Directs that data or information acquired by a statistical data center for exclusively statistical purposes: (1) be used only for statistical purposes; and (2) not be disclosed in identifiable form for any other purpose without the informed consent of the respondent. Permits the disclosure of data or information by an agency to one or more statistical data centers. States that the disclosure be made under the terms of a written agreement. Provides for coordination and oversight of confidentiality and disclosure policies by the Director. Requires: (1) the head of each statistical data center to report to OMB each disclosure agreement and the results of any review of information security undertaken at the request of OMB or any similar review undertaken on the initiative of the statistical data center or an agency supplying data or information to such a center; and (2) OMB to include a summary of all such reports and any actions taken by OMB in its annual report to the Congress on statistical programs.</summary>
</bill>
