<bill session="108" type="h" number="2910" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Multiemployer Pension Security Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947 to provide special rules for Teamster plans relating to termination and funding.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400406"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2003-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1659"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1492"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1492"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Defined contribution plans"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Pension trust guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2003--Introduced.
Multiemployer Pension Security Act of 2003 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), the Internal Revenue Code, the National Labor Relations Act, and the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947 with respect to teamster plans and their funding. Defines a teamster plan as a plan: (1) to which more than one employer is required to contribute; and (2) which is maintained pursuant to one or more collective bargaining agreements between The International Brotherhood Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers of America or its locals and more than one employer. Declares that a teamster plan shall not be treated as a multiemployer plan, and each employer that has an obligation to contribute to a teamster plan shall be treated as a contributing sponsor maintaining a separate single-employer plan, including with respect to partition and allocation of assets and liabilities. Requires the assets of a teamster plan to be invested by the trustees as one master trust, and each contributing employer's share of the plan assets to be adjusted annually according to master trust accounting principles for the employer's plan contributions, benefit payments with respect to its ongoing liability and transition liability (if any), and share of investment returns and administrative expenses. Requires the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation to guarantee 100 percent of the transition liabilities of each teamster plan. Defines transition liabilities as the sum of the accrued benefit liabilities under a teamster plan (as a whole, as if it were treated as a single multiemployer plan rather than a collection of single-employer plans) attributable to: (1) participants who are not employed in credited service for any employer under the plan; and (2) the credited service of other participants with an employer that does not have an obligation to contribute to the teamster plan. Requires the premium rates for plan termination insurance charged by the Corporation for teamster plans to be the same as those charged for single-employer plans. States that each employer with an obligation to contribute to a teamster plan shall be responsible for paying the premiums attributable to the single-employer plan the employer is treated as maintaining. Requires any additional premium to phased in over ten plan years. Authorizes the Corporation to allow an employer to contribute all or part of such additional premium directly to the teamster plan, in lieu of payment to the Corporation. Authorizes an employer with an obligation to contribute to a teamster plan to terminate its participation in either a standard or a distress termination. Requires establishment of a funding standard account for each employer with an obligation to contribute to a teamster plan. Prescribes formulae for specified minimum funding of, and minimum contributions to, a teamster plan. Prohibits any increase in benefits unless a teamster plan is sufficiently funded.</summary>
</bill>
