<bill session="104" type="h" number="2953" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Personal Investment Plan Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Social Security Act to provide for personal investment plans funded by employee social security payroll deductions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400604"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1996-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="824"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/1996--Introduced.
Personal Investment Plan Act of 1995 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code and title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to require covered employers to have a plan for withholding certain contributions from the wages of their eligible employees electing to participate for investment according to the individual employee's personal investment plan. Defines personal investment plan as: (1) any personal investment retirement plan restricted to certain contribution deposits in the Personal Investment Fund, established in the Treasury by this Act; or (2) any individual retirement plan restricted to certain contribution deposits and administered or issued by a bank. Requires the Personal Investment Fund to be governed by a Personal Investment Fund Board under a system similar to the Thrift Savings Program for Federal employees. Covers self-employed individuals. Specifies reduced social security tax rates for participating employees and self-employed individuals. Sets forth civil penalties for employers who fail to establish a personal investment payroll deduction plan or observe certain requirements with respect to it. Provides for adjustments to primary insurance amounts under the OASDI program.</summary>
</bill>
