<bill session="106" type="h" number="3538" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transit Commuter Credit Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage the use of public transportation systems by allowing individuals a credit against income tax for expenses paid to commute to and from work or school using public transportation, and to reduce corporate welfare.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="2000-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2000-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2000-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-01-27">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-03">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Depletion allowances"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy tax credits"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Mineral industries"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Secondary recovery of oil"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/27/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Credit for Public Transportation Commuting Expenses Title II: Modifications to Treatment of Foreign Oil and Gas Income Title III: Limitations on Payments Under Defense Contracts Title IV: Repeal of Certain Incentives for Oil and Gas Exploration and Development and for Mining Title V: Repeal of Exclusion for Citizens or Residents of United States Living Abroad Transit Commuter Credit Act of 2000 - Title I: Credit for Public Transportation Commuting Expenses - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a credit for 20 percent ($150 maximum) of an individual's employment or education related public transportation commuting expenses.Title II: Modifications to Treatment of Foreign Oil and Gas Income - Treats certain taxes paid or accrued to a foreign country with respect to foreign oil and gas income as not creditable for purposes of the foreign tax credit.Treats foreign oil and gas extraction income, and foreign oil related income as separate income categories. Eliminates such categories' exclusion from income for specified purposes. (Changes references to foreign base company oil related income to foreign oil and gas income.)Title III: Limitations on Payments Under Defense Contracts - Prohibits use of Department of Defense funds to pay restructuring costs associated with the merger or acquisition of a Department contractor.Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1995 to extend a specified annual contractor restructuring reporting requirement. Sets forth additional information requirements for such report and a related report by the Comptroller General.Amends Federal law to set forth specified compensation limitations for Department contracts.Title IV: Repeal of Certain Incentives for Oil and Gas Exploration and Development and for Mining - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal: (1) expensing of intangible drilling and development costs for oil and gas wells and geothermal wells; (2) expensing of mine development and exploration costs; (3) percentage depletion for mines and wells, including oil and gas wells; and (4) the enhanced oil recovery credit.Title V: Repeal of Exclusion for Citizens or Residents of United States Living Abroad - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal the foreign earned income and housing allowance gross income exclusion for U.S. citizens and residents abroad.</summary>
</bill>
