<bill session="107" type="h" number="5211" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 17, United States Code, to limit the liability of copyright owners for protecting their works on peer-to-peer networks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2002-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400212" joined="2002-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2002-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2002-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1395-1396"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Copyright infringement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2002--Introduced.
Amends Federal copyright law to protect a copyright owner from liability in any criminal or civil action for impairing, with appropriate technology, the unauthorized distribution, display, performance, or reproduction of his or her copyrighted work on a publicly accessible peer-to-peer file trading network, if such impairment does not, without authorization, alter, delete, or otherwise impair the integrity of any computer file or data residing on the computer of a file trader.Denies such liability protection to a copyright owner who does not comply with certain notification requirements or who: (1) impairs the availability within a publicly accessible peer-to-peer file trading network of a computer file or data that does not contain a work in which the owner has an exclusive copyright; (2) causes economic loss to any person other than affected file traders; or (3) causes other economic loss of more than $50.00 per impairment to the property of the affected file trader.Conditions a copyright owner's protection from liability upon seven-days' notice to the Department of Justice of the specific technologies intended for use to impair unauthorized distribution, display, performance, or reproduction of a copyrighted work. Requires notice as well, upon request, to an affected file trader or the assignee of an Internet Protocol address used by an affected file trader.Provides for a cause of action against a copyright owner for wrongful impairment, including an action by the Attorney General for injunctive relief in certain circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
