<bill session="104" type="h" number="1053" updated="2012-11-01T22:44:05-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit Members of the House of Representatives from using official funds for the production or mailing of newsletters, to reduce by 50 percent the amount which may be made available for the Official Mail Allowance of any such Member, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408839"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional allowances"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>02/24/1995--Introduced.
Prohibits a Member of the House of Representatives from using any official funds for the production or mailing of a newsletter. Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991 to change the Official Mail Allowance for Members of the House of Representatives to not more than the product of: (1) one and one-half times the single-piece rate applicable to first class mail (currently, three times such rate); and (2) the number of addresses in the congressional district. Requires any unobligated funds remaining in the Official Mail Allowance of a Member of the House at the end of a session of Congress to be deposited into the general fund of the Treasury and applied toward the reduction of the Federal budget deficit.</summary>
</bill>
