<bill session="105" type="h" number="2249" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-07-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for carrying out the Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977 for fiscal years 1998 and 1999, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1997-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-07-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1514"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-07-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-08-01T12:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 105-238, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-08-01T12:17:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Resources Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Aug. 1, 1997.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-08-01T12:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-08-01T12:17:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="135">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 135.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="910"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Earth science research"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Earthquake engineering"/>
    <term name="Earthquake prediction"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Highspeed trains"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Seismology"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Test facilities"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/1997--Introduced.
Amends the Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977 to authorize appropriations for FY 1998 and 1999 to: (1) the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to carry out the National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program; and (2) the Secretary of the Interior for such responsibilities as may be assigned to the Director of the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) under such Act, with specified funds earmarked for the Global Seismic Network and for carrying out a competitive, peer-reviewed program under which FEMA, in close coordination with and as a complement to related activities of the USGS, awards grants to, or enters into cooperative agreements with, State and local governments and persons or entities from the academic community and the private sector. Earmarks funds for responsibilities under such Act for FY 1998 and 1999 for: (1) the National Science Foundation (NSF) for engineering research and geosciences research; and (2) the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). Requires the Director of USGS to: (1) conduct and report to the Congress on a program to develop a prototype real-time seismic warning system; and (2) provide for an assessment of and report to the Congress on regional seismic monitoring networks in the United States. Authorizes the Director of NSF to use funds made available under such Act to develop and make available to schools and local educational agencies for use by schools, at a minimal cost, earth science teaching materials that are designed to meet the needs of elementary and secondary school teachers and students. Requires the Director to conduct and report to the Congress on a project to improve the seismic hazard assessment of seismic zones. Requires the Director of FEMA to report to the Congress on the need for additional Federal disaster-response training capabilities that are applicable to earthquake response. Requires NSF, FEMA, USGS, and NIST to jointly develop a comprehensive plan for earthquake engineering research to effectively use existing testing facilities and laboratories, upgrade facilities and equipment as needed, and integrate new, innovative testing approaches to the research infrastructure in a systematic manner.</summary>
</bill>
