<bill session="108" type="h" number="1947" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Armed Forces Housing Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that members of the Armed Forces who are married and have minor dependents are eligible for military family housing containing more than two bedrooms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400304" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2003-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Military construction operations"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2003--Introduced.
Armed Forces Housing Improvement Act - Makes a member of the armed forces who has a spouse and at least one dependent under 19 residing with such member eligible for military installation housing containing at least three bedrooms, regardless of such member's grade, rank, or rating. Considers housing containing less than three bedrooms inadequate housing for such member.Directs the Secretaries of the military departments to require the military base housing office of each installation to review and revise its housing market analysis and military family housing requirements to accommodate such policy.Prohibits military housing construction funds appropriated before this Act from being obligated until such Secretaries certify to Congress that: (1) such analyses and requirements have been revised; and (2) the unobligated funds will be used to accommodate such policy and implement such analyses and requirements.</summary>
</bill>
