<bill session="106" type="h" number="2634" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-19T19:04:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-07-19T19:04:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drug Addiction Treatment Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Drug Addiction Treatment Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Drug Addiction Treatment Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Controlled Substances Act with respect to registration requirements for practitioners who dispense narcotic drugs in schedule IV or V for maintenance treatment or detoxification treatment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1999-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1999-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="1999-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1999-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1999-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1999-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1999-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1999-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1999-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-10-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-11-03T17:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Commerce. H. Rept. 106-441, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-03T17:43:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 3, 1999.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-03T17:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-11-03T17:44:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="255">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 255.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bliley moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6374-6377" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6374-6375" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18T10:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2634.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18T10:48:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-19T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6564" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-07-19T19:04:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="416" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 412 - 1 (Roll no. 416).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-19T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-19T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR 7/27/2000 H7200" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="740">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 740.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="486"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="486"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug addiction"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Heroin"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Opium"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2000--Passed House amended.
Drug Addiction Treatment Act of 2000 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to waive the requirement that practitioners who dispense narcotic drugs to individuals for maintenance or detoxification treatment annually obtain a separate registration for that purpose, and that the Attorney General register an applicant to dispense narcotic drugs to individuals for such treatment, in the case of the dispensing by a practitioner of narcotic drugs in schedule III, IV, or V or combinations of such drugs (schedule III-V drugs) if the practitioner and the drugs meet specified conditions. Limits the total number of patients of either a sole practitioner or of a group to 30 patients at any one time. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to set different numerical ceilings according to the number of practitioners in the group practice.Requires that: (1) the practitioner, before dispensing schedule III-V drugs to patients for maintenance or detoxification treatment, submit to the Secretary a notification of intent to begin dispensing such drugs for that purpose, including certifications that the practitioner is a "qualifying physician" (defined to mean a physician who is licensed under State law and meets specified training and experience requirements), and has the capacity to refer the patients for appropriate counseling and other appropriate ancillary; and (2) the schedule III-V drugs have been approved for use in maintenance or detoxification treatment and have not been the subject of an "adverse determination" (i.e., requires additional standards regarding the qualifications of practitioners to provide such treatment, or requires standards regarding the quantities of the drugs that may be provided for unsupervised use).Sets forth specified procedural requirements to make the waiver effective. Directs the Attorney General, upon receiving a notification under this Act, to assign the practitioner involved an identification number for inclusion with the registration issued for the practitioner. Requires that the identification number be appropriate to preserve the confidentiality of patients for whom the practitioner has dispensed narcotic drugs under the waiver. Directs: (1) the Secretary, within 45 days after receiving a notification, to make a determination of whether the practitioner involved meets all waiver requirements; and (2) the Attorney General, if the Secretary fails to make such determination by the end of such period, to assign the physician an identification number.Requires the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration, the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, the Director of the Center for Substance Abuse Treatment, the Director of the National Institute on Drug Abuse, and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (consulted parties), to issue regulations or practice guidelines to address: (1) approval of additional credentialing bodies and their responsibilities; and (2) additional exemptions. Specifies that nothing in such regulations or guidelines may authorize any Federal official or employee to exercise supervision or control over the practice of medicine or the manner in which medical services are provided.Directs the Secretary: (1) to issue a treatment improvement protocol containing best practice guidelines for the treatment and maintenance of opiate-dependent patients; and (2) to develop the protocol in consultation with the consulted parties and other substance abuse disorder professionals, with the protocol guided by science.Prohibits a State, for three years, from precluding a practitioner from dispensing or prescribing drugs in schedule III-V to patients for maintenance of detoxification treatment unless the State enacts a law prohibiting a practitioner from dispensing such drugs.Authorizes the Secretary and the Attorney General, for three years, to make determinations regarding whether: (1) treatments provided under such waivers have been effective forms of maintenance and detoxification treatment in clinical settings; (2) such waivers have significantly increased the availability of such treatment; and (3) such waivers have adverse public health consequences. Authorizes the Secretary or the Attorney General, after consulting each other, to terminate the waiver mechanism after announcing their decision in the Federal Register. Authorizes appropriations to assist the Secretary with the additional duties established for the Secretary pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
