<bill session="107" type="h" number="3746" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Excellence Demonstration Program Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII to establish a comprehensive centers for medical excellence demonstration program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2002-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="1756"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospices (Terminal care)"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2002--Introduced.
Medical Excellence Demonstration Program Act of 2001 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a demonstration program under which the Secretary conducts population-based demonstration projects to test the use of providing incentives to comprehensive centers for medical excellence that: (1) eliminate underuse of effective care by beneficiaries; (2) ensure the safety of care provided to such individuals; (3) reduce scientific uncertainty in the delivery of care through outcomes measurement and research; (4) encourage shared decision-making for specific treatments and the management of chronic disease and end-of-life care; (5) encourage resource allocation decisions based on efficient practice benchmarks; (6) promote the conservative delivery of care when more intensive care is wasteful if not harmful; and (7) reward such centers for improving the quality of care and achieving efficient allocation of resources.Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) a Medicare claims-based information system that links individual sites and providers benchmarks for evaluating health care quality and efficiency; and (2) within the Department of Health and Human Services a National Steering Committee for Comprehensive Centers for Medical Excellence Demonstration Projects to recommend the design of such demonstration program and to provide a forum for coordination of Federal support for it.</summary>
</bill>
