<bill session="106" type="h" number="5122" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient Protection Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Health Care Quality Improvement Act of 1986 to provide for the availability to the public of information reported to the National Practitioner Data Bank under such Act, to establish additional reporting requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2000-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2000-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="2000-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2000-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2000-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2000-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Public Availability of Physician Information in National Practitioner Data Bank Title II: Reporting Requirements Regarding National Practitioner Data Bank Title III: Duty to Obtain Information Title IV: General Provisions Patient Protection Act of 2000 - Title I: Public Availability of Physician Information in National Practitioner Data Bank - Amends the Health Care Quality Improvement Act of 1986 to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to promulgate regulations under which the public may obtain, through the Internet, specified physician information contained in the National Practitioner Data Bank, including patient care incidents. Requires the inclusion of information regarding medical malpractice payments and criminal acts.Title II: Reporting Requirements Regarding National Practitioner Data Bank - Requires the inclusion, within certain reports required for such Data Bank, of information regarding the physician's medical field, date of licensing and years of experience, and professional license number. Requires each State Board of Medical Examiners to report criminal acts of physicians.Requires each physician to report, for the Data Bank, each felony conviction and sets forth sanctions for failure to report.Title III: Duty to Obtain Information - Requires Federal hospitals and State Boards of Medical Examiners to obtain physician information required under this Act.Title IV: General Provisions - Requires the Secretary, on request, to provide State Boards of Medical Examiners a summary of information reported in the Data Bank on physicians licensed in that State.</summary>
</bill>
