<bill session="104" type="h" number="759" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense Welfare Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the effectiveness of Federal welfare efforts and increase citizen participation in fighting poverty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400225"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401081" joined="1995-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1995-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1995-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1995-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="1995-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="1995-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="1995-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="406863" joined="1995-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="407817" joined="1995-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1995-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1995-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="1995-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1995-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="1995-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E232"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, Commerce, Economic and Educational Opportunities, Banking and Financial Services, the Judiciary, Resources, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Native American and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-09">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, HHS.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1468-1469"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-24">
      <text>See H.R.4.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG26" subcommittee="Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII14" subcommittee="Native American and Insular Affairs" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="4"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agricultural surpluses"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Appalachia"/>
    <term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
    <term name="Birth control"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Day care centers for the aged"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal Services Corporation"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to the poor"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Migrant education"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and the aged"/>
    <term name="Old age assistance"/>
    <term name="Paternity"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Refugee policy"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seasonal labor"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in education"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Summer employment"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban economic development"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Welfare reform"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Capping the Aggregate Growth of Welfare Spending Title II: Empowering Taxpayers to Participate in Poverty Relief Efforts Title III: Promoting Strong Families and Parental Responsibility Common Sense Welfare Reform Act of 1995 - Title I: Capping the Aggregate Growth of Welfare Spending - Establishes a cap on the growth of total Federal spending on certain welfare programs. (Sec. 101) Subjects to such spending limit the following programs: (1) the welfare block grant program established under this Act; (2) Head Start programs under the Head Start Act; (3) cash, medical, and social services assistance programs for refugees and entrants under Immigration and Nationality Act and the Refugee Education Assistance Act of 1980; (4) the special supplemental food program for women, infants, and children under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966; (5) programs providing general assistance to Indians under the Snyder Act; (6) programs providing Indian health services under the Indian Health Care Improvement Act; (7) programs providing Indian housing improvement grants; and (8) programs providing Indian and Native American employment training. Provides for reconciliation of such spending growth limits through specified procedures for allocations and reductions based on spending caps, and through consultation with specified congressional committees. (Sec. 102) Entitles each State to an annual welfare block grant payment based on a specified formula under a five-year program. Establishes the Welfare Revolving Fund. (Sec. 103) Eliminates certain welfare programs, under the following categories: (1) cash aid (Social Security Act (SSA) programs for Aid to Families with Dependent Children, Supplemental Security Income, foster care and adoption assistance, and grants to territories for aid to the aged, blind, or disabled); (2) medical aid (SSA program for maternal and child health services block grants, and Public Health Service Act programs for community health centers and migrant health centers); (3) food aid (the entire Food Stamp Act of 1977 and its food stamp program, the school lunch program under the National School Lunch Act (NSLA), the entire Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983 and its emergency food assistance program, nutrition programs for the elderly under the Older Americans Act of 1965, the school breakfast program under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (CNA), and other specified child and adult food programs); (4) housing aid (certain rental assistance and public housing programs under the United States Housing Act of 1937, certain interest reduction assistance under the National Housing Act, rent supplement assistance under the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968, and Housing Act of 1949 programs for specified rural housing and rental assistance); (5) energy aid (the entire Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 and its low-income home energy assistance programs, and the weatherization assistance program under the Energy Conservation and Production Act); (6) education aid (Higher Education Act of 1965 programs for Pell grants, Federal supplemental educational opportunity grants, Federal TRIO programs, grants to States for State student incentives, and grants to institutions and consortia to encourage women and minority participation in graduate education, and Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 programs for improving local education agency basic programs for disadvantaged and for migratory children); (7) jobs and training aid (Job Training Partnership Act programs for adult training, summer youth employment and training, the Job Corps, and Native Americans and migrant and seasonal farmworkers, the older American community service employment program under the Older Americans Act of 1965, and the JOBS program under SSA); (8) social services (SSA block grants to States for social services, the entire Community Services Block Grant Act (except specified provisions) and its community services block grant program, the entire Legal Services Corporation Act of 1974 and its legal services program, the FEMA emergency food and shelter program under the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act, PHSA programs of research regarding family planning and population issues and of voluntary family planning projects, and the entire Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973); and (9) community aid (community development block grants and urban development action grants under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974, and the entire Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965 with its Appalachian regional development program (terminating the Appalachian Regional Development Commission)). Revises the Older Americans Act of 1965 with respect to supportive services for older individuals to include a Senior Opportunities and Services program. (Sec. 104) Requires the use for deficit reduction of all savings to the Federal Government resulting from the spending cap imposed under this Act. Prohibits the use of such savings to fund increased spending under any programs that are not subject to the spending cap. Provides that budgetary effects resulting from enactment of this title shall not be counted under the Balanced Budgetary and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1965 with respect to deficit amounts in excess of the statutory maximum (paygo scorecard) which trigger an offsetting sequestration. Title II: Empowering Taxpayers to Participate in Poverty Relief Efforts - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to allow an individual tax credit for charitable contributions to certain private charities providing assistance to the poor. Title III: Promoting Strong Families and Parental Responsibility - Amends the IRC to allow an additional earned income credit for married individuals. (Sec. 302) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a system for the reporting of information relating to child support obligations of employees. Amends SSA title VI part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) to require a State role in such system. (Sec. 303) Amends SSA title VI part D to require: (1) State registries of child support orders; and (2) certain procedures for accessibility of State information relating to child support. (Sec. 304) Expands the Parent Locator Service. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an Interstate Local Network linking the Parent Locator Service and all State databases relating to child support enforcement. Requires prescription of regulations governing information sharing among States, within States, and between States and the Parent Locator Service. (Sec. 305) Requires certain State procedures for collection and distribution of child support through income withholding. Provides for development of a uniform withholding order. Requires States to have laws requiring employers to withhold child support pursuant to uniform withholding orders. (Sec. 306) Requires development of a uniform abstract of a child support order for use by all State courts to record specified information with respect to each child support order in the registry.</summary>
</bill>
