<bill session="105" type="h" number="3224" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Privacy Protection Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide protection from personal intrusion for commercial purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1998-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1998-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="1998-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Press"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Stalking"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/1998--Introduced.
Privacy Protection Act of 1998 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit and set penalties for persistently following or chasing any individual in the United States for the purpose of obtaining a visual image, sound recording, or other physical impression of that or another individual (the image) if: (1) the image was intended to be, or was in fact, sold, published, or transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce, or the person attempting to capture such image moved in commerce to do so; (2) the individual has a reasonable expectation of privacy from such intrusions and has taken reasonable steps to ensure that privacy; (3) the individual has a reasonable fear that death or bodily injury will result from that following or chasing; and (4) the obtaining of the image is for commercial purposes. Authorizes a person subjected to a violation to obtain appropriate relief in a civil action against the person engaging in the violation. Directs the court to allow the prevailing party a reasonable attorney's fee and other litigation costs. Specifies that it is not a defense to such a prosecution or civil action that no image was captured or sold. Subjects to a Federal criminal charge or civil liability only a person physically present at the time. Makes this Act inapplicable with respect to official law enforcement activities.</summary>
</bill>
