<bill session="104" type="h" number="3769" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">O&amp;C Forest Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the conditional transfer of the Oregon and California Railroad Grant Lands, the Coos Bay Military Wagon Road Grant Lands, and related public domain lands to the State of Oregon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402010"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Resource Conservation, Research and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG27" subcommittee="Resource Conservation, Research and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forests"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Railroad land grants"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State aid to local areas"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Sustainable forestry"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/1996--Introduced.
O&amp;C Forest Transfer Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, subject to a qualifying legislative resolution of assent from the State of Oregon filed on or before December 31, 1999, to transfer to Oregon specified real property constituting the Oregon and California (O&amp;C) Railroad Grant Lands, the Coos Bay Military Wagon Road Grant Lands, all federally owned timberlands within one or more O&amp;C counties currently managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), and certain land and structures utilized as offices or in related administrative capacities. Outlines terms required in the qualifying resolution of assent, including: (1) the requirement that Oregon manage the transferred lands for sustained yield, permanent timber production benefitting the economic stability of local communities; (2) the adoption of a State land management plan; (3) the establishment of an O&amp;C Lands Fund for timber sales deposits and disbursements to O&amp;C counties within the transferred lands, as well as to Oregon to cover land management costs; (4) the administration of a mineral rights program for individuals; (5) a prohibition against the sale of any transferred lands capable of timber production; (6) a reservation from entry for commercial timber production; (7) the continuation of current recreational uses; and (8) the establishment of a program providing an employment preference within the Oregon Department of Forestry in transferred land management positions to persons currently employed by the BLM in such capacity. Provides a U.S. right of reentry onto such transferred lands when the land is not being managed in accordance with the transfer conditions and such noncompliance has not been corrected within two years of such determination. Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture, if a qualifying resolution of assent has been filed in a timely manner, to commence the preparation of amendments to Federal land management plans. Suspends as of January 1, 2004, specified Federal laws rendered obsolete by the land transfers under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
