<bill session="106" type="h" number="4722" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Defense Privatization and Outsourcing Moratorium Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To impose a temporary moratorium on the privatization and outsourcing of Department of Defense functions that are currently being performed by Department of Defense civilian employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="2000-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="2000-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2000-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="2000-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2000-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Military Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2000--Introduced.
Department of Defense Privatization and Outsourcing Moratorium Act - Prohibits any commercial or industrial type function currently being performed by Department of Defense (DOD) civilian employees from being converted to performance by the private sector until five years after the Secretary of Defense certifies to Congress that all actions necessary to carry out the 1995 round of military base closures and realignments under the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 have been completed. Makes an exception for such a function being converted, or being considered for conversion, to private performance under a DOD strategic sourcing or business process and re-engineering plan.Requires the Secretary to report to Congress evaluating: (1) each conversion that was carried out since October 1, 1996; and (2) each function that was considered for conversion since such date, but not converted.Directs the Secretary, on account of such moratorium, to provide for an adjustment in the operating budgets of the armed forces and military installations to compensate for the fact that such budgets were previously reduced to reflect savings anticipated from the conversion of such functions to private sector performance.</summary>
</bill>
