<bill session="107" type="hj" number="118" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preliminary Authorization for the Use of Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide preliminary authorization for the use of force against Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1782"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7435"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control verification"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2002--Introduced.
Preliminary Authorization for the Use of Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002 - Authorizes the President to use the U.S. armed forces: (1) to enforce United Nations Security Council Resolution 687 in order to secure the dismantlement or destruction of Iraq's weapons of mass destruction program and its prohibited ballistic missile program; or (2) in the exercise of individual or collective self-defense, to defend the United States or allied nations against a grave threat posed by those programs. Requires, before such authority may be exercised: (1) the President to make available to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate his determination that the United States has attempted to seek, and the Security Council has adopted after September 12, 2002, a resolution authorizing such action to enforce Resolution 687 or that the threat to the United States or allied nations posed by those programs is so grave that the use of force is necessary, notwithstanding the Security Council's failure to approve the resolution; and (2) Congress to approve the President's determination in a joint resolution.Requires the President to keep Congress fully and currently informed on matters relevant to this Act.Declares that this Act is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization for use of the armed forces, consistent with requirements of the War Powers Resolution.</summary>
</bill>
