<bill session="104" type="hr" number="437" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-21T20:04:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-05-21T20:04:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3259) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 1997 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-05-16T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-581, by Mr. Goss.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-16T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3259 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by title. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment to the commitee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order unless printed in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 6 of rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-05-16T17:29:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="225">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 225.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21T19:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5357-5360" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21T19:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21T20:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-05-21T20:04:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21T20:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="3259"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/1996--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 3259 (intelligence and intelligence-related activities authorization).</summary>
</bill>
