<bill session="105" type="h" number="2003" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-07-23T13:54:00-04:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-07-23T13:54:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Balanced Budget Agreement bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Budget Enforcement Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform the budget process and enforce the bipartisan balanced budget agreement of 1997.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="401033" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1997-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400577" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="1997-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1997-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1997-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404996" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="405313" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="406047" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="1997-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1997-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1997-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1997-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="408142" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400520" joined="1997-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1997-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="409618" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409633" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400609" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400610" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1997-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400410" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1997-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1997-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="1997-07-17" withdrawn="1997-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400026" joined="1997-07-17" withdrawn="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="406284" joined="1997-07-17" withdrawn="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1997-07-17" withdrawn="1997-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-20">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-20">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-22T20:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 192 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2003 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23T11:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 192 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23T11:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 192.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5595-5622" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23T11:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2003 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23T11:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 192, the House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23T13:07:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23T13:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Thurman moved to recommit with instructions to The Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23T13:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23T13:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23T13:44:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 148 - 279, 1 Present (Roll no. 300).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5613-5621" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE" datetime="1997-07-23T13:54:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="301" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Failed by recorded vote: 81 - 347 (Roll no. 301).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="192"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget reconciliation"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Child support enforcement"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Economic forecasting"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Entitlements"/>
    <term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal budget process"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal home loan banks"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Presidential messages"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley Authority"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley development"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Ensure that the Bipartisan Balanced Budget Agreement of 1997 Achieves Its Goal Title II: Enforcement Provisions Budget Enforcement Act of 1997 - Title I: Ensure that the Bipartisan Balanced Budget Agreement of 1997 Achieves Its Goal - Sets forth a timetable for completion of certain budget actions by the President, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), and the Congressional Budget Office (CBO). (Sec. 102) Directs the President to submit a special message with the OMB Analysis of Actual Spending Levels and Projections for the Upcoming Year if such Analysis indicates that: (1) deficits or outlays in the most recent fiscal or budget year exceeded or are projected to exceed deficit targets or caps, as appropriate; or (2) revenues in such years were less than or projected to be less than revenue targets. Requires such message to include proposed legislative changes to: (1) offset the net deficit, outlay excess, or revenue shortfall; or (2) revise the deficit or revenue targets or outlay caps contained in this Act. Sets forth congressional procedures for the consideration of legislation to address excess deficits or outlays and revenue shortfalls. (Sec. 103) Requires presidential budgets to be consistent with the spending, revenue, and deficit levels established in this Act or to recommend changes to such levels. Makes it out of order in the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any concurrent budget resolution unless it is consistent with the levels set forth in this Act. (Sec. 104) Sets forth consolidated deficit (or surplus) and revenue targets for FY 1998 through 2002. (Sec. 105) Requires OMB to submit a report containing account numbers and spending limits for specific entitlement categories to the President and the Congress. Applies direct spending caps, effective upon submission of such report, to all entitlement authority except for undistributed offsetting receipts and net interest outlays. Sets forth entitlement categories subject to caps. (Sec. 106) Requires determinations of direct spending caps (as well as any breaches of such caps and actions necessary to remedy such breaches) to be based on certain economic assumptions set forth in the joint explanatory statement of managers accompanying the concurrent resolution on the budget for FY 1998 (House Concurrent Resolution 84) and subject to periodic reestimation based on changed economic conditions or changes in eligible population. (Sec. 107) Provides for automatic adjustments to deficit and revenue targets and caps for entitlements and other mandatory spending to reflect changes in specified economic and other conditions. Title II: Enforcement Provisions - Directs OMB: (1) to compile a statement of actual deficits, revenues, and direct spending for a fiscal year, following the end of that year, identifying such deficits, revenues, and spending by categories of entitlements and other mandatory spending; and (2) in any year in which actual or projected deficits, revenues, or spending in violation of revenue targets or caps by more than one percent of the applicable total revenues or direct spending for the year concerned occurs, to issue a report to the President and the Congress, estimating necessary spending reductions. (Sec. 202) Provides for enforcement of the direct spending caps on categories of spending established under title I of this Act. Applies specified enforcement rules and procedures for any fiscal year in which direct spending exceeds the applicable direct spending cap. (Sec. 203) Sets forth: (1) general rules triggering sequestration to reduce spending for programs subject to direct spending caps; (2) special rules for direct spending programs with certain characteristics; and (3) rules for insurance and loan programs and State grant program formulas. Requires a within session sequester under certain conditions. (Sec. 204) Sets forth procedures for enforcing revenue targets, including delays in implementing tax credits, deductions, exclusions, or cuts under the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1997. (Sec. 205) Exempts certain budget accounts, activities within accounts, or income from sequestration. Authorizes the President to exempt any military personnel account from sequestration or provide for a lower uniform percentage reduction that would otherwise apply, subject to specified congressional notification requirements. (Sec. 206) Sets forth special rules for sequestration orders for: (1) the child support enforcement program under the Social Security Act; (2) the Commodity Credit Corporation; (3) the earned income tax credit; (4) regular and extended unemployment compensation; (5) the Federal Employees Health Benefits Fund; (6) the Federal Housing Finance Board; (7) Federal pay; (8) Medicare; (9) the Postal Service Fund; (10) Department of Energy power marketing administration funds or the Tennessee Valley Authority fund; and (11) programs which provide a businesslike service in exchange for a fee. (Sec. 207) Directs CBO and OMB to report to the President and the Congress the budget baselines for the budget year and the next nine fiscal years. Specifies requirements for the budget baseline. (Sec. 208) Requires amounts to be withheld from allocation to the appropriate congressional committees (within the discretionary caps for each fiscal year) and reserved for natural disasters and other emergency purposes. Provides that such amounts shall be at least one percent of total budget authority and outlays available within those caps for the fiscal year concerned. Sets forth conditions under which reserved amounts shall be made available for allocation to such committees. Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to make it out of order in the House or the Senate to consider legislation containing an emergency designation if it also provides an appropriation or direct spending for any other item or contains other matter. Permits such legislation to contain rescissions or spending reductions.</summary>
</bill>
