<bill session="104" type="h" number="3815" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-10-11">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Miscellaneous Trade and Technical Corrections Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Miscellaneous Trade and Technical Corrections Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical corrections and miscellaneous amendments to trade laws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400085"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-07-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-29T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 104-718.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-07-29T16:49:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="383">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 383.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30T10:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crane moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30T10:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8673-8679" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30T10:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-07-30T10:36:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30T10:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Finance"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-25">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Reported to Senate by Senator Roth with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-09-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="633">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 633.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11805-11813" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Amendment SP 5419 proposed by Senator Nickles for Senator Roth.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Amendment SP 5419 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1996-09-28" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28T23:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crane asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-09-28T23:03:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12152-12164" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28T23:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1996-10-01">
      <text>By Senator Roth from Committee on Finance filed written report. Report No. 104-393.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-10-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-10-11">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-10-11" type="public" number="104-295">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-295.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Antidumping"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Barges"/>
    <term name="Beverages"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Cattle"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Citrus fruits"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Coffee"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Container ships"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fireworks"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Free ports and zones"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Frozen food"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Herbicides"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Italy"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leather industry"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lighterage"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Machinery in industry"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Motorcycles"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Property"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Silver"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Spices"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Swine"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Tea"/>
    <term name="Telescopes"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Textile industry and fabrics"/>
    <term name="Thailand"/>
    <term name="Tools"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5419"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/28/1996--Passed Senate amended.
Miscellaneous Trade and Technical Corrections Act of 1996 - Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to require that, in the case of a claim for the reliquidation (refund) of excess duties paid on certain entries of North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) products, interest on such a claim accrue from the date of the claim. (Sec. 3) Amends Federal customs law to repeal the requirement that certain small vessels departing from a foreign port, or which visited a hovering vessel, carry a certificate for the importation into the United States of alcoholic spirits. Requires all persons who are indebted to the Government under the customs laws to pay all costs associated with the collection of such debt. (Sec. 4) Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to require certain customs fees charged against merchandise imported from a foreign trade zone to be applied only to the value of the privileged or nonprivileged part of such merchandise. Declares that the similar application of such customs fees to imported U.S. agricultural products processed and packed in a foreign trade zone shall be effective to entries made on or after certain dates. (Sec. 7) Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to authorize the United States Customs Service to extend for up to 18 months the time for filing a drawback (refund) claim for duties if a major disaster on or after January 1, 1994, prevented timely filing of such claim. (Sec. 8) Directs the Customs Service to provide for the liquidation or reliquidation (refund) of certain entries (televisions) made at New York, New York, in accordance with the results of an administrative review, during the period from May 1, 1984, through March 31, 1985, by the International Trade Administration of the Department of Commerce (case number A-580-008). (Sec. 9) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to grant duty-free treatment, through February 1, 1999, of the personal effects of, and other equipment imported and used by, participants, their families and associated members, and officials involved in the 1998 Goodwill Games. (Sec. 12) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to state that importers of civil aircraft that have been entered duty-free: (1) shall maintain such supporting documentation as the Secretary of the Treasury may require; and (2) shall be deemed to certify that such an imported article is a civil aircraft, or has been imported for use in civil aircraft and will so be used. (Currently, importers must file a statement, along with the supporting documentation, with the appropriate customs officer declaring that such article is and will be used as a civil aircraft, or that it has been imported for use in civil aircraft, and that it has been approved for such use by the Federal Aviation Administration.) (Sec. 14) Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to provide that certain marking requirements with respect to imported articles and containers shall not apply to: (1) certain coffee and tea products; and (2) spice products. (Sec. 15) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to grant duty-free treatment to certain imported silver, gold, and platinum bars. Provides for staged rate reductions for specified items. (Sec. 16) Grants duty-free treatment to certain semimanufactured forms of gold. (Sec. 17) Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to repeal the mandate for the East-West Trade Statistics Monitoring System. (Sec. 18) Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to revise requirements for the retroactive electronic filing (reconciliation) of entries with the Customs Service. (Sec. 19) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to impose a specified duty on the foreign value content of certain motor vehicles manufactured in a foreign trade zone, exported to and subsequently imported from a NAFTA country. (Sec. 20) Makes technical and conforming amendments to the Uruguay Round Agreements Act and the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act. (Sec. 23) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to liquidate or reliquidate as duty-free a certain entry of warp knitting machines. Requires a refund of duties and interest paid with respect to such entry. (Sec. 24) Suspends, through December 31, 1998, the duty on methyl 2-(4- (2,4-dichlorophenoxy)phenoxy) propionate (diclofop-methyl) in bulk form or in forms or packages for retail sale containing no other pesticide products. (Sec. 25) Grants duty-free treatment to: (1) 2-amino-3-chlorobenzoic acid, methyl ester; and (2) 3,3-diaminobenzidine (tetraamino biphenyl). (Sec. 27) Amends the Customs and Trade Act of 1990 to declare that the duty on foreign repairs made to U.S.-flag vessels shall not apply to the cost of equipment or spare parts for repairs made to certain U.S.-flag LASH (Lighter Aboard Ship) barges that entered the United States between January 1, 1993, and December 31, 1994, provided certain conditions are met. (Sec. 28) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to impose duties upon certain fireworks. Increases the column one duty rate regarding specified other types of fireworks. (Sec. 29) Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to provide for a personal allowance exemption, upon their return to U.S. customs territory, from duties on merchandise purchased by U.S. residents in a duty-free sales enterprise, provided the person meets certain exemption eligibility requirements. (Sec. 30) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to suspend, through December 31, 2006, the duty on U.S. made motorcycles previously exported and brought temporarily into the United States by nonresidents who participate in the Sturgis Motorcycle Rally and Races. (Sec. 31) Amends the Foreign Trade Zones Act to permit deferral of duty payment on merchandise admitted into a foreign trade zone for use as production equipment until such equipment is completely assembled, installed, tested, and used in the production for which it was admitted. (Sec. 32) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to reduce, through December 31, 1998, the duty on n-phenyl-n'- (1,2,3-thiadiazol-5'yl urea (thidiazuron) in bulk or in forms or packages for retail sale. (Sec. 33) Grants, through December 31, 1999, duty-free treatment to: (1) 2,3,3-trimethyl-indolenine; and (2) bis (4-amino-3- methylcyclohexyl)-methane. (Sec. 35) Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to prohibit the President from designating a country a beneficiary developing country under the generalized system of preferences if the Secretary of State determines under the Export Administration Act of 1979 that such country has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism. (Sec. 36) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to suspend, through March 31, 1997, the duty on certain chemicals used in the formulation of an HIV protease inhibitor. (Sec. 37) Requires buffalo leather from Thailand that is entered into the United States under certain entry numbers to be liquidated or reliquidated as if entered on June 30, 1995. (Sec. 38) Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to proscribe any fee assessment for certain customs services provided in connection with the arrival of any passenger on board a commercial vessel traveling only between ports within U.S. customs territory (unless the vessel's journey originates and terminates at the same place in the United States without intervening stops). (Sec. 41) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to liquidate or reliquidate as duty-free certain entries of lead fuel test assembles. Requires a refund of duties paid with respect to such entries. (Sec. 42) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to suspend, through December 31, 2000, the duty on certain injection molding machines. (Sec. 43) Directs the Customs Service to provide for the liquidation or reliquidation (refund) of certain entries of color televisions made at various ports, in accordance with the final results of an administrative review, during the period from April 1, 1984, through March 31, 1991, by the International Trade Administration of the Department of Commerce (case number A-580-008). (Sec. 44) Grants duty-free treatment to professional books, implements, instruments, and tools of trade, occupation, or employment in repair and maintenance services, when returned to the United States after having been exported for use temporarily abroad, if imported by or for the account of the person who exported such items. (Sec. 45) Grants, through December 31, 2000, duty-free treatment to yttrium oxide and cerium aluminum terbium of a kind used as luminophores. (Sec. 46) Provides for the liquidation or reliquidation at a lower duty rate of certain entries of pharmaceutical grade phospholipids. (Sec. 47) Authorizes and directs the Secretary of the Treasury to admit duty-free, after March 31, 1997, certain structures, parts, and components used in the Gemini Telescopes Project, in Mauna Kea, Hawaii. (Sec. 48) Amends the Trade and Tariff Act of 1984 to extend indefinitely the existing duty-free treatment of articles provided by the Max Planck Institute for Radioastronomy, Germany, to Steward Observatory, Arizona. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to admit duty-free large binocular telescope components, parts, and equipment provided by the Arcetri Astrophysical Observatory and the Max Planck Institute for use by the Steward Observatory of the University of Arizona. (Sec. 49) Directs the Customs Service to liquidate or reliquidate (refund) certain entries of frozen concentrated orange juice. (Sec. 50) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to set the duty rate, including specified staged rate reductions, for certain twine, cordage, ropes, and cable. (Sec. 51) Suspends, through December 31, 2000, the duty on certain fatty acid esters. (Sec. 52) Grants duty-free treatment to a Mobile Bison Slaughter Unit for use by the Pte Hca Ka. (Sec. 53) Exempts from tariff treatment under the Schedule certain aircraft parts and equipment. (Sec. 54) Directs the Customs Service to provide for the liquidation or reliquidation (refund) of certain entries of live swine, in accordance with the final results of the administrative review, during the period from April 1, 1988, through March 31, 1989, by the International Trade Administration of the Department of Commerce. (Sec. 55) Provides, based on the decision issued by the United States Court of International Trade in Pfaff American Sales Corp. v. United States, for the liquidation or reliquidation (refund) of certain entries of sewing machines. (Sec. 56) Suspends, through December 31, 1998, the duty on: (1) certain textured rolled glass sheets; and (2) n,n-diethyl-m-toluidine (DEMT). (Sec. 58) Directs the International Trade Commission to report to the appropriate congressional committees on: (1) the impact of NAFTA and the Uruguay Round Agreements on U.S. imports and exports of live cattle for slaughter and fresh, chilled, and frozen beef; and (2) the steps taken by the United States, since the enactment of NAFTA, to prevent the transshipment of such items through Mexico and Canada for importation into the United States. (Sec. 59) Authorizes the President to waive certain quota requirements for those products that exceed them for 1994, as in effect on June 30, 1995, and which lost eligibility for duty-free treatment under the generalized system of preferences as of July 1, 1995.</summary>
</bill>
