<bill session="108" type="h" number="2070" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare+Choice Revitalization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to revitalize and improve the Medicare+Choice program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400161"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400139" joined="2003-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2003-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Welfare recipients"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2003--Introduced.
Medicare+Choice Revitalization Act of 2003 - Amends part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to make each annual Medicare+Choice capitation rate for a Medicare+Choice payment area for a contract year equal to the largest of the amounts specified under current law or, for 2004 and any subsequent year, 100 percent of the fee-for-service costs for the Medicare+Choice payment area for services covered under Medicare parts A (Hospital Insurance) or B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) for individuals entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B who are not enrolled in a Medicare+Choice plan for the year.Provides that, in determining the adjusted average per capita cost of Medicare+Choice for a year, such cost shall be adjusted to include the Secretary of Health and Human Services's estimate, on a per capita basis, of the amount of additional payments that would have been made in the area involved under Medicare if individuals entitled to Medicare benefits had not received services from facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) or the Department of Defense (DOD).Revises the calculation of the national standardized annual Medicare+Choice capitation rate used in determining the input-price-adjusted annual national Medicare+Choice capitation rate for a Medicare+Choice payment area.Terminates use of a payment adjustment budget neutrality factor after 2003.Raises the minimum percentage increase for calculation of annual Medicare+Choice capitation rates, beginning 2004, to 104 percent of the annual rate for the area for the previous year.Provides for the inclusion of costs of DOD and VA military facility services to Medicare-eligible beneficiaries in calculation of Medicare+Choice payment rates.Makes permanent the current Medicare+Choice reporting deadlines, and makes the month of November the permanent annual coordinated election period.Declares that Federal standards supercede certain State law or regulations with respect to Medicare+Choice plans.Prescribes requirements for specialized Medicare+Choice plans for special needs beneficiaries, allowing them to be any type of coordinated care plan.</summary>
</bill>
