<bill session="106" type="h" number="4278" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fishable Waters Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to establish a program for fisheries habitat protection, restoration, and enhancement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400395"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2000-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="2000-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400578" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="2000-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="2000-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2441"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural runoff"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Farmland protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Forestry"/>
    <term name="Freshwater ecology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Groundwater pollution"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nonpoint source pollution"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban runoff"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2000--Introduced.
Fishable Waters Act of 2000 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (the Act) to require States, in order to be eligible for assistance under the Fishable Waters Act of 2000, to establish programs for the protection and restoration of fresh water, estuarine, and marine fisheries habitat and for the enhancement of access for fisheries uses through watershed planning and the implementation of projects and measures that meet such Act's requirements.Establishes minimum program requirements. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary), upon approval of a program submitted by a State, to: (1) make grants to the State for program administration; and (2) enter into a memorandum of understanding with the State under which the State may make grants to designated watershed councils for development of comprehensive fisheries habitat protection, restoration, and enhancement plans and interim recommendations that address high priority factors causing imminent adverse impacts or threats to fisheries habitat located in high priority portions of waters within a watershed.Permits States to designate watershed councils to carry out comprehensive fisheries habitat protection, restoration, and enhancement plans that meet specified minimum requirements. Sets forth council requirements. Requires States, in designating such councils, to give preference to existing councils or similar bodies organized under other authorities for purposes similar to those under this Act. Makes designated councils eligible to receive funding to carry out planning functions.Requires councils to collect and consider the best available scientific information and develop additional data and information as necessary. Provides for revisions or updates of comprehensive fisheries plans at least once every five years. Requires submission of plans or interim recommendations to the State for approval.Makes projects and measures that support or implement specific recommendations contained in a plan or interim recommendation eligible for financial support from a State's fisheries habitat account established pursuant to this Act. Authorizes States to provide funds from a fisheries habitat account to persons who enter into binding contracts for implementation of projects and measures recommended by councils pursuant to approved plans or interim recommendations. Prohibits expenditures from such accounts for the planning, engineering, design, or construction of dams or of roads on public lands. Requires States to establish a system of limits on the maximum percentage of total costs for a project that may be provided from such accounts based on a priority ranking of recommendations. Permits expenditures from such accounts for the payment of up to 15 percent of required non-Federal shares under certain Federal environmental, agriculture, forestry, wildlife, flood control, and water resources programs if recommended in a plan or interim recommendations.Authorizes, if specifically recommended in a plan or interim recommendations, increases in expenditures pursuant to Federal programs for flood damage compensation for loss of crops, livestock, or structures with respect to specifically designated lands within a watershed that would be subject to increased flooding due to certain recommended projects. Requires the baseline jurisdictional status of any agricultural lands on which wetlands may be created or expanded as a result of flooding or altered drainage pursuant to such projects to revert to their baseline jurisdictional status upon termination of any project agreement. Provides that a permit under the Act shall not be required for discharges from any wetlands created or expanded for agricultural pollution control purposes if pollutants entering such wetlands result only from normal agricultural practices such as crop production, raising of livestock, or silvicultural activities.Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, to establish a community fisheries habitat revitalization program. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, pursuant to such program, to provide funding and technical assistance to State fish and wildlife agencies for development and construction of projects designed to improve urban watersheds and public access to the waters of such watersheds in order to restore fisheries habitat or enhance fisheries uses and to provide recreational opportunities. Describes eligible projects and project priorities. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to report annually to Congress on the program.Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a community fisheries habitat clearinghouse to support local implementation of projects under the program.Sets forth limitations on funding under the program. Authorizes appropriations.Requires the Secretary to publish a report at least biennially on the progress of watershed council programs. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to publish a report at least biennially describing the state of the Nation's fishery habitats as well as the overall progress being achieved in protecting and restoring such habitats.Requires the Secretary of the Interior to compile and provide scientific information for consideration by State fish and wildlife agencies in developing fisheries-related indicators and associated habitat characteristics and for consideration by councils in characterizing waters and establishing watershed objectives pursuant to this Act. Authorizes such factors to be established by such agencies to set forth the appropriate factors, indicators, measurements, and other considerations which will be indicative of a healthy, resilient, diverse, and productive aquatic system and may distinguish among general categories of fisheries based upon natural variations.Requires the Secretary to make grants to States for fisheries programs approved under this Act. Authorizes appropriations.Requires States with approved programs to establish fisheries habitat accounts for providing financial support for projects and measures recommended by watershed councils.Authorizes appropriations for grants to States to enable States to provide funds to any person, through a fisheries habitat account, for implementation of: (1) any measures for restricting livestock access to waters within a designated watershed and for providing alternative water supplies for such livestock; and (2) approved recommendations.Requires the Secretary to provide Congress with an annual survey of projected funding needs for States with approved fisheries programs.Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out responsibilities under this Act.Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Directors of the Fish and Wildlife Service and the Geological Survey, to establish a national planning program for protection and restoration of fisheries habitat through improved floodplain management practices on major waterways.Directs the Secretary of the Interior to issue information describing methodologies for identifying instream flows necessary to protect fisheries habitat. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Directors of the Geological Survey and the Fish and Wildlife Service, to provide technical assistance and prepare and disseminate technical information on fisheries-related needs for instream flows to the public. Authorizes appropriations for expenditures related to support the maintenance of designated instream flows or volumes.Treats Indian tribes as States for purposes of this Act.(Sec. 4) Reauthorizes appropriations for FY 2002 through 2006 under the Act for grants for: (1) implementation of nonpoint source pollution control management programs; and (2) groundwater quality protection activities to advance States toward implementation of comprehensive nonpoint source pollution control programs. Authorizes appropriations for such years to carry out this Act as well.</summary>
</bill>
