<bill session="104" type="hc" number="103" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing support for equal and fair access to higher education in the Albanian language in the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1996-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1996-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404298" joined="1996-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1996-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="405560" joined="1996-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1996-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407817" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1996-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1996-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-22">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from State.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="sc" number="31"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Albanians"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Macedonia"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Pardons"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Textbooks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/1995--Introduced.
Calls for the Government of the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia to: (1) ensure the fair treatment of all of its citizens regardless of ethnic background and the establishment of Albanian-language pedagogical faculties at established universities in Macedonia; and (2) consider all means by which higher education conducted in the Albanian language can be provided, including the establishment of an Albanian-language university. Commends the efforts by the High Commissioner for National Minorities of the Organization on Security and Cooperation in Europe, the Council of Europe, and the Working Group on Ethnic Minorities of the International Conference on the Former Yugoslavia to offer guidance and mediation to the Macedonian Government and representatives of the Albanian minority in resolving the issue of higher education in the Albanian language. Urges: (1) the President to express to that Government strong U.S. support for measures that will contribute to democracy and stability in Macedonia and offer appropriate support for the efforts of the High Commissioner and the Macedonian Government to ensure access to higher education in the Albanian language; and (2) the President of Macedonia to employ appropriate authority under the Constitution of Macedonia to pardon those convicted of charges relating to the events that accompanied attempts to open university-level classes in the Albanian language at Tetovo, Macedonia, in February 1995.</summary>
</bill>
