<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1004" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="5715" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2008-04-17T13:45:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-04-17"/>
  <description>Manager's amendment made technical and conforming changes to the bill; stated that loan limit increases available under this Act are available only to students meeting the requirements of section 484(a) of the HEA; targeted the loan limit increases to those students and families in most need; in regard to school-wide lender-of-last-resort eligibility, specified that the Secretary of Education shall determine whether a school qualifies and provided criteria for the Secretary to consider in making the determination; specified that funds received by lenders from loan sales be used to originate new loans; clarified that the Secretary has the authority to enter into forward commitments to purchase new loans; and clarified that, at the discretion of the Secretary, a loan purchased by the Secretary may continue to be serviced by the current lender.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 110-590 to make technical and conforming changes; state that loan limit increases available under this Act are available only to students meeting the requirements of section 484(a) of the HEA; target the loan limit increases to those students and families in most need; in regard to school-wide lender-of-last-resort eligibility, specifies that the Secretary of Education shall determine whether a school qualifies and provides criteria for the Secretary to consider in making the determination; specifies that funds received by lenders from loan sales be used to originate new loans; clarifiy that the Secretary has the authority to enter into forward commitments to purchase new loans; and clarifies that, at the discretion of the Secretary, a loan purchased by the Secretary may continue to be serviced by the current lender.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-17T11:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. George Miller.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2462-2463, H2466-2467" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2462" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2008-04-17T13:45:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="203">
      <text>On agreeing to the Miller, George amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 413 - 0 (Roll no. 203).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
