<bill session="104" type="h" number="461" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lorton Correctional Complex Closure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To close the Lorton Correctional Complex, to prohibit the incarceration of individuals convicted of felonies under the laws of the District of Columbia in facilities of the District of Columbia Department of Corrections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400435"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1995-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1995-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1995-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-01-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E59-60"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-09">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-09">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="201"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/9/1995--Introduced.
Lorton Correctional Complex Closure Act - Transfers the Lorton Correctional Complex to the Administrator of General Services (within six years) for disposal in accordance with an implementation plan for the closure of the Complex. Prohibits the establishment of any future District of Columbia (DC) prison facility in Virginia without the approval of the Governor of Virginia. Directs that any DC felon (excluding any individual convicted of a misdemeanor, as a juvenile offender, or any person detained pending trial in DC Superior Court) who is committed to the custody of the Attorney General for a term of imprisonment on or after the enactment date of this Act be incarcerated in a facility designated by the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, in accordance with such rules as the Attorney General may establish to assure that the treatment of such felons is similar to that of others under the control of the Director. Sets forth transition provisions. Requires the Administrator to submit to the Congress an implementation plan for the closure of the Complex which shall identify actions with respect to the future use of the land on which the Complex is located and other specified issues. Establishes a Commission on Closure of the Lorton Correctional Complex. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) a process for submission of the final implementation plan; (2) review of the Commission's proposal; (3) comments by the Commission and its members on the plan to the Administrator; (4) submission of a final plan; (5) automatic implementation of the plan; (6) membership, terms, vacancies, compensation, powers, and termination of the Commission; and (7) staff, experts, and consultants to the Commission. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
