<bill session="104" type="h" number="3653" updated="2012-11-01T22:45:19-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Citizens' Right to Know Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require candidates for the House of Representatives or the Senate to file information included in quarterly candidate reports with the Federal Election Commission within 48 hours of the time the information becomes available, to require all reports filed with the Federal Election Commission to be filed electronically, to require the information contained in such reports to be made available through the Internet, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400528"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Computers in politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>06/13/1996--Introduced.
Citizens' Right to Know Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require that, in addition to filing certain reports, each principal campaign committee of a candidate for the House of Representatives or the Senate file the information required to be included in such reports with the Federal Election Commission (FEC) not later than 48 hours after the information becomes available to the committee. Requires electronic filing of FEC reports beginning January 1, 1999, with the exception of reports filed by a political committee reporting less than the designated threshold amount of contributions or expenditures during the election cycle for which the report is filed. Specifies the threshold amount as: (1) for an authorized committee, $50,000; or (2) for any other political committee, such amount as the FEC may establish by regulation. Directs the FEC to develop and make available without charge any computer software required for the electronic filing of FEC reports. Makes the information contained in FEC reports available on the Internet. Prohibits the use of internet information for commercial purposes or for soliciting contributions.</summary>
</bill>
