<bill session="106" type="h" number="4407" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campus Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to require that registered sexually violent offenders provide notice of any attendance at institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400606"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2000--Introduced.
Campus Protection Act - Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to require any person who is required to register in a State under the Act (as a sexually violent offender) to provide notice to that State of: (1) each institution of higher education in that State at which that person is enrolled; and (2) each change in his or her enrollment status. Requires each State to provide to each institution of higher education in such notice and to the law enforcement agency having jurisdiction over each institution all information with respect to such person that has been collected under the State registration program, including the information in that notice.(Sec. 3) Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require each eligible institution participating in a program regarding Federal assistance to higher education to disseminate information to prospective and enrolled students regarding information contained in such a notice received from a State.</summary>
</bill>
