<bill session="106" type="h" number="2904" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-08T18:31:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-08T18:31:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to reauthorize funding for the Office of Government Ethics.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400608"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-09-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T10:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 106-433, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T10:31:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 2, 1999.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T10:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-11-02T10:31:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="253">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 253.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08T15:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McHugh moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08T15:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11664-11666" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08T15:02:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2904.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08T15:12:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08T18:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11676-11677" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-11-08T18:31:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="575" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 386 - 1 (Roll no. 575).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08T18:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-08T18:31:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-11-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="422">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 422.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1503"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Office of Government Ethics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/1999--Passed House amended.
Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to extend through FY 2003 the authorization of appropriations for the Office of Government Ethics.Amends the Federal criminal code provisions concerning bribery, graft, and conflicts of interest to include within the definition of "special Government employee" a Reserve officer or officer in the National Guard who is serving voluntarily for not to exceed 130 days during any period of 365 consecutive days. Includes as an "officer" and "employee" the following: (1) an individual retained, designated, appointed, or employed in the U.S. Government or in the District of Columbia government to perform with or without compensation and subject to the supervision of the President, Vice President, Member of Congress, Federal judge, or officer or employee of the U.S. or District Government a Federal or District function (as defined in this Act) under authority of law or executive Act; (2) a Reserve officer or officer in the National Guard who is serving voluntarily for not to exceed 130 days during any period of 365 consecutive days; and (3) the President, Vice President, Member of Congress, or Federal judge to the extent specified under such provisions.Excludes as an officer or employee or special Government employee: (1) enlisted members of the armed forces; and (2) an individual who is retained, designated, or appointed without compensation specifically to act as a representative of an interest on an advisory committee established pursuant to the Federal Advisory Committee Act or any similarly established committee whose meetings are generally open to the public.</summary>
</bill>
