<bill session="105" type="h" number="16" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Health Insurance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a program of national health insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Dentists"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health services administration"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home nursing"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical associations"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice insurance"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="National health insurance"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Value-added tax"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Benefits and Eligibility Title II: Participation of Physicians, Dentists, Nurses, Hospitals, and Others Title III: Local Administration Title IV: State Administration Title V: National Health Insurance Board; National Advisory Medical Policy Council; General Administrative Provisions Title VI: Eligibility Determinations, Complaints, Hearings, and Judicial Review Title VII: Application of Act to Individuals Covered Under Medicare Program Title VIII: Fiscal Provisions Title IX: Miscellaneous Provisions Title X: Value Added Tax and National Health Care Trust Fund Title XI: Study and Development of Cost Control Mechanisms National Health Insurance Act - Title I: Benefits and Eligibility - Makes medical services available to eligible individuals. (Sec. 102) Authorizes the National Health Insurance Board to limit services when personnel, facilities, or funds are inadequate. (Sec. 103) Allows patient choice of physicians and hospitals. (Sec. 105) Makes Federal grants to States under the Social Security Act available to the States for services for uninsured needy individuals. Title II: Participation of Physicians, Dentists, Nurses, Hospitals, and Others - Authorizes State agreements with individuals or organizations for service provision. (Sec. 208) Regulates payment bases and rates, requiring local adjustments. (Sec. 210) Allows providers to choose their practice locality and, consistent with State law and professional ethics, reject patients. Title III: Local Administration - Decentralizes administration to local administrative committees or officers. (Sec. 303) Requires establishment in each health service area of a local area committee and local professional committees. Title IV: State Administration - Expresses the intent of the Congress that benefit provisions be administered by each State. Provides for Board administration if State plans are not approved and complied with. Title V: National Health Insurance Board; National Advisory Medical Policy Council; General Administrative Provisions - Establishes: (1) in the Department of Health and Human Services the National Health Insurance Board; (2) the National Advisory Medical Policy Council. Title VI: Eligibility Determinations, Complaints, Hearings, and Judicial Review - Requires that the Secretary of Health and Human Services determine benefit eligibility. (Sec. 602) Describes complaint investigation procedures. Title VII: Application of Act to Individuals Covered Under Medicare Program - Limits, for individuals entitled to benefits under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, benefits under this Act to services for which the individual is not eligible under Medicare. (Sec. 702) Mandates a study of the relationship of this Act's program and Medicare. Title VIII: Fiscal Provisions - Makes National Health Care Trust Fund amounts available for expenditures under this Act. (Sec. 802) Directs the Board to determine amounts to be made available from the Fund and allotments to the States. (Sec. 803) Authorizes grants to: (1) educational institutions regarding the training of personnel providing or administering benefits; and (2) individuals in courses regarding the provision or administration of benefits. Requires that funds be made available. Title IX: Miscellaneous Provisions - Requires that benefits first become available on a specified date. Title X: Value Added Tax and National Health Care Trust Fund - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a tax on each taxable transaction (the sale of property, performance of services, and importing of property by a taxable person in a commercial-type transaction). Sets the tax rate at zero for: (1) retail food, principal residence housing (sale and rental), and medical care; (2) certain transactions involving governmental entities; and (3) certain tax-exempt organizations. Makes the person selling the property or services liable for the tax. (Sec. 1002) Establishes the National Health Care Trust Fund. Appropriates to the Fund amounts received from the value added tax. Allows the Fund to be used only to carry out the program under this Act. Title XI: Study and Development of Cost Control Mechanisms - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) conduct a study on controlling benefit costs, including malpractice claims and malpractice insurance costs; (2) report to the Congress; and (3) implement the report's recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
