<bill session="107" type="hc" number="275" updated="2013-07-14T18:59:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-03-06T13:26:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-03-06T13:26:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress that hunting seasons for migratory mourning doves should be modified so that individuals have a fair and equitable opportunity to hunt such birds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-02-27">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-03-04T14:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-362.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-03-04T14:09:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="126">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 126.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-03-05T18:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 353 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 275 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-06T11:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 353 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-06T13:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 353.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H708-710" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-06T13:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 275 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-06T13:18:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 353 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-06T13:18:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John Shimkus to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-06T13:18:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H. Con. Res. 275.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-06T13:25:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H. Con. Res. 275.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-06T13:26:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-03-06T13:26:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H709" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-03-06T13:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="107" type="hr" number="353"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Game and game birds"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2002--Reported to House without amendment.
Expresses the sense of Congress that, to provide a fair and equitable opportunity for individuals to hunt for mourning doves: (1) the Migratory Bird Treaty Act of 1918 should be modified to allow for mourning dove hunting during the last week in August in areas north of 37 degrees north latitude; (2) the United States should begin discussions with the appropriate parties to ensure that all Americans have an opportunity to harvest migratory mourning doves in an equitable manner; and (3) hunters and wildlife management agencies in States north of 37 degrees north latitude should support an earlier opening date for the mourning dove hunting season.</summary>
</bill>
