<bill session="108" type="h" number="4661" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-07T11:41:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-07T11:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Spyware bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Internet Spyware (I-SPY) Prevention Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Internet Spyware (I-SPY) Prevention Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Internet Spyware (I-SPY) Prevention Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to discourage spyware, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2004-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2004-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1235"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-23T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 108-698.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-09-23T15:19:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="426">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 426.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06T15:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06T15:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8250-8252" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06T15:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4661.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07T11:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8649-8650" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-10-07T11:41:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="503" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 415 - 0 (Roll no. 503).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/6/2004 H8250" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07T11:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer hackers"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2004--Passed House amended.
Internet Spyware (I-SPY) Prevention Act of 2004 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit intentionally accessing a protected computer without authorization, or exceeding authorized access, by causing a computer program or code to be copied onto the protected computer, and intentionally using that program or code: (1) in furtherance of another Federal criminal offense; (2) to obtain or transmit personal information (including a Social Security number or other government-issued identification number, a bank or credit card number, or an associated password or access code) with intent to defraud or injure a person or cause damage to a protected computer; or (3) to impair the security protection of that computer. Prohibits any person from bringing a civil action under State law premised upon the defendant's violating this Act. Provides that this Act does not prohibit any lawfully authorized investigative, protective, or intelligence activity of a law enforcement agency or a U.S. intelligence agency. Authorizes appropriations for each of FY 2005 through 2008 to the Attorney General for prosecutions needed to discourage the use of spyware (i.e., software that aids in gathering and sending information about a person or organization, or in asserting control over their computer, without their knowledge or consent) and the practice called phishing (i.e., using the websites of, or e-mails that appear to be sent from, well known legitimate businesses to deceive Internet users into revealing personal information that can be used to defraud those users). Expresses the sense of Congress that the Department of Justice should use this Act and all other available tools to vigorously prosecute those who use spyware to commit crimes and those that conduct phishing scams.</summary>
</bill>
