<bill session="105" type="hj" number="94" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Continuing Appropriation (first)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 1998, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406863"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-26T09:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Livingston asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Appropriations be discharged from the further consideration of H.J. Res. 94 when called up; and that it be in order at any time on Monday, September 29, 1997, or any day thereafter, to consider the joint resolution in the House; that the joint resolution be considered as read for amendment; that the joint resolution be debatable for not to exceed one hour, to be equally divided and controlled by Mr. Livingston and Mr. Obey; and that the previous question be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion, except one motion to recommit, with or without instructions. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-26T09:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Livingston asked unanimous consent That the Committee on Appropriations be discharged from the further consideration of H.J. Res. 94 when called up; and that it be in order at any time on Monday, September 29, 1997, or any day thereafter, to consider the joint resolution in the House; that the joint resolution be considered as read for amendment; that the joint resolution be debatable for not to exceed one hour, to be equally divided and controlled by Mr. Livingston and Mr. Obey; and that the previous question be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion, except one motion to recommit, with or without instructions. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-29T17:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-29T17:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated by order of the House of September 26, 1997.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-29T17:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by order of the House of Sept. 26.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8097-8101" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-29T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of the order of the House on Friday, September 26, 1997, the House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-29T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-09-29T18:11:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="461" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 355 - 57 (Roll no. 461).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-09-29T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1997-09-30" how="roll" result="pass" roll="261" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 99-0. Record Vote No: 261.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10204" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1997-09-30">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1997-09-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1997-09-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1997-09-30" type="public" number="105-46">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-46.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Export-Import Bank of the United States"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/1997--Introduced.
Makes appropriations for FY 1998 for continuing projects or activities, including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees, which were conducted in FY 1997 and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority would be available in: (1) the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998; (2) the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998; (3) the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 1998; (4) the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1998; (5) the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1998; (6) the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1998; (7) the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998; (8) the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998; (9) the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1998; (10) the Military Construction Appropriations Act, 1998; (11) the Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 1998; (12) the Treasury, Postal Service, and General Government Appropriations Act, 1998; and (13) the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998. Sets forth the rates of (current rates, with specified exceptions), and limitations on, such funding. Provides funding under this resolution until enactment into law of any covered appropriation or the applicable appropriations Act or October 23, 1997, whichever occurs first. Continues provisions of the Immigration and Nationality Act pertaining to a visa waiver pilot program for certain visitors through the effective period of this resolution. Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to extend the authority to enter into new flood insurance contracts through October 23, 1997. Authorizes the District of Columbia government to delay repayment of the 1997 Treasury advances beyond October 1, 1997, until it receives the full year Federal contribution. Waives any interest or penalties otherwise applicable to late payments. Continues the issuing authority of the Overseas Private Investment Corporation through the effective period of this resolution. Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to extend the Export-Import Bank's functions through October 23, 1997. Extends, through October 23, 1997, certain provisions of the Immigration and Nationality Act pertaining to the issuance of immigrant visas within 90 days' of an alien's departure and the adjustment to permanent resident status of certain aliens.</summary>
</bill>
