<bill session="105" type="h" number="3246" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-26T20:24:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-03-26T20:24:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Small Business and Employee Fairness bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fairness for Small Business and Employees Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Fairness for Small Business and Employees Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Fairness for Small Business and Employees Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assist small businesses and labor organizations in defending themselves against government bureaucracy; to ensure that employees entitled to reinstatement get their jobs back quickly; to protect the right of employers to have a hearing to present their case in certain representation cases; and, to prevent the use of the National Labor Relations Act for the purpose of disrupting or inflicting economic harm on employers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400568" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404009" joined="1998-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="1998-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400547" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400225" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1998-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1998-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="409228" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410136" joined="1998-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1998-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1998-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400540" joined="1998-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="1998-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-02-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E195-196"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 7 - 3.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 18.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-17T18:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Dreier notified the House that members wishing to offer amendments to the bill should submit 55 copies of proposed amendments to the Committee on Rules (Rm. 312, Capitol) by 2 p.m. on Monday, March 23, 1998.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-18T15:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 105-453.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-03-18T15:51:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="259">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 259.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T14:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 393 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3246. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. No amendment to shall be in order except the amendment printed in the report accompanying this resolution, to be offered in the order and manner specified in the report, and not subject to further amendment or a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T18:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 393 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T18:15:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 393 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T18:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Bill McCollum to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T18:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 393.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1609-1623" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T18:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3246. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. No amendment shall be in order except the amendment printed in the report accompanying this resolution, to be offered in the order and manner specified in the report, and not subject to further amendment or a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T18:15:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T19:28:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 393, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Goodling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T20:05:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3246.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T20:06:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T20:06:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-03-26T20:24:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="78" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 202 - 200 (Roll No. 78).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T20:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="393"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining unit"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor union elections"/>
    <term name="Labor union membership"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h538"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/26/1998--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Truth in Employment Title II: Fair Hearing Title III: Justice on Time Title IV: Attorneys Fees Fairness for Small Business and Employees Act of 1998 - Title I: Truth in Employment - Amends the National Labor Relations Act (NLRA) to provide that nothing in specified prohibitions against unfair labor practices by employers shall be construed as requiring an employer to employ any person who is not a bona fide employee applicant, in that such person seeks or has sought employment with the employer with the primary purpose of furthering another employment or agency status. (Sec. 103) Declares that this title shall not affect the rights and responsibilities under NLRA of any employee who is or was a bona fide employee applicant, including the right to: (1) self-organization; (2) form, join, or assist labor organizations; (3) bargain collectively through representatives of their own choosing; and (4) engage in other concerted activities for the purpose of collective bargaining or other mutual aid or protection. Title II: Fair Hearing - Directs the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) to provide for a hearing upon due notice to determine the appropriateness of the bargaining unit, if a petition for an election requests to certify a unit which includes the employees employed at one or more facilities of a multi-facility employer, and in the absence of an agreement by the parties regarding the appropriateness of the bargaining unit at issue. Requires the NLRB, in making such determination, to consider functional integration, centralized control, common skills, functions and working conditions, permanent and temporary employee interchange, geographical separation, local autonomy, the number of employees, bargaining history, and other factors it considers appropriate. Title III: Justice on Time - Requires the NLRB to state its findings of fact and to issue and serve corrective orders, including reinstatement of an employee with or without backpay, or issue an order dismissing the complaint, within 365 days after the filing of a charge of unfair labor practice involving an unlawful discharge, except in cases of extreme complexity. Directs the NLRB to report annually to specified congressional committees on any cases pending for more than one year, including an explanation of the factors contributing to such a delay, and recommendations for prompt resolution of such cases. Title IV: Attorneys Fees - Provides for awards of attorney's fees and costs in administrative or court proceedings involving the NLRB, without regard to whether the NLRB's position was substantially justified or special circumstances make an award unjust, if the prevailing parties are employers or labor organizations with no more than 100 employees and a net worth of no more than $1.4 million at the time the adversary adjudication was initiated.</summary>
</bill>
