<bill session="106" type="h" number="2786" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Interstate Transmission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for expansion of electricity transmission networks in order to support competitive electricity markets and to bring the benefits of less regulation of such markets to the public, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400539"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1999-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1999-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1999-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
Interstate Transmission Act - Amends the Federal Power Policy Act (FPA) to incorporate within its jurisdiction the unbundled transmission of electric energy sold at retail.(Sec. 3) Directs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to determine by rule or order which facilities used for the transmission and delivery of electric energy are used in interstate commerce (subject to its jurisdiction), and which are used for local distribution (subject to State jurisdiction).Redefines "interstate commerce" to include, for FPA purposes, consumption of electricity in a foreign country.(Sec. 4) Repeals the statutory constraints placed upon the disposition of property by a public utility subject to FERC jurisdiction.(Sec. 5) Requires FERC to permit a transmitting utility to recover all its costs incurred in connection with the transmission services and necessary associated services, including the costs of any enlargement of transmission facilities. Prescribes guidelines for FERC review of rates, charges, terms, and conditions for transmission service, including: (1) voluntary innovative pricing policies; (2) negotiated rates; and (3) recovery of market-based rates for transmission services.(Sec. 6) Authorizes a transmitting utility to require both its transmission customers and any transmitting utility with which it is interconnected to observe policies or standards adopted by a FERC- approved electric reliability organization as a prerequisite to receiving transmission service.(Sec. 7) Authorizes FERC encouragement of the formation of regional transmission organizations to enhance transmission of electric energy in interstate commerce.</summary>
</bill>
