<bill session="105" type="h" number="2839" updated="2012-11-01T22:48:45-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Quality Child Care for Federal Employees Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the quality of child care provided through Federal facilities and programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on House Oversight, the Judiciary, Ways and Means, and Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" name="House Banking and Financial Services" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Child care block grants"/>
    <term name="Child care workers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>11/06/1997--Introduced.
Quality Child Care for Federal Employees Act - Mandates that a Federal agency that either operates, or contracts for operation of, a child care center in a facility owned or leased by an executive agency obtain the appropriate State and local licenses and comply with child care licensing requirements. Directs the Administrator of General Services to: (1) establish and enforce child care health, safety and facility standards; and (2) require child care center compliance with accreditation standards issued by a nationally recognized accreditation organization approved by the Administrator. Prescribes enforcement procedures. Instructs the Architect of the Capitol and the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts to promulgate regulations for child care centers in legislative and judicial facilities which are no less stringent than those issued by the Administrator. Confers upon the Architect and the Director child care center duties and authorities comparable to those of the Administrator. Provides for technical assistance, studies, and reviews in order to assist child care center operator compliance with this Act. Instructs the Administrator to establish an interagency council to facilitate cooperation and coordinate policy regarding the provision of child care in the Federal Government. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, the Secretaries of Education, of Housing and Urban Development, and of Labor, and the Attorney General to ensure that any child care made available under any Federal financial assistance program shall be provided by an accredited child care center or a credentialed child care professional. Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to authorize the use of community development block grants to establish accredited child care centers by upgrading existing child care facilities to meet standards for accredited child care centers or by renovating existing structures for use as accredited child care centers.</summary>
</bill>
