<bill session="106" type="h" number="4764" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the United States Trade Representative to enter into negotiations to eliminate price controls imposed by certain foreign countries on prescription drugs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400581"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="2000-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Italy"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Price regulation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2000--Introduced.
Directs the United States Trade Representative (USTR) to enter into negotiations with the Governments of the other G-8 countries (Canada, France, Germany, Great Britain, Italy, Japan, Russia, and the United States) in order to achieve their agreement to eliminate price controls on innovative medicines and the unfair trade practices that result from the application of price controls.Declares that, if within 12 months negotiations have not achieved such objectives, the USTR shall recommend to Congress the most effective measures (including those specified by the Trade Act of 1974) for eliminating the disparity between the price of prescription drugs in the United States and the price of prescription drugs in the other G-8 countries, with the goal of reducing the price of prescription drugs for U.S. consumers.Requires recommended measures to be of a nature and amount that fully reflect the economic harm inflicted on patients and health care in the United States, and the harm inflicted on the U.S. economy when countries pay the country specific marginal costs of prescription drugs and let the United States cover the research and development costs of innovative prescription drugs.</summary>
</bill>
