<bill session="104" type="hr" number="528" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-25T13:28:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-09-25T13:28:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 2202) to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to improve deterrence of illegal immigration to the United States by increasing border patrol and investigative personnel, by increasing penalties for alien smuggling and for document fraud, by reforming exclusion and deportation law and procedures, by improving the verification system for eligibility for employment, and through other measures, to reform the legal immigration system and facilitate legal entries into the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-829, by Mr. Dreier.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-09-24T17:57:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="281">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 281.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-24T17:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2202. Waiving all points of order against the conference report and against its consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-25T11:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11071-11079" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-25T11:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-25T13:06:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-09-25T13:28:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="430" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 254 - 165 (Roll no. 430).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-25T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="2202"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/1996--Introduced.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the conference report on H.R. 2202 (illegal immigration deterrence).</summary>
</bill>
