<bill session="106" type="h" number="3418" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Energy Employees' Beryllium Compensation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Energy Employees Pilot Project Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Paducah Employees' Exposure Compensation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a compensation program for employees of the Department of Energy, its contractors, subcontractors, and beryllium vendors, who sustained a beryllium-related illness due to the performance of their duty; to establish a compensation program for certain workers at the Paducah, Kentucky, gaseous diffusion plant; to establish a pilot program for examining the possible relationship between workplace exposure to radiation and hazardous materials and illnesses or health conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400519" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="1999-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Beryllium"/>
    <term name="Bone diseases"/>
    <term name="Breast cancer"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Digestive diseases"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Leukemia"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Lung cancer"/>
    <term name="Lung diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Plutonium"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radiation victims"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Stomach diseases"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Thyroid diseases"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Energy Employees' Beryllium Compensation Act Title II: Energy Employees Pilot Project Act Title III: Paducah Employees' Exposure Compensation Act Title I: Energy Employees' Beryllium Compensation Act - Energy Employees' Beryllium Compensation Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) to include in subsequent regulations: (1) additional definitions to those set forth in this Act with respect to vendors, processors, or producers of beryllium or related products; and (2) criteria by which a claimant may establish the existence of a covered illness.(Sec. 105) Prescribes guidelines for: (1) the Secretary to administer this Act; (2) determinative criteria for exposure to beryllium in the performance of duty; (3) compensation for disability or death, medical services, and vocational rehabilitation; (4) computation of pay; (5) limitations on receiving compensation; (6) coordination of benefits; and (7) retroactive compensation.(Sec. 112) Declares: (1) this Act to be the exclusive remedy against the United States, its instrumentalities, and specified contractors and subcontractors; and (2) acceptance of payment under this Act shall be in full settlement of all claims. Declares void any assignment of a claim for compensation under this Act.(Sec. 120) Establishes in the Treasury the Energy Employees' Beryllium Compensation Fund for the payment of compensation and other benefits and expenses under this Act.(Sec. 121) Provides for forfeiture of benefits by persons convicted of fraud with respect to Federal or State workers' compensation benefits.(Sec. 122) Authorizes the Secretary to prescribe regulations for the administration and enforcement of this Act. Mandates that such regulations provide for a Beryllium Compensation Appeals Panel to make final decisions on appeals.(Sec. 125) Authorizes appropriations.Title II: Energy Employees Pilot Project Act - Energy Employees Pilot Project Act - Directs the Secretary to conduct a pilot program to examine the relationship between workplace exposures to radiation, hazardous materials, and occupational illness or other adverse health conditions.(Sec. 203) Mandates that a physicians' panel of specialists in health conditions related to occupational exposure to radiation and hazardous materials selected by the contractor that managed DOE's East Tennessee Technology Park (facility) prepare a report on medical examinations of a specified number of current and former facility employees.(Sec. 205) Authorizes the Secretary to make specified compensation awards to facility employees found to have sustained an adverse health condition resulting from exposure to radiation or hazardous materials. Grants employees the option to elect such award in lieu of compensation under the Energy Employees' Beryllium Compensation Act. Deems such award to be payment in full settlement of claims against the United States, contractors, and subcontractors.(Sec. 211) Authorizes appropriations.Title III: Paducah Employees' Exposure Compensation Act - Paducah Employees Exposure Compensation Act - Establishes in the Treasury the Paducah Employees' Exposure Compensation Fund to be disbursed exclusively by the Attorney General for the payment of compensation claims to eligible Paducah employees. Authorizes appropriations to the Fund.(Sec. 305) Deems such award to be payment in full settlement of claims against the United States, contractors, and subcontractors.(Sec. 308) Limits the amount of claimants' attorney's fees.</summary>
</bill>
