<bill session="104" type="h" number="2971" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security Individual Retirement Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Social Security Act to reduce Social Security taxes and to provide for Social Security individual retirement accounts funded by Social Security payroll deductions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-23">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1231"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/23/1996--Introduced.
Social Security Individual Retirement Act of 1996 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reduce the social security taxes on employees, employers, and the self-employed for 1997 and thereafter. Amends title II (Old-Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require employers to have in effect a social security payroll deduction plan for employees. Requires such plan to provide for employers to deduct the prescribed social security employee contribution for transfer to a social security individual retirement account of the employee. Provides for self-employed individuals to deposit into such accounts the prescribed social security contributions. Requires transfer of the social security individual retirement account of a deceased individual to a similar account maintained by the decedent's eligible survivor. Sets forth penalties for failure to establish and maintain such accounts. Requires amounts deducted from employee wages to be shown on W-2 forms. Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to exempt social security payroll deduction plans which do not provide for employer contributions from provisions governing employee benefit plans. Provides for: (1) adjustments in the primary insurance amounts of employees and self-employed individuals with social security individual retirement accounts under SSA title II; and (2) the tax treatment of such accounts in a manner similar to individual retirement accounts.</summary>
</bill>
