<bill session="104" type="h" number="877" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wounded Knee National Tribal Park Establishment Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Wounded Knee National Tribal Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1995-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1995-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1995-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1995-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1995-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="411677" joined="1995-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-02-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E311"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="382"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="382"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/1995--Introduced.
Wounded Knee National Tribal Park Establishment Act of 1995 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish the Wounded Knee National Tribal Park consisting of a North and South unit at which national monuments should be erected to memorialize the Indian victims of the 1890 Wounded Knee Massacre. Directs the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with the Cheyenne River Sioux (for the North unit) and the Oglala Sioux (for the South unit) tribes to carry out planning, design, construction, operation, maintenance, and replacement activities at monument sites at their respective unit. Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance to both tribes, as well as training and employment to tribal members in the operation and maintenance of both units. (Sec. 5) Authorizes each such tribe to acquire lands for inclusion in the North or South unit of the Park. Allows the Secretary to provide financial assistance for such purchases. Directs each tribe to manage its respective unit. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to plan, design, and construct the national monuments on each Park unit after consultation with an advisory committee established under this Act. Requires the Secretary to complete and report to the Congress on feasibility studies to: (1) establish and mark the route taken by Chief Big Foot and his band from the Cheyenne River Indian Reservation to Wounded Knee as a national historic trail; and (2) establish a visitor information and orientation center on the Cheyenne River Indian Reservation. (Sec. 8) Establishes the Wounded Knee National Tribal Park Advisory Commission. (Sec. 9) Authorizes either tribe or its designated agency or authority to enter into an agreement with a nonprofit corporation to raise funds from private sources to be used in lieu of, or to supplement, any Federal funds made available by appropriations for Park purposes. (Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
