<bill session="106" type="h" number="4473" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Computers in Our Community Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to establish a program to distribute funds to State educational agencies to advance the use of technology to effectively teach our students computer skills and improve the general educational performance of students, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400438"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="2000-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2000-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="2000-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Community centers"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School planning"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State aid to education"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/2000--Introduced.
Computers in Our Community Act - Amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to establish a Computers in Our Community Program.(Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Commerce (the Secretary), acting through the Assistant Secretary, to make grants to participating SEAs for allocation among local educational agencies (LEAs). Allows such funds to be used for: (1) purchase of computers that meet a minimum standard as determined by the Secretary; (2) the electrical wiring that schools may require to connect computers to each other and to the Internet; and (3) hiring technological assistants to ensure that each school has access to a trained computer professional to provide technology training for teachers and perform maintenance of computer systems. Allows the use of such funds to pay a maximum of one technological assistant per: (1) five elementary schools; (2) three middle schools; and (3) two high schools.Directs the Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary, to award competitive grants to the following entities for the following programs: (1) nonprofit organizations, to establish job training programs for preparing low-income individuals for computer and technology related jobs (digital divide workforce training initiative); (2) community centers and libraries, to provide greater access to, instruction on, and assistance with computers and the Internet (technology access); (3) institutions of higher education (IHEs) that create successful partnerships between their education and computer departments to create software or Internet applications to train teachers in using computers, and using computers to teach students or to use in the classroom to teach students (computer curriculum partnership). Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Education to develop a clearinghouse to make available to other schools throughout the Nation information derived from activities of IHE recipients of curriculum partnership grants.Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 4) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish the Computers in Our Communities Trust Fund. Transfers to such Fund amounts equivalent to certain taxes on communications. Makes amounts in such fund available for appropriations to carry out the Computers in Our Communities Program.(Sec. 5) Reduces an excise tax on telephone and other communications services.</summary>
</bill>
