<bill session="105" type="h" number="2952" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Indoor Air Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize a national program to reduce the threat to human health posed by exposure to contaminants in the air indoors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1998-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sick building syndrome"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/1997--Introduced.
Indoor Air Act of 1997 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to publish: (1) a list of common significant indoor air health risks; and (2) concurrently with such list, voluntary guidelines for identifying, reducing, and preventing such risks. Requires the Administrator to give priority to conducting and providing financial or other assistance to studies concerning indoor air quality. Directs the Administrator to: (1) report to the Congress on persons operating contractor businesses engaged in the identification, reduction, and prevention of significant indoor air health risks and on the need for a program to certify contractors engaged in such activities; and (2) establish a voluntary certification program for contractors engaged in the identification of such risks. Imposes fees for certification. Authorizes the suspension or revocation of certifications for violations of certification requirements. Directs the Administrator to publish and disseminate the list of common significant indoor air health risks, the guidelines for identifying, reducing, and preventing such risks, and indoor air health advisories addressing the health effects of such risks. Requires the Administrator to develop a voluntary program to provide Federal recognition to buildings that are operated and maintained to prevent or minimize such risks and that provide significant energy efficiency benefits. Authorizes the Administrator to provide grants to States and local governments to implement programs to identify, reduce, and prevent such risks. Requires the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health to implement a Building Assessment Program to provide assistance and guidance to employers and employees on measures to reduce such risks. Authorizes the Director, at the request of an employer or employee, to conduct on-site assessments of buildings. Directs the Administrator to ensure that the presentation of information on significant indoor air health risks is unbiased and informative. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
