<bill session="105" type="h" number="3311" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Expanding International Education for All Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve international education at postsecondary institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400312"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1998-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Black education"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Curriculum planning"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Government internships"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in government"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/1998--Introduced.
Expanding International Education for All Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to revise title VI (International Education). (Sec. 2) Revises part A (International and Foreign Language Studies) with respect to incentive grants for the creation of undergraduate international studies and foreign language programs. Allows graduate schools, along with baccalaureate degree granting institutions and community and junior colleges of higher education, to be included as part of a consortium that serves undergraduates and is eligible for a grant. Revises the Federal and non-Federal shares of the cost of planning and establishing at the undergraduate level: (1) a foreign language program; (2) an international studies program; or (3) (new in this Act) a business and international education program. Revises allowable uses of grant funds to include: (1) acquisition of research and instructional materials; (2) establishment of a network with other institutions of higher education and resource centers focused on strengthening foreign language study and international studies programs; (3) development of new opportunities for learning foreign languages, including the less commonly taught languages; (4) international education programs designed to develop or enhance linkages between two- to four-year institutions of higher education, or baccalaureate and postbaccalaureate programs or institutions; (5) in-service and faculty development activities designed to strengthen instruction and research capacity of the institution; and (6) faculty travel in foreign areas, regions, and countries. Establishes certain grant conditions. Establishes, under part A, a program of discretionary grants for technological innovation and cooperation for foreign information access. (Replaces the current discretionary grants program for acquisition of and access to periodicals and other research materials published outside the United States.) (Sec. 3) Revises part C (Institute for International Public Policy) with respect to the non-Federal share and source of funds for minority foreign service professional development. Directs the Institute to make institutional development grants to strengthen international affairs programs at Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, Tribally Controlled Indian Community Colleges, and minority institutions. (Sec. 4) Revises the Institute's share of the cost of the junior year program. Authorizes the Institute to carry out a summer abroad program. (Sec. 5) Directs the Institute to enter into agreements with specified types of institutions of higher education to conduct postbaccalaureate internships in Washington, D.C., with work experience to assist the students to prepare for a Master's degree program. Requires such internship program to be carried out with the assistance of the Woodrow Wilson Fellowship Program. (Sec. 6) Establishes in the executive branch an Interagency Committee on Minority Careers in International Affairs to: (1) advise the Secretary and the Institute on part C programs; and (2) promote policies in furtherance of part C objectives in each participating department and agency. (Sec. 7) Extends through FY 2003 the authorization of appropriations for part C.</summary>
</bill>
