<bill session="105" type="h" number="2954" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Fair Franchise Practices Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish minimum standards of fair conduct in franchise sales and franchise business relationships, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2281-2282"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Trade associations"/>
    <term name="Trade regulation"/>
    <term name="Tying devices (Antitrust law)"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/1997--Introduced.
Federal Fair Franchise Practices Act of 1997 - Prohibits any person, in connection with the advertising, offering, sale, or promotion of any franchise, from: (1) employing a device, scheme, or artifice to defraud; (2) engaging in an act, practice, course of business, or pattern of conduct which operates or is intended to operate as a fraud upon any prospective franchisee; (3) obtaining property, or assisting others in so doing, by negligently making an untrue statement of a material fact or any failure to state a material fact; and (4) discriminating among prospective franchisees on the basis of race, sex, religion, disability, or national origin. (Sec. 4) Prohibits any franchisor or subfranchisor, in connection with the performance, enforcement, renewal, and termination of any franchise agreement, from: (1) engaging in an act, practice, course of business, or pattern of conduct which operates as a fraud upon any person; (2) discriminating among franchisees on the basis of race, sex, religion, disability, or national origin; (3) hindering or prohibiting the free association of franchisees for any lawful purpose, including the formation of or participation in any trade association made up of franchisees; and (4) discriminating against a franchisee by imposing requirements not imposed on other similarly situated franchisees or otherwise retaliating against any franchisee for membership or participation in a franchisee association. Prohibits a franchisor from: (1) terminating a franchise agreement prior to its expiration without good cause; (2) prohibiting a franchisee from obtaining equipment, fixtures, supplies, or services used in the business licensed by the franchise agreement from sources of the franchisee's choosing, with exceptions; and (3) prohibiting, or enforcing a prohibition against, a franchisee from engaging in any business at any location after the expiration (or termination for good cause) of a franchise agreement. (Sec. 5) Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) minimum standards of conduct (good faith, due care, and limited fiduciary duty) for each party to a franchise agreement; (2) a prohibition against requiring the inclusion of a franchise agreement term or condition which violates this Act or relieves a person from a duty or liability under this Act; (3) a prohibition against the waiver from compliance with this Act; (4) legal actions brought by persons injured or damaged by violations; (5) the right to arbitration or mediation in lieu of a legal action; (6) authorized legal actions by State attorneys general on behalf of State residents for alleged violations; and (7) the obligation to comply with all applicable State franchising laws to the extent not inconsistent with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
