<bill session="104" type="h" number="3884" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Postal Service Due Process Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 39, United States Code, to require that traditional equitable principles be applied by the United States Postal Service in determining whether or not to exercise its temporary detention authority with respect to mail alleged to be deceptive or misleading.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404280"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402657" joined="1996-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="1996-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" subcommittee="Postal Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lotteries"/>
    <term name="Postal crimes"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/1996--Introduced.
Postal Service Due Process Act - Directs a U.S. district court to enter a temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction directing the detention of a defendant's incoming mail by the postmaster pending conclusion of statutory proceedings concerning the defendant's use of the mail through false representation or lotteries to obtain or distribute money, or for obtaining real or personal property, only upon application therefor by the Postal Service and upon a showing that: (1) the Postal Service is likely to prevail in such proceedings; (2) the public would suffer irreparable harm if the application were not granted; (3) no adequate remedy at law exists; and (4) the harm that would be caused to the public by not granting the application exceeds the harm that would be caused to the defendant by granting it.</summary>
</bill>
