<bill session="107" type="h" number="142" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airline Competition Preservation Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to oversee the competitive activities of air carriers following a concentration in the airline industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="199"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airline rates"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Predatory pricing"/>
    <term name="Price discrimination"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Travel agents"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/3/2001--Introduced.
Airline Competition Preservation Act of 2001 - Amends Federal transportation law to authorize the Secretary of Transportation, on his own initiative or on a complaint, to: (1) investigate whether an air carrier is charging an unreasonably high fare or an average fare for interstate air transportation on a route; and (2) upon an affirmative finding, order the carrier to reduce the fare, offer the reduced fare for a specific number of seats on the route, and offer rebates to individuals who have been charged the fare.Prescribes fare offering requirements for a dominant air carrier (which accounts for more than 50 percent of total annual boardings) that institutes or changes its fares with respect to a route in interstate air transportation to or from a hub airport in a manner that: (1) results in fares lower than or comparable to fares offered by a new entrant air carrier; and (2) increases the passenger capacity at which such fares are offered on the route to a level two or more times the capacity previously offered by the air carrier at such fares on the route, and two or more times the total capacity offered by the new entrant air carrier on the route. Requires such a dominant air carrier to continue (in the two-year period beginning on the date that such fares and additional capacity are instituted) to offer such fares with respect to not less than 80 percent of the highest number of seats per week for which the dominant air carrier has offered them.Authorizes the Secretary, on his own initiative or on complaint, to: (1) investigate whether a dominant air carrier at a hub airport is charging higher than average fares at the airport; and (2) upon an affirmative finding, order the carrier to take specified actions to increase opportunities for competition at the hub airport.Makes this Act effective immediately upon the Secretary's determination that three or fewer air carriers account for 70 percent or more of the scheduled revenue passenger miles in interstate air transportation as a result of specified consolidations, mergers, or acquisitions.</summary>
</bill>
