<bill session="107" type="h" number="1209" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-08-06">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Status Protection Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Child Status Protection Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Child Status Protection Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Child Status Protection Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Child Status Protection Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Child Status Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to determine whether an alien is a child, for purposes of classification as an immediate relative, based on the age of the alien on the date the classification petition with respect to the alien is filed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400544"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2001-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-03T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Judiciary have until 6:00 p.m. on April 20 to file a report on H.R. 1209. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-04-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-04-20T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 107-45. Filed late, pursuant to previous special order.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-04-20T17:23:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="28">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 28.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-06-06T10:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-06T10:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2901-2903" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-06T10:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1209.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-06T11:03:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-06T11:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2907-2908" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-06-06T12:01:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="152" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 416 - 0 (Roll no. 152).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2901" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-06-06T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-05-16">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-05-16">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-05-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="377">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 377.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-06-13">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5560-5561" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5560" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-13">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2002-06-13" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-06-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-22T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4989-4992" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-22T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1209.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2002-07-22T14:25:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4989-4990" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-07-22T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2002-07-22">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2002-07-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2002-08-06">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2002-08-06" type="public" number="107-208">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 107-208.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="672"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="672"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Age (Law)"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Divorcees"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Single people"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3846"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/13/2002--Passed Senate amended.
Child Status Protection Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide that the determination of whether an unmarried alien son or daughter of a U.S. citizen is considered an "immediate relative child" (under 21 years old) shall be made at the time an immigration visa petition is filed for such classification on his or her behalf. (Under existing law unmarried children may apply for immigrant status as immediate relatives without numerical limitation.)Makes similar determinations in the case of: (1) permanent resident parents who subsequently naturalize after having filed family-sponsored immigration petitions for a son or daughter (age determination at time of parents' naturalization); or (2) citizen parents who filed family-sponsored immigration petitions for a married son or daughter and such son or daughter later divorces (age determination at time of divorce).(Sec. 3) States that with respect to an unmarried son or daughter seeking status as family-sponsored, employment-based, or diversity "child" (unmarried, under 21 years old) immigrant: (1) such an alien's age will be determined using the age of the alien on the date on which an immigrant visa becomes available reduced by the number of days in which the petition was pending; and (2) if the alien's age is determined to be 21 years or older the original (pre-21 years old) priority date shall be retained.(Sec. 4) States that a son or daughter who was unmarried and under 21 years old when the parent applied for asylee or refugee status shall retain such "child" classification during the pendency of the asylee or refugee application.(Sec. 6) Provides that the family-sponsored petition of an unmarried alien son or daughter whose permanent resident alien parent subsequently becomes a naturalized U.S. citizen shall be converted to a petition for an unmarried son or daughter of a U.S. citizen, unless the son or daughter elects otherwise. States that any petition priority date assigned prior to such naturalization may be maintained regardless of whether or not the petition is converted.(Sec. 7) States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit or deny specified benefits for alien children.(Sec. 8) States that the amendments made by this Act shall take effect upon enactment of this Act and shall apply to an alien beneficiary of: (1) an immigrant petition approved but not with a final determination prior to such date; (2) a petition pending on or after such date; or (3) an application pending before the Department of Justice or Department of State on or after such date.</summary>
</bill>
