<bill session="106" type="h" number="3519" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-08-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-08-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">World Bank AIDS Prevention Trust Fund Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">World Bank AIDS Marshall Plan Trust Fund Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">World Bank AIDS Marshall Plan Trust Fund Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Global AIDS and Tuberculosis Relief Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Global AIDS Research and Relief Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">International Tuberculosis Control Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Global AIDS and Tuberculosis Relief Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Global AIDS Research and Relief Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">International Tuberculosis Control Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for negotiations for the creation of a trust fund to be administered by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development of the International Development Association to combat the AIDS epidemic.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2000-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="2000-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2000-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2000-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2000-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2000-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2000-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2000-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2000-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2000-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2000-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2000-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2000-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-03-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 4.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-03-28T18:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Banking and Financial Services. H. Rept. 106-548.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-03-28T18:07:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="298">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 298.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-05-15T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Leach moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-15T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3016-3025" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-15T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3519.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-05-15T17:54:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3016-3018" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-05-15T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-26">
      <text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-26">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7619-7624" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-07-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27T17:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Leach asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-07-27T18:00:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H7177-7181" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H7177-7180" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27T18:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-08-08">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-08-19">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-08-19" type="public" number="106-264">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-264.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Orphans"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis research"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Virus research"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4018"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/26/2000--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Assistance to Countries with Large Populations Having HIV-AIDS Subtitle A: United States Assistance Subtitle B: World Bank AIDS Trust Fund Title II: International Tuberculosis Control Title III: Administrative Authorities Global AIDS and Tuberculosis Relief Act of 2000 - Title I: Assistance to Countries with Large Populations Having HIV-AIDS - Global AIDS Research and Relief Act of 2000 - Sets forth the purposes of this Act, including to: (1) help prevent human suffering through the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of the human immunodeficiency virus and the acquired immune deficiency syndrome (HIV-AIDS); and (2) help ensure the viability of economic development, stability, and national security in the developing world by advancing research to understand the causes associated with HIV-AIDS in developing countries and assist in the development of an AIDS vaccine.Subtitle A: United States Assistance - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to declare that the agency responsible for administering this Act should make the prevention and control of HIV-AIDS a priority in the foreign assistance program for developing foreign countries. Authorizes appropriations (earmarking amounts for training and training facilities in sub-Saharan Africa and U.S. voluntary contributions to the Global Alliance for Vaccines and Immunizations and the International AIDS Vaccine Initiative).Subtitle B: World Bank AIDS Trust Fund - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to enter into negotiations with the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (World Bank) or the International Development Association, and with their member nations and other interested parties, for the establishment within the World Bank of the World Bank AIDS Trust Fund (including an Advisory Board to the Trust Fund). Sets forth the purposes of the Trust Fund, including to: (1) assist in the prevention and eradication of HIV-AIDS and the care and treatment of individuals infected with HIV-AIDS; and (2) provide support for the establishment of programs that provide health care and primary and secondary education for children orphaned by the HIV-AIDS epidemic. Requires the Secretary to report to the appropriate congressional committees with respect to the Trust Fund.(Sec. 141) Authorizes appropriations.Title II: International Tuberculosis Control - International Tuberculosis Control Act of 2000 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to revise requirements for assistance for health programs in developing countries to declare that Congress recognizes: (1) the growing international problem of tuberculosis; and (2) that the means exist to control and treat it, and that it is therefore a major objective of the foreign assistance program to control the disease.(Sec. 203) Declares that Congress expects the agency primarily responsible for administering this Act to: (1) coordinate with the World Health Organization, the Centers for Disease Control, the National Institutes of Health, and other organizations toward the development and implementation of a comprehensive tuberculosis control program; and (2) set as a goal the detection of at least 70 percent of the cases of infectious tuberculosis, and the cure of at least 85 percent of the cases detected, in those countries in which the agency has established development programs, by December 31, 2010.Authorizes appropriations.Title III: Administrative Authorities - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the Administrator of the agency primarily responsible for administering certain foreign assistance funds to provide program and management oversight for activities funded under this Act and conducted in countries in which the agency does not have a field mission or office.(Sec. 302) Revises requirements for termination of assistance under such Act. Authorizes the President, in order to make an equitable settlement of termination claims under extraordinary contractual relief standards, to adopt as a contract or other obligation of the United States Government, and assume any attendant liabilities, any contract with a U.S. or third-country contractor that had been funded with assistance under such Act and the Arms Export Control Act before assistance termination.Declares that amounts certified as having been obligated for assistance subsequently terminated by the President, or pursuant to any provision of law, shall continue to remain available and may be reobligated to meet any necessary expenses arising from the termination of such assistance.Declares that provisions of this or any other Act requiring the termination of assistance under this or any other Act shall not be construed to require the termination of guarantee commitments entered into before the effective date of the assistance termination.</summary>
</bill>
