<bill session="106" type="hr" number="412" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-02T10:47:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-02-02T10:47:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2005) to establish a statute of repose for durable goods used in a trade or business.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400327"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-02-01T15:45:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-491, by Ms. Pryce (OH).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-01T15:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2005 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. After general debate, the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill, for the purpose of amendment, the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. No amendment shall be in order except for those printed in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-02-01T15:46:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="166">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 166.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-02-02T10:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H171-173" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-02T10:30:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 412.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-02T10:47:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2000-02-02T10:47:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H171" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-02-02T10:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="2005"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2000--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (modified open) for the consideration of H.R. 2005 (statute of repose for durable goods used in a trade or business).</summary>
</bill>
