<bill session="108" type="h" number="207" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Controlled Substances Act with respect to the placing of certain substances on the schedules of controlled substances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2003-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2003-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="2003-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400200" joined="2003-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2003-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2003-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400303" joined="2003-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2003-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2003-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Education Reform" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Steroids"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/2003--Introduced.
Amends the Controlled Substances Act to modify the definition of "immediate precursor" to include a substance which the Attorney General has designated as the immediate chemical precursor of an anabolic steroid that has been scheduled as a controlled substance which either is a metabolite of a scheduled anabolic steroid or is transformed in the body directly into a scheduled anabolic steroid or the metabolite of a scheduled anabolic steroid.Authorizes the Attorney General to place the immediate precursor of a scheduled anabolic steroid in the same schedule as that anabolic steroid or in any other schedule with a higher numerical designation (without regard to specified requirements, including the requirement that a substance promote muscle growth). States that once such an immediate precursor is placed in a schedule, it becomes a controlled substance and the Attorney General may schedule an immediate precursor of that substance.Authorizes the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy to undertake education programs at the grade and high school levels to highlight the harmful effects of steroids and steroid precursor use by youths. Requires the Director to use funds made available for such programs for existing State and local anti-drug programs, primarily for education programs that directly communicate with teachers, principals, coaches, and children at the school level on the harmful effects of steroids and steroid precursors.</summary>
</bill>
