<bill session="106" type="h" number="3846" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-09T21:49:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-03-09T21:49:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to increase the minimum wage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400373"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T22:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 434 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3081 and H.R. 3846. H.R. 3081 shall be considered in the House and shall be considered as read. In lieu of the amendment recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill, the text of H.R. 3832 shall be considered as adopted. Debate shall continue for not to exceed two hours, equally divided and controlled, and there shall be one motion to recommit, with or without instructions. H.R. 3846 shall be considered in the House, shall be considered as read, and shall be debatable for one hour, equally divided and controlled. Specified amendments are in order and consist of those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. There shall be one motion to recommit, with or without instructions. Finally, in the engrossment of H.R. 3081, the text of H.R. 3846 as passed by the House shall be added as new matter at the end of H.R.3081, after whi...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T15:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 434 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T18:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodling called up the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T18:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Point of order raised by Mr. Largent on the content of the measure. Mr. Largent stated that the bill violated section 425(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to the extent that it imposed intra-governmental expenses in the form of an unfunded mandate totaling more than $50 million. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T18:33:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Chair noted that the point of order raised by Mr. Largent met the threshold required under the rule and allotted 20 minutes of debate, equally divided and controlled, for the purpose of determining whether or not consideration of the measure will go forward. At the conclusion of debate, the Chair will put the question of consideration of the measure before the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T19:14:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to consider the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 274 - 141 (Roll no. 42).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T19:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 434.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H879-902" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H881-882" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T19:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3081 and H.R. 3846. H.R. 3081 shall be considered in the House and shall be considered as read. In lieu of the amendment recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill, the text of H.R. 3832 shall be considered as adopted. Debate shall continue for not to exceed two hours, equally divided and controlled, and there shall be one motion to recommit, with or without instructions. H.R. 3846 shall be considered in the House, shall be considered as read, and shall be debatable for one hour, equally divided and controlled. Specified amendments are in order and consist of those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. There shall be one motion to recommit, with or without instructions. Finally, in the engrossment of H.R. 3081, the text of H.R. 3846 as passed by the House shall be added as new matter at the end of H.R.3081, after whi...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T19:17:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Chair announced that the decision of the House was to consider the bill and the House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T20:22:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 434 the House proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T21:09:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T21:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Clay moved to recommit with instructions to Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T21:10:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion provide for striking sections 2, 3, and 4 from the bill and to insert a new section at the end of the bill setting new guidelines for the minimum wage scale in the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T21:19:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T21:36:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 181 - 243 (Roll no. 44).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H899-900" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-03-09T21:49:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="45" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 282 - 143 (Roll no. 45).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T21:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T21:50:00-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 3081.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T21:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 434, H.R. 3846 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="434"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="hr" number="434"/>
    <bill relation="includes" session="106" type="h" number="3081"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer industry"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer programming"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing personnel"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Funeral industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Intranets"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Sales personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Systems analysis"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="World Wide Web"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h593"/>
    <amendment number="h594"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/8/2000--Introduced.
Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (FLSA) to increase the Federal minimum wage (currently $5.15 per hour) to: (1) $5.48 per hour during the year beginning April 1, 2000; (2) $5.81 per hour during the year beginning April 1, 2001; and (3) $6.15 per hour beginning April 1, 2002.(Sec. 2) Revises an exemption from FLSA minimum wage and overtime compensation requirements for certain computer professionals to include computer network and database analysts, and computer systems, network, and database designers and developers.(Sec. 3) Exempts from FLSA minimum wage and overtime compensation requirements any employee in a sales position, if: (1) the employee has specialized or technical knowledge related to products or services being sold; (2) the employee's sales are predominantly to persons who are entities to whom the employee has made previous sales or the employee's position does not involve initiating sales contacts; (3) the employee has a detailed understanding of customers' needs and exercises discretion in offering a variety of products and services; (4) the employee receives a base compensation at a specified minimum rate and additional compensation based on sales attributable to the employee; (5) the employee's aggregate compensation based upon sales reaches a specified minimum level; and (6) the rate of annual compensation or base compensation for an employee who did not work for an employer for an entire calendar year is prorated to reflect annual compensation which would have been earned if the employee had been compensated at the same rate for the entire calendar year. Makes such exemption inapplicable to individuals employed as route sales drivers.(Sec. 4) Exempts licensed funeral directors and licensed embalmers from FLSA minimum wage and overtime compensation requirements.(Sec. 5) Allows a State to preempt the Federal minimum wage if the State: (1) sets a minimum wage rate of at least $5.15 per hour (the current Federal minimum wage); and (2) applies that rate to as many workers in the State as would otherwise be covered by the Federal minimum wage rate.</summary>
</bill>
