<bill session="104" type="h" number="4230" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rehabilitation and Return to Work Opportunity Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make improvements in the rehabilitation programs provided for disabled individuals under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300014"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="404520" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="406625" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="1996-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1774"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to handicapped services"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Unemployed"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Introduced.
Rehabilitation and Return to Work Opportunity Act of 1996 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to establish under the Social Security Administration a Rehabilitation and Return-to-Work Program for assessing the capability for vocational adjustment of individuals determined to be disabled under the OASDI and Supplemental Security Income (SSI) programs. Provides that the individual shall be determined capable of vocational adjustment upon determination of a reasonable possibility that the individual will be capable, upon the provision of vocational rehabilitation services, of performing substantial gainful activity. Places such program under the administrative authority of private sector regional administrators in each service region in which it is implemented. Requires such administrators to hire network coordinators for their particular service regions to: (1) ensure that adequate choices for vocational rehabilitation services are made available to service recipients; and (2) otherwise oversee specified requirements relating to service providers, including requirements that they develop jointly with each recipient, after an employment evaluation, an individual employment plan outlining employment preparation steps. Prescribes a specified milestone payment system for use under such program. Establishes the Rehabilitation and Return-to-Work Commission in the Social Security Administration and charges it with specific program development responsibilities, including oversight of the program once it is fully implemented. Authorizes appropriations. Provides for a five-year period of Medicare continuation coverage for certain OASDI disability benefit recipients who return to work. Makes permanent Medicare secondary payer rules relating to disability. Repeals the mandate and authority for continuation hospital insurance benefit coverage for certain temporarily out-of-work individuals. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide employers a one-time tax credit equal to the first year of Federal Insurance Contributions Act taxes paid for certain disabled individuals they hire.</summary>
</bill>
