<bill session="104" type="h" number="1472" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financing Corporation and Savings Association Insurance Fund Restoration Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for sufficient funding to cover the costs of the Financing Corporation, to provide funds to carry out the purposes of the Savings Association Insurance Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E855-856"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Financing Corporation"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Resolution Trust Corporation"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/1995--Introduced.
Financing Corporation and Savings Association Insurance Fund Restoration Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (FDIA) to repeal the prerequisite that the Chairperson of the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) make specified certifications to the Congress as a condition for making available to the Savings Association Insurance Fund (SAIF) certain funds that had been appropriated to the Resolution Trust Corporation but were not expended by it. Amends the Federal Home Loan Bank Act to mandate that the FDIC make amounts transferred from the SAIF available to the Financing Corporation (FICO) to cover the interest payments, issuance costs, and custodial fees on FICO obligations. Amends the FDIA to repeal the minimum assessments requirements for a deposit insurance fund risk-based assessment system. Amends the Federal Home Loan Bank Act to include within FICO's assessment authority specified SAIF members and Bank Insurance Fund members whose deposits are treated as insured by the SAIF.</summary>
</bill>
