<bill session="104" type="h" number="1444" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Beverage Container Reuse and Recycling Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require a refund value for certain beverage containers, and to provide resources for State pollution prevention and recycling programs, and for other programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401310" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1995-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1995-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1995-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1995-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="406284" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1995-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1995-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1995-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1995-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1995-06-07" withdrawn="1995-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E820-821"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Beverage containers"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/1995--Introduced.
National Beverage Container Reuse and Recycling Act of 1995 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit the sale of beer, mineral water, soda water, wine coolers, or carbonated soft drinks in beverage containers by retailers and distributors unless such containers carry a refund value of ten cents. Requires distributors to collect from retailers the refund value for each beverage sold to retailers and retailers to collect from consumers the refund value for each beverage sold to consumers. Requires retailers and distributors to pay the refund on returned containers of brands (in the same kind and size of container) sold. Directs distributors to pay annually to a State unclaimed refund amounts (the amount by which the total refund value of all containers sold by distributors exceeds the amount paid by distributors to persons in that State). Makes unclaimed refunds available to a State for carrying out pollution prevention and recycling programs. Prohibits distributors and retailers from: (1) selling beverages in metal beverage containers with detachable openings; and (2) disposing of containers subject to this Act or any metal, glass, or plastic from such containers (other than the top or seal) in landfills or solid waste disposal facilities. Makes this Act inapplicable to States that have adopted requirements identical to those under this Act or that have demonstrated achievement of a recycling or reuse rate for beverage containers of at least 70 percent. Prohibits States or political subdivisions that impose taxes on the sale of beverage containers from imposing any tax on the amount attributable to the refund value of such containers. Provides for the adjustment for inflation of the ten-cent refund amount at ten-year intervals. Prescribes civil penalties for violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
