<bill session="107" type="hc" number="335" updated="2013-07-14T18:59:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-02-28T11:39:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-02-28T11:39:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the significance of Black History Month and the contributions of Black Americans as a significant part of the history, progress, and heritage of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400541"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-28T11:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Government Reform discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-28T11:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Davis, Jo Ann asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-28T11:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H643-645" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-28T11:27:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with debate on the resolution under a reservation of objection. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-02-28T11:39:00-05:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H645" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-02-28T11:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-02-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Black history"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Multiculturalism"/>
    <term name="Special months"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2002--Introduced.
Recognizes the significance of Black History Month, an important time to recognize the contributions of Black Americans in the Nation's history. Encourages the continued celebration of this month to provide an opportunity for all U.S. people to learn more about the past and to better understand the experiences that have shaped the Nation.Expresses the sense of Congress that Black American contributions are a significant part of U.S. history and the ethnic and racial diversity of the United States enriches and strengthens the Nation.</summary>
</bill>
