<bill session="104" type="h" number="4061" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Financial Management Improvement Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of uniform accounting systems, standards, and reporting systems in the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300096"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Management information systems"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/1996--Introduced.
Federal Financial Management Improvement Act of 1996 - Requires each Federal agency to: (1) implement and maintain financial management systems that comply with Federal requirements, Federal accounting standards, and the U.S. Government Standard General Ledger at the transaction level; and (2) give priority in funding and provide sufficient resources to implement this Act. Requires: (1) audit reporting of whether an agency's financial management systems comply with requirements; (2) compliance determination by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), acting through the Controller of the Office of Federal Financial Management; and (3) if there is noncompliance with the standards, a remediation plan. Sets forth a limitation on the time period for bringing the agency's financial management systems into compliance. Allows the transfer of up to two percent of agency funds for priority financial management system improvements. Requires a report by the Director of OMB if an agency fails to bring its financial management systems into compliance within the specified time period. Directs the: (1) Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House, jointly, to study and submit a report to the Congress on how the Congress and the legislative branch may achieve compliance; and (2) Chief Justice of the United States to study and submit a report to the Congress on how the judiciary may achieve compliance. Sets forth: (1) reporting requirements; (2) definitions; and (3) the effective date.</summary>
</bill>
