<bill session="105" type="h" number="1083" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Fair Franchising Practices Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish certain uniform rights, duties, and enforcement procedures relating to franchise agreements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400003"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Choice of law"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Employee ownership"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Management"/>
    <term name="Management consultants"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Trade associations"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Tying devices (Antitrust law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/1997--Introduced.
Federal Fair Franchising Practices Act of 1997 - Requires a franchise (contract to enter into a franchised business) to include an implied duty to act in good faith in the performance and enforcement of rights and duties established in the franchise. (Sec. 3) Requires a franchisor to exercise the skill and knowledge normally possessed by franchisors in good standing in similar communities or trade areas, unless the franchisor: (1) represents that it has greater skill or knowledge; or (2) conspicuously disclaims that it has the normal skill or knowledge. (Sec. 4) Allows a franchisor to negotiate with a prospective franchisee concerning changes in franchise terms. (Sec. 5) Allows a franchisee to obtain equipment, fixtures, supplies, and services (goods) for the franchised business from any source, as long as they meet a reasonable standard of quality, except for: (1) a reasonable quantity of goods that the franchisor requires a franchisee to obtain from the franchisor; (2) goods that are a central feature of the franchised business; and (3) goods made by the franchisor that incorporate a trade secret. (Sec. 6) Prohibits a franchisor, without good cause, from terminating or refusing to renew a franchise whose terms are indeterminate. (Sec. 7) Authorizes a franchisee to transfer a transferable interest to a transferee who meets a franchisor's reasonable, essential, and nondiscriminatory standards for new franchisees or transferees. Requires appropriate notice of, and consent to, such a transfer. Outlines other transfer conditions, requirements, and prohibitions. (Sec. 8) States that a franchisor may not prohibit a franchisee from engaging in any lawful business at any location: (1) after expiration of the franchise term; (2) after termination of the franchise by the franchisee for good cause; or (3) after a transfer by the franchisee of its full franchise interest. (Sec. 9) Provides for freedom of association and collective bargaining rights for franchisees. (Sec. 10) Prohibits a franchisor from placing a new business outlet in unreasonable proximity to an established franchised outlet, with certain conditions and exceptions. (Sec. 11) Prohibits discrimination in the granting of franchises, the transfer of franchise interests, and the administration of a franchise system. (Sec. 12) Provides a private right of action for a franchise party who is injured by a violation of this Act or specified Federal regulations relating to business venture requirements.</summary>
</bill>
