<bill session="104" type="h" number="2653" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tobacco Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 and the Agricultural Act of 1949 to improve the operation of the Government Flue-cured and Burley tobacco programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409400"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Risk Management and Specialty Crops.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG24" subcommittee="Risk Management and Specialty Crops" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Acreage allotments"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Farm production quotas"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Marketing orders"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/1995--Introduced.
Tobacco Amendments Act of 1995 - Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 to extend tobacco marketing assessment authority. States that such fees shall be used to pay for other tobacco programs not covered by user fees or other specified assessments or contributions. (Sec. 3) Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 to revise farm acreage allotment and marketing quota reduction provisions. (Sec. 4) Makes a specified farm reconstitution provision applicable to burley (burley) tobacco. (Sec. 5) Reduces a certain percentage threshold regarding disaster-transfer of flue-cured (flue-cured) tobacco quotas. (Sec. 6) Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 to expand the tobacco types subject to no net cost assessment. (Sec. 7) Amends the Tobacco Adjustment Act of 1938 to repeal certain tobacco export reporting requirements. (Sec. 8) Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 to repeal certain flue-cured and burley marketing quota reduction provisions. (Sec. 9) Amends the Tobacco Inspection Act to provide for civil penalties and cease and desist orders for violations of such Act. Grants U.S. district courts jurisdiction in such matters. (Sec 10.) Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 to permit flue-cured or other tobacco quota or allotment transfers across within-State county lines if approved by producer referendum. Eliminates certain burley quota transfer provisions for Tennessee and Virginia. (Sec. 11) Eliminates certain tobacco exports from flue- cured and burley national marketing quota calculations. (Sec. 12) Revises certain burley marketing quota lease and transfer provisions. (Sec. 14) Increases maximum acreage transfers. (Sec. 15) States that performance rendered in good faith reliance upon Department of Agriculture advice or actions may be accepted as meeting appropriate marketing quota requirements. (Sec. 16) Harmonizes certain flue-cured and burley sales dates. (Sec. 17) Authorizes a recent farm purchaser to sell burley or flue-cured marketing quotas within one year of such purchase.</summary>
</bill>
