<bill session="108" type="h" number="5181" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Employee Freedom from Invasion of Privacy Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect employees from invasion of privacy by employers by prohibiting certain video monitoring and audio monitoring of employees by their employers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400318"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2004-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1749"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contractors"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2004--Introduced.
Employee Freedom from Invasion of Privacy Act - Prohibits employers from engaging in video or audio monitoring of employees in restroom facilities, dressing rooms, or other areas in which it is reasonable to expect employees to change clothing. Establishes maximum civil penalties for violators. Requires the Secretary of Labor to: (1) provide written notice and an opportunity for a hearing before assessing penalties; and (2) determine the amount of penalties taking into account the nature of the violation and specified factors with respect to the violator. Authorizes judicial review of an assessment order for employers who requested a hearing. Authorizes the Attorney General to file suit to recover civil penalties assessed under this Act if an employer fails to pay. Authorizes the Secretary to commence civil actions for injunctive relief to prevent violations of this Act. Authorizes employees aggrieved by an employer's violation of this Act to commence a civil action against the employer for injunctive relief, damages (if the violation is knowing), or both. Asserts that this Act does not alter State law or collective bargaining agreements except where inconsistent with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
