<bill session="104" type="h" number="1475" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Deposit Insurance Fund Merger Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To merge the Bank Insurance Fund and the Savings Association Insurance Fund, to require savings associations to continue to pay assessments to the Financing Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E855-856"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Financing Corporation"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/1995--Introduced.
Deposit Insurance Fund Merger Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (FDIA) to: (1) establish the deposit insurance fund for insured depository institutions; (2) abolish the Bank Insurance Fund (BIF) and the Savings Association Insurance Fund (SAIF); (3) transfer such Funds' assets and liabilities to the deposit insurance fund; and (4) deposit into such fund all amounts assessed against insured depository institutions. Prescribes guidelines under which the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) shall keep a full and complete accounting of all costs, expenses, and receipts. Sets forth an assessments schedule for former BIF members capped at rates applicable before the funds' merger. Repeals guidelines pertaining to the moratorium on conversion transactions and to exit fees. Amends the Federal Home Loan Bank Act to reflect amendments made by this Act regarding payment of Financing Corporation costs by former SAIF members and their successors. Amends the FDIA to authorize the FDIC to impose a one-time special SAIF capitalization assessment.</summary>
</bill>
