<bill session="106" type="h" number="5422" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Streamlined Environmental Reporting and Pollution Prevention Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish an integrated environmental reporting program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2000-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="2000-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2000-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control equipment"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2000--Introduced.
Streamlined Environmental Reporting and Pollution Prevention Act of 2000 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to integrate and streamline reporting requirements.Requires the Administrator, to ensure consistency and facilitate use of the integrated reporting program, to: (1) allow each person required to submit information to the Administrator to report to one point of contact using a single electronic system or paper form and, in the case of any person subject to more than one annual reporting requirement, at one time during the year; (2) identify environmental or occupational safety or health reporting requirements that are not administered by the Administrator; (3) implement data standards and a nomenclature understandable to persons without environmental expertise; (4) consolidate reporting of information that would be required to be reported at more than one point in the same data submission; (5) provide for data formats and submission protocols that conform with public-domain standards for electronic commerce, are accessible to a majority of reporting persons, and provide for data integrity and reliability; (6) publish a document that the Administrator shall use as the framework for databases in which reported data are kept and that the Administrator shall allow other Federal agencies and governments to use; (7) establish an electronic service center to assist reporting persons; (8) provide each reporting person access to scientifically sound, publicly available information on pollution prevention technologies and practices; (9) provide protection of confidential business information; and (10) promote development of software that helps reporting persons in assembling and submitting information and receiving information on pollution prevention technologies and practices .Provides that nothing in this Act requires a person to use the integrated reporting program instead of an existing reporting method.(Sec. 4) Requires the Administrator, at the request of any Federal, State, tribal, or local agency, to coordinate the integration of reporting required under this Act with similar efforts by the agency that are consistent with this Act.Authorizes the Administrator to develop a procedure under which a person that is required to report information under laws administered by the Administrator and laws administered by a State, tribal, or local agency to report all required information through one point of contact using a single electronic system or paper form and, in the case of persons subject to more than one annual reporting requirement, at one time during the year.Directs the Administrator, to facilitate reporting by persons with facilities in more than one State, tribal, or local jurisdiction, to encourage the use of a common data format by any State, tribal, or local agency coordinating with the Administrator.(Sec. 6) Requires the Administrator to report to Congress on provisions of law that explicitly prohibit or hinder the integration of reporting and other actions required under this Act.(Sec. 7) Provides that nothing in this Act: (1) changes any provision of Federal, State, tribal, or local law or the obligation of any person to comply with any provision of law; (2) alters any person's obligation to provide information required under any reporting requirement; or (3) authorizes the Administrator to require the reporting of additional information or to eliminate the reporting of information currently required to be reported.(Sec. 8) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
