<bill session="106" type="hr" number="189" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-08T11:30:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-06-08T11:30:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 150) to amend the Act popularly known as the Recreation and Public Purposes Act to authorize disposal of certain public lands or national forest lands to local education agencies for use for elementary or secondary schools, including public charter schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T21:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-164, by Mr. Sessions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25T21:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 150 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Resources now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. The Chairman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whether the Member offering an amendment has caused it to be printed in the Congressional Record. Any Member may demand a separate vote in the House on any amendment adopted in the Committee or to the Committee amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-05-25T21:14:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="62">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 62.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T11:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3774-3776" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T11:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 189.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T11:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1999-06-08T11:30:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T11:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="150"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/1999--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 150 (education land grant).</summary>
</bill>
