<bill session="104" type="hj" number="173" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to protect the rights of victims of crime.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1996-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1996-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="1996-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1996-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="1996-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1996-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="411214" joined="1996-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administration of criminal justice"/>
    <term name="Bail"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pleas (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Speedy trial"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1996--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Grants victims of violent crimes or crimes for which the defendant can be imprisoned for a period longer than one year the following rights: (1) to receive notice of, and to be present at, every stage of the public proceedings, unless the court determines there is good cause for the victim not be present; (2) to comment at any such proceeding involving the possible release of the defendant, the acceptance of any plea agreement, or sentencing; (3) to be informed of the defendant's release or escape; (4) to reasonable protection from physical harm or intimidation relating to the proceeding; (5) to have the proceedings resolved in a prompt and timely manner; and (6) to have the court order restitution from the defendant upon conviction. Makes such rights available to victims upon request to the prosecuting authority and in the manner provided by law under this amendment. Grants power to the legislatures of the States and the Congress to enforce this amendment by appropriate legislation.</summary>
</bill>
