<bill session="106" type="h" number="5030" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Steel Industry National Historic Park Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Steel Industry National Historic Park in the State of Pennsylvania and to provide for the extension of the Potomac Heritage National Scenic Trail between Cumberland, Maryland, and Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400114"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="2000-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Factories"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Steel Industry National Historic Park Title II: Extension of Potomac Heritage National Scenic Trail Steel Industry National Historic Park Act of 2000 - Title I: Steel Industry National Historic Park - Establishes in Pennsylvania the Steel Industry National Historic Park for inclusion within the National Park System. Specifies the historic properties to be included within the Park. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire by donation specified property for inclusion within such Park.Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into a cooperative agreement for Park purposes; and (2) provide technical assistance for the preservation of Park structures, maintenance of the cultural landscape, and local Park preservation planning.Directs the Secretary to prepare and submit to specified congressional committees a Park general management plan.Authorizes appropriations.Title II: Extension of Potomac Heritage National Scenic Trail - Amends the National Trails System Act to direct the Secretary to designate the system of trails between Cumberland, Maryland, and Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, known as the Allegheny Trail Alliance Trails as components of the Potomac Heritage National Scenic Trail.</summary>
</bill>
