<bill session="108" type="hr" number="527" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Celebrating the 50th anniversary of the opening of the Falcon International Dam, recognizing the dam's importance as a source of water and power and as a symbol of friendship and cooperation between the United States and the United Mexican States, and urging Mexico to honor all of its obligations under the 1944 Treaty Relating to the Utilization of Waters of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400339"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International rivers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2004--Introduced.
States that the House of Representatives: (1) celebrates the 50th anniversary of the opening of Falcon International Dam in 1954; (2) recognizes that the building of the Dam was an extraordinary project and that operating its facilities continues to represent a substantial undertaking; (3) acknowledges recent payments by the United Mexican States under the 1944 Treaty Relating to the Utilization of Water of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande between the United States and Mexico and urges Mexico to honor all of its obligations under such Treaty; and (5) recommits itself to the binational effort and spirit in which the Dam was constructed.</summary>
</bill>
