<bill session="104" type="h" number="189" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil Recycling and Safe Handling Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act and the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (Superfund) to provide for the recycling and management of used oil and to reduce emissions of lead into the ambient air, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402763"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Arsenic"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cadmium"/>
    <term name="Chromium"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Petroleum recycling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum storage"/>
    <term name="Polychlorinated biphenyls"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Oil Recycling and Safe Handling Act of 1995 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to revise provisions concerning the management of used oil. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to list as a hazardous waste any used oil and any product derived from such oil that fails to meet certain specifications for flashpoint, lead, arsenic, chromium, cadmium, halogens, and polychlorinated biphenyls. Permits fuel containing used oil that meets specifications without treatment to be marketed as containing ingredients that are not hazardous wastes if the oil and fuel are analyzed to demonstrate compliance. Exempts used oil generated by petroleum refining or production facilities which is to be refined along with normal process streams from requirements for hazardous waste under the Solid Waste Disposal Act if it is inserted into the refining process or production pipeline. Directs the Administrator to promulgate regulations for the management of used oil classified as a hazardous waste. Exempts from such regulation generators of used oil which is household waste, curbside collection programs, and specified scrap materials. Exempts certain used oil generators and collectors from hazardous waste regulations under the Solid Waste Disposal Act (other than those under this Act) if they meet certain recycling, transportation, disposal, and recordkeeping requirements. Applies standards for hazardous waste transporters and facilities to hazardous used oil transporters and facilities. Requires hazardous used oil facilities to obtain hazardous waste management permits. Directs the Administrator to require producers and importers of lubricating base stock to guarantee the reuse of an annually increasing percentage of used lubricating oil. Requires States to provide incentives to persons who accept and collect used oil. Imposes fees on lubricating base stock sold at retail and provides for the use of such fees for State and local used oil collection efforts. Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act to prohibit any person from bringing an action against (currently, recovering response costs or damages from) service station dealers for response costs or damages resulting from releases of used (currently, recycled) oil, subject to certain conditions.</summary>
</bill>
