<bill session="108" type="h" number="4062" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-04-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for an additional temporary extension of programs under the Small Business Act and the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 through June 4, 2004, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400252"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400045" joined="2004-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2004-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-31T10:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Manzullo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-31T10:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1746-1750" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-31T10:23:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4062.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-03-31T10:37:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1746-1747" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-31T10:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2004-04-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3595" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-04-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-04-02">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2004-04-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-04-05">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2004-04-05" type="public" number="108-217">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-217.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="2186"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Venture capital"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/5/2004--Public Law.
(Sec. 1) Extends through June 4 (currently, April 2), 2004, under the same terms and conditions, the authorization for any program, authority, or provision, including any pilot program, that is authorized under the Small Business Act (the Act) or the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (SBIA) as of September 30, 2003. (Sec. 2) Amends the SBIA to extend through FY 2004 (currently, May 21, 2004) the authority of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to charge and collect certain fees in connection with the guarantee of development company debentures under the small business investment program. (Sec. 3) Amends the Act to authorize the SBA to make specified amounts in purchases of participating securities and guarantees of debentures under the SBIA small business investment company program. (Sec. 4) Provides that, during the period beginning on the enactment of this Act and ending on September 30, 2004, in the case of any combination financing by a small business (receiving a loan guaranteed by the SBA and a commercial loan, no portion of which is guaranteed by the Federal Government), the amount of the commercial loan shall not exceed the gross amount of the guaranteed loan which is part of the financing. Allows the commercial loan to be: (1) made by the lender providing the guaranteed financing or by a different lender; (2) secured by a senior lien; and (3) made by a lender in the Preferred Lenders Program. Requires a fee to be paid by the lender to the SBA if the commercial loan has a senior credit position to that of the guaranteed loan. (Sec. 5) Directs the SBA Administrator, during the same period as above, to assess and collect a loan guarantee fee, which shall be a percentage of the outstanding balance of the deferred participation share of the loan. Terminates, during such period, the authority of lenders under SBA-guaranteed loans to retain any loan guarantee fees collected. (Sec. 6) Limits the authority to make Express Loans to those lenders deemed qualified by the Administrator. Increases, until the end of FY 2004, the maximum loan amount under the Express Loan Pilot Program. Gives a qualified lender the option to participate in such Program. (Sec. 7) Continues through FY 2004 current SBA guaranteed loan deferred participation standards. (Sec. 8) Provides through FY 2004: (1) an increase in SBA guaranteed loan limits; and (2) an additional loan guarantee fee.</summary>
</bill>
