<bill session="108" type="h" number="5337" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit members of Congress from entering into any agreement with any foreign person or any commercial entity for the purpose of influencing or seeking a change in a law or regulation of the United States that would ease any restriction on a state sponsor of terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2004--Introduced.
Amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to redefine agent of a foreign principal to include Members of Congress who enter into written agreements with any foreign person to modify any Federal law or regulation that would result in easing any restriction imposed on any country the government of which has been determined by the Secretary of State, for purposes of specified Federal law, to be a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism. Amends the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 to deem any agreement or action on behalf of a foreign person or a business concern which is prohibited under the Federal criminal code to be U.S. export assistance prohibited under such Act. (Currently, U.S. assistance and financing is prohibited for exports to Cuba or for commercial exports to Iran, Libya, North Korea, or Sudan.) Expresses the sense of Congress that any Member of Congress who violates the Federal criminal code should be sanctioned under the appropriate congressional rule.</summary>
</bill>
