<bill session="107" type="h" number="4672" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Pension Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that, if an individual is expelled from Congress, any Member service previously rendered by that individual shall be noncreditable for purposes of determining eligibility for or the amount of any benefits which might otherwise be payable out of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund based on the service of that individual, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400279"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2002-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2002-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2002-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2002-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional pensions"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2002--Introduced.
Congressional Pension Accountability Act - Provides that: (1) all service as a Member of Congress of an individual who is expelled from Congress shall be noncreditable for purposes of determining eligibility for, or the amount of, any annuity which might otherwise be payable out of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund based on such service; (2) all Government contributions to the Thrift Savings Plan for that individual while that individual was performing Member service (and attributed earnings) shall be forfeited; and (3) the portion of such an individual's lump-sum credit which is attributable to such Member service (less any amount previously refunded or paid as annuity benefits) shall be payable to such individual or, if deceased, to the appropriate beneficiary or beneficiaries.</summary>
</bill>
