<bill session="104" type="h" number="4261" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Save Manatees and Alleviate Red Tide Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to expedite issuance of and implement a contingency plan for responding to red tide events involving Florida Manatees, and to authorize the Director to make grants for research and evaluation of potential methods of therapeutic intervention for manatees intoxicated by red tide brevetoxins.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400510"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1996-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Manatees"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine mammal protection"/>
    <term name="Red tide"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Introduced.
Save Manatees and Alleviate Red Tide Act - Directs the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to issue a contingency plan under the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 for responding to red tide events involving Florida manatees, and implement such plan as part of the Florida manatee recovery program. Authorizes the Director to make grants for research and evaluation of potential methods of therapeutic intervention for manatees intoxicated by red tide brevetoxins, including immunotherapy using antibrevetoxin antibodies. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Marine Mammal Commission to conduct: (1) a comprehensive review of the scientific findings of investigations into the spring 1996 Florida manatee red tide mortality event; and (2) an interdisciplinary conference to discuss review findings for recommending actions to the Congress to protect the Florida manatee from red tide events. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
