<bill session="105" type="h" number="3800" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Assistance Reform Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to require that assistance provided to a foreign country under part I of that Act, other than assistance provided on a cash transfer basis, shall be in the form of credits redeemable only for the purchase of United States goods and services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/1998--Introduced.
Foreign Assistance Reform Act of 1998 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to require non-cash transfer assistance provided to a foreign country be in the form of credits redeemable only for the purchase of U.S. goods and services (currently, purchase may be for goods and services outside the United States). Directs the President to ensure that: (1) such purchases, and the ports of departure for those goods, are distributed equitably throughout the United States; and (2) U.S. goods are available at fair prices. Requires that the Comptroller General have access to records and personnel necessary to carry out monitoring and auditing. Authorizes the President to waive the requirements of this Act on a case-by-case basis to the extent that it is important to U.S. national interests.</summary>
</bill>
