<bill session="106" type="hr" number="387" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-18T17:57:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-18T17:57:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 1180) to amend the Social Security Act to expand the availability of health care coverage for working individuals with disabilities, to establish a Ticket to Work and Self-Sufficiency Program in the Social Security Administration to provide such individuals with meaningful opportunities to work, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-11-18T03:48:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-482, by Mr. Hastings (WA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-18T03:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 1180 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-11-18T03:48:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="164">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 164.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-11-18T17:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12822-12823" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-18T17:46:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 387.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-18T17:57:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1999-11-18T17:57:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-18T17:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="1180"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/1999--Introduced.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the conference report on H.R. 1180 (health care coverage and meaningful work opportunities for working individuals with disabilities).</summary>
</bill>
