<bill session="105" type="h" number="2534" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-08T15:39:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-11-08T15:39:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reauthorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reauthorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reauthorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform, extend, and repeal certain agricultural research, extension, and education programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400079"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="1997-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="410084" joined="1997-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1997-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry, Resource Conservation and Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-25">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-08">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-10-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-11-04T23:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Agriculture. H. Rept. 105-376.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-11-04T23:50:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="221">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 221.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T13:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (OR) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T13:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10354-10371, H10384" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T13:04:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T13:43:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T15:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-11-08T15:39:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="618" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 291 - 125 (Roll no. 618).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T15:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-01-27">
      <text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-24">
      <text>For Further Action See S.1150.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAG27" subcommittee="Forestry, Resource Conservation and Research" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="725"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2737"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2876"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="1150"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="1150"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aflatoxins"/>
    <term name="Agricultural colleges"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural diversification"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural experiment stations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agricultural industries"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pests"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative agriculture"/>
    <term name="Alternative crops"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animal genetics"/>
    <term name="Animal germplasm resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Antibiotics"/>
    <term name="Ants"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bacterial diseases"/>
    <term name="Beef"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Botanical gardens"/>
    <term name="Chromosome mapping"/>
    <term name="Citrus fruits"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="Crisis management"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Farm manure"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to disability services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to rural areas"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fish culture"/>
    <term name="Food contamination"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Food supply"/>
    <term name="Foodborne diseases"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Forestry education"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Forests"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Fruit trade"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Goats"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grassland ecology"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Hepatitis"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydrocarbons"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="Integrated pest management"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agricultural cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Livestock industry"/>
    <term name="Lyme disease"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Marketing orders"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Meteorological research"/>
    <term name="Methyl bromide"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Moths"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Natural foods"/>
    <term name="New products"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Organic farming"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Peanuts"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pesticide residues in food"/>
    <term name="Pesticides policy"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Plant diseases"/>
    <term name="Plant ecology"/>
    <term name="Plant genetics"/>
    <term name="Plant germplasm resources"/>
    <term name="Potatoes"/>
    <term name="Poultry industry"/>
    <term name="Poultry inspection"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Renewable natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-help devices for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Sorghum"/>
    <term name="Sustainable agriculture"/>
    <term name="Swine"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trade associations"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Virus diseases"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wheat"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
    <term name="Wool"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/1997--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Coordination, Planning, and Definitions Regarding Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Title II: Reform of Existing Research, Extension, and Education Authorities Subtitle A: Smith-Lever Act and Hatch Act of 1887 Subtitle B: National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 Subtitle C: Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 Subtitle D: National Research Initiative Subtitle E: Other Existing Laws Title III: Extension or Repeal of Research, Extension, and Education Initiatives Subtitle A: Extensions Subtitle B: Repeals Title IV: New Research, Extension, and Education Initiatives Subtitle A: Partnerships for High-Value Agricultural Product Quality Research Subtitle B: Precision Agriculture Subtitle C: Other Initiatives Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reauthorization Act of 1997 - Title I: Coordination, Planning, and Definitions Regarding Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education - Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary) to establish priorities and specified management principles for federally supported and conducted agricultural research, extension, and education. (Sec. 102) Revises the definition of "food and agricultural sciences." (Sec. 103) Revises specified consultation provisions with respect to the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board. (Sec. 104) Directs the Secretary to provide for: (1) scientific peer review of research grants and merit review of extension and education grants by the Cooperative State Research, Education, and Extension Service; and (2) scientific peer review of research activities of the Department of Agriculture (Department). Requires pre-funding merit review of college and university research and extension activities. Makes related amendments to the Smith-Lever Act and the Hatch Act of 1887. (Sec. 105) Makes all colleges and universities eligible for agricultural research, extension, and education cost-reimbursable agreements. (Sec. 106) Directs the Secretary to: (1) create performance guidelines for Department research, extension, and education programs; and (2) evaluate such programs' national scope and benefits. Title II: Reform of Existing Research, Extension, and Education Authorities - Subtitle A: Smith-Lever Act and Hatch Act of 1887 - Amends specified Acts to make their common names (Smith-Lever Act and the Hatch Act of 1887) their official titles. (Sec. 202) Revises such Acts with respect to: (1) matching funds; and (2) plans of work for recipient institutions. Subtitle B: National Agricultural Research, Extension and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 - Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 with respect to 1890 land grant colleges, including Tuskegee University, to: (1) revise extension and research plans of work provisions; and (2) direct the Secretary to develop protocols to evaluate multi-State and mult-institutional programs. (Sec. 212) Establishes a phased-in matching funds requirement for such institutions beginning with FY 2000. Requires each institution to report to the Secretary by September 30, 1999, identifying non-Federal fund sources. Changes specified references to Tuskegee Institute to Tuskegee University. (Sec. 213) Includes "teaching" within such Act's international research and extension activities. (Sec. 214) Transfers authority for a specified agricultural research facilities task force from the Research Facilities Act to the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977. Repeals the Research Facilities Act. Subtitle C: Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 - Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to authorize appropriations through FY 2002 for the agricultural genome initiative (currently the plant genome mapping program). Subtitle D: National Research Initiative - Amends the Competitive, Special, and Facilities Research Grant Act to authorize the Secretary to waive the matching requirement for certain small college or university projects (based upon equipment cost and use). Subtitle E: Other Existing Laws - Amends the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Research Act of 1978 to: (1) authorize the Secretary to use specified amounts available from forestry competitive research grants for certain high priority forestry research areas; and (2) direct the Secretary to establish a program to inventory and analyze public and private U.S. forests. Title III: Extension or Repeal of Research, Extension, and Education Initiatives - Subtitle A: Extensions - Amends the Competitive, Special, and Facilities Research Grant Act to authorize appropriations through FY 2002 for competitive, special, and facilities research grants. (Sec. 302) Amends the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 to authorize appropriations through FY 2002 for "1994 Institutions" (Indian and tribal colleges), and institutional capacity building grants. (Sec. 303) Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to authorize appropriations and programs through FY 2002 for: (1) education grants for Hispanic-serving institutions; (2) agricultural extension and research, and State experiment stations; (3) food and agricultural science education; (4) research on the production and marketing of alcohols and industrial hydrocarbons from agricultural commodities and forest products; (5) policy research centers; (6) human nutrition intervention and health promotion research; (7) pilot research program to combine medical and agricultural research; (8) food and nutrition education program; (9) animal health and disease continuing and national or regional research; (10) grants to upgrade agricultural and food sciences facilities at 1890 land-grant colleges; (11) national research and training centennial centers; (12) supplemental and alternative crops research; (13) aquaculture research and extension; and (14) rangeland research. (Sec. 319) Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act Amendments of 1985 to authorize appropriations through FY 2002 for Federal agricultural research facilities. (Sec. 320) Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to authorize appropriations through FY 2002 for: (1) national genetics resources program; (2) agricultural telecommunications program; (3) assistive technology program for farmers with disabilities; (4) national rural information center clearinghouse; and (5) water quality research. (Sec. 325) Amends the Critical Agricultural Materials Act to authorize appropriations through FY 2002 for the critical agricultural materials program. Subtitle B: Repeals - Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to repeal grant authority for aquaculture research facilities at Illinois State University and Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. (Sec. 342) Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act Amendments of 1981 to repeal the dairy goat research program. (Sec. 343) Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to repeal the livestock product safety and inspection program. (Sec. 344) Amends the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 to repeal FY 1998 through 2002 authorization of appropriations for agricultural research, extension, and education. Title IV: New Research, Extension, and Education Initiatives - Subtitle A: Partnerships for High-Value Agricultural Product Quality Research - Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to an eligible partnership (a land-grant college acting in partnership with other colleges, Federal laboratories, and nonprofit research entities) to coordinate research and extension activities to enhance the quality of high-value agricultural products. Authorizes FY 1998 through 2002 appropriations. Subtitle B: Precision Agriculture - Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to promote precision agriculture (as defined by this Act), including the encouragement of national and multi-State precision agriculture partnerships. Authorizes FY 1998 through 2002 appropriations, with funds reserved for education and information dissemination projects. Subtitle C: Other Initiatives - Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act to authorize the Secretary to: (1) make grants for high-priority research and extension activities (in lieu of existing specialized research programs); and (2) appoint a related task force. Authorizes FY 1998 through 2002 appropriations. (Sec. 422) Authorizes the Secretary to make grants for an organic agriculture research and extension initiative. Authorizes FY 1998 through 2002 appropriations. (Sec. 423) Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to authorize the Secretary to: (1) provide for a joint United States-Mexico agricultural research program; and (2) make grants to colleges and universities for international agricultural science and education programs (authorizes appropriations). (Sec. 425) Directs the Secretary to continue operation of the Food Animal Residue Avoidance Database program. Authorizes program grants for colleges and universities. (Sec. 426) Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with private entities to use the facilities and expertise of the Agricultural Research Service (ARS) to develop and commercialize new biobased products. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 427) Directs the Secretary to establish the Thomas Jefferson Initiative for Crop Diversification for the production and marketing of new and nontraditional crops. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 428) Authorizes the Secretary to establish an integrated research, education, and extension grant program. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 429) Amends the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 to authorize the Secretary to make grants to 1994 Institutions to conduct agricultural research that addresses high priority tribal, national, and multi-State concerns. Authorizes FY 1998 through 2002 appropriations. Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions - States that the Secretary shall be the principal executive branch official with respect to agricultural and food sciences research and extension. (Sec. 502) Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a Food Safety Research Information Office in the National Agricultural Library; and (2) periodically update nutrient composition data. (Sec. 505) Amends Federal law to make fees collected at the National Arboretum available to the Secretary without further appropriations. (Sec. 506) Provides that fees collected by ARS from the Patent Culture Collection shall be retained for Collection maintenance and operation. (Sec. 507) Authorizes the Agricultural Marketing Service to reimburse the American Sheep Industry Association for certain marketing order expenses incurred under the Sheep Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 1994. (Sec. 508) Designates the Subtropical Agricultural Research Center in Weslaco, Texas, as the Kika de la Garza Subtropical Agricultural Research Center. (Sec. 509) Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) a substantial amount of ARS funds regarding methyl bromide alternatives should be used for research in real conditions, such as pre-planting and post-harvest conditions; (2) the Secretary and the Secretary of Education should cooperate in providing school-based agricultural education; and (3) the Secretary should designate a department crisis management team.</summary>
</bill>
