<bill session="106" type="h" number="1739" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Money, Clean Elections Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform the financing of Federal elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1999-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400181" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1999-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400613" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1999-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-21">
      <text>Re-referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" subcommittee="Postal Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign debates"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/1999--Introduced.
Clean Money, Clean Elections Act - Title I: Clean Money Financing of House Election Campaigns - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to add a new title V (Clean Money Financing of House Election Campaigns) under which is set forth eligibility and qualifying contribution requirements, seed money provisions, and benefits of clean money financing of election campaigns. Defines the terms "qualifying contribution" and "seed money contribution."(Sec. 102) Sets forth requirements applicable to clean money candidates regarding the following: (1) contributions and expenditures; and (2) personal funds use.Directs the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to: (1) determine whether the candidate meets the eligibility requirements; and (2) certify whether or not the candidate is a clean money candidate.Establishes in the Treasury a House of Representatives Election Fund for the FEC to deposit unspent seed money contributions, qualifying contributions, penalty amounts, and amounts appropriated for clean money financing.Requires the FEC to assess a certain civil penalty against a clean money candidate when such candidate makes an expenditure from funds other than clean money funds.Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 103) Sets forth reporting requirements regarding certain expenditures of private money candidates.Title II: Independent Expenditures; Coordinated Political Party Expenditures - Amends FECA to set forth requirements for reporting of certain independent expenditures.(Sec. 202) Redefines the term "independent expenditure."(Sec. 203) Limits expenditures that may be made by political party committees in connection with the general election campaign of a House election in which one or more of the candidates is a clean money candidate.(Sec. 204) Requires a committee of a political party, before making coordinated expenditures in excess of $5,000 for a Federal election, to certify to the FEC that it has not and will not make any independent expenditures in connection with such campaign. Prohibits a party committee that determines to make coordinated expenditures to transfer or receive any transfer of funds in the same election cycle from any other party committee that determines to make independent expenditures in connection with the same campaign for Federal office.Title III: Voter Information - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to entitle clean money candidates to receive specified free broadcast time.(Sec. 302) Allows clean money candidates to receive certain broadcast media rates for use of a television broadcasting station. Prohibits preemption of the use of a broadcasting station by a legally qualified candidate for Congress, except under circumstances beyond a station's control.(Sec. 303) Amends FECA to revise requirements for publication and distribution of statements and solicitations, including applying the requirements to political committees (currently applicable to any person). Sets forth: (1) political advertising provisions for print and broadcast or cablecast communications; and (2) reporting requirements for issue advertisements.(Sec. 304) Amends Federal postal law to prohibit franked mass mailings (except about a public meeting) by a Member in his or her election year, unless such Member will not be a candidate for any Federal office.Title IV: Soft Money of Political Parties - Amends FECA with respect to soft money to: (1) prohibit a national committee of a political party (including a national congressional campaign committee of a political party) from soliciting or receiving contributions or making expenditures not subject to FECA; (2) require a State, district, or local committee of a political party to make Federal election year expenditures (with exceptions) from funds subject to FECA; (3) prohibit a national, State, district, or local committee from soliciting or donating funds to a tax-exempt organization; and (4) prohibit an incumbent or candidate for Federal office, or an agent of a candidate or an incumbent, from soliciting or receiving funds not subject to FECA, or to solicit or receive funds for a non-Federal election in excess of certain limits or from prohibited sources (with exceptions for State or local candidates in compliance with State law).(Sec. 402) Establishes aggregate contribution limits for political committees established and maintained by a State committee of a political party and increases the aggregate contribution limit for any individual in any calendar year.(Sec. 403) Prescribes reporting requirements pertaining to political committees. Eliminates the exception for building funds relating to the definition of contribution.Title V: Restructuring and Strengthening of the Federal Election Commission - Revises FECA requirements for the composition and terms of FEC Commissioners.Authorizes the FEC to: (1) conduct random post election audits to ensure voluntary FECA compliance; (2) seek injunctions; and (3) expedite its procedures for certain complaints.(Sec. 504) Revises the standard for an investigation by the FEC of a violation to require the FEC to investigate a violation when it has reason to open an investigation on whether (currently, reason to believe that) a violation of FECA has been committed or is about to be committed.(Sec. 505) Revises requirements relating to the powers of the FEC to authorize it to: (1) appeal a petition for certiorari before the Supreme Court; and (2) issue a subpoena without the signature of the chairperson or the vice chairperson.(Sec. 507) Amends FECA to mandate electronic filing of FEC reports for public availability on the Internet and at FEC offices. Establishes within FEC reporting requirements specified time frames for separate, detailed notifications to the FEC and other appropriate Federal officials when any contribution is received by any political committee within a certain period of time surrounding the election.Title VI: Miscellaneous Provisions - Provides for: (1) severability of the provisions of this Act; (2) U.S. Supreme Court review of constitutional issues; and (3) the effective date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
