<amendment session="105" chamber="h" number="23" updated="2013-07-17T07:51:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="400" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="1997-04-17T16:00:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <offered datetime="1997-04-17"/>
  <description>Amendment includes technical changes; delays the publication of patent applications from small business concerns or independent inventors until 3 months after a second notification on the merits is made by the Patent and Trademark Office (PTO); retains the practice of charging small businesses and independent inventors a reduced application fee; separates operational and policy functions of the PTO and creates an Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property Policy to develop patent and trademark policy; establishes an incentive program to train patent and trademark examiners; and strikes authority to accept gifts or donations of services.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to make several technical changes to the bill, including the following: 1. Allow small businesses and independent inventors to forestall the publication of their patents until three months after the second inspection and approval; 2. continue the current practice of charging small businesses and independent inventors a reduced fee; require that inventors be included as members of the proposed Patent and Trademark Office Advisory Board; 3. eliminates provisions in the bill allowing the Patent Office to borrow money from priveate entities to fund operations; 4. Allows inventor and university patent applicants to respond to Patent examiner's inquiries without reducing the intervening time from their 17-year patent protection; 5. noarrow the limitation on multiple patent re-examination requests from a single inventor to a single proceeding. from a single inventor to a single proceeding.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-04-17T14:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Coble.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1997-04-17T16:00:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Coble amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
