<bill session="104" type="h" number="1519" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Low Income Community Development Tax Credit Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit for the construction and renovation of nonresidential buildings in distressed areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buildings"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Industrial buildings"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/1995--Introduced.
Low Income Community Development Tax Credit Act of 1995 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow, as part of the general business credit, a tax credit (equal to a percentage of its basis) for placing a nonresidential building in service in a distressed area, with a greater credit allowed for a new building than an existing building. Provides for calculation of the basis of such buildings according to the rules governing the low-income housing credit. Defines a distressed area as one in which at least 70 percent of the households have an income that is no more than 80 percent of the area median gross income. Increases the credit with respect to buildings in areas in which income is lower. Treats rehabilitation expenditures, provided they are above a certain threshold, as a separate new building. Imposes an annual State distressed area building credit ceiling.</summary>
</bill>
