<bill session="104" type="h" number="3683" updated="2012-11-01T22:45:19-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Campaign Integrity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit use of labor organization dues and fees for political activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400405"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government employees' political activities"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor union finances"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Union dues"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>06/19/1996--Introduced.
Congressional Campaign Integrity Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit the use of labor organization dues and fees for contributions or expenditures in any Federal election or to promote any political activity or organization. (Sec. 3) Prohibits candidates for Federal office from making any loans to their campaigns. (Sec. 4) Increases the contribution limitation applicable to individuals. Decreases the limitation on multicandidate political committee contributions to be equal to the limitation applicable in the preceding. (Sec. 5) Prohibits a candidate for the office of Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress from accepting contributions from individuals other than in-State individual residents which total the same as, or in excess of, the total of contributions accepted from in-State individual residents. (Sec. 6) Limits soft money contributions and expenditures of political parties. (Sec. 7) Sets forth reporting requirements concerning political committees. Allows a State political party committee to file a State report in lieu of any report required to be filed by this Act, if the Federal Election Commission determines such reports contain substantially the same information. (Sec. 8) Modifies reporting requirements concerning soft money for election activity aggregating in excess of $2,000 disbursed or obligated by any individual other than political parties.</summary>
</bill>
