<bill session="105" type="h" number="3007" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commission on the Advancement of Women in Science, Engineering, and Technology Development Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Commission on the Advancement of Women in Science, Engineering, and Technology Development Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Commission on the Advancement of Women and Minorities in Science, Engineering, and Technology Development Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Commission on the Advancement of Women and Minorities in Science, Engineering, and Technology Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Commission on the Advancement of Women in Science, Engineering, and Technology Development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1998-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1998-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1998-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1998-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2317"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Basic Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-23">
      <text>Subcommittee on Basic Research Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-05-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-06-03T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 105-562, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-06-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-06-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Fawell moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7664-7669" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-09-14T14:55:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11303" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-01">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1998-10-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-06">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-10-14" type="public" number="105-255">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-255.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Basic Research" name="House Science"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY17" subcommittee="Technology" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family leave"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in government"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Minority teachers"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientists in government"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination against women"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Women educators"/>
    <term name="Women engineers"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women in government"/>
    <term name="Women in labor unions"/>
    <term name="Women scientists"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/1998--Passed House amended.
Commission on the Advancement of Women and Minorities in Science, Engineering, and Technology Development Act - Establishes the Commission on the Advancement of Women and Minorities in Science, Engineering, and Technology Development. Directs the Commission to review available research and conduct additional necessary research to: (1) identify the number of women, minorities, and individuals with disabilities in the United States in specific types of occupations in science, engineering, and technology development; (2) examine the preparedness of such persons to pursue careers in such fields and to advance to positions of greater responsibility within academia, industry, and government; (3) describe the practices and policies of employers and labor unions relating to the recruitment, retention, and advancement of such persons in such fields; (4) identify the opportunities for, and artificial barriers to, the recruitment, retention, and advancement of such persons in such fields; (5) compile a synthesis of available research on lawful practices, policies, and programs that have successfully led to the recruitment, retention, and advancement of such persons in such fields and issue recommendations with respect to lawful policies that Government (including the Congress and appropriate Federal agencies), academia, and private industry can follow; (6) identify the disincentives for such persons to continue graduate education in such fields and the disincentives that lead to a disproportionate number of such persons leaving such fields; (7) identify university undergraduate programs that are successful in retaining such persons in such fields; (8) assess the extent to which the recommendations of the Task Force on Women, Minorities, and the Handicapped in Science and Technology have been implemented; (9) compile a list of all federally funded reports on the subjects of encouraging such persons to enter the fields of science and engineering and retaining such persons in the science and engineering workforce that have been issued since the Task Force submitted its report to the Congress; (10) assess the extent to which the recommendations contained in such reports have been implemented; and (11) evaluate the benefits of family-friendly policies such as the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 in order to assist recruiting, retaining, and advancing women in the fields of science, engineering, and technology. Requires the Commission to report its findings and recommendations to the President, the Congress, and the highest executive official of each State within one year after its members have been appointed. Terminates the Commission 30 days after the submission of its report. Directs the Commission to provide the information gathered to the National Science Foundation (NSF) which shall act as a central repository and make such information available to the public, including through the Internet. Requires NSF and any other Federal agency to provide any information requested by the Commission, including: (1) data on academic degrees awarded to such persons in science, engineering, and technology development and workforce representation and the retention of such persons in such fields; and (2) information gathered by NSF in the compilation of its biennial report on Women, Minorities, and Persons with Disabilities in Science and Engineering. Requires the Commission to review such information and include in its report: (1) recommendations on how to correct any deficiencies in the collection and analysis of the information which might impede the characterization of the factors which affect the attraction and retention of such persons in such fields; and (2) an assessment of the NSF's biennial report and recommendations on how that report could be improved. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1999 and 2000.</summary>
</bill>
