<bill session="106" type="h" number="752" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Airline Consumer Rights bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airline Passenger Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a national policy of basic consumer fair treatment for airline passengers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E258"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="383"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="383"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airline rates"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Travel agents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/1999--Introduced.
Airline Passenger Fairness Act - Amends Federal aviation law to revise provisions prohibiting an air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent from engaging in unfair or deceptive practices or unfair methods of competition in air transportation to include within the definition of such prohibited practices an air carrier's failure to: (1) inform a ticketed passenger, upon request, whether the flight on which the passenger is ticketed is oversold; (2) permit a passenger holding a confirmed reserved space on a flight to use portions of that passenger's ticket for travel, rather than the entire ticket, regardless of the reason any other portion of the ticket is not used; (3) deliver a passenger's checked baggage within 24 hours after the arrival of the flight on which the passenger traveled and on which the passenger checked the baggage, except for reasonable delays in delivery of such baggage; (4) provide a consumer full access to all fares for that air carrier, regardless of the technology the consumer uses to access the fares if such information is requested by that consumer; (5) provide notice to each passenger holding a confirmed reserved space on a flight with reasonable prior notice when a scheduled flight will be delayed for any reason (other than reasons of national security); (6) inform passengers accurately and truthfully of the reason for the delay, cancellation, or diversion of a flight; (7) refund the full purchase price of an unused ticket if the passenger requests a refund within 48 hours after the ticket is purchased; and (8) disclose to consumers information that would enable them to make informed decisions about the comparative value of frequent flyer programs among airlines.</summary>
</bill>
