<bill session="108" type="h" number="3186" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Geospatial Preparedness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish and maintain geospatial preparedness for the Nation with the National Spatial Data Infrastructure and integrated applications and systems required for homeland security, national defense, electronic government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400074"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Geographic information systems"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2003--Introduced.
Geospatial Preparedness Act - Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to direct the Chief Information Officer (CIO) of the Department of Homeland Security to work with the Departments of the Interior and Justice, the National Imagery and Mapping Agency, other appropriate Federal agencies, and members of the Federal Geographic Data Committee to use and enhance the National Spatial Data Infrastructure for homeland security purposes. Directs the CIO to establish security and policy guidelines for the acquisition, processing, and dissemination of geospatial data depicting critical infrastructure and strategic assets in the United States. Requires the: (1) Secretary to establish the Office of Geospatial Management within the Office of the CIO; and (2) Geospatial Manager to work with the CIO to design, manage, coordinate, and implement comprehensive geospatial initiatives.</summary>
</bill>
