<bill session="106" type="h" number="2910" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-30T12:23:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-09-30T12:23:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Transportation Safety Board Amendments Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Transportation Safety Board Amendments Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Transportation Safety Board Amendments Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize appropriations for the National Transportation Safety Board for fiscal years 2000, 2001, 2002, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1999-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1930-1931"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-09-27T15:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 106-335.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-09-27T15:06:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="195">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 195.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-09-29T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 312 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2910 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Makes in order the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure amendment in the nature of a substitute as an original bill for the purpose of amendment, modified by the amendment printed in H. Rept. 106-347. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T11:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 312 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T11:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 312.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9032-9040" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T11:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2910 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Makes in order the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure amendment in the nature of a substitute as an original bill for the purpose of amendment, modified by the amendment printed in H. Rept. 106-347. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T11:23:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 312 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T11:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Bill Barrett to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T11:23:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2910.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T11:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Weiner.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T11:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2910.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T11:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T11:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-09-30T12:23:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="462" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 420 - 4 (Roll no. 462).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-09-30T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="312"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2412"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air bases"/>
    <term name="Air traffic controllers"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Bus drivers"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Flight crews"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National Transportation Safety Board"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Pipeline safety"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sabotage"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Truck drivers"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h507"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/30/1999--Passed House amended.
National Transportation Safety Board Amendments Act of 1999 - Amends Federal transportation law to define the term "accident" to include damage to or destruction of vehicles in surface or air transportation or pipelines, regardless of whether the initiating event is accidental or not.(Sec. 3) Grants the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) authority to: (1) negotiate and enter into agreements with private entities, Federal, State, and local governments, and foreign governments for the provision of technical services or training in accident investigation theory and technique; and (2) require that such entities provide appropriate consideration for the reasonable costs of any goods, services, or training provided by the NTSB.(Sec. 4) Authorizes the NTSB to pay an employee with basic pay at a rate of GS-10 or above an overtime hourly rate of time-and-a-half for work performed at an accident scene (including travel to or from the scene) and other work critical to an accident investigation. Specifies limits on total NTSB overtime payments in a calendar year.(Sec. 5) Prohibits the NTSB from disclosing publicly any part of a surface vehicle video recorder recording or transcript of oral communications by or among drivers, train employees, or other operating employees responsible for the movement and direction of the vehicle or vessel, or between such operating employees and company communication centers, regarding an accident investigated by the NTSB. Requires the NTSB to make public any part of a transcript or any written depiction of visual information relevant to an accident, provided certain conditions are met. Subjects surface vehicle recordings (voice or video recorder) and transcripts of accidents (written depiction of visual information obtained from a video recorder) to specified requirements for discovery and use in a judicial proceeding.Prescribes requirements for installation and use of recording devices on surface vehicles.(Sec. 6) Requires the NTSB to relinquish investigative priority to the Federal Bureau of Investigation with respect to an accident if the Attorney General determines that circumstances reasonably indicate that such accident may have been caused by an intentional criminal act.(Sec. 8) Limits the Federal law compliance review authority of the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation with respect to the NTSB to its financial management and business operations (including internal accounting and administration control systems).(Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
