<bill session="106" type="h" number="5317" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Fiscal Responsibility and Accountability Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase accountability for Government spending and to reduce wasteful Government spending.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, Armed Services, Science, Resources, Banking and Financial Services, International Relations, Veterans' Affairs, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air force personnel"/>
    <term name="Air force procurement"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Antimissile missiles"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Artillery"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missile defenses"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting Board of Governors"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compulsory military service"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Engines"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Export subsidies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fighter aircraft"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Intercontinental ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in astronautics"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military aircraft"/>
    <term name="Military airlift"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Military helicopters"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military promotions"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Naval personnel"/>
    <term name="Naval procurement"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fusion"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear submarines"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Selective Service System"/>
    <term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space stations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Trade and Development Agency"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
    <term name="Transport aircraft"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Increased Accountability and Reduction in Medicare Waste and Fraud Title II: Increased Accountability and Reduction of Wasteful Defense Spending Title III: Reduction and Reform of Antienvironmental Spending Subtitle A: Program Terminations and Fees Subtitle B: Mining Provisions Title IV: Amendments of Internal Revenue Code of 1986 Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions to Reduce Wasteful and Inefficient Spending Comprehensive Fiscal Responsibility and Accountability Act of 2000 - Title I: Increased Accountability and Reduction in Medicare Waste and Fraud - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for increased medical reviews and anti-fraud activities under the Medicare Integrity Program.(Sec. 102) Authorizes appropriations for the purpose of carrying out, and expanding nationwide, the Health Care Anti-Fraud, Waste and Abuse Community Volunteer Demonstration Projects (Medicare Senior Waste Patrol) conducted by the Administration on Aging pursuant to the Omnibus Consolidated Appropriations Act, 1997.(Sec. 103) Amends the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 to repeal certain requirements for application of inherent reasonableness to all Medicare part B (Supplemental Medical Insurance) services other than physicians' services. Makes such repeal applicable as if such provisions had never been enacted.Amends SSA title XVIII with respect to the application of inherent reasonableness to all Medicare part B services other than physicians' services. Repeals the prohibition against the Secretary of Health and Human Services' applying factors that would increase or decrease the payment under part B during any year for any particular item or service by more than 15 percent from such payment during the preceding year. Makes such revision effective as of August 5, 1997.(Sec. 104) Directs the Secretary to require Medicare carriers to use commercial claims auditing systems in the processing of claims under part B of the Medicare program for the purpose of identifying billing errors and abuses.Title II: Increased Accountability and Reduction of Wasteful Defense Spending - Requires cancellation by the appropriate military department of the F-22 aircraft program, the Comanche helicopter program, and the Crusader artillery program.(Sec. 204) Prohibits the Secretary of the Navy, through FY 2009, from contracting for the procurement of more than eight Virginia class submarines (including current contracts).(Sec. 205) Prohibits further obligation of funds for production of Trident D5 missiles.(Sec. 206) Directs the President to reduce U.S. nuclear delivery systems to within START II limits.(Sec. 207) Directs the Secretary of Defense to reach an agreement with other member nations of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to establish a common NATO airlift capability of 20 C-17 aircraft, thereby eliminating the identical number currently required to be procured by the Air Force in fiscal years 2002 and 2003.(Sec. 208) Prohibits the Secretary of the Air Force from contracting for the procurement of additional C-130 aircraft for FY 2001 through 2005.(Sec. 209) Directs the Secretaries of the Air Force and Navy to reduce the requirements for pilots in nonflying positions.(Sec. 210) Requires the Secretary of Defense to implement a program to reduce the ratio of enlisted-to-officer personnel of each of the military departments to at least six to one by January 1, 2005.(Sec. 211) Amends the Military Selective Service Act to restrict current military registration requirements to periods during which a declaration of national emergency is declared, and authorizes the President to declare and terminate such a period. Requires the termination of such a declaration after a ten-day period of continuous congressional session unless Congress enacts a law ratifying the declaration.Provides that, except during such a national emergency: (1) the President may not appoint a person to serve on a civilian local board, appeal board, or similar agency of the Selective Service System (SSS); and (2) no such board may meet.Requires the SSS Director to report to Congress detailing a standby emergency manpower mobilization program to be used by the SSS during declared periods of national emergency.(Sec. 212) Makes unallowable as costs under a defense contract expenses incurred by a contractor related to a corporate merger, and prohibits Department of Defense funds from being used to pay such expenses.(Sec. 213) Prohibits any new assistance from being provided under the Foreign Military Financing Program account under the Arms Export Control Act.(Sec. 214) Prohibits the amount appropriated for the National Missile Defense program for any fiscal year from exceeding that appropriated for FY 2000, adjusted for inflation.(Sec. 215) Prohibits the total amount obligated for programs and activities of the Central Intelligence Agency for FY 2001 from exceeding that obligated for FY 2000.Title III: Reduction and Reform of Antienvironmental Spending - Subtitle A: Program Terminations and Fees - Prohibits the Department of Energy from obligating further funding for: (1) the Nuclear Energy Research Initiative; (2) the National Ignition Facility; (3) Tokamak fusion reactors; and (4) research on diesel engines for cars and light trucks.(Sec. 305) Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to instruct the Secretary of Energy to adjust the Nuclear Waste Fund fee annually for inflation.Subtitle B: Mining Provisions - Sets forth a statutory scheme which mandates a royalty of eight percent of the net smelter return from the production of locatable minerals, including their concentrates or products, located or converted under the general mining laws.(Sec. 312) Exempts from such royalty requirement any minerals processed at a facility by the same entity which extracted them if an urban development action grant has been made regarding any portion of such facility pursuant to the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974.(Sec. 313) Prohibits the issuance of any Federal mining patent or mill site claim after September 27, 2000, unless before that date: (1) the patent application was filed; and (2) specified requirements for vein or lode claims and placer claims were fully complied with.(Sec. 314) Requires the holder of each mining claim: (1) converted under the general mining laws to pay the Secretary an annual claim maintenance fee of $100 per claim; and (2) located pursuant to such laws to pay an annual claim maintenance fee of $200 per claim. Requires the amount of such fees to be credited against the royalties for the respective claims.Title IV: Amendments of Internal Revenue Code of 1986 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to provide for the termination, beginning January 1, 2001, of subpart C ( Taxation of Foreign Sales Corporations) of Part III (Income from Sources Without the United States) of Chapter N (Tax Based on Income From Income From Sources Within or Without the United States).(Sec. 402) Denies employers a deduction for payments of excessive compensation (more than 25 times the lowest compensation paid any other employee).(Sec. 403) Prohibits the deduction of tobacco advertising and promotional expenses.(Sec. 404) Amends IRC Subchapter N (Tax Based On Income From Sources Within Or Without the United States) provisions concerning the source rules for personal property sales to provide, as a general rule, for the exception of certain sales of inventory property from such provisions.Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions to Reduce Wasteful and Inefficient Spending - Prohibits the National Aeronautics and Space Administration from obligating any further funding for the International Space Station.(Sec. 502) Prohibits: (1) the Overseas Private Investment Corporation from issuing any contract of insurance or reinsurance, or any guaranty, or enter into any agreement to provide financing; and (2) the Export-Import Bank of the United States from providing any guarantee, insurance, or extension of credit, or participating in any extension of credit, except pursuant to a commitment made by it before enactment of this Act.(Sec. 504) Abolishes the Trade and Development Agency.(Sec. 505) Repeals the Television Broadcasting to Cuba and the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Acts.Authorizes appropriations for international broadcasting operations (including Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, Voice of America, and Radio Free Asia). Authorizes appropriations for Radio Free Asia.(Sec. 506) Directs the Secretaries of Defense and of Veterans Affairs to: (1) establish a joint office for the procurement of pharmaceuticals for the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs; and (2) develop and implement jointly a common clinically-based formulary for their respective pharmaceutical programs.</summary>
</bill>
