<bill session="107" type="h" number="1337" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Native American Languages Act Amendments Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Native American Languages Act to provide for the support of Native American Language Survival Schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400554"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2001-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2001-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Pacific Islanders"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2001--Introduced.
Native American Languages Act Amendments Act of 2001 - Amends the Native American Languages Act to authorize the Secretary of Education to provide funds to Native American Language Educational Organizations (Organizations), Native American Language Colleges, Indian tribal governments, organizations that demonstrate potential to become Organizations, or a consortia of such organizations, colleges, or tribal governments to establish Native American Language Nest programs (site-based education programs conducted through a Native American language) for students below the age of seven and their families.Authorizes the Secretary to provide funds to such Organizations, colleges, or governments to operate, expand, and increase Native American Language Survival Schools throughout the United States and its territories for Native American children and Native American language-speaking children.Requires the Secretary to provide funds to establish three specified demonstration programs that will provide assistance to Schools and Nests at: (1) Ka Haka 'Ula O Ke'elikolani College of the University of Hawaii at Hilo, in consortium with the 'Aha Punana Leo, Inc., and with other entities if deemed appropriate by such college; (2) Piegan Institute of Browning, Montana; and (3) the Alaska Native Language Center of the University of Alaska at Fairbanks, in consortium with other entities deemed appropriate by such center. Authorizes such programs to: (1) establish endowments for furthering their activities relative to the study and preservation of Native American languages; and (2) use funds to provide for the rental, purchase, construction, maintenance, and repair of facilities.</summary>
</bill>
