<bill session="108" type="hr" number="149" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-09T18:01:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-04-09T18:01:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the condolences of the House of Representatives in response to the assassination of Prime Minister Zoran Djindjic of Serbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2003-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2003-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bereuter moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H2885-2887" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 149.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-09T17:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H2999-3000" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2003-04-09T18:01:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="126" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 425 - 1 (Roll no. 126).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR 4/08/2003 H2885" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-09T18:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Assassination"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal courts"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Montenegro"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Serbia"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2003--Passed House without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced on March 19, 2003. The summary of that version is repeated here.)Offers the condolences of the House of Representatives and its deepest sympathy to the people of Serbia and the family of Zoran Djindjic following the assassination of Prime Minister Djindjic.States that the House of Representatives understands that organized criminal groups within Serbian society continue to threaten the free and democratic government of Serbia and Montenegro.Recognizes that while implementing necessary reforms and cooperating with the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia may carry significant risks for the leadership of Serbia and Montenegro, these reforms and this cooperation are necessary and must continue.Declares the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should: (1) support continued democratic reforms initiated by Zoran Djindjic; (2) urge his successors to dedicate themselves to continue to support his road to reform; and (3) pledge to assist Serbia and its new leadership in accomplishing these necessary reforms, including efforts to fight organized crime and corruption.</summary>
</bill>
