<bill session="108" type="h" number="1497" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sikes Act Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Sikes Act Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize title I of the Sikes Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400322"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-05-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-05-14T19:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-100, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-14T19:28:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 13, 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-13T15:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-13T15:37:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="76">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 76.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exotic animals"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Game and game birds"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2003--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Sikes Act Reauthorization Act of 2003 - Amends the Sikes Act (which requires the Department of Defense and the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to develop and implement plans to manage natural resources on certain military lands) to reauthorize appropriations and expenditures for FY 2004 through 2008 for conservation programs on military installations. Declares the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense should take whatever steps are necessary to ensure full implementation (consistent with the findings of this Act) of the Sikes Act requirement that sufficient numbers of professionally trained natural resources management and law enforcement personnel be available and assigned responsibility to perform tasks necessary to carry out conservation programs on military installations, including preparation and implementation of integrated natural resource management plans. Requires the Secretary of a military department to advise the Secretary of the Interior and the head of the appropriate State fish and wildlife agency of intent to prepare or revise an integrated natural resources management plan. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, the head of the appropriate State fish and wildlife agency, and the Secretary of the military department that prepares or revises the plan each to certify that the plan they agree upon adequately addresses conservation, protection, and management of the fish and wildlife resources. Requires the Secretary of a military department to publish notice and provide an opportunity for public comments of the intent to prepare or revise an integrated natural resource management plan. Requires that an integrated natural resource management plan in Guam provide for management, control, and eradication of invasive species that are not native to the ecosystem of the military installation, and the introduction of which cause or may cause harm to military readiness, the environment, the economy, or human health and safety.</summary>
</bill>
