<bill session="104" type="h" number="2845" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Environmental Equal Rights Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to allow petitions to be submitted to prevent certain waste facilities from being constructed in environmentally disadvantaged communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402763"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E13"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1996--Introduced.
Environmental Equal Rights Act of 1995 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize individuals residing in an environmentally disadvantaged community in which a new solid or hazardous waste management facility is proposed to be constructed to petition the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency or the State to prevent the facility from being constructed or from operating in such community. Denies such a petition only if the proponent of the proposed facility establishes that: (1) there is no alternative location that poses fewer health and environmental risks; and (2) the facility will not release contaminants or engage in any activity that is likely to increase the cumulative impact of contaminants on the environmentally disadvantaged community. Defines an "environmentally disadvantaged community" as an area within two miles of the borders of a site on which a waste management facility is proposed to be constructed and that meets specified criteria concerning minority populations, poverty, and existing hazardous or solid waste facilities or hazardous waste sites.</summary>
</bill>
