<bill session="105" type="h" number="1370" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-06T18:36:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-10-06T18:36:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Export-Import Bank Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Export-Import Bank of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="404634" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400508" joined="1997-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1997-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-07-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-07-31T18:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Banking and Financial Services. H. Rept. 105-224.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-07-31T18:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="132">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 132.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-09-29T21:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 255 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1370 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Banking and Financial Services now printed in the bill. No other amendment shall be in order except those printed in the report accompanying this resolution, if offered in the order and manner specified in the report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T13:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 255 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 255.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8188-8207" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1370 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Banking and Financial Services now printed in the bill. No other amendment shall be in order except those printed in the report accompanying this resolution, if offered in the order and manner specified in the report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 255 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ken Calvert to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T13:36:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McDermott moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Failed by recorded vote: 128 - 291 (Roll no. 470).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T15:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 255, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Evans amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>At the Conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Evans amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Evans requested a recorded vote and, pending that request, made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 255, further proceedings were postponed and the point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T15:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. DeLauro moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Failed by recorded vote: 162 - 257 (Roll no. 471).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair announced that consideration would resume on the Evans amendment, on which a recorded vote had been requested and further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 255, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lafalce amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T16:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Castle moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1370 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8373-8383, H8395-8397" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 255, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rohrbacher amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Castle asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Rohrbacher amendment, and a subsequent amendment to be offered later, be limited to not to exceed 20 minutes, Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Rohrbacher amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Rohrbacher amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Rohrbacher objected to the vote and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 255, further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Rohrbacher amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T15:51:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Rohrbacher amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Rohrbacher objected to the vote and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 255, further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T15:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 255, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Solomon amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Vento amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T16:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1370 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T18:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T18:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1370.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T18:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T18:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-10-06T18:36:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="492" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 378 - 38 (Roll no. 492).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T18:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T18:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Laid on the table. See S. 1026 for further action.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8397" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="255"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="105" type="s" number="1026"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="1026"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate accountability"/>
    <term name="Corporate management"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Export subsidies"/>
    <term name="Export-Import Bank of the United States"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Guided missiles"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Tied aid credit"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h403"/>
    <amendment number="h404"/>
    <amendment number="h405"/>
    <amendment number="h411"/>
    <amendment number="h412"/>
    <amendment number="h413"/>
    <amendment number="h414"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/6/1997--Passed House amended.
Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to extend the authority of the Export-Import Bank of the United States through FY 2001. Reauthorizes the Bank's tied aid credit program. (Sec. 3) Extends, through FY 2001, the Bank's authority to extend credit for the sale to a foreign country of nonlethal defense articles or services the primary end use of which will be for civilian purposes. (Sec. 4) Revises Bank procedures governing the denial of the extension of credit to foreign countries based on the national interest to: (1) require the President to consult with specified congressional committees before determining that such a denial is in the U.S. national interest; and (2) require written notification to the President of the Bank of such determination, including the applications or categories of applications for credit which should be denied. (Sec. 5) Directs the General Counsel of the Bank to designate an attorney to serve as Assistant General Counsel for Administration, whose duties shall include oversight of and advice to Bank directors, officers, and employees on ethics, conflicts of interest, personnel, and other administrative matters. (Sec. 6) Requires the Board of Directors of the Bank to: (1) take prompt measures to promote the expansion of its loan, guarantee, and insurance programs in sub-Saharan Africa; (2) establish an advisory committee to advise it on the implementation of policies and programs to support such expansion; and (3) report annually to the Congress on steps it has taken to implement such policies and programs and any advisory committee recommendations. (Sec. 7) Revises the composition of the Advisory Committee of the Bank to include the appointment of not less than two members from the labor community. (Sec. 8) Directs the Chairman of the Bank to: (1) implement a program to provide information about its programs to companies which have not previously participated in them; and (2) report to the Congress on such activities within one year of enactment of this Act. (Sec. 9) Directs the Board of Directors of the Bank to implement procedures to ensure that, in selecting firms to which to provide financial assistance, preference is given to those that have shown a commitment to reinvestment and job creation in the United States. (Sec. 10) Directs the Board of Directors of the Bank to give preference to entities that adhere to certain environmental and fair employment principles under a corporate code of conduct when determining whether to guarantee, insure, or extend credit to an entity (except a small business) with respect to the export of any good or service to China. Directs the Bank to work with the Clearinghouse on Corporate Responsibility that is being developed by the Department of Commerce to ensure that recipients of such assistance are made aware of, and have access to, resources and organizations that can assist them in developing and monitoring global codes of corporate conduct. (Sec. 11) Changes the name of the Export-Import Bank of the United States to the United States Export Bank. (Sec. 12) Requires the President to notify the Bank of any transfer by Russia of an SS-N-22 or SS-N-26 missile system to China. Directs the Bank, upon notification, to deny any guarantee, insurance, or extension of credit in connection with the export of any good or service to Russia. (Sec. 13) Prohibits the Bank from guaranteeing, insuring, or extending credit with respect to the export of any good or service to an entity that: (1) employs children in violation of U.S. law regarding child labor; or (2) has not made a binding commitment to not employ children in such manner.</summary>
</bill>
