<bill session="104" type="h" number="2126" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-01">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY96, Defense</title>
    <title type="popular">Defense Department FY96 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Department of Defense for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400439"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-07">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-14">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-11">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-13">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-07-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-07-27T23:08:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against the bill, and against its consideration were reserved.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-27T23:18:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-208, by Mr. Young (FL).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-07-27T23:19:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="107">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 107.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-07-28T16:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 205 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2126 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI shall be waived. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments. Upon adoption of this resolution, an amendment striking sections 8021 and 8024 of the bill shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole. During consideration of the bill for amendment, the Chairman of the Committee may grant priority in recognition to those Members who have had proposed amendments printed in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-31T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 205 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-31T21:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 205.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8052-8060" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-31T21:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2126 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI shall be waived. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments. Upon adoption of this resolution, an amendment striking sections 8021 and 8024 of the bill shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole. During consideration of the bill for amendment, the Chairman of the Committee may grant priority in recognition to those Members who have had proposed amendments printed in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-31T21:30:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 205 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-31T21:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable F. James Sensenbrenner Jr. to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-31T21:30:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-31T21:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2126 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T11:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8609-8663" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T11:13:00-04:00">
      <text>TIME LIMITATION - Mr. Murtha asked unanimous consent that during the further consideration of the bill, the time remaining for all amendments be limited to 5 hours (excluding time consumed by recorded votes and proceedings incidental thereto). Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T11:13:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF AMENDMENTS - Mr. Young (AK) asked unanimous consent that during the further consideration of the bill that the order of business be as follows: 1. One of the amendments printed in the Congressional Record numbered 10, 11,18, 34, or 56, by Representative Kasich or Obey to be debatable for 60 minutes; 2. One or more of the amendments printed in the Congressional Record numbered 37, 58, 59, or 61 by Representatve Obey to be debatable for not more than 20 minutes: 3. One of the amendments printed in the Congressional Record numbered 3 or 15, by Representative Dornan, together with the amendment numbered 48 as a substitute therefor, by Representative DeLauro, to be jointly debatable for 30. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T11:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T11:18:00-04:00">
      <text>TIME LIMITATION - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement the Committee of the Whole proceeded with up to one hour of debate on the Kasich amendment numbered 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T12:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Obey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T13:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Dornan amendment and the Delauro substitute amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of the debate on the Sanders amendment the Chair put the question and announced that by a voice vote the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sanders objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. The Chair announced that further proceedings regarding the amendment would be postponed until a later time and the point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on the Schroeder amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mrs. Schroeder objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. The Chair postponed further proceedings. The point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair announced the order of business to be the further consideration of amendments on which proceedings had been postponed, in the order in which they were postponed. The Chair then put the question on the Sanders amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2126.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 205, an amendment striking sections 8021 and 8024 of the bill was considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:03:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the remaining amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Obey motion to recommit the bill to the Committee on Appropriations with instructions that the Committee report the bill back to the House forthwith, with an amendment to reduce the maximum amount of individual compensation allowed to be charged to the government for payment on new contracts from $250,000 to $200,000 per year.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:28:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-09-07T18:46:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="646" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 294 - 125 (Roll No. 646).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07T18:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2126.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-08">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12893" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-08">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 1087 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1995-09-08" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 1087 with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-09-08">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment asks for a conference, appoints conferees Stevens; Cochran; Specter; Domenici; Gramm; Bond; McConnell; Mack; Shelby; Hatfield; Inouye; Hollings; Johnston; Byrd; Leahy; Bumpers; Lautenberg; Harkin.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12893" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-13T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8887" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-13T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-13T20:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (FL) moved to close certain portions of the conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-13T20:45:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to close certain portions of the conference. Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 414 - 2 (Roll no. 661).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8888" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-13T20:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>PROCEEDINGS VACATED - Mr. Young (FL) asked unanimous consent to vacate the proceedings of September 13, 1995, in which the House disagreed to the Senate amendment to the bill H.R. 2126, and agreed to the conference requested by the Senate, provided that the order of the House of the same day which enabled closed meetings of the conference shall remain in effect. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (FL) asked unanimous consent that the House proceedings of Sept. 13, 1995 be vacated.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to proceedings of Sept. 13, 1995 vacated Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8915" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (FL) asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8915" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with up to one hour of debate on the motion to instruct House conferees to insist on the provisions of section 8075 of the House bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:31:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8915" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-14T13:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Young (FL), McDade, Livingston, Lewis (CA), Skeen, Hobson, Bonilla, Nethercutt, Neumann, Murtha, Dicks, Wilson, Hefner, Sabo, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-19">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-20">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-21">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-22">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-25T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 104-261 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9453-9498" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-27T19:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 232 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2126. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration shall be waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-28T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 232 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (FL) brought up conference report H. Rept. 104-261 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 232.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9698-9709" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29T14:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit with instructions to the conference committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions to conference committee Failed by recorded vote: 176 - 240, 1 Present (Roll no. 699).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9708" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1995-09-29T14:56:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="700" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 151 - 267, 1 Present (Roll no. 700).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9709" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (FL) asked unanimous consent that the House insist on its disagreement to the Senate amendment and asked for a further conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to insist on its disagreement to the Senate amendment and asked for a further conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion to instruct conferees on the part of the House to reduce total spending in the bill by $3 billion, compared to the amount provided in the House bill, to be derived from deleting funds of low priority "Procurement", "Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation" and other projects contained in the House or Senate bills that were not included in the President's Budget, provided that military pay or Operation and Maintenance readiness activities shall not be reduced below the levels provided in the House-passed version of the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on the motion to instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T16:22:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 134 - 290 (Roll no. 721).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10248-10255" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T16:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T16:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Young (FL), McDade, Livingston, Lewis (CA), Skeen, Hobson, Bonilla, Nethercutt, Istook, Murtha, Dicks, Wilson, Hefner, Sabo, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (FL) moved to close portions of the conference relating to national security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T16:41:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to close portions of the conference relating to national security Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 418 - 3 (Roll no. 722).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10255" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-18T16:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-19">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-19">
      <text>Senate agreed to the request for a further conference. By Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-19">
      <text>Senate appointed conferees Stevens; Cochran; Specter; Domenici; Bond; McConnell; Mack; Shelby; Gregg; Hatfield; Inouye; Hollings; Johnston; Byrd; Leahy; Bumpers; Lautenberg; Harkin.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-07T18:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Metcalf announced his intention to offer a motion to instruct conferees on the part of the House to insist on secs. 8102 and 8111 of the House passed version of the bill, relating to restricting the deployment of the U.S. Armed Forces in the former Yugoslavia.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-08T16:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Metcalf announced his intention to offer a motion on Thursday, November 9, 1995, to instruct conferees on the part of the House to insist on secs. 8102 and 8111 of the House passed version of the bill, relating to restricting the deployment of the U.S. Armed Forces in the former Yugoslavia.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-09T17:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Metcalf announced his intention to offer a motion on Friday, November 10, 1995, to instruct conferees on the part of the House to insist on secs. 8102 and 8111 of the House passed version of the bill, relating to restricting the deployment of the U.S. Armed Forces in the former Yugoslavia.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-09">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-13T18:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Metcalf announced his intention to offer a motion on Tuesday, November 14, 1995, to instruct conferees on the part of the House to insist on secs. 8102 and 8111 of the House passed version of the bill, relating to restricting the deployment of the U.S. Armed Forces in the former Yugoslavia.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-15T21:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 104-344 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12415-12427" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T00:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 271 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2126. Upon the adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider the conference report to accompany the bill. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration shall be waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T12:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 271 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T12:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (FL) brought up conference report H. Rept. 104-344 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 271.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T12:38:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T13:52:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T13:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to recommit with instructions to the conference committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T13:53:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions to conference committee was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T14:17:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions to conference committee Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 121 - 307 (Roll no. 805).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13063" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="1995-11-16T14:23:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="806" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 270 - 158 (Roll no. 806).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13064" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16T14:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Further conference report considered in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Senate agreed to further conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 59-39. Record Vote No: 579.</text>
      <reference ref="CR  S17170" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1995-11-16">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1995-11-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1995-11-18">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1995-12-01">
      <text>Sent to Archivist of the United States unsigned.</text>
    </action>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1995-12-01" type="public" number="104-61">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-61.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAP02" subcommittee="National Security" name="House Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="205"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="232"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="271"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="104" type="s" number="1087"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1087"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="104" type="s" number="1087"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Air bases"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Air force personnel"/>
    <term name="Air force procurement"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Amphibious ships"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Army personnel"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Army procurement"/>
    <term name="Artificial satellites"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missile defenses"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Battleships"/>
    <term name="Beer"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Brain"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="CIS countries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Combat vehicles"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Conversion of industries"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Courts-martial and courts of inquiry"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense burdensharing"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Destroyers"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Drone aircraft"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic forecasting"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Electromagnetic waves"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Electronics in military engineering"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Engines"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Guided missiles"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Humanitarian intervention"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Infantry"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International propaganda"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Kurds"/>
    <term name="Kuwait"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Land mines"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Launch vehicles"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Life sciences"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Macedonia"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine engines"/>
    <term name="Marines"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Materials research"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military aircraft"/>
    <term name="Military airlift"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military base agreements"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military communications"/>
    <term name="Military construction operations"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military helicopters"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Military intelligence"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Military leave"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military sealift"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Military transportation"/>
    <term name="Military weapons"/>
    <term name="Minerals"/>
    <term name="Minesweeping"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missing in action"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Naval aviation"/>
    <term name="Naval bases"/>
    <term name="Naval personnel"/>
    <term name="Naval procurement"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear submarines"/>
    <term name="Nuclear warships"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Pacific area"/>
    <term name="Palau Islands"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf War"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Pets"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Post exchanges"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Presidential protection"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Private aviation"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Protection of animals"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Raw materials"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
    <term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rockets (Ordnance)"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Shiites"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space warfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Steel"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Submarines"/>
    <term name="Supercomputers"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Surface-to-air missiles"/>
    <term name="Tactical nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Tanks (Combat vehicles)"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Telescopes"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Warships"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
    <term name="Wine"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Wounds"/>
    <term name="Yugoslavia"/>
    <term name="Zinc"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h705"/>
    <amendment number="h706"/>
    <amendment number="h707"/>
    <amendment number="h708"/>
    <amendment number="h750"/>
    <amendment number="h751"/>
    <amendment number="h752"/>
    <amendment number="h753"/>
    <amendment number="h754"/>
    <amendment number="h755"/>
    <amendment number="h756"/>
    <amendment number="h757"/>
    <amendment number="h758"/>
    <amendment number="h759"/>
    <amendment number="h760"/>
    <amendment number="h761"/>
    <amendment number="h762"/>
    <amendment number="h763"/>
    <amendment number="h764"/>
    <amendment number="h765"/>
    <amendment number="h766"/>
    <amendment number="h767"/>
    <amendment number="h768"/>
    <amendment number="h769"/>
    <amendment number="h770"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/15/1995--Conference report filed in House, 2nd conference report.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Military Personnel Title II: Operation and Maintenance Title III: Procurement Title IV: Research, Development, Test and Evaluation Title V: Revolving and Management Funds Title VI: Other Department of Defense Programs Title VII: Related Agencies Title VIII: General Provisions Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 1996 - Title I: Military Personnel - Appropriates funds for FY 1996 for active-duty and reserve personnel in the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, and Air Force and for National Guard personnel in the Army and Air Force. Title II: Operation and Maintenance - Appropriates funds for FY 1996 for the operation and maintenance (O&amp;M) of the Army, Navy, Air Force, and the defense agencies (including a transfer of funds in each case), the Marine Corps, the reserve components, and the Army and Air National Guards. Appropriates funds for the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Armed Forces, environmental restoration, defense (including a transfer of funds), the 1996 Summer Olympics, overseas humanitarian, disaster, and civic aid assistance, and nuclear threat reduction programs with respect to republics of the former Soviet Union. Title III: Procurement - Appropriates funds for FY 1996 for procurement by the armed forces and its reserve components of aircraft, missiles, weapons, tracked combat vehicles, ammunition, shipbuilding and conversion, and for other procurement. Appropriates funds for defense-wide procurement and for National Guard and reserve equipment. Title IV: Research, Development, Test and Evaluation - Appropriates funds for FY 1996 for research, development, test and evaluation by the armed forces and defense agencies. Appropriates funds for the Directors of Test and Evaluation and Operational Test and Evaluation. Title V: Revolving and Management Funds - Appropriates funds for: (1) the Defense Business Operations Fund; and (2) programs under the National Defense Sealift Fund. Title VI: Other Department of Defense Programs - Appropriates funds for: (1) the Department of Defense (DOD) medical and health care programs; (2) the destruction of lethal chemical agents and munitions; (3) drug interdiction and counter-drug activities, defense (including a transfer of funds); and (4) expenses and activities of the Office of the Inspector General in carrying out the Inspector General Act of 1978. Title VII: Related Agencies - Appropriates funds for: (1) the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System Fund; (2) national security scholarships, fellowships, and grants (using funds derived from the National Security Education Trust Fund); (3) expenses of the Intelligence Community Management Account; and (4) authorized payments to the Kaho'olawe Island Conveyance, Remediation, and Environmental Restoration Trust Fund. Title VIII: General Provisions - Specifies authorized, restricted, and prohibited uses of appropriated funds, including authorized fund transfers between and among various DOD accounts. (Sec. 8010) Authorizes procurement funds appropriated under this Act to be used for multiyear procurement contracts for UH-60 Blackhawk and Apache Longbow helicopters, as well as the M1A2 tank upgrade. (Sec. 8012) Prohibits during FY 1996 the management by end strengths of DOD civilian personnel. (Sec. 8027) Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to establish with host governments of NATO-member countries an account for the deposit of residual value amounts negotiated in the return of U.S. military installations to such countries. (Sec. 8044) Authorizes DOD to incur obligations of up to $350 million for DOD personnel compensation, military construction projects, and supplies and services in anticipation of receipts of contributions from the government of Kuwait. (Sec. 8045) Earmarks funds from this Act for the Civil Air Patrol. (Sec. 8046) Prohibits any funds appropriated under this Act from being used to establish a new federally funded research and development center (FFRDC). Allows FFRDC consultants to be paid for such services only to the same extent as members of the Defense Science Board. Limits the amount that may be obligated during FY 1996 for financing activities of defense FFRDCs. (Sec. 8047) Provides Buy American requirements with respect to the DOD procurement of carbon, alloy, or armor steel plating. (Sec. 8054) Authorizes the payment of voluntary separation incentive payments to military personnel. (Sec. 8062) Limits to $315 million the total amount that may be appropriated under this Act for FY 1996 to fund the Uniformed Services Treatment Facilities program. (Sec. 8065) Allows FY 1996 DOD O&amp;M appropriations to be used to purchase items having an investment unit cost of not more than $100,000. (Sec. 8068) Prohibits the use of funds: (1) for the modification of an aircraft, weapon, ship, or other equipment that the military department concerned plans to retire or otherwise dispose of within five years after completion of the modification; (2) to transport chemical munitions to the Johnston Atoll for storage or demilitarization (with an exception and an authorized wartime waiver by the President); (3) by a DOD entity without compliance with the Buy American Act; (4) for assistance to or programs in the Democratic People's Republic of North Korea unless specifically appropriated for such purpose; (5) to reduce the civilian medical and medical support personnel assigned to military treatment facilities below the September 30, 1995, level; (6) for the procurement of ball and roller bearings not produced by a domestic source and of domestic origin; (7) for payments on new contracts on which allowable costs charged to the Government include payments for individual compensation at a rate in excess of $200,000 per year after July 1, 1996; (8) for the design, development, acquisition, or operation of more than 47 Titan IV expendable launch vehicles; (9) to support or finance during FY 1996 the activities of the Defense Policy Advisory Committee on Trade: (10) to establish additional field operating agencies of any element of DOD during FY 1996, except for those funded within the National Foreign Intelligence Program; or (11) to transport military personnel to Edwards Air Force Base for training rotations at the National Training Center after April 15, 1996. (Sec. 8072) Earmarks funds appropriated under this Act for the mitigation of adverse environmental impacts on Indian lands resulting from DOD activities. (sec. 8073) Limits the use of funds appropriated under this Act for the High Performance Computing Modernization Program to the acquisition and sustainment of operations. (Sec. 8075) Directs the Secretary, to the extent authorized by law, to issue loan guarantees in support of U.S. defense exports not otherwise provided for, with a total loan guarantee contingent liability limit of $15 billion. Requires that: (1) exposure fees collected by the Secretary be paid by the country involved and not financed as part of a guaranteed loan; and (2) the Secretary provide quarterly reports to specified congressional committees concerning such loan guarantees. (Sec. 8083) Rescinds specified funds from various accounts under prior defense appropriations Acts. (Sec. 8092) Directs the Secretary, upon the enactment of this Act, to make specified transfers between various DOD appropriation accounts. (Sec. 8096) Prohibits funds available to either DOD or the Central Intelligence Agency for drug interdiction or counter-drug activities from being transferred to another department or agency except as specifically provided in an appropriations law. (Sec. 8097) Authorizes DOD O&amp;M funds appropriated for increasing energy and water efficiency in Federal buildings to be transferred to other DOD funds or accounts for related projects. (Sec. 8098) Earmarks specified FY 1996 Air Force appropriations for obligation only for those Titan IV vehicles and related activities under contract as of the date of enactment of this Act. (Sec. 8100) Requires at least 30 percent of the pentaborane currently stored at Edwards Air Force Base, California, to be retained until the Secretary of Energy makes certain certifications to the appropriations committees with respect to the use of the pentaborane at the Idaho National Engineering Laboratory. (Sec. 8101) Reduces by $30 million the total amount appropriated in titles II through IV of this Act for savings achieved through increased management of contractor automatic data processing costs charged under DOD acquisition contracts. (Sec. 8102) Requires, no later than October 1, 1995, that each DOD disbursement in excess of $5 million be matched to a particular obligation before the disbursement is made. Provides exceptions. (Sec. 8104) Prohibits funds appropriated to the Army from being obligated for the procurement of 120mm mortars or mortar ammunition manufactured outside the United States. (Sec. 8107) Authorizes the Secretary of the Air Force to enter into agreements to modify leases of housing units being constructed if deemed to be in the best interests of DOD. (Sec. 8107A) Extends through FY 1997 the authorization for a military construction project at an Indiana, Pennsylvania armory. (Sec. 8108) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated by this Act for the lease or charter by DOD of certain vessels for the transportation of fuel or oil unless such vessels are constructed with a double hull. (Sec. 8109) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated or made available in this Act to the Navy to develop or procure either: (1) main propulsion engines for the LPD-17 class of ships; or (2) an emergency generator set for the New Attack Submarine, unless such equipment is powered by a diesel engine manufactured in the United States by a domestically operated entity. (Sec. 8112) Directs the Secretaries of Defense and the Army to reconsider the decision not to include the infantry military occupational specialty among the military skills and specialties for which special pays are provided under the Selected Reserve Incentive Program. (Sec. 8113) Directs the Secretary of Defense to report quarterly to specified congressional committees on all costs incurred by DOD in implementing or supporting United Nations (UN) Security Council resolutions. (Sec. 8114) Limits to $52 million the amount that may be obligated or expended for the dismantling and destruction of chemical weapons of the former Soviet Union until the President makes certain certifications to the Congress with respect to the neutralization of Russia's chemical weapons and the resolution of issues under the Wyoming Memorandum of Understanding and the 1990 Bilateral Destruction Agreement. (Sec. 8115) Expresses the sense of the Congress that, in the event of a deployment or participation of U.S. armed forces in any international peacekeeping, peace enforcement, and humanitarian assistance operation, the President must consult with bipartisan congressional leadership and specified congressional committees. Provides exceptions. Requires such consultation at least 15 days before such deployment or participation, whenever possible, with a national security exception. States that, whenever there is such a deployment, the President should, within 90 days, seek emergency supplemental appropriations to meet DOD's incremental costs associated with such deployment. (Sec. 8116) Expresses the sense of the Senate that France and China should abide by the current international moratorium on nuclear test explosions and refrain from conducting underground nuclear tests in advance of a comprehensive test ban treaty. (Sec. 8117) Prohibits, unless specified congressional committees are notified 15 days in advance, the use of FY 1995 DOD funds for the transfer to another nation or international organization of any defense articles or services for use in an international peacekeeping, peace-enforcement, or humanitarian assistance operation. (Sec. 8118) Prohibits the use of funds made available under this Act for: (1) making a financial contribution to the UN for the cost of any UN peacekeeping activity or for payment of any U.S. arrearage to the UN; (2) administering any policy that permits the performance of abortions at DOD medical treatment or other facilities, except where the life of the mother is endangered or where the pregnancy is the result of an act of rape or incest; (3) the procurement of munitions unless such acquisition fully complies with the Competition in Contracting Act; (4) implementing any change to the computation of military retired pay as required by law in FY 1995 for military personnel who entered the armed forces before September 8, 1980; (5) paying a DOD contractor for amounts paid to any employee that represent a bonus which is part of restructuring costs associated with a business combination; or (6) financing housing for any individual who was a member of the military forces of the Soviet Union or the Russian Federation. (Sec. 8124) Expresses the sense of the Congress that none of the funds available to DOD shall be obligated or expended for the deployment or participation of any U.S. armed forces in any peacekeeping operation in Bosnia-Herzegovina, unless such deployment or participation is specifically authorized by a law enacted after the date of enactment of this Act. Provides exceptions. (Sec. 8125) Reduces by $832 million the total amount appropriated in this Act to reflect savings from revised economic assumptions. Allocates such reduction among various military departments and accounts. (Sec. 8126) Earmarks funds from revenues collected by the Defense Business Operations Fund for termination liability, lease, and operational costs for aircraft to accomplish the VC-137 aircraft mission. (Sec. 8127) Authorizes the obligation of Air Force missile procurement funds for the payment of satellite on-orbit incentives in the fiscal year in which the incentive payment is earned. (Sec. 8128) Earmarks specified Army and Air Force funds for the support of a NATO Alliance Ground Surveillance program based on the Joint Surveillance-Target Attack Radar System. (Sec. 8129) Makes specified reductions in funding under title IV for Army, Navy, Air Force, and Defense-wide research, development, test and evaluation. Prohibits any such reduction from funds made available for ballistic missile defense. (Sec. 8130) Requires fixed and mobile telecommunications support to be provided by the White House Communications Agency to the United States Secret Service without reimbursement in connection with protection services at the White House Security Complex in the Washington, D.C. Metropolitan Area and Camp David, Maryland.</summary>
</bill>
