<bill session="105" type="h" number="3017" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rights of the Child Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Calling for ratification of the United Nations Convention on the Rights of the Child.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2301"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International labor activities"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Treaty-making power"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/1997--Introduced.
Rights of the Child Act of 1997 - Expresses the sense of the Congress that the President should submit and seek the advice and consent of the Senate by December 31, 1998, to ratification of the Convention on the Rights of the Child. (Sec. 4) Directs the Attorney General, before such submission, to meet with the attorneys general of the States and U.S. territories to determine their recommendations concerning any limitations that should accompany a proposed resolution of ratification of the U.N. Convention on the Rights of the Child. (Sec. 5) Establishes an advisory commission concerning the economic, social, cultural, political, and civil rights of children. Directs the commission to report to the Congress any recommendations agreed to by a majority of its members on any limitations to the Convention on the Rights of the Child advisable to facilitate ratification. (Sec. 6) Authorizes additional appropriations for U.S. contributions to: (1) the International Labor Organization for the activities of the International Program on the Elimination of Child Labor; and (2) the U.N. Commission on Human Rights for programs relating to bonded child labor that are carried out by the Subcommittee and Working Group on Contemporary Forms of Slavery. (Sec. 7) Prohibits the importation into the United States of any product manufactured or mined, in whole or in part, by bonded child labor. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe regulations to carry out this prohibition. (Sec. 8) Prohibits U.S. assistance to the government of a foreign country for any fiscal year unless the President certifies to the Congress for such fiscal year that such government has enacted, and is enforcing, laws against child prostitution and the sexual exploitation of children. Authorizes waivers of such prohibition in the national security interest of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
