<bill session="107" type="h" number="1098" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-03-21T12:09:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-03-21T12:09:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Maritime Policy Improvement Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Maritime Policy Improvement Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the recording and discharging of maritime liens and expand the American Merchant Marine Memorial Wall of Honor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2001-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2001-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2001-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T10:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. LoBiondo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T10:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1023-1025" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T10:58:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1098.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T10:58:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T12:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1036-1037" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-03-21T12:09:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="55" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 415 - 3 (Roll no. 55).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1023-1025" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T12:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-05-03">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-07-27">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Hollings without amendment. With written report No. 107-48.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-07-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="107">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 107.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="1214"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Merchant marine"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Private legislation"/>
    <term name="Sailing ships"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2001--Passed House without amendment.
Maritime Policy Improvement Act of 2001 - Amends the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 1996 to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to issue a certificate of documentation with appropriate endorsement for employment in the coastwise trade to a specified vessel.(Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to make grants to the American Merchant Marine Veterans Memorial Committee, Inc., to construct an addition to the American Merchant Marine Memorial Wall of Honor located at the Los Angeles Maritime Museum in San Pedro, California. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 5) States that the discharge from a vessel of any agricultural cargo residue material in the form of hold washings shall be governed exclusively by the provisions of the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships that implement Annex V to the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution from Ships.(Sec. 6) Revises the method for recording and discharging certain maritime liens.(Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary of Transportation to prescribe a tonnage measurement as a small passenger vessel for a named vessel for purposes of applying the optional regulatory measurement.(Sec. 8) Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to issue a certificate of documentation with appropriate endorsement for employment in the coastwise trade to twenty specified vessels.(Sec. 9) Authorizes exempting two specified vessels from certain inspection requirements for passenger vessels so long as the vessels are owned by nonprofit organizations and operated as nonprofit memorials to merchant mariners.(Sec. 10) Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to issue a certificate of documentation with appropriate endorsement for employment in the coastwise trade to three specified vessels.(Sec. 11) Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to issue a certificate of documentation with appropriate endorsement for employment in the coastwise trade to a specified vessel, under specified circumstances.(Sec. 12) Permits, for a limited period of time, the 10 sailboats participating in the New World Challenge Race to transport guests, who have not contributed consideration for their passage, from and around the ports of San Francisco and San Diego, California, before and during stops of that race.(Sec. 13) Permits a specified vessel to be transferred to or placed under a foreign registry or sold to a person that is not a U.S. citizen and transferred to or placed under a foreign registry.</summary>
</bill>
