<bill session="107" type="hc" number="410" updated="2013-07-14T18:59:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Supporting peace and democracy in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, and an end to the plunder of its natural resources.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400538"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="2002-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2002-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2002-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2002-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2002-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E908-910"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Democratic Republic of Congo"/>
    <term name="Diamonds"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="Logging"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="War crime trials"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2002--Introduced.
Declares that Congress joins the international community in supporting peace and democracy in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and an end to the plunder of its natural resources..Calls for the President to: (1) direct the U.S. representative to the United Nations (UN) to work to bring before the UN Security Council a resolution imposing sanctions against the sale of diamonds mined in the Congo unless the diamonds are certified as not funding the conflict there; (2) urge the Security Council to give priority to steps to control the illegal harvesting of timber in the Congo; and (3) send U.S. representatives to advise leaders of the Congo, countries whose armed forces occupy it, and countries whose support sustains rebel groups operating there that peace in the Congo is in their national security interests and that continued strife there threatens to impede the war against terrorism.Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the UN and the international community should condemn combatants in the Congo for failing to abide by the 1999 Lusaka Peace Accords and for inflicting suffering on civilians; and (2) the U.S. Government should not grant a visa to any individual (or family members) suspected of committing war crimes in the Congo and should transfer any such individual found in the United States to the jurisdiction of the International War Crimes Tribunal for prosecution.</summary>
</bill>
