<bill session="106" type="h" number="216" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Access to Quality Care Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to protect consumers in managed care plans and preserve against preemption certain State causes of action.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400296"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1999-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1999-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="1999-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1999-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1999-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1999-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1999-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1999-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Euthanasia"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Gynecology"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Physician-patient privilege"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prenatal care"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Access to Quality Care Subtitle A: Promoting Quality Care by Ensuring Access to Health Care Professionals Subtitle B: Promoting Quality Care by Ensuring Access to Health Care Services Subtitle C: Promoting Quality Care by Ensuring Fair Resolution of Grievances Subtitle D: Promoting Quality Care by Ensuring Fair Plan Administration Subtitle E: Definitions Title II: Application of Quality Care Standards to Group Health Plans and Health Insurance Coverage Under Public Health Service Act Title III: Amendments to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 Title IV: Effective Dates; Coordination in Implementation Access to Quality Care Act of 1999 - Title I: Access to Quality Care - Subtitle A: Promoting Quality Care by Ensuring Access to Health Care Professionals - Requires a health care insurer offering health care coverage through a network of contracted professionals and providers to offer at a reasonable premium an enrollment option for non-network coverage unless such option is otherwise available to enrollees. (Sec. 102) Requires a group health plan and a health insurance issuer to provide for enrollee choice of personal health professional and access to adequate types of care. Subtitle B: Promoting Quality Care by Ensuring Access to Health Care Services - Requires a group health care plan and a health care insurer to provide for: (1) specialist care; (2) continuity of care; (3) emergency room services; (4) obstetric and gynecological services; and (5) pediatric services. Subtitle C: Promoting Quality Care by Ensuring Fair Resolution of Grievances - Sets forth internal and external review procedures, including: (1) enrollee notice of adverse coverage determinations; (2) time limits for benefit determinations and internal appeals; (3) physician review of initial coverage determinations; (4) independent medical expert review of initial review determinations, and penalties for denial of such review. Subtitle D: Promoting Quality Care by Ensuring Fair Plan Administration - Prohibits a group health professional or provider plan from offering incentives to reduce or limit medically necessary services with respect to a specific enrollee. (Sec. 133) Sets forth specified enrollee information access requirements, including: (1) plan description, limitations, and benefits; (2) enrollee costs; (3) dispute resolution procedures; (4) network characteristics; (5) care management; (6) inclusion of drugs and biologicals in formularies; (7) preauthorization and utilization review procedures; (8) accreditation status of health insurance issuers and service providers; and (9) performance criteria. (Sec. 138) Requires a group health plan and a health insurance issuer to establish a quality assessment program. Subtitle E: Definitions - Defines specified terms. (Sec. 152) States that nothing in this title shall be construed to preempt State law with respect to health insurance issuers or group health plans. Title II: Application of Quality Care Standards to Group Health Plans and Health Insurance Coverage under Public Health Service Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to apply quality care provisions under title I of this Act to group health plan and health insurance coverage under such Act. Title III: Amendments to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Income Act of 1974 (ERISA) to apply quality care provisions under title I of this Act to group health plan and health insurance coverage under such Act. (Sec. 302) Permits certain actions under State law (rather than under ERISA) involving health insurance enrollees, but stipulates that such actions are not authorized against an employer or other plan sponsor, with specified exceptions. Title IV: Effective Dates; Coordination in Implementation - Sets forth specified effective dates under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
