<bill session="106" type="h" number="5500" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Justice for American Victims of Terrorism Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Attorney General to establish an office in the Department of Justice to monitor acts of international terrorism alleged to have been committed by Palestinian individuals or individuals acting on behalf of Palestinian organizations and to carry out certain other related activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="2000-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2000-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="2000-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="2000-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2000-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indictments"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/2000--Introduced.
Justice for American Victims of Terrorism Act of 2000 - Directs the Attorney General to establish within the Department of Justice an office to: (1) monitor acts of international terrorism alleged to have been committed by Palestinians or individuals acting on behalf of Palestinian organizations; (2) collect and offer rewards for information against individuals alleged to have committed such acts; (3) negotiate with the Palestinian Authority or related entities to obtain financial compensation for U.S. nationals or their families injured or killed by such terrorist acts; (4) establish and implement alternative methods to apprehend, indict, prosecute, and convict individuals who commit such acts; (5) contact victims' families and provide updates on the progress to apprehend, indict, prosecute, and convict the individuals who commit such acts; and (6) provide for the permanent stationing of an appropriate number of U.S. officials in Israel, in territory administered by Israel and by the Palestinian Authority, and elsewhere.</summary>
</bill>
