<bill session="107" type="h" number="1974" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Western States Energy Consumer Protection Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Power Act to provide the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission with authority to order certain refunds of electric rates, to require the Commission to expand its market mitigation plan, and to provide the Secretary of Energy with authority to revoke the market mitigation plan under certain circumstances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="2001-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="2001-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power failures"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Electricity"/>
    <term name="Energy demand"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy shortages"/>
    <term name="Energy transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Price regulation"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="West (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2001--Introduced.
Western States Energy Consumer Protection Act of 2001 - Instructs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to issue orders which make applicable to all interstate public utility electric energy sales in the western energy market a specified State of California market monitoring and mitigation plan that is based upon competitive bids to replicate competitive pricing.Authorizes termination of such plan if the Secretary of Energy determines that it results in decreased supply or increased demand for electric energy within the territory encompassed by the Western States Coordinating Council.Directs FERC to require a vendor of bundled natural gas transported into the State of California to disclose that portion of the sale price attributable to: (1) the price paid by the seller for such gas; and (2) the price paid for transportation of the gas.Precludes FERC and the Secretary from requiring sales of electric energy or natural gas in any State in the western region without a reasonable assurance of payment.Authorizes a State public utility commission in the western energy market to prohibit electric energy sales outside the service area of the pertinent public utility if that would impair the ability of such utility to meet in-State demand.Amends the Federal Power Act to prescribe guidelines to accelerate the effective date of FERC-ordered wholesale rate refunds.</summary>
</bill>
