<bill session="107" type="h" number="4844" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wild Sky Wilderness Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Wild Sky Wilderness Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance ecosystem protection and the range of outdoor opportunities protected by statute in the Skykomish River valley of the State of Washington by designating certain lower-elevation Federal lands as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400232"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2002-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2002-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="2002-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2002-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2002-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2002-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-03">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-11T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-747.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-10-11T12:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="467">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 467.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="2565"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="2565"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Columbia River development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Helicopter transportation"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/2002--Reported to House amended.
Wild Sky Wilderness Act of 2002 - Designates certain lands in the Skykomish River valley, Washington, as the Wild Sky Wilderness, to be managed by the Secretary of Agriculture.Directs the Secretary to establish a hiking trail plan. Authorizes the use of helicopter access to construct and maintain a joint Forest Service and Snohomish County repeater site, in compliance with a Forest Service approved communications site plan, to improve communication for safety, health, and emergency services. Authorizes the use of floatplanes on Lake Isabel where such use has already become established.Authorizes the Secretary to acquire specified priority acquisition lands by purchase, donation, or exchange. Directs that the boundaries of the Snoqualmie National Forest and the Wild Sky Wilderness be adjusted to encompass any lands so acquired. Directs the Secretary to assure adequate access to private in-holdings within the Wild Sky Wilderness. States that valuation of private lands shall be determined without reference to any restrictions on access or use which arise out of designation as a wilderness area.Requires the Secretary to exchange specified lands with the Chelan County Public Utility District if the District offers to the Secretary lands within the Snoqualmie National Forest, Washington, in exchange for a permanent easement, including helicopter access, consistent with such levels as used as of the date of this Act's enactment, to maintain an existing snowtel site on land within the Wenatchee National Forest, Washington.Sets forth conditions for consummation of the exchange and for reversion to the United States if the District no longer needs to maintain a snowtel site.</summary>
</bill>
