<bill session="105" type="hc" number="58" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Establishing the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 1998 and setting forth appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 1999, 2000, 2001, and 2002.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400572"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget reconciliation"/>
    <term name="Capital budgets"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Debt limit"/>
    <term name="Decision making in public administration"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Television frequency allocation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/1997--Introduced.
Establishes the congressional budget for the Government for FY 1998. Sets forth appropriate budgetary levels for FY 1999 through 2002. (Sec. 2) Lists recommended budgetary levels and amounts, for FY 1998 through 2002, with respect to: (1) Federal revenues; (2) new budget authority; (3) budget outlays; (4) deficits; (5) public debt; (6) new direct loan obligations; and (7) new primary loan guarantee commitments. (Sec. 3) Lists the appropriate levels of new budget authority, budget outlays, new direct loan obligations, and new primary loan guarantee commitments for each of specified major functional categories for FY 1998 through 2002. (Sec. 4) Sets forth appropriate levels of new budget authority and budget outlays for Federal investments for each of specified major functional categories for FY 1998 through 2002. (Sec. 5) Establishes reconciliation procedures. Specifies outlay reductions for the House Committee on Commerce and the House Committee on Ways and Means for each of FY 1998 through 2002. Directs the House Committee on Ways and Means to report changes in laws within its jurisdiction: (1) such that the total level of revenues for that committee is increased by specified amounts in each of such fiscal years; and (2) that provide for the establishment of an Investment Trust Fund as a separate account in the Treasury, into which shall be transferred revenues realized by the acution of spectrum allocations by the Federal Communications Commission. Requires that amounts in that fund be used exclusively for programs assumed under Federal investments provisions of this resolution. (Sec. 7) Expresses the sense of the Congress regarding budget trends. Declares that the increasing portion of the Federal budget absorbed by interest payments and consumption programs, particularly health spending, has led to a declining level of domestically financed investment and may adversely affect the ability of the economy to grow at the levels needed to provide for future generations. (Sec. 8) Expresses the sense of the Congress regarding the need to maintain Federal investments. Declares that a balanced program to improve the economy should be based on the concurrent goals of eliminating the deficit and maintaining Federal investment in programs that enhance long-term productivity such as research and development, education and training, and physical infrastructure improvements. (Sec. 9) Expresses the sense of the Congress regarding the treatment of Federal investments within the budget. Declares that: (1) the current budget structure focuses primarily on short-term spending and does not highlight for decision making purposes the differences between Federal spending for long-term investment and that for current consumption; and (2) in order to restructure the Federal budget to make such a distinction, it is necessary to identify an investment component in the Federal budget and establish specific budgetary targets for such investments.</summary>
</bill>
