<bill session="105" type="h" number="3973" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Trinity River Basin Fish and Wildlife Restoration Reauthorization Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize and amend the Trinity River Basin Fish and Wildlife Management Act of 1984.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409228"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1998-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fish culture"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/1998--Introduced.
Trinity River Basin Fish and Wildlife Restoration Reauthorization Act of 1998 - Amends the Trinity River Basin Fish and Wildlife Management Act of 1984 to extend and increase authorized appropriations for the Trinity River Basin fish and wildlife management program. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to ensure that all expenditures of Federal funds for the purposes of the program are made in a manner consistent with such priorities, policies, and technical and fiscal review processes as are established by the Trinity River Basin Fish and Wildlife Task Force. Prohibits amounts expended by a contractor for administrative, indirect, and overhead costs in carrying out a contract of less than $5,000 from exceeding 20 percent of the total amount of Federal funds obligated or expended under the contract. Directs the Secretary to require that any bid or proposal for a contract of $5,000 or more to be funded under the management program, and any such contract, separately identify the amount that is authorized to be expended by a contractor under the contract for such costs. Requires the Task Force, not later than October 1, 2000, and every three years thereafter, to evaluate and report to the Congress on the results of, and improvements required for, the management program; and (2) initiate such changes as may be required in program policies, procedures, and activities to assure that the purposes and requirements of such Act are achieved.</summary>
</bill>
