<bill session="106" type="h" number="4732" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Energy Fair Pricing Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require certain actions with respect to the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) or any other cartel engaged in oil price fixing, production cutbacks, or other market-distorting practices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400248" joined="2000-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1103"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1103" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Cartels"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="OPEC countries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Price fixing"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2000--Introduced.
International Energy Fair Pricing Act of 2000 - Sets forth U.S. policy with respect to international organizations and international financial institutions that support or recognize the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC).Directs the President to report to Congress with respect to: (1) any loan, guarantee, or technical assistance provided by any international financial institution that directly or indirectly supports any OPEC program or country, or any other cartel, engaging in production cutbacks or other market-distorting practices; (2) energy sector loans of, technical assistance provided by, and policies of each international financial institution, including an analysis of the extent to which they promote the complete dismantlement of international oil price fixing arrangements and the development of a market-based system for the exploration, production, and marketing of petroleum resources; (3) Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) efforts to review market-distorting practices of international cartels, including OPEC, and specific actions that OECD member countries can undertake to combat such practices; and (4) U.S. actions to ensure that the OECD expands upon its activities and programs regarding the operation of international cartels.Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to direct the President, in providing assistance for the development of indigenous energy resources in developing non-OPEC countries, to ensure that such assistance is not used to support, directly or indirectly, OPEC programs or countries, or any other cartel, if OPEC or such cartel engages in oil price fixing.</summary>
</bill>
