<bill session="113" type="h" number="555" updated="2013-07-17T15:52:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">BLM Live Internet Auctions Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Mineral Leasing Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct onshore oil and gas lease sales through Internet-based live lease sales, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2013-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2013--Introduced.
BLM Live Internet Auctions Act - Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct onshore oil and gas lease sales through Internet-based live bidding methods. Requires each individual Internet-based lease sale to conclude within seven days. Directs the Secretary to analyze the first 10 such lease sales, including estimates of: (1) increases or decreases in such lease sales, compared to sales conducted by oral bidding; and (2) the total cost or savings to the Department of the Interior as a result of such sales, compared to sales conducted by oral bidding. Requires the report to evaluate the demonstrated or expected effectiveness of different structures for lease sales which may provide an opportunity to better maximize bidder participation, ensure the highest return to the federal taxpayers, minimize opportunities for fraud or collusion, and ensure the security and integrity of the leasing process.</summary>
</bill>
