<bill session="106" type="h" number="5237" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Death Penalty Moratorium Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To institute a moratorium on the imposition of the death penalty at the Federal and State level until a National Commission on the Death Penalty studies its use and policies ensuring justice, fairness, and due process are implemented.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="2000-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="DNA fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in criminal justice administration"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Forensic medicine"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Mentally disabled"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Moratorium on the Death Penalty Title II: National Commission on the Federal Death Penalty National Death Penalty Moratorium Act of 2000 - Title I: Moratorium on the Death Penalty - Prohibits the Federal Government and any State from carrying out the death penalty until Congress considers the final findings and recommendations of the National Commission on the Death Penalty and enacts legislation repealing this provision and implementing or rejecting the guidelines and procedures recommended by the Commission.Title II: National Commission on the Federal Death Penalty - Establishes the National Commission on the Federal Death Penalty.(Sec. 202) Directs the Commission to: (1) conduct a thorough study of all matters relating to the administration of the death penalty to determine whether it comports with constitutional principles and requirements of fairness, justice, equality, and due process; and (2) establish guidelines and procedures for the administration of the death penalty which ensure that death penalty cases are administered fairly and impartially in accordance with due process, minimize the risk that innocent persons may be executed, and ensure that the death penalty is not administered in a racially discriminatory manner. Sets forth requirements regarding submission of a preliminary and a final report.</summary>
</bill>
