<bill session="106" type="h" number="1288" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient Safety Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require Medicare providers to disclose publicly staffing and performance in order to promote improved consumer information and choice, to protect employees of Medicare providers who report concerns about the safety and quality of services provided by Medicare providers or who report violations of Federal or State law by those providers, and to require review of the impact on public health and safety of proposed mergers and acquisitions of Medicare providers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400178"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1999-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="1999-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1999-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1999-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1999-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1999-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="1999-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1999-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="1999-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1999-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="1999-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="1999-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug utilization"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Gays"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health care industry"/>
    <term name="Hospital accreditation"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospital medical staff"/>
    <term name="Hospital patients"/>
    <term name="Hospital personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospital records"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lesbians"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Mortality"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Vital statistics"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1999--Introduced.
Patient Safety Act of 1999 - Requires providers under the Medicare program, as a condition for continued participation in the program, to make publicly available certain minimum information, in addition to information specified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, regarding nurse staffing and patient outcomes. Requires the following to be made public along with its source and currency status: (1) data regarding complaints filed with the State agency with oversight over health care services, the Health Care Financing Administration, or a provider accrediting agency; (2) compliance with the standards deemed to demonstrate compliance with conditions of Medicare participation; and (3) data regarding investigations and findings as a result of those complaints and the findings of scheduled inspection visits. Allows the Secretary to waive or reduce reporting requirements in the case of a small provider for whom their imposition would be unduly burdensome. Prohibits Medicare providers from terminating or taking any other adverse action against any employee or groups of employees for certain actions, including those taken for the purpose of notifying the provider of conditions potentially dangerous or injurious to patients receiving services from the provider or to employees of the provider. Requires provider suspension from participation in Medicare for taking such an adverse action. Requires any provider under Medicare that files with the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission notification of a transaction required to be reported under the Clayton Act to provide to the Secretary with a report that includes: (1) the overall impact of such transaction on the health services available and readily accessible to the community; and (2) the impact of such transaction on each of various specified subjects, including the availability and accessibility of services to the poor, the uninsured, ethnic minorities, women, the disabled, and the lesbian and gay communities. Requires public availability of such reports, public hearings on their elements and any other factors related to the health, safety, and welfare of patients and the community involved, secretarial review of each such proposed transaction based on the report, hearing testimony, and any other relevant factors. Deems any provider that executes a transaction found to have a negative impact on health and safety (or that fails to file a required report) not to be in compliance with the conditions of Medicare participation. Mandates the provider's immediate suspension from program participation if it completes a transaction that poses immediate jeopardy or irreparable harm to patient health, safety, or welfare.</summary>
</bill>
