<bill session="104" type="hr" number="480" updated="2012-11-01T22:43:21-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to implement the recommendations of the Task Force on Committee Review regarding committee operations, procedures, and staffing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300003" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="1996-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1996-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="411214" joined="1996-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="411550" joined="1996-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on House Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSRU" name="House Rules"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional casework"/>
    <term name="Congressional caucuses"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee staffing"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional office operations"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Congressional witnesses"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Management audit"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Teleconferencing"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>07/16/1996--Introduced.
Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to require each standing committee (other than the Appropriations and Budget Committees) to either establish oversight committees or designate at least three staff members to be solely responsible for oversight. Directs the Committee on House Oversight to: (1) modify its committee funding policies to allow committees to use General Accounting Office and executive branch detailees; and (2) develop an electronic program such that Members may track and categorize their casework requests and report their findings to a central House unit. Expresses the sense of the House that: (1) the Oversight Committee should provide committees with sufficient investigative resources; (2) the General Counsel should provide more timely, proactive, and strategic advice to committees respecting the issuance of subpoenas and the lack of compliance by officials; and (3) committees should better utilize the Corrections Day process. (Sec. 2) Directs the Committee to make resources available to the Chief Administrative Officer to perform management and technology audits of committees. (Sec. 3) Directs the Parliamentarian to: (1) establish a comprehensive program to train selected committee staff to serve as parliamentary advisors; and (2) commence to recodify the Rules at the beginning of the 105th Congress. (Sec. 5) Allows Members to participate in committee hearings through audiovisual contact under specified circumstances. Authorizes each committee to not apply the five-minute rule in the interrogation of witnesses in a hearing to the extent that the rules of that committee so permit. Expresses the sense of the House encouraging committees to utilize alternative hearing formats. (Sec. 6) Provides that no point of order shall lie against any committee report for failing to comply with certain voting requirements on reporting measures if the report is in substantial compliance. Repeals a requirement regarding inflationary impact statements. Directs that specified reports contain a statement of performance goals. Provides that if two or more committees jointly study or investigate any matter, such committees may file a joint report. (Sec. 7) Limits the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight to six, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure to five, subcommittees. Repeals: (1) an exception for the Appropriations Committee from the requirement that whenever any entity is to be granted authorization for the payment of its expenses, such authorization initially shall be procured by one primary expense resolution reported by the Oversight Committee; and (2) a limitation on committees' sittings during the five-minute rule. Expresses the sense of the House that the respective party caucus and conference should enforce subcommittee assignment limits. (Sec. 8) Requires the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to determine whether any complaint against a Member, officer, or employee of the House is properly filed and, if so, whether a preliminary investigation is warranted. Sets forth: (1) further requirements regarding preliminary investigations and limits on participation on the Committee or an investigative panel; and (2) provisions regarding the handling of frivolous complaints.</summary>
</bill>
