<bill session="104" type="h" number="2824" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Snowbasin Land Exchange Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize an exchange of lands in the State of Utah at Snowbasin Ski Area.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-03-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 26 - 15.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-03-25T14:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 104-493.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-03-25T14:41:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="236">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 236.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2402"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2402"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2402"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1371"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Winter sports facilities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/1995--Introduced.
Snowbasin Land Exchange Act of 1995 - Requires the Secretary of Agriculture, subject to specified terms and conditions, to transfer certain lands within the Cache National Forest in Utah to the Sun Valley Company in exchange for specified Company lands of approximate equal value to become a part of the Wasatch or Cache National Forests as appropriate. Adjusts the boundaries of such Forests to encompass the lands. Requires such lands to be managed in accordance with the Weeks Act and other applicable laws, rules, and regulations of National Forest System lands. Finds that, based on congressional review, the Phase I facilities identified and described in the Snowbasin Ski Area Master Development Plan dated October 1995 to be located on National Forest System lands, or any modifications thereof mutually agreed to by the Secretary and the Company, are reasonable and necessary to accommodate the 2002 Olympics. Directs the Secretary to issue all necessary permits and authorizations for construction and operation of such facilities in accordance with specified procedures and provisions of this Act. Requires the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees on whether construction and operation of Phase I facilities have provided for sufficient environmental protection on National Forest lands affected by such facilities.</summary>
</bill>
