<bill session="106" type="h" number="5595" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hispanic Health Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for programs regarding the health of Hispanic individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400339"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2000-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2000-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2000-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="2000-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2000-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="2000-10-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1986"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Child mental health services"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to substance abuse programs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Minority women"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Suicide"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Youth"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/27/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Annual Report to Congress on Programs for Improving Health Status of Hispanic Individuals Title II: Diabetes Control and Prevention Title III: HIV Prevention Activities Regarding Hispanic Individuals Title IV: Prevention of Latina Adolescent Suicides Title V: Bilingual Health Professionals Title VI: Cultural Competence Title VII: Hispanic-Serving Health Professions Schools Title VIII: Data Regarding Race and Ethnicity Title IX: General Provisions Hispanic Health Act of 2000 - Title I: Annual Report to Congress on Programs for Improving Health Status of Hispanic Individuals - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to report to Congress on programs carried out through the Public Health Service for improving the health status of Hispanic individuals regarding diabetes, HIV infection, AIDS, substance abuse, and mental health.Title II: Diabetes Control and Prevention - Authorizes appropriations for: (1) diabetes education and prevention activities for Hispanic individuals; and (2) implementation of recommendations of the Diabetes Research Working Group.Title III: HIV Prevention Activities Regarding Hispanic Individuals - Directs the Secretary to: (1) carry out activities relating to HIV prevention activities among Hispanic individuals; and (2) make grants to Hispanic-serving institutions for carrying out HIV- related projects among racial and ethnic minority groups.Title IV: Prevention of Latina Adolescent Suicides - Directs the Secretary to carry out a grant program for reducing suicide attempts among Latina adolescents. Authorizes appropriations.Title V: Bilingual Health Professionals - Directs the Secretary to carry out a program for training bilingual health professionals in the treatment of minority health conditions. Authorizes appropriations.Title VI: Cultural Competence - Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop educational materials on providing health services in a culturally competent manner; (2) establish a Center for Linguistic and Cultural Competence in Health Care; and (3) carry out cultural competence demonstration projects at two hospitals. Authorizes appropriations.Title VII: Hispanic-Serving Health Professions Schools - Directs the Secretary to make grants to Hispanic-serving health professions schools to recruit Hispanic individuals for enrollment. Authorizes appropriations.Title VIII: Data Regarding Race and Ethnicity - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary to collect and maintain health care race and ethnicity data.(Sec. 802) Directs the Secretary to develop outcome measures used to evaluate, by race and ethnicity, the performance of health care programs and projects to individuals under Medicare and Medicaid programs (titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act).Title IX: General Provisions - Provides definitions and an effective date.</summary>
</bill>
