<bill session="105" type="h" number="167" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Training and Employment Bill of Rights Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for a Veterans' Employment and Training Bill of Rights, to strengthen preference for veterans in hiring, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1997-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1997-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1997-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1997-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1997-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="1998-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="1997-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1997-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="1998-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1997-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E79"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contempt of court"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled veterans"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Missing in action"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' preference"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in government"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Veterans' Training and Employment Bill of Rights Act of 1997 - Entitles the following covered persons to priority of services under any federally-funded workforce preparation, development, or delivery program or service, as long as such person otherwise meets participation eligibility requirements: (1) veterans who have a service-connected disability or who served on active duty in a campaign or expedition for which a campaign badge has been authorized; (2) the spouse of any person who died of a service-connected disability or who has a total permanent disability resulting from a service-connected disability; (3) the spouse of any member serving on active duty who is listed as missing in action, captured in the line of duty by a hostile force, or forcibly detained or interned by a foreign government or power; and (4) the spouse of a veteran who died while a permanent service-connected disability was in existence. Requires State and local entities performing such programs or services to inform covered individuals of the availability of such services. Directs the Secretary of Labor to report annually to the congressional veterans' committees concerning an evaluation of such priority program and its level of services. (Sec. 3) Requires Federal contracts or grants of $100,000 or more for the procurement of personal property and non-personal services to contain a provision under which the party receiving the contract or grant agrees to take affirmative action to employ and advance qualified veterans who: (1) are disabled; (2) served on active duty during a war or in a campaign or expedition for which a campaign badge has been authorized; or (3) while serving on active duty, participated in a U.S. military operation for which an armed forces service medal was awarded. Directs the President to implement promulgating regulations which require the contractee or grantee to list employment openings with local employment agencies and to give priority to qualifying veterans. (Sec. 4) Requires veterans qualifying under this Act to be given appropriate recruitment (currently, readjustment) appointments within the Federal Government. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to provide specified veterans' employment rights and benefits assistance to veterans qualifying under this Act. Provides for the filing, investigation, and determination of claims by qualifying individuals that an entity has failed to comply with the hiring requirements provided under this Act. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary to allocate an additional ten full-time equivalent positions from the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor to the Veterans' Employment and Training Service to carry out work training and employment services for qualifying individuals.</summary>
</bill>
