<bill session="105" type="h" number="2700" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oxon Run Parkway Land Transfer and Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain lands to the District of Columbia for use for single-family homes for low and moderate income individuals and families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-10-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2045"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Moderate income housing"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/22/1997--Introduced.
Oxon Run Parkway Land Transfer and Restoration Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the District of Columbia specified District land formerly known as United States Reservation 501 in Oxon Run Park, subject to the condition that it be developed into a community of single-family homes with ancillary facilities for low and moderate income individuals and families and recreational facilities. Requires disclosure to the District of the current property condition and its former uses. Provides for: (1) inspection and treatment of the conveyed property; (2) District authority to reconvey such property within six months if it cannot be used for the above purposes; (3) a reversionary interest to the United States if the property is not used for such purposes or if construction for such uses has not commenced within specified periods; and (4) savings provisions.</summary>
</bill>
