<bill session="105" type="h" number="4342" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-08-04T13:21:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-08-04T13:21:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Miscellaneous Trade and Technical Corrections Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Miscellaneous Trade and Technical Corrections Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make miscellaneous and technical changes to various trade laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400085"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1998-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-07-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 105-671.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-08-03T18:21:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="379">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 379.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-08-04T13:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crane moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-04T13:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7057-7071" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-04T13:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-08-04T13:21:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-08-04T13:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-10">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Finance"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-29">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Reported to Senate by Senator Roth with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 105-356.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="666">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 666.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="1945"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2236"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2237"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2238"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2239"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2245"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2246"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2268"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2269"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2270"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2322"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2324"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2325"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2520"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2521"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2576"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2622"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2622"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2686"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2770"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2857"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3083"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3191"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3193"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3194"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3195"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3196"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3197"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3198"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3199"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3200"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3201"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3202"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3244"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3268"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3289"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3316"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3324"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3328"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3355"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3357"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3358"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3359"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3360"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3364"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3365"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3366"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3367"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3368"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3369"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3370"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3372"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3373"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3375"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3384"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3385"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3386"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3387"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3388"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3389"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3390"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3391"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3392"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3393"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3394"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3414"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3415"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3416"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3417"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3427"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3428"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3431"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3432"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3446"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3477"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3480"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="4045"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="4856"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Aircraft engines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Antidumping"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Chemotherapy"/>
    <term name="Clothing industry"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Copying processes"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Dyes and dyeing"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Electronics industry"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Free ports and zones"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Glass and glass industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Herbicides"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Jewelry trade"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leather industry"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Machinery"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Plastics"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Rockets (Aeronautics)"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific instruments and apparatus"/>
    <term name="Shoe industry"/>
    <term name="Soccer"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Textile industry"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade fairs"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
    <term name="Tugboats"/>
    <term name="Video display terminals"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women athletes"/>
    <term name="Wool"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/1998--Reported to Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Miscellaneous Trade Corrections Title II: Temporary Duty Suspensions and Reductions; Other Trade Provisions Subtitle A: Temporary Duty Suspensions and Reductions Subtitle B: Other Trade Provisions Miscellaneous Trade and Technical Corrections Act of 1998 - Title I: Miscellaneous Trade Corrections - Makes various specified miscellaneous technical corrections to the Trade Act of 1974 and other specified Federal law involving: (1) abolishment of the East-West Foreign Trade Board; (2) repeal of the requirement that certain small vessels departing from a foreign port, or which visited a hovering vessel, carry a certificate for the importation into the United States of alcoholic spirits; (3) repeal of the exemption of documented tugs with a Great Lakes endorsement from certain entry and clearance requirements; (4) change of general most-favored-nation (MFN) status to general or normal trade relations (NTR) status under the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States; and (5) conforming amendments to obsolete references to the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT). (Sec. 1003) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to allow certain entries of television receivers, monitors, and picture tubes, and combination TV-VCRs with a diagonal measurement of up to 34.29cm (currently, 33.02 cm), or 13.5 inches, to be classified as 13 inches for purposes of tariff treatment under the Schedule. Directs the Customs Service, upon proper request, to liquidate or reliquidate certain entries made on or after January 1, 1995, and before 15 days after enactment of this Act, as if such amendment applied to such entries. Title II: Temporary Duty Suspensions and Reductions; Other Trade Provisions - Subtitle A: Temporary Duty Suspensions and Reductions - Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to provide for temporary duty suspensions for: (1) specified chemicals and dyes through December 31, 2001; (2) snowboard boots with uppers of textile materials through December 31, 2001; (3) ink-jet textile printing machinery through December 31, 2001; (4) textile printing machinery through December 31, 2001; (5) substrates of synthetic quartz or synthetic fused silica imported into the United States in bulk or in forms or packages for retail sale through December 31, 2001; (6) power weaving machines (looms), shuttle type, for weaving fabrics between 30 cm and 4.9m in width, if entered without off-loom or large loom take- ups, drop wires, heddles, reeds, harness frames or beams, through December 31, 2001; (7) skating boots for use in the manufacture of in-line roller skates through December 31, 2001; (8) dual thrust chamber rocket engines, each having a maximum static sea level thrust exceeding 3,550 kN and nozzle exit diameter exceeding 127cm, through December 31, 2001; (9) certain manufacturing equipment through December 31, 2001; (10) textured rolled glass sheets through December 31, 2001; (11) certain anti-HIV drug substances through June 30, 1999; (12) certain high-performance loudspeakers not mounted in their enclosures, through December 31, 2001; (13) parts for use in the manufacture of certain high-performance loudspeakers through December 31, 2001; and (14) textile doubling or twisting machines through December 31, 1998. (Sec. 2129) Reduces the duty on a certain dye and on certain chemicals variously through December 31, 1998, December 31, 1999, December 31, 2000, and December 31, 2001. (Sec. 2161) Reduces the duty, for December 31, 1998, and December 31, 2001, respectively, on weaving machines (looms), shuttleless type, for weaving fabrics between 30cm and 4.9m in width, entered without off-loom or large loom takeups, drop wires, heddles, reeds, harness frames, or beams. Subtitle B: Other Trade Provisions - Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to extend to certain fine jewelry certain trade benefits of insular possessions of the United States. Mandates treatment as a product of the Virgin Islands, Guam, or American Samoa, during 1999 and 2000, of any article of jewelry assembled in such territory or possession. (Sec. 2502) Provides for the tariff treatment for certain components of scientific instruments and apparatus, as well as the application of the domestic equivalency test to such components. (Sec. 2503) Directs the U.S. Customs Service to liquidate or reliquidate (refund duty on) certain entries made at Los Angeles, California, and New Orleans, Louisiana, in accordance with the final decision of the International Trade Administration for shipments entered between October 1, 1984, and December 14, 1987 (case number A- 274-001). (Sec. 2504) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to convene a working group of interested parties and, by March 31, 1999, publish regulations and, if necessary, submit legislation to the Congress, to modify and simplify the processing of finished petroleum derivatives drawback claims. (Sec. 2505) Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to provide that packaging material produced in the United States (currently, any packaging material), which is used by the manufacturer or any other person on or for articles which are exported or destroyed, shall also be eligible for a refund (drawback) of 99 percent of any duty, tax, or fee imposed on the importation of such material used to manufacture or produce the packaging material. (Sec. 2506) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, by January 1, 2000, to provide for the inclusion of commercial importation data from foreign-trade zones in the National Customs Automation Program (an automated and electronic system for processing commercial importations). (Sec. 2507) Permits the deferral (until sale) of duty payment on any large yacht (a vessel exceeding 79 feet in length and used primarily for recreation or pleasure) that is imported for sale at a boat show, if the importer of record: (1) certifies to the Customs Service that it is imported for sale at a boat show in the United States; and (2) posts a bond in an amount equal to twice the amount of the duty ordinarily owed on such yacht. (Sec. 2508) Directs the appropriate customs officer, within 30 days from the date an application for further review is filed with respect to a protest to a decision of the Customs Service, to allow or deny such application. Requires that any allowed protest be forwarded to the customs officer who will conduct the further review. (Sec. 2509) Authorizes the Customs Service, notwithstanding the fact that a valid protest was not filed, to reliquidate an entry to refund merchandise processing fees paid on goods qualifying under the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) rules of origin for which no claim for preferential tariff treatment was made at the time of importation, provided that the importer meets certain conditions. (Sec. 2510) Authorizes the entry or withdrawal from a warehouse of international travel merchandise subject to a duty. (Sec. 2511) Revises requirements with respect to the five-year review by the administering authority and the International Trade Commission of countervailing duty or antidumping duty orders, notices of injury determination, or determinations to continue an order or suspension agreement. Excludes from the computation of the five-year period preceding such a review any period during which the importation of the subject merchandise is prohibited on account of U.S. imposition of certain sanctions under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act or other Federal law against the country in which such merchandise originates, if that country is not a member of the World Trade Organization. (Sec. 2512) Applies the rates of duty effective after December 31, 1994, under the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, if lower, to certain water resistant wool trousers that were entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, after December 31, 1988, and before January 1, 1995. (Sec. 2513) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to provide duty-free treatment of previously imported goods for which a duty was paid if they are: (1) exported within three years after the date of such previous importation; (2) sold for exportation and exported to individuals for personal use; (3) reimported without having been advanced in value or improved in condition by any process of manufacture or other means while abroad; (4) reimported as personal returns from those individuals, whether or not consolidated with other personal returns prior to reimportation; and (5) reimported by or for the account of the person who exported them from the United States within one year of such exportation. (Sec. 2514) Grants duty-free treatment, through December 31, 2002, to the personal effects of, and other equipment imported and used by, participants, their families and associated members, and officials involved in the 1999 International Special Olympics, the 1999 Women's World Cup Soccer, the 2001 International Special Olympics, the 2002 Salt Lake City Winter Olympics, and the 2002 Winter Paralympic Games. Declares that such articles shall be: (1) free of applicable taxes and fees; but (2) not exempt from routine customs inspections. (Sec. 2515) Directs the U.S. Customs Service, upon request, to liquidate or reliquidate (refund duty on) certain entries (filed at the port of Los Angeles) of indirect electrostatic copiers at the rate of duty that would have been applicable to such merchandise if they had been liquidated or reliquidated at a duty rate applicable to other automated data processing (ADP) thermal transfer printer units on the date of entry. (Sec. 2516) Directs the U.S. Customs Service to provide for the liquidation or reliquidation (refund) of certain entries in accordance with the provisions of Treasury Decision 86-126(M) and Customs Ruling No. 224697, dated November 17, 1994. (Sec. 2518) Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to authorize duty-free sales enterprises to be located, among other places, within a port of entry, or within 25 statute miles of a staffed port of entry, if reasonable assurance can be provided that the duty-free merchandise sold by the enterprise will be exported by individuals departing from the customs territory through an international airport located within the territory.</summary>
</bill>
