<bill session="104" type="hr" number="298" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Relating to the deployment of United States Armed Forces in and around the territory of the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina to enforce the peace agreement between the parties to the conflict in the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="1995-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on National Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Neutrality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/1995--Introduced.
Reiterates serious concerns and grave reservations regarding the President's policy to deploy 20,000 members of the U.S. armed forces on the ground in the territory of the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina. Calls for: (1) the President and the Secretary of Defense to rely on the judgment of, and ensure the provision of appropriate resources and support to, the commander of the U.S. armed forces that are deployed in and around the territory of the Republic in all matters affecting the safety, support, and well-being of such forces; and (2) the U.S. Government to be impartial and evenhanded with all parties to the conflict as necessary to assure the safety and protection of such forces.</summary>
</bill>
