<bill session="106" type="h" number="2939" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Debt Relief and IMF Reform Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide the highly indebted poor countries with relief from debts owed to the International Monetary Fund, to end United States participation in and support for the Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility of the International Monetary Fund, and to require certain conditions to be met before the International Monetary Fund may sell gold, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="1999-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1999-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1999-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1999-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1999-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1999-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1999-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="1999-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1999-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1999-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1999-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1999-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1939"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gold reserves"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/1999--Introduced.
Debt Relief and IMF Reform Act of 1999 - Amends the Bretton Woods Agreements Act to prohibit the U.S. director to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) from voting for any proposal to sell gold, unless: (1) Congress has enacted a joint resolution authorizing its sale; (2) the IMF has canceled all debts owed to it by countries eligible for debt relief under the Heavily Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) Initiative and Haiti; (3) the Secretary of the Treasury demonstrates to Congress that there is no other feasible way to finance the cancellation of such debts; (4) the most recent operational IMF budget has been published, with any information that could disrupt financial markets or affect adversely the national security of any country redacted, and other specified requirements met; (5) Congress has enacted a joint resolution certifying that the IMF is in full compliance with specified conditions imposed by title VI of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1999; (6) the proposal to sell meets certain conditions; (7) the interest accruing to the IMF on any investment of the residual sale proceeds will be used for the provision of debt relief for such countries without conditions; and (8) the U.S. Government budget displays costs of U.S. participation in the IMF, in accordance with the guidelines provided in the President's Commission on Budget Concepts.Prohibits U.S. officers, employees or agents from providing any thing of value to the IMF for the purpose of providing resources to the Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility (ESAF) or other concessional lending facility of the IMF. Amends the Bretton Woods Agreements Act to require the U.S. director of the IMF to use every effort to terminate the ESAF.Prohibits appropriations for payments to the IMF until it has canceled all debts owed to it by HIPCs and Haiti.Prohibits the U.S. governor to the IMF from voting for any proposal for any quota increase for the IMF, unless, before the proposal was made, Congress received notice of the proposal and the position of the Executive Branch on it, and Congress has enacted a joint resolution of approval.</summary>
</bill>
