<bill session="104" type="h" number="1683" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Employee Pension Plan Liability Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Federal cause of action for failure of State and local public employee pension plans to meet the terms of such plans, subject to differing burdens of proof depending on whether changes in the plan relating to employer contributions are subject, under the law of the principal State involved, to qualified review boards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E318"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Local officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/1995--Introduced.
Public Employee Pension Plan Liability Act of 1995 - Permits a participant or beneficiary under a public employee pension plan to bring a civil action against the plan to: (1) recover benefits due him or her under the plan's terms, to enforce his or her rights, or to clarify his or her rights to future benefits; (2) enjoin any act or practice which violates the plan's terms; or (3) obtain other appropriate equitable relief to enforce such terms or redress violations of them. Allows a plaintiff, in most instances, to prevail in such an action by proving the case by a preponderance of the evidence. Requires proof by clear and convincing evidence, however, if the action involves a plan under which changes in employer contributions are subject to review by a qualified review board. Grants State courts and U.S. district courts concurrent jurisdiction of such actions. Precribes the general requirements for a qualified review board. States that in general this Act applies to any public employee pension plan, with specified exceptions.</summary>
</bill>
