<bill session="104" type="hr" number="198" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-25T17:52:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-07-25T17:52:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 2076) making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-07-21T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-200, by Mr. Goss.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-21T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2076 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Points of order against provisions of the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI shall be waived. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments. During consideration of the bill for amendment, the Chairman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whether the Member offering an amendment has caused it to be printed in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-07-21T18:05:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="78">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 78.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-07-25T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7609-7614" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-25T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-25T17:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-07-25T17:52:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-07-25T17:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="2076"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the open rule for the consideration of H.R. 2076 (Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and related agencies appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
