<bill session="104" type="h" number="3479" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Alcohol Abuse Prevention Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Alcohol Advertising Accountability Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Alcohol Promotion and Advertising Tax Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Children's Protection from Alcohol Advertising Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">College Campus Alcohol Abuse Prevention and Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">End Taxpayer Promotion of Alcohol Overseas Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Sensible Advertising and Family Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To carry out a comprehensive program dealing with alcohol and alcohol abuse.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1996-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1996-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404520" joined="1996-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1996-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Economic and Educational Opportunities, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG26" subcommittee="Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Alcohol"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverage industry"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Beer"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Magnetic tapes"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Newspapers"/>
    <term name="Outdoor advertising"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Playgrounds"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="School discipline"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="School violence"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Students' rights"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Video games"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Wine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Higher Education and Alcohol Abuse Prevention Title II: Deductions for Alcohol Advertising or Promotion Title III: Promotion of Alcoholic Beverages Title IV: Children and Alcohol Advertising Title V: Alcohol Advertising Title VI: Health Warnings Title VII: Ingredient Labeling for Malt Beverages, Wine, and Distilled Spirits Comprehensive Alcohol Abuse Prevention Act of 1996 - Title I: Higher Education and Alcohol Abuse Prevention - College Campus Alcohol Abuse Prevention and Education Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to revise drug and alcohol abuse prevention program certification requirements (which must be met in order for a higher education institution to receive any Federal financial assistance) to require the programs to limit alcoholic beverage advertisements in the institution's newspapers and other publications to price and product identification. Prohibits: (1) distribution of promotional material encouraging alcohol consumption; (2) distribution of free alcohol; and (3) sponsorship or public support of any on-campus athletic, musical, cultural, or social program, event, or competition by any alcoholic beverage company or by any group of companies. Requires that identification, referral, or treatment of students and employees under such programs not jeopardize the their matriculation status or employment. Authorizes grants to institutions or consortia, and contracts with such institutions and other organizations, for programs of prevention and education (including treatment-referral) to reduce and eliminate the illegal use of drugs and alcohol and associated violence. Allows using the contracts for a higher education center for alcohol and drug abuse prevention to provide training, technical assistance, evaluation, dissemination, and associated services and assistance to the higher education community and higher education institutions. Mandates ten National Recognition Awards annually to institutions that have developed and implemented effective alcohol and drug abuse prevention and education programs. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Deductions for Alcohol Advertising or Promotion - Alcohol Promotion and Advertising Tax Fairness Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to disallow a deduction for the expense of advertising (via any means) or promoting any alcoholic beverage. Title III: Promotion of Alcoholic Beverages - End Taxpayer Promotion of Alcohol Overseas Act - Amends the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to prohibit the use of funds for overseas promotion of alcoholic beverages. Title IV: Children and Alcohol Advertising - Children's Protection from Alcohol Advertising Act of 1996 - Prohibits advertising or promoting alcoholic beverages on any audio tape, audio disc, videotape, video arcade game, computer game, or film. Prohibits outdoor advertising of alcoholic beverages within 1000 feet of any school, playground, or other public facility where individuals under 21 are reasonably expected to convene. Restricts alcohol print advertising in publications with an under-21 readership of 15 percent or more than two million to text only in black and white print. Limits alcohol television broadcast advertising between 7 a.m. and 10 p.m. to a picture of the beverage with factual, objective audio information. Mandates criminal fines and allows injunctions. Requires that alcohol manufacturers sponsoring events be identified in the corporate (not brand) name. Prohibits manufacturing or distributing non-beverage products with an identifiable brand of an alcoholic beverage manufacturer (but allows the corporate name). Title V: Alcohol Advertising - Alcohol Advertising Accountability Act of 1996 - Mandates: (1) an annual report to the Congress on alcohol advertising, its profile, and its effects, along with recommendations for legislation; and (2) establishment of a panel to assist in gathering information for the report. Title IV: Health Warnings - Sensible Advertising and Family Education Act - Declares it to be an unlawful or deceptive act under the Federal Trade Commission Act to advertise any alcoholic beverage through magazines, newspapers, brochures, promotional displays, radio, television (including cable, paid per view, or subscription), or other electronic means, unless the advertising includes one of specified health warnings. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to maintain toll free numbers referred to in some of the warnings. Title VII: Ingredient Labeling for Malt Beverages, Wine, and Distilled Spirits - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to deem a malt beverage, wine, or distilled spirit mislabeled unless it bears a label disclosing: (1) the alcoholic content; (2) the number of drinks (defining "drink" as .6 ounces of alcohol); (3) its ingredients and calories; (4) the common name of each ingredient, including additives; and (5) a toll-free number for help with a drinking problem. Authorizes appropriations for the toll-free number.</summary>
</bill>
