<bill session="106" type="h" number="5326" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense Drug Policy Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To introduce common sense to America's policy regarding controlled substances.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism treatment"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Cocaine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Continuum of care"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Crack (Drug)"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to substance abuse programs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities and crime"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Pleas (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Prison administration"/>
    <term name="Prison guards"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Suicide"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women prisoners"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Major Drug Trafficking Prosecution Title II: Protection of Women in Prisons Title III: Increased Funding for Prevention and Treatment of Substance Abuse in Federal Prison System Title IV: Prosecutorial Data Collection Title V: Clean Start Common Sense Drug Policy Act of 2000 - Title I: Major Drug Trafficking Prosecution - Prohibits commencement of a Federal prosecution for a drug offense involving an amount less than the minimum for an offense under the Controlled Substances Act or, in the case of cocaine, involving an amount less than 500 grams.Amends the Controlled Substances Act to repeal certain minimum sentencing periods for covered offenses.Title II: Protection of Women in Prisons - Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to require each State to provide to the Attorney General (AG) certain assurances that it has in effect certain policies and procedures designed to increase the protection of women in prisons and to address the victimization of women inmates.Title III: Increased Funding for Prevention and Treatment of Substance Abuse in Federal Prison System - Requires the AG to carry out a program for the prevention and treatment of substance abuse among individuals who are in Federal penal or correctional institutions or in criminal custody, with special consideration for those within 12 months of completing their sentences.Title IV: Prosecutorial Data Collection - Requires the AG to establish a requirement, binding on each Federal prosecutor, that the race, ethnicity, and gender of each person charged with a Federal criminal offense prosecuted by the Department of Justice, and each victim thereof, be reported to the AG at each stage of the prosecution. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide an identical requirement with respect to State prosecutions.Title V: Clean Start - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to outline eligibility requirements for expungement of a covered offense.</summary>
</bill>
