<bill session="106" type="h" number="3374" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Examination Enhancement and Insurance Fund Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen the special examination authority of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation in order to protect the Bank Insurance Fund and the Savings Association Insurance Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="2000-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12087-12090"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/1999--Introduced.
Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Examination Enhancement and Insurance Fund Protection Act - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act regarding special examinations of an insured depository institution to require that all reasonable efforts be made to: (1) coordinate FDIC special examinations with other Federal or State regulatory entities; and (2) minimize the disruptive effects of such examinations upon institution operations.Mandates that the Federal banking agencies: (1) grant access to the FDIC in as prompt a manner as practicable with respect to reports of examination and reports of conditions; and (2) establish procedures for providing the FDIC with access to additional information as needed for insurance purposes.</summary>
</bill>
