<bill session="104" type="h" number="2308" updated="2012-11-01T22:44:34-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To abolish the franking privilege for the House of Representatives and to provide for use of approved forms of postage and postage meters for official mail of the House of Representatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="1995-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-12">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-12">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Postal Service"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional allowances"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>09/12/1995--Introduced.
Abolishes the franking privilege in the House of Representatives. Makes available, in lieu of the Official Mail Allowance with respect to Members of the House, amounts for official mail under the Member's Representational Allowance, as allocated by the House Committee on House Oversight. Establishes a spending allowance for official mail with respect to House officers and employees. Makes such allowances available in the same manner and to the same extent as the Official Mail Allowance, except that they shall be used to purchase approved forms of postage rather than to pay for franked mail. Directs the Chief Administrative Officer of the House to take necessary actions to provide for use of postage meters to record the cost and volume of official mail under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
