<bill session="105" type="h" number="1993" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">School Bus Safety Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for school bus safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400611"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1997-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1997-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="404634" joined="1997-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1997-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1997-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1997-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-06-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1272-1273"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bus drivers"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled children"/>
    <term name="Driver education"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disabled students"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary school students"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Flammable materials"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="School buses"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seat belts"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/1997--Introduced.
School Bus Safety Act - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to prescribe Federal proficiency standards for school bus drivers who are required to possess a commercial driver's license to operate a school bus. Requires the Secretary, in prescribing such standards, to authorize States to establish their own proficiency standards in lieu of the Federal standards if the Secretary determines they are as rigorous as the Federal standards. Requires bus drivers to demonstrate their proficiency in operating a school bus in accordance with either the Federal or State standards. (Sec. 4) Directs the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to develop and disseminate guidelines on the safe transportation in school buses of children under the age of five. (Sec. 5) Amends Federal transportation law to require the Secretary to issue regulations applying Federal commercial motor carrier safety regulations to all interstate school operations by local educational agencies. Directs the Secretary to develop an education program informing all local educational agencies that they must comply with such regulations when providing interstate transportation on a school bus to and from school-sanctioned and school-related activities. (Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary to begin a rulemaking process to determine the feasibility of certain safety and access requirements for school buses. (Sec. 7) Prohibits a local educational agency, and any contractor providing transportation services to such agency, from employing a person as a school bus driver before the completion of a background check in the national criminal history background check system. Requires State criminal background check procedures to meet the guidelines set forth in the National Child Protection Act of 1993. Declares that no local educational agency or contractor providing it with transportation services shall be liable in an action for damages on the basis of a criminal conviction of a person employed as a school bus driver if a criminal background check was conducted but the conviction was not disclosed. Authorizes State and Federal fees (not exceeding actual cost) for assistance in the conduct of such checks. (Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary to: (1) issue a notice of proposed rulemaking with respect to minimum reporting criteria on traffic-related deaths and injuries under State highway safety programs; and (2) issue a final rule establishing such criteria. (Sec. 9) Directs the Secretary to enter into an agreement with the Transportation Research Board of the National Academy of Sciences to study and report to specified congressional committees on the safety issues attendant to transportation of school children to and from school and school-related activities by various transportation modes. (Sec. 10) Directs the Secretary to carry out a pilot program to assess the benefits of equipping school buses with Aaron Gordon type flight attendant double shoulder harness mechanisms or other safety restraint devices providing equal or greater passenger protection. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to one school district for equipping school buses with such safety restraint devices. (Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
