<bill session="112" type="h" number="3116" updated="2013-07-14T19:19:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">9/11 Review Commission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">See Something, Say Something Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">9/11 Review Commission Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">See Something, Say Something Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize certain programs of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412398" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412483" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412499" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2011-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 20 - 12.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Provisions of the following measures were included in H.R. 3116, as introduced: H.R. 915, H.R. 1299, H.R. 1411, H.R. 1922, H.R. 2042, H.R. 2356, H.R. 2623, and H.R. 2764. For other action see legislative histories under Legislation Referred.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Provisions of the following measures were adopted (in whole or in part) as amendments to H.R. 3116 during committee consideration: H.R. 607, H.R. 679, H.R. 1505, H.R. 1741, H.R. 1900, H.R. 2000, H.R. 2356, H.R. 2849, H.R. 3173, and H.Res  4729.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Provisions of the following measures were offered (in whole or in part) as amendments to H.R. 3116 but not adopted during Committee consideration: H.R. 176, H.R. 1105, H.R. 2269, and H.R  3011.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-20T21:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on 112-717, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-20">
      <text>Referred jointly and sequentially to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce for a period ending not later than Dec. 21, 2012 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdication of that committee pursuant to clause 1(f) of rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-20">
      <text>Referred jointly and sequentially to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology for a period ending not later than Dec. 21, 2012 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(p) of rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-20">
      <text>Referred jointly and sequentially to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure for a period ending not later than Dec. 21, 2012 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(r) of rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21T12:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21T12:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Science, Space, and Technology discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21T13:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-12-21T13:00:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="520">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 520.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="495"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="963"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1211"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1411"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1922"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2623"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3140"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5843"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="505"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1546"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2011--Introduced.
Department of Homeland Security Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (HSA) to establish in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) an Under Secretary for Policy who shall conduct long-range, risk-based, strategic planning for DHS. Directs the Secretary of DHS to designate a DHS official to coordinate efforts to counter homegrown violent Islamist extremism in the United States. Provides for the Office of International Affairs within DHS to be headed by an Assistant Secretary for International Affairs (currently, by a Director) who shall establish minimum requirements for training and supporting staff who are deployed abroad. Repeals the provisions establishing the Office of Domestic Preparedness. Directs the Secretary to conduct the quadrennial homeland security review in calendar year 2013. Revises the contents of such review. Requires the Secretary to establish: (1) an Acquisition Review Board, (2) a Capabilities and Requirements Council, and (3) an Acquisition Professional Career Program. Directs the Chief Procurement Officer and the Chief Human Capital Officer to submit a five-year strategic plan for DHS's acquisition workforce. Directs the Under Secretary for Management to establish a process to provide for the independent evaluation of the integrity and quality of major acquisitions. Modifies HSA provisions regarding fusion centers to provide for a DHS National Network of Fusion Centers Initiative to establish partnerships with state and major urban area fusion centers. Directs the Secretary to: (1) assign personnel with expertise in security of mass transit systems to participating state and major urban area fusion centers located in high-risk jurisdictions, and (2) develop a comprehensive strategy for the coordinated development and deployment of information sharing computer networks of DHS. Authorizes the Secretary to convert competitive service positions to excepted service positions as necessary to carry out DHS intelligence functions. 9/11 Review Commission Act - Establishes in the legislative branch a National Commission to Review the National Response Since the Terrorist Attacks of September 11, 2001. Amends HSA to direct: (1) the Secretary to issue a biodefense strategy that establishes detailed strategic biodefense objectives for DHS's mission areas; (2) DHS's Office of Intelligence and Analysis to support homeland security-focused intelligence analysis of terrorist plans to conduct attacks against the nation involving chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear materials; (3) the Under Secretary for Science and Technology to produce a terrorism risk assessment of such threats; (4) the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to assist state, local, and tribal authorities in promoting individual and community preparedness and collective response to such attacks; (5) the Secretary to carry out a program to detect a biological attack or event that poses a high risk to homeland security; (6) the Secretary to require the Under Secretary for Science and Technology to assess whether the development of technological screening capabilities for biological agents, pandemic influenza, and other infectious diseases should be undertaken by the Science and Technology Directorate to supportscreening at ports of entry and for other homeland security purposes; (7) the FEMA Administrator to develop a communications plan to provide information to the public related to such attacks; (8) the Secretary to develop response guidelines concerning weapons of mass destruction; (9) the Secretary to use the best available integrated plume models to enable rapid response activities following a chemical, biological, nuclear, or radiological attack or event; (10) the Under Secretary for Science and Technology to conduct tailored risk assessments to inform prioritization of national recovery activities; (11) the Secretary to issue guidance for cleanup and restoration of areas exposed to chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear materials; and (12) the Secretary to develop exercises that address analysis, indoor environmental cleanup methods, and decontamination standards. Amends HSA to direct: (1) the Assistant Administrator of the Grants Programs Directorate to serve as the Authorization Liaison Officer within FEMA; (2) the FEMA Administrator, the Assistant Secretary for Health Affairs, and the National Metropolitan Medical Response System Working Group to conduct a review of the Metropolitan Medical Response System Program; and (3) the Under Secretary for Science and Technology to conduct research to assist state, local, and tribal leaders and the private sector in developing the tools and methods to enhance rural preparation for and response to terrorist attacks and other incidents. Directs the Secretary to: (1) submit a comprehensive strategy for gaining operational control of the international borders between U.S. ports of entry in five years, and (2) maintain a force of not fewer than 21,300 Border Patrol agents and not fewer than 2,200 agents assigned to the northern border. Establishes in United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) a Border Enforcement Security Task Force program. Provides for a six-month pilot program to test the use of autonomous unmanned vehicles to patrol the maritime environment along the northern border and the land environment along the southern border. Directs the Secretary to issue Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Business Travel Cards. Establishes a Director of Operational Test and Evaluation. Authorizes a bioforensics analysis center in DHS to provide support for specified law enforcement and intelligence-related investigations and actions. Directs the Under Secretary for Science and Technology to establish a Homeland Security Science and Technology Fellows Program to facilitate the temporary placement of scientists in components of DHS with a need for scientific and technological expertise. Establishes within the Directorate of Science and Technology a Science and Technology Advisory Committee. Amends HSA to require the Director for the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office to: (1) have specified authorities and responsibilities for all radiological and nuclear research, development, testing, and evaluation programs of DHS; and (2) provide support to assist state, local, and tribal entities in implementing preventive radiological and nuclear detection capabilities. Requires the DHS Secretary to develop a five-year plan of investments necessary to implement DHS's responsibilities under the domestic component of the global nuclear detection architecture. See Something, Say Something Act of 2011 - Amends HSA to provide civil immunity to any person who, in good faith based on objectively reasonable suspicion, makes a voluntary report to an authorized official of suspicious activity indicating that an individual may be engaging in an act of terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
