<bill session="104" type="h" number="2744" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Postal Service Debt Reduction and Truth in Budgeting Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Postmaster General to submit to the Congress a plan for the reduction of the accumulated debt of the Postal Service within seven years.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400142"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" subcommittee="Postal Service" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debt"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
    <term name="United States Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/1995--Introduced.
Postal Service Debt Reduction and Truth in Budgeting Act - Requires the Postmaster General to submit to the Congress a plan providing for: (1) the reduction of the accumulated debt of the Postal Service, by September 30, 2003, to an amount that is not more than five percent of its annual revenues; and (2) maintenance of the accumulated debt at such level. Provides that, if the reduction is achieved, the Postal Service shall have the authority on or after October 1, 2005, to have accumulated debt of not more than seven and one half percent of its annual revenues. Requires the Postmaster General to include in the submission to the Congress of the Postal Service's budget for a fiscal year a detailed accounting of actual and budgeted revenues and expenditures for the preceding fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
