<bill session="107" type="h" number="3978" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">1993 World Trade Center Victims Compensation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide compensation and income tax relief for the individuals who were victims of the terrorist-related bombing of the World Trade Center in 1993 on the same basis as compensation and income tax relief is provided to victims of the terrorist-related aircraft crashes on September 11, 2001.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-14">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-14">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="2214"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2002--Introduced.
1993 World Trade Center Victims Compensation Act - States that the purpose of this Act is to provide compensation for victims physically injured or killed as a result of the terrorist-related bombing of the World Trade Center on February 26, 1993.Directs the Attorney General, acting through the Special Master, to administer the compensation program and establish procedural and substantive rules.Establishes claimants' rights during the review process. Excludes punitive damages from compensation. Reduces compensation by the amount of collateral source compensation received, or expected to be received, by claimant as a result of the bombing.Determines submission of a claim to be a waiver of a claimant's right to file a civil action (or to be party to an action) in any Federal or State court for damages sustained as a result of the bombing.Directs the Attorney General and Special Master to promulgate certain regulations related to carrying out the Act including procedures for hearings and presentation of evidence.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to include victims of the February 26, 1993, World Trade Center attack under Code provisions exempting terrorist victims from certain tax liabilities. Allows for a refund or credit which would otherwise be prevented before the close of the one-year period following enactment of the Act, provided the claim is filed before the close of such period.</summary>
</bill>
