<bill session="107" type="h" number="4961" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-26T21:08:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-06-26T21:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a National Bipartisan Commission on the Future of Medicaid.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400397"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1107"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T21:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 107-544.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-06-26T21:08:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="325">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 325.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Demography"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicaid managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State budgets"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2002--Reported to House without amendment.
Title IX (sic): Medicaid, Public Health, and Other Health Provisions - Subtitle A: Medicaid Provisions - Establishes the National Bipartisan Commission on the Future of Medicaid to: (1) review and analyze the long-term financial condition of the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (SSA); (2) identify the factors that are causing, and the consequences of, increases in costs under the Medicaid program; (3) analyze potential policies that will ensure both the financial integrity of the Medicaid program and the provision of appropriate benefits; (4) make recommendations for establishing incentives and structures to promote enhanced efficiencies and ways of encouraging innovative State policies; (5) make recommendations for establishing the appropriate balance between benefits covered, payments to providers, State and Federal contributions and, where appropriate, recipient cost-sharing obligations; (6) make recommendations on the impact of promoting increased utilization of competitive, private enterprise models to contain program cost growth, through enhanced utilization of private plans, pharmacy benefit managers, and other methods currently being used to contain private sector health-care costs; (7) make recommendations on the financing of prescription drug benefits currently covered under Medicaid programs, including analysis of the current Federal manufacturer rebate program, its impact upon both private market prices as well as those paid by other government purchasers, recent State efforts to negotiate additional supplemental manufacturer rebates and the ability of pharmacy benefit managers to lower drug costs; (8) review and analyze such other matters relating to the Medicaid program as the Commission deems appropriate; and (9) analyze the impact of impending demographic changes upon Medicaid benefits, including long term care services, making recommendations for how best to appropriately divide State and Federal responsibilities for funding these benefits.</summary>
</bill>
