<bill session="106" type="h" number="1770" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Employees' Overtime Pay Limitation Amendments Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to revise the overtime pay limitation for Federal employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1999-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2000-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2000-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2000-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-05-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E933"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1605"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Air traffic controllers"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/1999--Introduced.
Federal Employees' Overtime Pay Limitation Amendments Act of 1999 - Amends Federal Civil Service provisions regarding the computation of overtime pay to: (1) require that, for a Federal employee whose basic pay is at a rate which exceeds the minimum rate of basic pay for GS-10 (including any applicable locality-based comparability payment and any applicable special rate of pay), the overtime hourly rate of pay is an amount equal to the greater of one and one-half times the minimum hourly rate of basic pay for such grade or the hourly rate of the employee's basic pay, and all that amount is premium pay. Revises provisions regarding limitations on premium pay to: (1) allow an employee to be paid premium pay under certain circumstances only to the extent that the payment does not cause the aggregate rate of pay for any pay period for such employee to exceed the lesser of 150 percent of the minimum rate of basic pay payable for GS-15 or the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule; (2) prohibit an employee who is paid premium pay by reason of work in connection with an emergency which involves a direct threat to life or property, including a forest wildfire emergency, from being paid such pay if, or to the extent that, the aggregate of the basic pay and premium pay for such employee would, in any calendar year, exceed the lesser of 150 percent of the minimum rate of basic pay payable for GS-15 or the rate of pay for level V of the Executive Schedule; and (3) prohibit applying such premium pay limitation provisions to certain employees of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Department of Defense.</summary>
</bill>
