<bill session="106" type="h" number="3248" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Women's Health Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act and the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to information on the human papillomavirus (commonly known as HPV).</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400549" joined="1999-11-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400135" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1999-11-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1999-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="1999-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cervical cancer"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Condoms"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Herpes"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Psychology"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Warning labels"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/1999--Introduced.
Protecting Women's Health Act of 1999 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, to: (1) enter into cooperative agreements with States and other entities to conduct sentinel surveillance or other special studies to determine the prevalence in various age groups and populations of specific types of human papillomavirus (HPV) in different sites in various U.S. regions through collection of special specimens for HPV using a variety of laboratory-based testing and diagnostic tools; and (2) develop and analyze data from the HPV sentinel surveillance system. Directs the Secretary to make a progress report to Congress with respect to such requirements.Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to conduct prevention research on HPV. Directs the Secretary to make a progress report to Congress on such research and develop a final proposal. Requires such report to outline steps needed to make HPV a reportable disease and the best strategies to prevent future infections.Directs the Secretary to require the Department of HHS and HHS contractors and grantees to specifically state the effectiveness or lack of effectiveness of condoms in preventing the transmission of HPV, herpes, and other sexually transmitted diseases (STDs) in all publicly available informational materials related to condoms or STDs.Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to deem a condom to be misbranded unless its label bears information providing that condoms do not effectively prevent the transmission of HPV and that HPV can cause cervical cancer.</summary>
</bill>
