<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="1060" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:54-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="3230" sequence="7"/>
  <status datetime="1996-05-15">offered</status>
  <sponsor id="400610"/>
  <offered datetime="1996-05-15"/>
  <description>Amendments en bloc consist of the text of amendments numbered 13, 17 (as modified), 19 (as modified), 20 (as modified), 28, 31 (as modified), 32, 34, and 35 (as modified) printed on pages H5086-H5092 in the Congressional Record for May 15, 1996.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment comprised of nine amendments offered en bloc to change the date in the bill so that all 7 Uniformed Service Treatments Facilities will change to a new program at the same time; require a DOD study of the impact of mergers on eliminating excess capacity and reducing defense dependency by defense contractors to be reported to Congress in six months; authorize the transfer of naval vessels to certain foreign countries pursuant to the Administration's request earlier this year; state that any country which engages in unfair trade practices with the U.S. will be denied its blanket waiver of the Buy American Act; to express the sense of Congress that it is in the security interests of the U.S. to provide assistance to countries to improve security of fissile materials; continue Congressional support for continuation of the South West Border States Anti-Drug Information System; to direct the Secretary of the Army to submit a plan for the reutilization or disposal of the Mississippi Army Ammunition Plant to Congress not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the bill; to allow DOE to fund an already existing program to assist the Russian government in shutting down plutonium producing nuclear reactors out of unspent funds from prior years; and to designate $5 million to the Energy Department's Office of Environment, Sa.ety and Health to conduct annual inspections of compliance with nuclear safety requirements, to issue additional safety regulations, and to conduct investigations of potential safety violations involving occupational radiation hazards.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-05-15T14:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendments (A007) offered by Mr. Spence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-15T14:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Spence amendment (A007) modified by unanimous consent. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 430, the Spence amendments en bloc were allowed to be offered in a modified form.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-15T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the Spence amendments (A007) as modified Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
