<bill session="106" type="h" number="2535" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Postal Service Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To preserve, protect, and promote the viability of the United States Postal Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400425"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="1999-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO11" subcommittee="Postal Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Postal Rate Commission"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="United States Postal Service"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Ratemaking Flexibilities Title II: National Commission on Postal Efficiency and Enhancement Title III: Enhanced Authorities for the Postal Rate Commission Postal Service Enhancement Act - Title I: Ratemaking Flexibilities - Amends Federal postal service law to make procedures for determining postal rates and service fees inapplicable in the case of competitive products (products which are determined to have adequate competition in the open market). Prohibits the rate or fee for a noncompetitive product from subsidizing the rate or fee for a competitive product. Provides authority for incremental rate increases for noncompetitive products.(Sec. 104) Outlines conditions under which the Postal Service (Service) may enter into negotiated service agreements with mail users, including that: (1) the agreement will result in net benefits to the nationwide postal system; and (2) rates and fees payable under the agreement are calculated to yield revenues to the Service that are at least equal to revenues generated by rates chargeable for other mail services. Allows any such agreement that involves one or more noncompetitive products to be effective only after the Postal Rate Commission (Commission) first certifies that such agreement meets requirements applicable to all mail service agreements.(Sec. 105) Outlines conditions under which the Service may offer competitive products. Provides conditions under which a party who believes that the Service is offering a competitive product which does not conform to such conditions may lodge a complaint with the Commission.Title II: National Commission on Postal Efficiency and Enhancement - Establishes the National Commission on Postal Efficiency and Enhancement to review and report on the present practices and organizational structure of the Service, with a view toward identifying waste or inefficiency and improving the collection, processing, and delivery of mail.Title III: Enhanced Authorities for the Postal Rate Commission - Authorizes any Commission commissioner, any administrative law judge appointed by the Commission, and any Commission employee to administer oaths, examine witnesses, take depositions, and receive evidence. Authorizes the Commission Chairman, any designated commissioner, or any Commission-appointed administrative law judge to issue subpoenas and order the taking of depositions or responses to written interrogatories.</summary>
</bill>
