<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="1475" updated="2013-07-17T08:17:29-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="6169" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2012-08-02T15:46:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to lay out Democratic principles for tax reforms that call for increased revenues to bring down the national debt and invest in economic growth; a progressive tax rate structure; protecting the vulnerable; repeal of the AMT; discouraging tax haven abuse; elimination of tax breaks that ship jobs and profits overseas; promotion of domestic manufacturing; and preserving incentives for education, retirement, healthcare, home ownership, and small businesses.</description>
  <purpose>Printed in Part A of House Report 112-641 to lay out Democratic principles for tax reform that call for increased revenues to bring down our national debt and invest in economic growth; a progressive tax rate structure; protecting the vulnerable; repeal of the AMT; discouraging tax haven abuse; elimination of tax breaks that ship jobs and profits overseas; promotion of domestic manufacturing; and preserving incentives for education, retirement, healthcare, home ownership, and small business.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) in the nature of a substitute offered by Ms. Slaughter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5676-5680" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5676-5677" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A001) pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5678" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2012-08-02T15:46:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="550">
      <text>On agreeing to the Slaughter amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 176 - 246 (Roll no. 550).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5678" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
