<bill session="106" type="h" number="3686" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Clean Air Act and titles 23 and 49, United States Code, to provide for continued authorization of funding of transportation projects after a lapse in transportation conformity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400240"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2000-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2000-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2000-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2000-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2000-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Ground Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW10" subcommittee="Ground Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Highway planning"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2000--Introduced.
Amends the Clean Air Act to provide that a transportation project identified for funding in a transportation plan and transportation improvement program adopted under specified Federal-aid highway or mass transportation provisions shall remain eligible for funding after such plan or program no longer conforms with a State implementation plan (SIP) for national air quality standards as required by the Act if: (1) the plan and program met conformity requirements at the time at which a project agreement for the project was approved under such provisions; (2) the project is a transportation control measure; (3) the project qualifies for an exemption from the requirement that it come from a conforming metropolitan long-range transportation plan and improvement program under Federal regulations in effect on March 1, 1999; or (4) the project is exempt from a prohibition on approval of projects or grants under provisions requiring sanctions for failures to meet certain SIP requirements, excepting certain projects for highway ramp metering and traffic signalization.Amends Federal-aid highway and mass transportation provisions to authorize the amendment of long-range transportation plans or improvement programs that no longer conform to SIPs without a demonstration of conformity if the amendment is solely for the purpose of adding a transportation project: (1) for which the State submits to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency a request for approval as a transportation control measure; or (2) that qualifies for an exemption from the requirement that a project come from a conforming metropolitan long-range transportation plan and improvement program under Federal regulations in effect on March 1, 1999.</summary>
</bill>
