<bill session="105" type="h" number="3733" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Applied Engineering and Technology Center Investment Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the National Science Foundation to make grants for applied engineering and technology education equipment and capital improvements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400353"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1998-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1998-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="1998-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="410136" joined="1998-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="1998-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Basic Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Basic Research" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="College libraries"/>
    <term name="Community and college"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary school students"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial planning"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Microforms"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientific instruments and apparatus"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Textbooks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/1998--Introduced.
Applied Engineering and Technology Center Investment Act of 1998 - Authorizes the Director of the National Science Foundation to make grants to organizations that provide postsecondary education in applied engineering and technology for equipment and capital improvements needed to ensure that such education is provided using state-of-the-art instructional equipment and facilities. Permits amounts made available through such grants to be used in support of applied engineering and technology programs for specified purposes, including: (1) the purchase, rental, or lease of scientific laboratory equipment, including computer hardware and software, for educational purposes, including instructional and research purposes; (2) construction, maintenance, and renovation in classroom, library, laboratory, and other instructional facilities; (3) acquisition of library books, periodicals, microfilm, databases, software, and other educational materials; (4) funds and administrative management, and acquisition of equipment for use in strengthening funds management; (5) joint use of facilities, such as laboratories and libraries; and (6) establishing community outreach programs which will encourage elementary and secondary students to develop the academic skills and the interest to pursue postsecondary applied engineering and technology education. Prohibits an organization from receiving any grant unless that organization submits an application to the Director at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information as the Director may require. States that each grant application shall: (1) provide that the payments will be used for the purposes set forth under this Act; and (2) provide for making an annual report to the Director and for conducting (subject to a stated exception), at least once every two years, a financial and compliance audit of the organization regarding any funds obtained by it under this Act which covers the period since the most recent audit. Requires the Director to: (1) approve any application which meets the above requirements; and (2) not disapprove any application submitted under this Act, or any modification thereof, without first affording the applicant reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing. Requires any grant application to describe measurable goals for the organization's financial management and applied engineering and technology academic programs and include a plan of how the applicant intends to achieve those goals.</summary>
</bill>
