<bill session="104" type="h" number="3270" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disaster Prevention and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize and direct the Secretary of the Army to expeditiously construct a project for flood control on the Sacramento and American Rivers, California, and to authorize and direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the Army to enter into agreements that allow the State of California or other non-Federal sponsors to construct, without cost to the United States, a multipurpose dam and related facilities at Auburn on the American River.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1996-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="1996-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1996-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1996-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1996-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1996-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1996-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="1996-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="1996-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1996-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-23">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, Army.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Highway relocation"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Multipurpose projects"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Transfer of Auburn Dam and Reservoir Project Title II: Sacramento and American Rivers Flood Control Project Title III: Auburn Dam Water Conservation Project Disaster Prevention and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1996 - Title I: Transfer of Auburn Dam and Reservoir Project - Transfers from the Secretary of the Interior to the Secretary of the Army (Secretary) jurisdiction over the Auburn Dam and Reservoir Project. Provides a Project description and specifies the applicability of Federal reclamation and water resource project laws. Reduces by 50 percent the amount authorized to be appropriated for the Project. Title II: Sacramento and American Rivers Flood Control Project - Directs the Secretary to construct expeditiously the project for flood control and recreation on the Sacramento and American Rivers, California, substantially in accordance with a prior report of the Army Chief of Engineers and at a specified total estimated cost. Requires such Project to include the construction of a pumping plant, access roads, and appurtenant facilities with which to fulfill U.S. obligations to the Placer County Water Agency. Authorizes appropriations. Provides for possible future expansion and increased power generation at such plant. Directs the Secretary to cooperate with California to establish an independent consulting board to review plans for, and provide technical confirmation of, such Project. Authorizes appropriations. Provides for Project: (1) cost-sharing responsibilities; (2) feasibility and environmental studies; (3) soil and fish and wildlife mitigation measures; and (4) authority for certain levee and other flood control improvements. Requires the Secretaries to complete a comprehensive risk assessment of Folsom Dam and its ancillary facilities and to take appropriate actions with respect to its performance when operated in conjunction with the project authorized under this title. Authorizes the Secretary to undertake additional actions to extend flood protection in specified areas along the Sacramento and American Rivers. (Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary to construct specified features of the North Area Local Project of the American River Watershed Investigation, subject to entering into appropriate local cost-sharing agreements with non-Federal sponsors. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary to carry out a flood control project in Cirby, Linda, and Dry Creeks in Placer and Sacramento Counties, California. Title III: Auburn Dam Water Conservation Project - Authorizes the Secretaries to enter into agreements with California for the transfer to the United States of specified rights-of-way, water rights, and facilities constituting and adjacent to the Auburn Dam portion of the Central Valley Project and the project authorized under title II of this Act. Recognizes the existence of substantial national interest in the earliest development of a multipurpose Auburn Dam to provide flood protection, water conservation, recreation, and instream requirements for American River flows and other beneficial uses.</summary>
</bill>
