<bill session="106" type="h" number="5014" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Trails System Act to update the feasibility and suitability studies of 4 national historic trails and provide for possible additions to such trails.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-11">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Mormons"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="West (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2000--Introduced.
Amends the National Trails System Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to undertake a study to determine the feasibility of designating: (1) certain routes and cutoffs for inclusion within the Oregon National Historic Trail; (2) the southern alternative route from Wathena to Troy, Kansas, for inclusion within the Pony Express National Historic Trail; (3) certain Missouri Valley central and western routes and cutoffs for inclusion within the California National Historic Trail; (4) certain routes and cutoffs for inclusion within the Mormon Pioneer National Historic Trail; and (5) certain routes and cutoffs as shared components of the California and Oregon National Historic Trails. Requires the Secretary, as appropriate, to so designate such routes and cutoffs, to publish notice of such designation, and to submit study results to specified congressional committees.</summary>
</bill>
