<bill session="106" type="h" number="3859" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-20T16:36:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-06-20T16:36:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security and Medicare Safe Deposit Box Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Social Security and Medicare Lock-box Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to protect Social Security and Medicare surpluses through strengthened budgetary enforcement mechanisms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="2000-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2000-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2000-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="2000-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="2000-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="2000-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2000-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2000-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2000-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="2000-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="2000-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2000-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-20T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Herger moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-20T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4708-4714" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-20T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3859.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-20T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-20T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4723-4724" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-06-20T16:36:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="297" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 420 - 2 (Roll no. 297).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4708-4709" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-06-20T16:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read the first time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-06-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="627">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 627.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="1259"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1962"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2000--Passed House amended.
Social Security and Medicare Lock-box Act of 2000 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to provide a point of order in the House of Representatives or the Senate against consideration of any concurrent budget resolution or conference report or amendment pertaining thereto that would set forth: (1) an on-budget deficit for any fiscal year; or (2) an on-budget surplus for any fiscal year that is less than the projected surplus of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for such year.Makes it out of order in the House or the Senate to consider any bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report if the enactment of the reported bill or resolution, the adoption and enactment of an amendment, or the enactment of a bill or resolution in the form recommended in the conference report would: (1) cause or increase an on-budget deficit for any fiscal year; or (2) cause the on-budget surplus for any fiscal year to be less than the projected surplus of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for such year or increase the amount by which the on-budget surplus for any fiscal year would be less than such trust fund surplus for that year. Makes the point of order under (1) above inapplicable to social security reform legislation and that under (2) above inapplicable to Medicare reform legislation. Includes the receipts, outlays, and surplus or deficit in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors and Disability Insurance Trust Funds within the content of the concurrent budget resolution.Authorizes a waiver or suspension in the Senate of points of order under this Act only with a three-fifths majority. Requires the same majority to sustain an appeal on a ruling on such points of order.(Sec. 5) Requires any official Federal Government statement of the Federal or congressional budget surplus or deficit totals to exclude the outlays and receipts of the Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance Program under the Social Security Act. Requires such outlays and receipts to be submitted in separate social security budget documents.(Sec. 6) Prohibits the Federal Government budget submitted by the President from recommending: (1) an on-budget deficit for any covered fiscal year unless it includes proposed legislative language for social security reform legislation; or (2) an on-budget surplus for any fiscal year that is less than the projected surplus of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for that fiscal year unless it includes proposed legislative language for Medicare reform legislation.(Sec. 7) Defines "social security reform legislation" and "Medicare reform legislation" as a bill or joint resolution to save social security or Medicare, respectively, that specifies that it is reform legislation for purposes of this Act.(Sec. 8) Applies the amendments made by this Act to FY 2001 and subsequent fiscal years.Terminates the point of order relating to: (1) the on-budget deficit and budget resolution content amendments made by this Act upon enactment of social security reform legislation; and (2) the on-budget surplus and the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund upon enactment of Medicare reform legislation.</summary>
</bill>
