<bill session="106" type="hr" number="200" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-09T12:28:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-06-09T12:28:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1401) to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2000 and 2001 for military activities of the Department of Defense, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal years 2000 and 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T21:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-175, by Mrs. Myrick.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08T21:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1401 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Rule provides for an addtional one hour of general debate prior to the consideration of the last five amendments in part A of the rules Committee report on the U.S. policy relating to the conflict in Kosovo. Specified amendments are in order. Shall be in order to take from the Speaker's table S. 1059 and to consider it in the House. All points of order are waived. Shall be in order to trike all after the enacting clause of the Senate bill and insert in lieu thereof the provisions of H.R. 1401, as passed the House. Provides that H. Res. 195 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-06-08T21:55:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="67">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 67.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09T10:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3872-3883" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09T10:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 200.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09T12:06:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1999-06-09T12:28:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="179" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 354 - 75 (Roll no. 179).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09T12:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="hr" number="195"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="hr" number="195"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="1401"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/1999--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (modified closed) for the consideration of H.R. 1401 (defense authorization).</summary>
</bill>
