<bill session="107" type="h" number="5327" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey certain land in the Lake Tahoe Basin Management Unit, Nevada, to the Secretary of the Interior, in trust for the Washoe Indian Tribe of Nevada and California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="691"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/4/2002--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to convey certain land in the Lake Tahoe Basin Management Unit, Nevada, to the Secretary of the Interior, in trust for the Washoe Tribe of Nevada and California.Reserves for the United States a nonexclusive easement for public and administrative access to National Forest System land. Requires the Secretary to provide a reciprocal easement to the Tribe for vehicular access to such land to accommodate: (1) individuals with disabilities or who would otherwise have access difficulties; and (2) administrative or safety needs.Requires the Tribe to: (1) limit the use of the conveyed land to traditional and customary uses and stewardship conservation; (2) not permit any permanent or recreational development on, or commercial use of, such land (including commercial development, tourist accommodations, gaming, sale of timber, or mineral extraction); and (3) comply with environmental requirements that are no less protective than those that apply under the Regional Plan of the Tahoe Regional Planning Agency.</summary>
</bill>
