<bill session="106" type="h" number="3152" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Interest Declassification Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the identification, collection, and review for declassification of records and materials that are of extraordinary public interest to the people of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-27">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-27">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1801"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Presidential libraries"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/27/1999--Introduced.
Public Interest Declassification Act of 1999 - Establishes within the National Archives and Records Administration the Public Interest Declassification Board to: (1) direct and provide for the thorough, coordinated, comprehensive, and cost-effective identification, collection, review for declassification, and release to Congress, interested agencies, and the public of records and materials that are of extraordinary public interest; and (2) provide Congress, interested agencies, and the public with the fullest possible access to a documentary record of significant U.S. national security decisions and activities in order to support congressional oversight and legislative functions and executive policymaking, respond to public interest in national security matters, and promote reliable historical analysis and new avenues of historical study in national security matters.(Sec. 4) Authorizes the Board to recommend to the Archivist of the United States that an agency or Federal Presidential library (library) be directed to carry out records and materials identification, collection, and declassification review activities. Requires such agency or library to release records and materials that are unclassified or declassified as a result of such review.(Sec. 5) States that nothing in this Act shall limit the head of an agency to classify information or to continue the classification of information previously classified, or to grant or deny access to a special access program.(Sec. 6) Requires each agency and library that possesses or controls classified records or materials to develop standards and procedures for Board access thereto, as well as appropriate access by Board employees or employees of such agency or library. Provides access limits. Requires an annual activities report from the Board to the congressional intelligence committees.(Sec. 7) States that this Act does not create any right or benefit subject to judicial review.(Sec. 8) Directs the President to include in each annual budget submission a request for amounts for Board activities, including amounts to be transferred to agencies and libraries for activities under this Act. Requires such agency or library to provide the Board an estimate of such costs. Directs the Archivist to transfer to an agency or library the amount recommended by the Board. Authorizes the Board to recommend to the Archivist that additional amounts be transferred to such agency or library to ensure compliance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
