<bill session="106" type="h" number="1551" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-15T13:54:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-09-15T13:54:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Civil Aviation Research and Development Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Civil Aviation Research and Development Authorization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Civil Aviation Research and Development Authorization Act of 1991</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Federal Aviation Administration's civil aviation research and development programs for fiscal years 2000 and 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1999-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-07-12T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 106-223.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-07-12T15:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="129">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 129.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-09-14T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 290 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1551 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 290 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 290.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8320-8324" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1551 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John E. Sununu to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 290 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T13:30:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1551.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1551.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-09-15T13:54:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="290"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Aircraft construction"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Landing aids (Aeronautics)"/>
    <term name="Lasers"/>
    <term name="Navigation (Aeronautics)"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids (Aeronautics)"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development contracts"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h463"/>
    <amendment number="h464"/>
    <amendment number="h465"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/15/1999--Passed House amended.
Civil Aviation Research and Development Authorization Act of 1999 - Amends Federal transportation law to authorize FY 2000 and 2001 appropriations for certain Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) research and development (R&amp;D) programs. Requires the Department of Transportation's (DOT) annual budget request for the FAA to identify all of the activities carried out by it within the categories of basic research, applied research, and development, as classified by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Circular A-11. (Sec. 4) Requires the FAA's national aviation research plan to include, among other things, a highlight of the R&amp;D technology transfer activities that promote technology sharing among government, industry, and academia through the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980. (Sec. 5) Directs the Administrators of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the FAA to submit jointly to Congress an integrated civil aviation safety R&amp;D plan. (Sec. 6) Directs the Administrator of the FAA to make available through the FAA Internet home page abstracts relating to all research grants and awards made with funds authorized by this Act, except any material whose release is prohibited by law or regulation. (Sec. 7) Requires the Administrator of the FAA to conduct research to develop technologies and analyze information to predict the effects of aircraft design, maintenance, testing, wear, and fatigue on nonstructural aircraft systems. (Sec. 8) Directs the Administrator of the FAA to exclude from consideration for a FAA grant any person (except certain members of a recipient class) who received grant funds from a Federal funding source for a project that was not subjected to a competitive, merit-based award process. (Sec. 9) Prohibits an entity from spending funds appropriated under this Act unless it agrees to comply with the Buy American Act. Declares that it is the sense of Congress that entities receiving financial assistance under this Act should spend the assistance to purchase only American-made equipment or products. Requires the Administrator of the FAA to provide each recipient of such assistance notice of such Buy American requirements. (Sec. 11) Prohibits the use of funds for contracts with persons falsely labeling products as made in America. (Sec. 12) Encourages the FAA to conduct research on the laser visual guidance landing system.</summary>
</bill>
