<bill session="106" type="h" number="1506" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the orderly disposal of certain Federal land in the State of Nevada and for the acquisition of environmentally sensitive land in the State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-03">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health services administration"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Paleontology"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/1999--Introduced.
Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1999 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to dispose of public land in the State of Nevada under specified current land use plans other than land identified under the Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1998. Authorizes the State or local governments in the jurisdiction of which the land is located to obtain the land for local public purposes prior to the offering of such land for sale or exchange. Requires the Secretary to retain such land for conveyance to the State or a local government if such entities elect to obtain the land. Withdraws Federal land selected for disposal, subject to valid existing rights, from location and entry under the mining laws and from operation under the mineral and geothermal leasing laws until the Secretary terminates the withdrawal or the land is patented. Requires the Secretary, the local government that has jurisdiction over land identified for disposal, and the State to select land to be offered for sale or exchange. Sets forth requirements for sales, including those for competitive bidding. Bars the sale of a tract of land if the Federal costs of sale preparation and processing are estimated to exceed sale proceeds. Allocates the gross proceeds of land sales during a fiscal year as follows: (1) five percent to the State for the general education program; (2) 45 percent to the local government for use as determined by such government; and (3) 50 percent to the Special Account established by this Act. Sets forth requirements for land exchanges. Authorizes the Secretary, subject to certain consultation requirements, to use funds to acquire environmentally sensitive land and interests in such land. Permits such acquisitions only from willing sellers and with the consent of the State and local governments with jurisdiction. Defines "environmentally sensitive land" as land that would: (1) promote the preservation of specified values that contribute to public enjoyment or biological diversity; (2) enhance recreational opportunities or public access; (3) provide the opportunity to achieve better management of public land through consolidation of Federal ownership; or (4) otherwise serve the public interest. Includes such lands in the definition of "entitlement land" for purposes of Federal provisions governing payment for entitlement land. Establishes a Special Account in the Treasury to carry out this Act. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
