<bill session="108" type="h" number="1253" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense Preble's Conservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to establish special requirements for determining whether the Preble's meadow jumping mouse is an endangered species or threatened species.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400394"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2003--Introduced.
Common Sense Preble's Conservation Act - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to provide that, in any case in which the Secretary of the Interior is required to use the best scientific and commercial data available with respect to determining whether the Preble's meadow jumping mouse is an endangered or threatened species, the Secretary: (1) in evaluating comparable data, shall give greater weight to scientific or commercial data that are empirical or have been field-tested or peer-reviewed; and (2) shall include data regarding population numbers of the species.Prohibits the Secretary from determining that the Preble's meadow jumping mouse is an endangered or threatened species unless the determination is supported by data obtained by observation of the species in the field.Directs the Secretary to: (1) accept and acknowledge receipt of data regarding the status of that species that is collected by an owner of land through observation of the species on the land, and include the data in the rule-making record compiled for any determination that the species is an endangered or threatened species; (2) solicit recommendations from the National Academy of Sciences and develop and maintain a list of qualified reviewers to participate in independent scientific review of actions; and (3) appoint randomly from among the list, before any action becomes final, three qualified individuals who shall review and report to the Secretary on the scientific information and analyses on which the proposed action is based.</summary>
</bill>
