<bill session="107" type="h" number="2604" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-01T13:49:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-05-01T13:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the United States to participate in and contribute to the seventh replenishment of the resources of the Asian Development Fund and the fifth replenishment of the resources of the International Fund for Agricultural Development, and to set forth additional policies of the United States towards the African Development Bank, the African Development Fund, the Asian Development Bank, the Inter-American Development Bank, and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2001-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2001-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="2001-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2001-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="2001-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2001-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2001-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Monetary Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-10-31">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-11-15T17:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 107-291.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-11-15T17:51:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="177">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 177.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-05-01T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Oxley moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-01T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1986-1990" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-01T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2604.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-05-01T13:49:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1986-1987" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-05-01T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSBA17" subcommittee="International Monetary Policy and Trade" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Arsenic"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bank directors"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Congressional witnesses"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Decision making in public administration"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Industrial productivity"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Malaria"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2001--Reported to House amended.
Amends the Asian Development Bank Act to authorize appropriations for: (1) the U.S. contribution to the seventh replenishment of the Asian Development Fund; and (2) the U.S. contribution to the fifth replenishment of the International Fund for Agricultural Development.(Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to report to specified congressional committees on the participation of the International Fund for Agricultural Development in the Enhanced Heavily Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) Initiative.(Sec. 3) Amends the International Financial Institutions Act to direct the Secretary to instruct the U.S. Executive Directors at certain international financial institutions, and the U.S. Governor of the International Fund for Agricultural Development, to: (1) support continued efforts by such institutions in the fight against HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria, and other infectious diseases; and (2) oppose any loan, grant, document, or strategy that is subject to endorsement or approval by the board of directors of such institutions, which includes user fees in impoverished countries, for primary education or primary healthcare, including prevention and treatment efforts for HIV/AIDS, malaria, tuberculosis, and infant, child, and maternal well-being.(Sec. 5) Sets forth provisions promoting greater transparency with regard to such institutions' activities. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to such institutions that have implemented transparency measures and have provided assurances that they will use such grants solely for such measures. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Secretary to report annually to specified congressional committees detailing steps taken by the U.S. Executive Directors at the institutions, by the finance ministers, and by such institutions to implement transparency measures with respect to their activities.(Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to instruct the U.S. Executive Directors at such institutions, and the U.S. Governor of the International Fund for Agricultural Development, to focus on poverty alleviation, economic growth, increased productivity, sustainable development, environmental protection, labor rights, and an increased focus on education.(Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to instruct the U.S. Executive Directors at such institutions, and the U.S. Governor of the International Fund for Agricultural Development, to oppose any loan which provides support for any project that includes a dam unless such project conforms to specified conditions, including that comprehensive assessments of the energy, water, and flood management needs to be met and different options for meeting them are developed before detailed studies are done and before building any new projects.(Sec. 8) Directs the Comptroller General of the United States to report to specified congressional committees on the benefits and costs of such institutions providing grants instead of loans.(Sec. 9) Commends Omar Kabbaj (an official of the Ministry of Finance of Morocco) for his successful reform efforts as President of the African Development Bank and Fund.(Sec. 10) Authorizes the Secretary to instruct the U.S. Executive Director at, or the U.S. Governor of, the regional multilateral development bank, when considering whether to approve a foreign country's application for assistance, to take into consideration whether it has taken or has committed to take actions that either contribute or do not contribute to efforts of the United States to respond to, deter, or prevent acts of international terrorism.(Sec. 11) Directs the Secretary to instruct the U.S. Executive Directors at such institutions, and the U.S. Governor of the International Fund for Agricultural Development, to use the U.S. vote to oppose the provision of assistance for a project that involves privatization of a government-held industry or sector if: (1) the privatization transaction is not implemented in a transparent manner; (2) the privatization is not implemented in a manner that adequately protects the interests of workers, small investors, and vulnerable groups; and (3) appropriate regulatory regimes have not been established to ensure the proper function of competitive markets in the industry or sector.(Sec. 12) Directs the Secretary to instruct the U.S. Executive Directors at such institutions, and the U.S. Governor of the International Fund for Agricultural Development, to oppose any loan, grant, document, or strategy that is subject to endorsement or approval by the board of directors of such institutions, if it includes any provision that would recommend the reduction of a country's minimum wage to a level of less than $2.00 per day.(Sec. 13) Directs the Secretary to instruct the U.S. Executive Director at the Asian Development Fund to use the U.S. vote to support projects directed at addressing arsenic contamination in drinking water in South Asia.</summary>
</bill>
