<bill session="106" type="h" number="5369" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening Abuse and Neglect Courts Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the administrative efficiency and effectiveness of the Nation's abuse and neglect courts and for other purposes consistent with the Adoption and Safe Families Act of 1997.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400327"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2000-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2000-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="708"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2271"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2272"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Court congestion and delay"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family courts"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Group homes for children"/>
    <term name="Guardian and ward"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Judicial statistics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Magistrates"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social workers"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in government"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in social service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2000--Introduced.
Strengthening Abuse and Neglect Courts Act of 2000 - Directs the Attorney General to award grants to State and local courts to: (1) enable such courts to develop and implement automated data collection and case-tracking systems for proceedings conducted by, or under the supervision of, an abuse and neglect court; (2) encourage the replication of such systems in abuse and neglect courts in other jurisdictions; and (3) require the use of such systems to evaluate a court's performance in complying with requirements of part B (child and family services) and part E (Federal payments for foster care and adoption assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act.Sets forth provisions regarding limits on the number and use of grants, application and matching requirements, notification to the State or appropriate child welfare agency, considerations in evaluating grant applications, diversity and length of awards, fund availability, and reporting requirements for grantees and the Attorney General. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 5) Directs the Attorney General to award grants to State and local courts for the purposes of: (1) promoting the permanency goals established in the Adoption and Safe Families Act of 1997; and (2) enabling such courts to reduce existing backlogs of cases pending in abuse and neglect courts, especially regarding cases to terminate parental rights and cases in which parental rights to a child have been terminated but an adoption of the child has not yet been finalized.Sets forth provisions regarding applications, use of funds, number of grants, availability of funds, and reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 6) Directs the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention of the Department of Justice to make a grant to the National Court-Appointed Special Advocate Association for purposes of: (1) expanding the recruitment, and building the capacity, of court-appointed special advocate programs located in the 15 largest urban areas; (2) developing regional, multi- jurisdictional court-appointed special advocate programs serving rural areas; and (3) providing training and supervision of volunteers in court-appointed special advocate programs.Sets forth provisions regarding limits on administrative expenditures and determination of urban and rural areas. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
