<bill session="104" type="h" number="4263" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Unemployment Compensation Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reinstate the emergency unemployment compensation program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400286"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Introduced.
Emergency Unemployment Compensation Amendments of 1996 - Reinstates the emergency unemployment compensation (EUC) program. Amends the Emergency Unemployment Compensation Act of 1991 to: (1) repeal the February 5, 1994, termination of the emergency unemployment compensation (EUC) program; and (2) extend the authorization for new claims for benefits under the program until six months after the enactment of this Act. Modifies the final phase-out period for continuation of claims. Provides for a similar extension of the program of temporary extended railroad unemployment insurance benefits (and modification of the phase-out period). Authorizes appropriations and the use of advance account funds to carry out the extension of the EUC program. Designates all direct spending amounts provided and all appropriations authorized by this Act as emergency requirements for purposes of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act).</summary>
</bill>
