<bill session="106" type="h" number="4227" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Technology Worker Temporary Relief Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Technology Worker Temporary Relief Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to the number of aliens granted nonimmigrant status described in section 101(a)(15)(H)(i)(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, to implement measures to prevent fraud and abuse in the granting of such status, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="2000-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2000-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-12">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-05-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 18 - 11.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-23T14:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 106-692.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-06-23T14:39:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="388">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 388.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Black employment"/>
    <term name="Clothing workers"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Physical therapy"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2000--Reported to House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Numerical Limitations on H-1B Nonimmigrants; Increased Portability of H-1B Status Title II: New Requirements on Petitioning Employers; Petition Filing Fee Reduction for Local Educational Agencies Title III: Noncompliance Provisions for H-1B 2Nonimmigrants Title IV: Extension of Provisions from the American Competitiveness and Workforce Improvement Act of 1998 Title V: Studies and Reports Technology Worker Temporary Relief Act - Title I: Numerical Limitations on H-1B Nonimmigrants; Increased Portability of H-1B Status - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (Act) to eliminate the FY 2000 numerical limitation on H-1B (specialty occupation) nonimmigrant visas. Provides for employer-specific, wage- conditioned FY 2001 and 2002 H-1B visa increases.(Sec. 102) Permits: (1) an H-1B alien, under specified circumstances, to accept new employment upon a prospective employer's filing of a new petition; and (2) employment during such petition's adjudication period.Title II: New Requirements on Petitioning Employers; Petition Filing Fee Reduction for Local Educational Agencies - Amends the Act to establish $40,000 H-1B minimum salary requirements, with exceptions for elementary or secondary teachers, an institution of higher education or related nonprofit entity, or a nonprofit or governmental research organization.(Sec. 202) Requires an H-1B employer to electronically submit specified information (nationality, academic degrees, wages) respecting such employees to the Secretary of Labor, who shall subsequently make such information available on the Internet.(Sec. 203) Establishes a $200 employer processing fee for an H-1B initial employment or employment change petition. Establishes an H-1B Processing Fee Account in the Treasury.(Sec. 204) Requires an H-1B alien seeking admission as a physical therapist to have completed a degree recognized by a Secretary of Labor-approved body as equivalent to a U.S. master's degree in physical therapy.(Sec. 205) Reduces to $100 the employer filing fee for local educational agencies.Title III: Noncompliance Provisions for H-1B Nonimmigrants - Amends the Act to require specialty occupation workers and fashion models admitted under other than H-1B status to obtain such status.(Sec. 302) Requires H-1B workers to work at least 35 hours per week, with exceptions for employers which are institutions of higher education or related nonprofit entities.(Sec. 303) Revises certain academic degree-related provisions. Eliminates the provision permitting substitution of work experience for the degree requirement.(Sec. 304) Directs the Attorney General to impose a $100 H-1B employer anti-fraud fee. Establishes an H-1B Noncompliance Account in the Treasury. Obligates specified fee amounts for anti-fraud and alien removal activities by the Attorney General and the Secretary of State.(Sec. 305) Requires a petitioning H-1B employer to: (1) be an institution of higher education, or a governmental or nonprofit entity; (2) be U.S. based and State or locally licensed whose place of business is used exclusively for business purposes; (3) have gross assets of at least $250, 000; or (4) provide specified business activity documentation.(Sec. 306) Requires an H-1B employer to file W-2 forms.Title IV: Extension of Provisions from the American Competitiveness and Workforce Improvement Act of 1998 - Amends the Act to extend the requirement that an H-1B dependent employer not displace U.S. workers to include labor applications filed by October 1, 2002.(Sec. 402) Amends the American Competitiveness and Workforce Improvement Act of 1998 to extend certain additional labor application investigative authority of the Secretary of Labor through September 30, 2002.(Sec. 403) Directs the Secretary of Labor to promulgate final regulations implementing all provisions of such Act, such regulations to take effect by September 30, 2000.Title V: Studies and Reports - Directs the Comptroller General to conduct H-1B program studies respecting: (1) employer measures to recruit qualified U.S. under represented workers (African American, Hispanic, women, disabled individuals) and recommend program modifications as necessary; (2) employee training and skills updating; and (3) the Attorney General's compliance with requirements respecting the number of such alien admissions.</summary>
</bill>
