<bill session="108" type="h" number="4038" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Intelligence Education and Training Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide training opportunities for Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies in intelligence analysis and dissemination, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2004-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="White collar crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2004--Introduced.
National Intelligence Education and Training Act - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) maintain an Academy for Law Enforcement Intelligence for training Federal, State, and local law enforcement officers and analysts in the analysis, dissemination, and management of intelligence; and (2) establish the Advisory Board on Law Enforcement Intelligence to advise the Attorney General regarding the Academy's operation, instruction and content of curriculum, appointment of staff and hiring of contract instructors, and efforts to promote the intelligence profession among undergraduate and graduate students. Directs the Attorney General to carry out a pilot program, known as the Law Enforcement Analyst Training Assistance Program, to assess providing for the preparation of selected students for employment as intelligence analysts for U.S. law enforcement agencies. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to direct that not less than 25 percent of COPS program grant funds be made available for activities to: (1) increase the number of State and local law enforcement officers or employees involved in developing intelligence for countering terrorism, crime, or both; (2) provide specialized training to not more than five intelligence officers per grant recipient to enhance observational, intelligence-gathering, foreign language, and analytical skills; (3) improve Federal-State-local law enforcement coordination; and (4) ensure that not less than one intelligence officer per grant recipient has at least a "top secret" level security clearance.</summary>
</bill>
