<bill session="107" type="h" number="5639" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Texas Band of Kickapoo Act Amendments</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the rights of United States citizenship and eligibility for Federal benefits for all enrolled members of the Kickapoo Tribe of Oklahoma and the Kickapoo Traditional Tribe of Texas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400540"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-10">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Loyalty oaths"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/2002--Introduced.
Texas Band of Kickapoo Act Amendments - Amends the Texas Band of Kickapoo Act to require the Kickapoo Tribe of Oklahoma and the Kickapoo Traditional Tribe of Texas (Tribes) to each update the membership roll of its members. Requires the Tribes to compile a list of their tribal members who permanently reside, but were not born in, the United States and are not otherwise citizens or nationals of the United States.Amends the Immigration and Naturalization Act to declare that a person who is of Kickapoo descent, a member of either of the Tribes, was born outside of, but permanently resides in the United States, and is not otherwise a citizen or national of the United States, may apply to the Attorney General for a United States certificate of citizenship. Authorizes the Attorney General to issue a certificate of citizenship to such individuals.Amends the Texas Band of Kickapoo Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to allow the Kickapoo Tribe of Oklahoma to relinquish its claim to beneficial title to the Kickapoo Reservation in Maverick County, Texas. Requires the Secretary, at the request of the Tribe, to accept such land as replacement land and take that land into trust for the benefit of the Kickapoo Tribe if there are no adverse legal claims on the land.Extends the eligibility of individuals for Federal Indian programs and services from the Texas Band of Kickapoo Indians to both Kickapoo Tribes.</summary>
</bill>
