<bill session="104" type="h" number="1306" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Samoa Economic Development Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To approve a multiyear program for the economic development and self-sufficiency of the United States territory of American Samoa.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="1995-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E685"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Native American and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-05">
      <text>See H.R.1332.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII14" subcommittee="Native American and Insular Affairs" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1332"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/1995--Introduced.
American Samoa Economic Development Act of 1995 - Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of the Interior for the Government of American Samoa for FY 1996 through 2005 to be used for: (1) construction, maintenance, and repair of American Samoa's capital assets; (2) operations of the Government of American Samoa; and (3) reduction of unbudgeted debt incurred by the Government of American Samoa in fiscal years prior to 1996. Requires amounts appropriated to be placed in a trust administered by a nongovernmental entity. Prohibits the release of funds for the construction of capital assets for FY 1997 and following years until: (1) the Government of American Samoa submits to the trustee a master plan of capital needs that ranks projects in order of priority for at least five years; and (2) such Government submits to the trustee a maintenance plan covering the anticipated life of the project and the project is initially funded. Approves the release of funds only for construction projects for specified public purposes. Prohibits the release of such funds, beginning in FY 1997, in the areas of communications, electrical power, public health, transportation, water, and wastewater until semiautonomous government agencies of the Government of American Samoa are established by local law. Requires funding provided to reduce the unbudgeted debt and for maintenance or repair of capital assets to be matched by non-Federal sources. Prohibits funds appropriated pursuant to this Act from being transferred to other accounts, loaned to other accounts or agencies, or used as collateral for loans made by the local government. Sets forth conditions on the release of trust funds to be used for construction of capital assets, debt reduction, and maintenance or repair. Requires the Government of American Samoa to obtain and submit an annual audit of its financial position to specified congressional committees. Withholds funds for government operations until a qualifying audit is received and reported. Authorizes the Comptroller General and the Inspector General to conduct audits of all funds of branches and semiautonomous authorities of the Government of American Samoa.</summary>
</bill>
