<bill session="104" type="hr" number="170" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-22T17:05:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-06-22T17:05:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1868) making appropriations for foreign operations, export financing, and related programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20T19:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-147, by Mr. Goss.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-20T19:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1868 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by title. Before consideration of any other amendment, it shall be in order to consider the amendments printed in part 1 of the report accompanying this resolution. Said amendments shall be considered shall be considered in the order and manner specified and debatable for 10 minutes each. After disposition of the amendments, the provisions of the bill as then perfected shall be considered as original text. Points of order against an amendment printed in part 2 of the report shall be waived. During further consideration of the bill, priority shall be given to amendments printed in the record.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-06-20T19:16:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="60">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 60.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22T15:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6233-6242" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22T15:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22T16:56:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 221 - 178 (Roll no. 418).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-06-22T17:05:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="419" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 217 - 175 (Roll no. 419).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-06-22T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="1868"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the open rule for the consideration of H.R. 1868 foreign operations appropriations).</summary>
</bill>
