<bill session="104" type="h" number="36" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pension Security Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and related provisions to improve pension plan funding, to limit growth in insurance exposure, to protect the single-employer plan termination insurance program by clarifying the status of claims of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation and the treatment of insolvent pension plans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Pension trust guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Amendments to Pension Plan Funding Requirements Title II: Amendments to Title IV of ERISA Title III: Employer Liability, Lien and Priority Pension Security Act of 1995 - Title I: Amendment to Pension Plan Fund - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to revise the additional funding requirements for pension plans that are not multiemployer plans to provide for an underfunding reduction requirement and a solvency maintenance requirement. Title II: Amendments to Title IV of ERISA - Amends title IV (Plan Termination Insurance) of ERISA to set forth limitations on the benefits guaranteed by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC). (Sec. 202) Revises provisions relating to: (1) enforcement of minimum funding requirements; (2) recovery ratio payable under PBGC guaranty; and (3) distress termination criteria for banking institutions. Eliminates a specified seventh revolving fund and transfers its assets and liabilities to the first revolving fund (i.e., the single-employer basic benefits guaranty fund). Title III: Employer Liability, Lien and Priority - Amends title IV of ERISA to revise limitations on employer liability liens and priority amounts. (Sec. 301) Provides that, in the case of plan terminations initiated on or after January 1, 1992, the lien of the PBGC for employer liability shall be determined according to a specified formula. Makes similar revisions relating to the amount of liability to the PBGC which is entitled to priority treatment in insolvency and bankruptcy cases. Provides that specified amendments under this Act shall be effective as if included under the Single-Employer Pension Plan Amendments of 1986 and the Pension Protection Act. Amends ERISA to provide for liability upon liquidation of a contributing sponsor of a single-employer plan. Makes such sponsor liable as though the plan had terminated in a distress termination, even if the sponsor's controlled group remains a contributing sponsor of the plan or is liable for payment of specified contributions or installments. Directs the PBGC to transfer such liability payments to the ongoing plans. (Sec. 302) Amends the Federal bankruptcy code to revise priority payment provisions with respect to: (1) unpaid contributions to pension plans under ERISA; and (2) certain liability arising from pension plan terminations under ERISA. (Classifies these priorities as expenses arising before, or administrative expenses arising after, the commencement of the case, depending on whether such unpaid contributions are attributable, or such plan termination occurs, before or after the filing of the petition for bankruptcy.) Amends the Bankruptcy Rules to require the bankruptcy court to give the PBGC notice of a bankruptcy petition filed (and all other notices required to be served on creditors and interested parties), in any case in which the debtor or an affiliate maintains a pension plan to which title IV of ERISA applies. (Sec. 303) Provides for determination of liability upon liquidation of contributing sponsor where the plan remains ongoing.</summary>
</bill>
