<bill session="105" type="h" number="3332" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Next Generation Internet Research Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Next Generation Internet Research Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Next Generation Internet Research Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the High-Performance Computing Act of 1991 to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 1999 and 2000 for the Next Generation Internet program, to require the Advisory Committee on High-Performance Computing and Communications, Information Technology, and the Next Generation Internet to monitor and give advice concerning the development and implementation of the Next Generation Internet program and report to the President and the Congress on its activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1998-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-05-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14T12:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14T12:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7643-7646" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14T12:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-09-14T12:39:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14T12:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14T12:39:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12051-12052" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1998-10-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-10-28">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-10-28" type="public" number="105-305">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-305.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="1609"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sparsely populated areas"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Supercomputers"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="World Wide Web"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/1998--Passed House amended.
Next Generation Internet Research Act of 1998 - Declares the purposes of this Act to be to: (1) authorize research programs related to high-end computing and computation, human-centered systems, high confidence systems, and education, training, and human resources; and (2) provide for the development and coordination of a comprehensive and integrated U.S. research program which will focus on a computer network infrastructure that promotes interoperability among advanced Federal computer networks, high-speed data access that is economical and that does not impose a geographic penalty, and flexible and extensible networking technology. Amends the High-Performance Computing Act of 1991 to include among its purposes: (1) promoting the more rapid development and wider distribution of networking management and development tools; and (2) promoting the rapid adoption of open network standards. Directs that the National High-Performance Computing Program provide for: (1) the development of technologies to advance Internet capacity and capabilities; and (2) high-performance testbed networks to enable the research, development, and demonstration of advanced networking technologies and to develop and demonstrate advanced applications. Authorizes the National Science Foundation, the Department of Energy, the National Institutes of Health, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology (the supporting agencies) to support the Next Generation Internet Program (Program). Includes among Program objectives: (1) increasing Internet capabilities and improving Internet performance; (2) developing an advanced testbed network connecting research sites; and (3) developing advanced Internet applications that meet national goals and agency mission needs. Directs the President's Information Technology Advisory Committee to assess the extent to which: (1) the Program carries out the purposes of this Act and addresses concerns relating to geographic penalties (costs imposed on Internet users in rural or other locations that are greater than those imposed on users in large population areas or areas closer to network facilities), technology transfer to and from the private sector, and the adequacy of Internet access by historically Black colleges and universities, Hispanic serving institutions, and small colleges and universities; (2) the roles of Federal departments and agencies involved in implementing the Program are clear, complementary, and non-duplicative; and (3) Federal support in fundamental research in computing is sufficient to maintain U.S. leadership in the field. Requires the Advisory Committee to assess Program implementation and report on its findings and recommendations at least annually to the President and specified congressional committees. Authorizes appropriations to the supporting agencies for FY 1999 and 2000 for the Program. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to request the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a comprehensive study of specified matters relating to the short and long term effects on trademark rights of adding new generic top-level domains and related dispute resolution procedures, including: (1) trademark rights clearance processes for domain names; (2) domain name trademark rights dispute resolution; (3) infringement liability for registrars or technical management bodies; and (4) technical and policy options for Internet addressing schemes. Requires: (1) an interim and final report from the Council to the Secretary; and (2) the submission of such reports to specified congressional committees. Authorizes appropriations for the study.</summary>
</bill>
