<bill session="106" type="h" number="1224" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">All-Payer Graduate Medical Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for comprehensive financing for graduate medical education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="1999-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="1999-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1999-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1999-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1999-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1999-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1999-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="1999-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1999-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1999-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1999-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1999-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-03-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E524-525"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Rural hospitals"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Self-insurance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching hospitals"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Health Care Workforce Trust Fund; Payments to Teaching Teaching Hospitals Subtitle A: Establishment and Financing of Fund Subtitle B: Additional Payments to Teaching Hospitals Subtitle C: Conforming Changes in Medicare Payment for Directs Costs of Graduate Medical Education Title II: Health Workforce Priorities Title III: Modification in Medicare Payment for IME and DSH Title IV: Additional Payments for Graduate Education For Non- Physician Health Professionals All-Payer Graduate Medical Education Act - Title I: Health Care Workforce Trust Fund; Payments to Teaching Hospitals - Subtitle A: Establishment and Financing of Fund - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish the Health Care Workforce Trust Fund to provide for the financing of graduate medical education. Appropriates to the Fund amounts from: (1) specified fees imposed on health insurance; (2) the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund; and (3) the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund. Subtitle B: Additional Payments to Teaching Hospitals - Provides for payments to eligible teaching hospitals. Requires a study of this title's impact. Subtitle C: Conforming Changes in Medicare Payment for Direct Costs of Graduate Medical Education - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise provisions concerning the formula for graduate medical education costs. (Sec. 122) Excepts rural and underserved urban areas from certain limitations on the number of medical residents. (Sec. 123) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to study and report to specified congressional committees on the appropriateness of the level of documentation that should be required in a patient's medical record of professional services of a teaching physician, as a condition of payment under Medicare part B for such services Title II: Health Workforce Priorities - Requires a plan to reduce medical residency training positions in the United States to 110 percent of the annual number of students graduating from a U.S. medical school. Title III: Modification in Medicare Payment for IME and DSH - Modifies specified Medicare payments for the indirect costs of graduate medical education (IME) and disproportionate share (DSH) hospitals. Requires the Secretary to develop and implement a plan for IME hospitals to report annually on how they contribute to education, improvements in clinical services and research infrastructure, and community services operated by or in such hospitals. Title IV: Additional Payments for Graduate Education for Non- Physician Health Professionals - Requires the Secretary to develop a plan followed by the making of payments to support institutions providing graduate medical education to non-physician health professionals.</summary>
</bill>
