<bill session="108" type="hr" number="325" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Commemorating the 9th anniversary of the attack on the Argentine Jewish Mutual Aid Association (AMIA) in Buenos Aires, Argentina, and highlighting the attack as characteristic of the threat to the United States from radical Islamic organizations operating from Latin America.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2003-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2003-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="2003-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400022" joined="2003-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2003-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2003-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="2003-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2003-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2003-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2003-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2003-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2003-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2003-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2003-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2003-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2003-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2003-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2003-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Argentina"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Central America"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Community centers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iranians"/>
    <term name="Islamic fundamentalism"/>
    <term name="Jews"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2003--Introduced.
Reiterates the condemnation of the House of Representatives of the attack on the AMIA Jewish Community Center in Buenos Aires, Argentina, on July 18, 1994, and honors its victims. Urges the Government of Argentina to fulfill its international obligations and its promise to the Argentine people by pursuing the local and international connections to this act of terrorism, wherever it may lead, and to properly punish all those involved. Welcomes Argentine President Nestor Kirchner's political will to pursue the investigation of the bombing of the AMIA to its ultimate conclusions. Calls on the President of the United States to: (1) raise this issue in bilateral discussions with Argentine officials; and (2) underscore the U.S. concern regarding the past delay in the resolution of this case. Recommends that the President of the United States create more mechanisms for intra-regional information sharing and, where needed, joint counter-terrorism operations. Encourages the President of the United States to provide democratic governments in South America and Central America with the necessary financial resources as well as equipment and training for intelligence and security forces. Recommends that the U.S. Representative to the Organization of American States seek support from the countries composing the Inter-American Committee Against Terrorism to assist, if needed, in the investigation of this terrorist attack. Calls on all governments in the Western Hemisphere to pursue an anti-terrorism campaign based on unity of purpose, dedication of resources, constant vigilance, and cooperation. Calls on the Islamic Republic of Iran to: (1) respond favorably to the Argentine arrest warrant for five Iranian citizens believed to be responsible for the 1994 attack on the AMIA; and (2) cease any and all assistance to terrorist organizations, and renounce any and all involvement with terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
