<bill session="108" type="h" number="3566" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 to establish a program using geospatial and information management technologies to inventory, monitor, characterize, assess, and identify forest stands and potential forest stands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400419"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="1910"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Acid rain"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exotic animals"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forestry"/>
    <term name="Forests"/>
    <term name="Geographic information systems"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Reforestation"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Tree diseases"/>
    <term name="Weather"/>
    <term name="West (U.S.)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2003--Introduced.
Amends the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to use geospatial and information management technologies (including remote sensing imaging and decision support systems) to inventory, monitor, and identify National Forest System and private (with consent) forest stands. Directs the Secretary to carry out such program through: (1) remote sensing technology of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) and the United States Geological Survey; (2) emerging geospatial capabilities in research activities; (3) validating techniques; and (4) integration of results into pilot operational systems. Directs the Secretary to address: (1) environmental threats (including insect, disease, invasive species, fire, acid deposition, and weather-related risks and other episodic events); (2) forest degradation, and preventive management practices; and (3) characterization of vegetation types, density, fire regimes, and post-fire effects. Directs the Secretary to designate a facility in the Ochoco National Forest headquarters within Forest Service Region 6 to address such issues, with particular emphasis on coniferous forest stands in the Western United States. Directs the Secretary develop an early warning system for catastrophic environmental forest threats.</summary>
</bill>
