<bill session="104" type="h" number="3108" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit the construction of flood control projects by non-Federal interests.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1996-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1996-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment Prior to Referral.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Civil engineering"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/1996--Introduced.
Authorizes non-Federal interests (NFIs) to undertake flood control projects, subject to obtaining any required permits in advance of actual construction. Authorizes an NFI or the Secretary of the Army, upon request, to undertake all necessary studies and engineering for such projects. Authorizes any NFI which has received from the Secretary a favorable recommendation for a flood control project (or separable element thereof) to carry out such project if a final environmental impact statement has been filed. Directs the Secretary to monitor any project for which a permit is granted to ensure permit compliance. Authorizes the Secretary to reimburse any NFI for the Federal share of an authorized flood control project if the Secretary: (1) approves the construction plans of the NFI; and (2) finds that such construction is economically justified and environmentally acceptable.</summary>
</bill>
