<bill session="107" type="h" number="5039" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Humboldt Project Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Humboldt Project Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey title to certain irrigation project property in the Humboldt Project, Nevada, to the Pershing County Water Conservation District, Pershing County, Lander County, and the State of Nevada.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Received from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-07-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-07-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-09T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-648.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-09-09T18:13:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="395">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 395.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="4708"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/2002--Reported to House amended.
Humboldt Project Conveyance Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to convey all right, title, and interest in and to the lands and features of the Humboldt Project, including all water rights for storage and diversion, to the Pershing County Water Conservation District (PCWCD), the State of Nevada, the Pershing County government, and the Lander County government, consistent with the terms and conditions set forth in the Memorandum of Agreement between PCWCD and Lander County dated January 24, 2002, the Conceptual Agreement between PCWCD and the State dated October 28, 2001, and the Letter of Agreement between Pershing County and the State dated April 16, 2002.(Sec. 4) Requires PCWCD to pay the United States the net present value of miscellaneous revenues associated with the lands and facilities to be conveyed.Requires the entity receiving title under this act to pay the United States the fair market value for any withdrawn land conveyed, as well as the real estate transfer costs for any land or facility conveyed.Declares that the State of Nevada will not be responsible for any payments for land or facilities under this Act.Declares that any proposal by the State to reconvey to another entity land conveyed by the Secretary must provide fair market value to the Unites States for the lands and for continued management of the lands for recreation, wildlife habitat, wetlands, or resource conservation.(Sec. 6) Revokes the Secretarial Orders dated March 16, 1934, and April 6, 1956, that withdrew public lands for the Rye Patch Reservoir and the Humboldt Sink.(Sec. 7) Exempts the United States from liability for damages arising out of any act, omission, or occurrence relating to the Humboldt project, except for damages caused by acts of negligence committed by the United States, its employees or agents prior to the date of conveyance.(Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary to complete, prior to conveyance, all actions required under the National Environment Policy Act of 1969.(Sec. 9) Declares that upon conveyance of the lands and facilities, the Humboldt Project will no longer be a Federal reclamation project and the district shall not be entitled to receive any future reclamation benefits with respect to the project, except those benefits that would be available to other nonreclamation districts.</summary>
</bill>
