<bill session="104" type="h" number="3675" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY97, Transportation</title>
    <title type="popular">Transportation Department FY97 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Department of Transportation and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1997, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400435"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-27">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-19">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-06">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-06">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-06">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-06-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-19T23:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-631, by Mr. Wolf.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-06-19T23:37:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="316">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 316.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-25T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 460 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3675 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI shall be waived except as specified in the resolution. Where points of order are waived against part of a paragraph, points of order against a provision in another part of such paragraph may be made only against such provision and not against the entire paragraph. Bill is open to amendments. An amendment printed in sec. 2 of this resolution shall be considered as having been adopted in the Committee of the Whole and in the House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T01:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 460 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T01:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 460.</text>
      <reference ref="6/26/1996 CR H6964-6973" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T01:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3675 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI shall be waived except as specified in the resolution. Where points of order are waived against part of paragraph, points of order against a provision in another part of such paragraph may be made only against such provision and not against the entire paragraph. Bill is open to amendments. An amendment printed in sec. 2 of this resolution shall be considered as having been adopted in the Committee of the Whole and in the House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T01:08:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 460 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T01:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Doug Bereuter to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T01:09:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T01:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Wolf moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T01:13:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T01:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3675 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T21:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7067-7092" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T21:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T21:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Coble raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Coble stated that the provisions contained on page 10, line 25 through page 11, line 3 (relating to boating safety--Aquatic Resources Trust Funds) contained an expenditure of funds not previously authorized by law and was, therefore, in violation of clause 2 of rule XXI of the rules of the House. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T22:33:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on the Oberstar amendment, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was agreed to. Mr. Wolf demanded a recorded vote and, pending that request, made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, further proceedings were postponed and the point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T23:02:00-04:00">
      <text>vote postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T23:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Wolf asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on any further amendment to the bill be limited to 10 minutes, except for an amendment by Mr. Collins (Ga) and Mr. Andrews. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T23:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T23:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T23:31:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on the Andrews amendment, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Andrews demanded a recorded vote and, pending that request, made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, further proceedings were postponed and the point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T23:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27T23:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-28T00:08:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on the Collins (GA) amendment, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the amendment was not agreed to. Mr. Collins demanded a recorded vote and, pending that request, made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, further proceedings were postponed and the point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-28T00:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair announced that proceedings would resume on those amendments on which recorded votes had been requested and further consideration had been postponed. The amendments would be considered in the following order: Oberstar, Filner, Andrews, Collins (GA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-28T00:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3675.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-28T00:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-28T00:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-06-28T01:08:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="292" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 403 - 2 (Roll no. 292).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/27/1996 H7092-7099" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-06-28T01:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Transportation. Approved for full committee consideration with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-07-18">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-19">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported to Senate by Senator Hatfield with amendments. With written report No. 104-325.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-07-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="504">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 504.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9118-9149" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5123 proposed by Senator Hatfield.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5123 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5124 proposed by Senator Hatfield.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5124 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5125 proposed by Senator Hatfield.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5125 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5126 proposed by Senator Lautenberg.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5126 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5127 proposed by Senator Hatfield for Senator Kohl.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5128 proposed by Senator Hatfield for Senator Bond.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5127 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5128 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5129 proposed by Senator Hatfield for Senator Kerrey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5129 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5130 proposed by Senator Hatfield for Senator Levin.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5130 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5131 proposed by Senator Dorgan.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5131 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5132 proposed by Senator McCain.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Motion to table SP 5132 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 82-17. Record Vote No: 255.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5133 proposed by Senator Dewine.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5134 proposed by Senator Dorgan.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5133 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5134 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5135 proposed by Senator Murkowski.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Proposed amendment SP 5135 withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5136 proposed by Senator Hatfield for Senator Pressler.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5136 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5137 proposed by Senator Hatfield for Senator Kempthorne.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5137 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5138 proposed by Senator Hatfield for Senator Pressler.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5138 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5139 proposed by Senator Hatfield for Senator Gorton.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5139 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5140 proposed by Senator Exon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30">
      <text>Amendment SP 5140 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9265-9288" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5141 proposed by Senator Baucus.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5142 proposed by Senator Lautenberg for Senator Wellstone.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5142 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5143 proposed by Senator Lautenberg for Senator Wyden.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5143 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Motion to table SP 5141 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 42-57. Record Vote No: 260.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5144 proposed by Senator Lautenberg.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5144 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5145 proposed by Senator Lautenberg.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5145 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5146 proposed by Senator Cohen.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5146 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5147 proposed by Senator Gramm to Amendment SP 5141.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5147 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Amendment SP 5141 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1996-07-31" how="roll" result="pass" roll="261" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Yea-Nay Vote. 95-2. Record Vote No: 261.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendments asks for a conference, appoints conferees Hatfield; Domenici; Specter; Bond; Gorton; Shelby; Lautenberg; Byrd; Harkin; Mikulski; Reid.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9287" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Wolf asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:25:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10048" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained in the motion require the managers on the part of the House to disagree to Senate amendment numbered 150.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10048" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Wolf, DeLay, Regula, Rogers, Lightfoot, Packard, Callahan, Dickey, Livingston, Sabo, Durbin, Coleman, Foglietta, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-05">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-11">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-16T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 104-785 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10387-10426" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 522 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 3675. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18T12:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 522 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18T13:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Wolf brought up conference report H. Rept. 104-785 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 522.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18T13:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18T13:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18T13:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="1996-09-18T13:52:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="419" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 395 - 19 (Roll no. 419).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10567" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-09-18" how="roll" result="pass" roll="294" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 85-14. Record Vote No: 294.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10794" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1996-09-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1996-09-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-09-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-09-30" type="public" number="104-205">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-205.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAP12" subcommittee="Transportation" name="House Appropriations"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP12" subcommittee="Transportation" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="460"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="522"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Age and employment"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Architecture and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Automobile fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Aviation insurance"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Beach erosion"/>
    <term name="Boating accidents"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Child molesting"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee motivation"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Ferries"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highspeed trains"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Highway use tax"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Landing aids (Aeronautics)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Light rail transit"/>
    <term name="Lighthouses and lightships"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Locomotives"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Mandatory retirement"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="National Transportation Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Navigation (Aeronautics)"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution control"/>
    <term name="Oils and fats"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Railroad commuting traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad finance"/>
    <term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad research"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroad terminals"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Robbery"/>
    <term name="Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space flight"/>
    <term name="St. Lawrence Seaway"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
    <term name="Stress (Psychology)"/>
    <term name="Sugar"/>
    <term name="Sugar and sugar trade"/>
    <term name="Sugar trade"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Test facilities"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Traffic signs and signals"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the physically handicapped"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban transportation"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Vegetable trade"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1234"/>
    <amendment number="h1235"/>
    <amendment number="h1236"/>
    <amendment number="h1237"/>
    <amendment number="h1238"/>
    <amendment number="h1239"/>
    <amendment number="h1240"/>
    <amendment number="h1241"/>
    <amendment number="s5123"/>
    <amendment number="s5124"/>
    <amendment number="s5125"/>
    <amendment number="s5126"/>
    <amendment number="s5127"/>
    <amendment number="s5128"/>
    <amendment number="s5129"/>
    <amendment number="s5130"/>
    <amendment number="s5131"/>
    <amendment number="s5132"/>
    <amendment number="s5133"/>
    <amendment number="s5134"/>
    <amendment number="s5135"/>
    <amendment number="s5136"/>
    <amendment number="s5137"/>
    <amendment number="s5138"/>
    <amendment number="s5139"/>
    <amendment number="s5140"/>
    <amendment number="s5141"/>
    <amendment number="s5142"/>
    <amendment number="s5143"/>
    <amendment number="s5144"/>
    <amendment number="s5145"/>
    <amendment number="s5146"/>
    <amendment number="s5147"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/16/1996--Conference report filed in House.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of Transportation Title II: Related Agencies Title III: General Provisions Title IV: Miscellaneous Highway Provisions Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997 - Title I: Department of Transportation - Makes appropriations for FY 1997 (with specified rescissions, limitations on obligations and direct loans, and liquidations of contract authorizations) for: (1) the Office of the Secretary of Transportation; (2) the Coast Guard; (3) the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA); (4) the Federal Highway Administration (FHA); (5) the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration; (6) the Federal Railroad Administration; (7) the Federal Transit Administration; (8) the Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation; (9) the Research and Special Programs Administration; (10) the Office of the Inspector General; and (11) the Surface Transportation Board. Requires the use of funds for the Office of Secretary of Transportation to investigate anticompetitive practices in air transportation and enforce specified provisions of Federal law against such practices. Establishes in the Treasury an administrative services franchise fund, to be available without fiscal year limitation, for the costs of capitalizing and operating certain centralized FAA services. Title II: Related Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY 1997 for: (1) the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board; and (2) the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB). Title III: General Provisions - Sets forth specified prohibitions, limitations, permissions, and mandates with respect to the use of appropriations under this Act identical or very similar to those enacted in the Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996 (Public Law 104-50). (Sec. 321) Reduces the amount of funds provided in this Act for the Transportation Administrative Service Center. (Sec. 327) Prohibits the use of funds (as in Public Law 104-50) for employee training which: (1) does not meet identified needs for knowledge, skills, and abilities bearing directly upon the performance of official duties; (2) contains elements likely to induce high levels of emotional response or psychological stress in some participants; (3) does not require prior employee notification of the content and methods to be used in the training and written end of course evaluations; (4) contains any methods or content associated with religious or quasi-religious belief systems or "new age" belief systems; (5) is offensive to, or designed to change, participants' personal values or lifestyle outside the workplace; or (6) includes content related to human immunodeficiency virus-acquired immune deficiency syndrome (HIV-AIDS) other than that necessary to make employees more aware of its medical ramifications and the workplace rights of HIV-positive employees. (Sec. 334) Amends Federal transportation law to exempt from certain State and local laws construction or specified financial activity with respect to any improvement by or on behalf of Amtrak in connection with the Northeast Corridor Improvement Project, or any land on which such improvement is located and adjoining, surrounding or any related land. (Sec. 335) Prohibits the use of funds to construct, or to pay the salaries or expenses of Department of Transportation (DOT) personnel who approve or facilitate the construction of, a third track on the Metro-North Railroad Harlem Line in the vicinity of Bronxville, New York, if a final environmental impact statement for the project has not been completed. (Sec. 336) Amends Federal mass transportation law to include the locally preferred alternative for the South-North Corridor Project in the federally-funded Tri-County Metropolitan Transportation District of Oregon Light Rail Program. (Sec. 336a) Amends the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (ISTEA) and the Federal Transit Act Amendments of 1991 to increase the funds available for the Westside Light Rail Project of the Tri-County Metropolitan Transportation District of Oregon. (Sec. 337) Allows a specified amount funds made available to Cleveland for the Cleveland Dual Hub Corridor Project or Cleveland Dual Hub Rail Project in FY 1991, 1992, and 1994, to be made available for the Berea Red Line Extension and the Euclid Corridor Improvement projects. (Sec. 338) Earmarks specified funds made available to Michigan under specified Federal law for FY 1997 for the purchase of buses and bus-related equipment and facilities. (Sec. 339) Makes additional appropriations for activities of the National Civil Aviation Review Commission. (Sec. 340) Requires the transfer to Kauai, Hawaii, of certain under the Federal Transit Administration's Discretionary Grants program. (Sec. 341) Enacts into law specified provisions of H.R. 1361, as passed the House of Representatives on May 9, 1995, mandating conveyance to the Montauk Historical Association of the Light Station Montauk Point at Montauk, New York. (Sec. 342) Provides that certain improvements identified as highest priority in ISTEA shall not be treated as an allocation for Interstate maintenance. (Sec. 343) Expresses the sense of Congress that entities receiving assistance under this Act should comply with the Buy American Act and purchase U.S.-made equipment and products to the greatest extent practicable. Prohibits the use of funds for contracts with persons falsely labeling products as made in America. (Sec. 344) Makes receipts collected from users of fitness centers operated by or for DOT available to support their operation and maintenance. (Sec. 345) Prohibits the use of NTSB funds for any study to determine the feasibility of allowing individuals who are more than 60 years of age to pilot commercial aircraft. (Sec. 346) Reduces funds in this Act for bonuses and cash awards for DOT employees, including those in the Senior Executive Service. (Sec. 347) Exempts the National Passenger Railroad Corporation (Amtrak) from any State or local law relating to the payment or delivery of abandoned or unclaimed personal property to government authority with respect to passenger rail tickets (beginning April 20, 1972) for which no refund has been or may be claimed. (Sec. 348) Directs the FAA to provide personnel at Dutch Harbor, Alaska, to provide real-time weather and runway observation and other aviation safety functions. (Sec. 349) Provides for DOT voluntary separation incentive payments and mandatory consequent reduction of funded employee positions. (Sec. 350) Amends the District of Columbia Code with respect to child custody and the visitation rights of parents in pending cases in which: (1) the child asserts that a party to the case has been sexually abusive with the child; (2) the child has resided outside of the United States for at least 24 consecutive months; (3) any of the parties has denied custody or visitation to another party in violation of a court order for at least 24 consecutive months; and (4) any of the parties has lived outside of the District of Columbia during such period of denial of custody or visitation. Denies child custody or visitation rights with respect to such a child age 13 or over, without the child's consent, to a party the child asserts has been sexually abusive. Declares that, if any person had actual or legal custody of such a child or offered him or her safe refuge while the case (or any related action) was pending, the court may not deprive such person of custody or visitation rights over the child or otherwise impose sanctions on the person on the grounds that the person had such custody or offered such refuge. (Sec. 351) Directs the FAA Administrator to provide for an independent assessment of the FAA acquisition management system, including a review of the Administrator's efforts in promoting the use of full and open competition, and report its findings to the Congress. (Sec. 352) Amends Federal transportation law to authorize the State of Nebraska to allow through FY 1997 the operation within its boundaries of longer combination vehicles that were not in actual operation on June 1, 1991, to transport sugar beets from the harvesting field to storage, market, factory, or stockpile or from stockpile to storage, market, or factory. (Sec. 353) Authorizes States to use specified funds for incentive payments to local governments, matching those made by railroads to such governments, for permanent closure of public at-grade railway-highway crossings. (Sec. 354) Requires, in order for the Coast Guard to use certain funds to issue or enforce certain regulations under the Edible Oil Regulatory Reform Act, that such regulations recognize and provide, with respect to fats, oils, and greases, for differences in physical, chemical, biological, and other relevant properties, and in environmental effects. (Sec. 355) Reserves a specified portion of funds for the Federal Rail Administration to establish and operate the Institute for Railroad Safety, as authorized by the Swift Rail Development Act of 1994. (Sec. 356) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act to levy penalties before September 1, 1997, on the States of Maine or New Hampshire based on non-compliance with Federal vehicle weight limitations. Title IV: Miscellaneous Highway Provisions - Prohibits on U.S. Route 15 in Virginia between the Maryland border and the intersection with U.S. Route 29: (1) any semitrailer units operating in a truck tractor-semitrailer combination whose semitrailer unit is more than 48 feet long; and (2) certain truck tractor-semitrailer-trailer combinations specified under Federal transportation law. (Sec. 402) Amends the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to provide for: (1) feasibility studies, preliminary engineering, and construction of a new bridge and approaches over the Mobile River, Alabama; and (2) improvements to the VIPA Molasses Dock intermodal port facility on the island of St. Croix, Virgin Islands, to enable the facility to handle multiple cargo tasks. (Sec. 404) Authorizes certain funds (already authorized for highway-railroad grade crossing separations in Mineola, New York) for other grade crossing improvements in Nassau and Suffolk Counties in New York. (Sec. 405) Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to modify certain agreements to provide a specified additional line of credit usable to replace otherwise required contingency reserves, if the modification is supported by the amount of the original appropriation. (Sec. 406) Amends specified Federal law (for continuing appropriations, FY 1988) to authorize the use of specified Traffic Improvement Demonstration Project funds to include the upgrading of existing local roads in the vicinity of Petoskey, Michigan. (Sec. 407) Requires that an amount appropriated for a Lake Shore Drive extension study, Whiting, Indiana, in the Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1995 be made available for a congestion relief project for construction of a four-lane road and overpass at Merrillville, Indiana. (Sec. 408) Makes certain funds available for construction of Baldwin Road as part of the highway safety improvement project, Michigan. (Sec. 409) Authorizes specified transfers of funds among Minnesota highway projects, at the option of the Minnesota Department of Transportation. (Sec. 410) Amends ISTEA with respect to rural access and innovative projects for the Pennsylvania localities of Mifflin, Fulton, and Clearfield.</summary>
</bill>
