<bill session="108" type="h" number="1376" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the Enhanced Heavily Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) Initiative.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2003-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2003-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2003-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2003-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2003-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2003-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2003-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental degradation"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Gross national product"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Malaria"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2003--Introduced.
Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 for the U.S. payment to the Heavily Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) Trust Fund administered by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (World Bank). Authorizes additional appropriations for payment to such Fund to meet the additional financing needs of the Enhanced HIPC Initiative, provided the Secretary of the Treasury determines that an agreement by certain multilateral financial institutions regarding modification of the Initiative has been reached. Amends the International Financial Institutions Act to direct the Secretary to commence immediately efforts within the Paris Club of Official Creditors, as well as the World Bank, the International Monetary Fund (IMF), and other appropriate multilateral development institutions, to accomplish certain modifications in the Initiative, including requiring that: (1) the amount of debt stock reduction for a country eligible for debt relief under the Initiative be sufficient to reduce, for a specified period, the net value of outstanding public guaranteed debt of the country and its annual payments due on such debt to not more than specified formulated percentages; and (2) the debt cancellation under such Initiative not be conditioned on any agreement by an impoverished country to implement or comply with policies that deepen poverty or degrade the environment, or that implement user fees on primary education or primary health care, increase the cost to consumers with incomes of less than $2.00 per day for access to clean drinking water, or that undermine internationally recognized worker rights. Makes ineligible for debt relief any country that: (1) supports international terrorism; (2) engages in gross violations of internationally recognized human rights; or (3) has been designated as a "Tier 3" nation pursuant to the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 for its failure to cooperate on international trafficking in persons prevention efforts. Conditions debt cancellation upon the country's agreeing to ensure that the financial benefits of such debt relief are applied to programs to combat poverty and to redress environmental degradation. Amends certain Federal laws to prohibit the provision of foreign assistance or the transfer of certain weapons and technology to countries (or persons) that fail to cooperate with the United States on efforts to combat international terrorism. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on options to expand debt relief to non-HIPC countries.</summary>
</bill>
