<bill session="106" type="h" number="2126" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">After School Education and Anti-Crime Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve academic and social outcomes for students and reduce both juvenile crime and the risk that youth will become victims of crime by providing productive activities during after school hours.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="1999-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="817"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child care block grants"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Delinquency prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary school students"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="High school students"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Middle schools"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="School-age child care"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="Student activities"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban education"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in education"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1999--Introduced.
After School Education and Anti-Crime Act of 1999 - Revises the 21st Century Community Learning Centers Act to: (1) authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) for the support of public elementary or secondary schools, including middle schools, that serve communities with substantial needs for expanded learning opportunities for children and youth in the communities, to enable the schools to establish or expand projects that benefit specified community needs; (2) direct the Secretary, in awarding grants, to assure an equitable distribution of assistance among the States and among urban and rural areas of the United States; and (3) direct the Secretary to award such grants for a period not to exceed five years.(Sec. 6) Requires an LEA, to be eligible to receive a grant, to submit an application including: (1) information demonstrating that the LEA will provide not less than 35 percent of the annual cost of the activities assisted under the project from sources other than funds provided under the Act, which may be provided in cash or in kind, and provide not more than 25 percent of the annual cost of the activities assisted under the project from funds provided by the Secretary under other Federal programs that permit their use; and (2) an assurance that the LEA, in each year of the project, will maintain the agency's fiscal effort, from non-Federal sources, from the preceding fiscal year.(Sec. 7) Allows the use of grant funds to establish or expand community learning centers. Allows such centers to provide one or more of specified activities, including after school programs that: (1) include (at least two of the following) mentoring programs, academic assistance, recreational activities, or technology training; and (2) may include drug, alcohol, and gang prevention activities, health and nutrition counseling, and job skills preparation activities. Limits the amount of appropriated funds that may be used for after school programs.(Sec. 8) Directs an LEA to: (1) request volunteers from business and academic communities, and law enforcement organizations, to serve as mentors or to assist in other ways; (2) ensure that youth in the local community participate in designing the after school activities; (3) develop creative methods of conducting outreach to youth in the community; (4) request donations of computer equipment and other materials and equipment; and (5) work with State and local park and recreation agencies so that activities carried out by the agencies prior to this Act's enactment are not duplicated.(Sec. 10) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
