<bill session="108" type="h" number="5301" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freedom to Display the American Flag Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that the right of an individual to display the flag of the United States on residential property not be abridged.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400017"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Condominium (Housing)"/>
    <term name="Cooperative housing"/>
    <term name="Flags"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Homeowners' associations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2004--Introduced.
Freedom to Display the American Flag Act of 2004 - States that a condominium association, cooperative association, or residential real estate management association may not adopt or enforce any policy, or enter into any agreement, that would restrict or prevent an association member from displaying the U.S. flag on residential property within the association with respect to which such member has a separate ownership interest or a right to exclusive possession or use. States that nothing in this Act shall be considered to permit any display or use that is inconsistent with: (1) Federal law or any rule or custom pertaining to the proper display or use of the flag; or (2) any reasonable restriction pertaining to the time, place, or manner of displaying the flag necessary to protect a substantial interest of the condominium, cooperative, or residential real estate management association.</summary>
</bill>
