<bill session="107" type="h" number="3556" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Afghanistan Illegal Drug Eradication Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit assistance for Afghanistan unless the national government of Afghanistan undertakes efforts to control illegal drugs in Afghanistan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2001-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Opium"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/20/2001--Introduced.
Afghanistan Illegal Drug Eradication Act - Prohibits U.S. assistance for Afghanistan unless the President determines and certifies to Congress that the national Government of Afghanistan: (1) does not engage in the cultivation of poppies or drug trafficking or otherwise facilitate the cultivation, production, transportation, or distribution of illegal drugs; (2) has destroyed all illegal drugs held in storage at locations owned, operated, controlled, or seized by the Government; and (3) has established and is implementing appropriate institutional mechanisms to prohibit the cultivation, production, transportation, and distribution of illegal drugs, including appropriate enforcement mechanisms.Prohibits assistance for an individual or entity in Afghanistan that cultivates, produces, transports, or distributes illegal drugs. Requires any officer or employee of a U.S. department or agency to report any knowledge of facts or circumstances that reasonably indicate that any individual or entity in Afghanistan that receives U.S. assistance is involved in any such activity to the Attorney General and the Inspector General or head of the department or agency involved.</summary>
</bill>
