<bill session="108" type="h" number="986" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tobacco Market Transition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To replace the existing Federal tobacco program with a federally chartered corporation to ensure the stability of the price and supply of domestically produced tobacco, to compensate quota holders for the loss of tobacco quota asset value, to provide transition assistance for active tobacco producers, to increase the competitiveness of domestically produced tobacco, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="2003-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops and Foreign Agriculture Programs.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG14" subcommittee="Specialty Crops and Foreign Agriculture Programs" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Acreage allotments"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Farm production quotas"/>
    <term name="Federal incorporation"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Marketing orders"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2003--Introduced.
Tobacco Market Transition Act - Establishes in the Treasury the Tobacco Community Revitalization Trust Fund, which shall be administered by the Tobacco Production Control Corporation (Corporation). States that amounts shall be used for program expenses and to compensate tobacco producers and quota holders for costs related to the changeover from the current tobacco program to the program provided for by this Act.Directs the Corporation to provide: (1) compensation (based upon pounds and base quota level) to eligible tobacco quota holders for loss of tobacco quota asset value; and (2) transition payments (based upon pounds and production base) to eligible active tobacco producers.Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to forgive specified loans made to tobacco producer-owned cooperative marketing associations, and transfer related inventories to the Commodity Credit Corporation. Transfers related funds held in a No Net Cost Tobacco Fund or No Net Cost Tobacco Account to the Fund.Directs the Corporation to consider transition payments for other persons involved in tobacco production and marketing.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to treat: (1) tobacco quota holder compensation as long-term capital gain; and (2) transition payments as ordinary income.Establishes the Tobacco Production Control Corporation which shall: (1) be responsible for promulgating rules governing the production, marketing, importation, exportation, and consumer quality assurances for each kind of tobacco; (2) establish a system of tobacco production and marketing licensing (sets forth license provisions); (3) determine tobacco base price levels; and (4) conduct a program referendum if requested by a certain number of licensees.Repeals the Tobacco Control Act and specified other agricultural provisions to terminate tobacco marketing quota and related programs.</summary>
</bill>
