<bill session="107" type="h" number="520" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Emergency Steel Loan Guarantee Act of 1999 to provide for increased loan guarantees for steel companies under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400611"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy, Technology and Economic Growth.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA18" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy, Technology, and Economic Growth" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Corporate debt"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Corporate management"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Steel"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2001--Introduced.
Amends the Emergency Steel Loan Guarantee Act of 1999 to permit the use of guaranteed loan proceeds to repay outstanding debts of a qualified steel company.Sets a maximum principal loan guarantee of 95 percent if the Loan Guarantee Board determines that the aggregate amount of imported steel during the prior year exceeds 30 percent of the aggregate amount of domestic steel produced during that year.Permits conversion of such loan guarantee to a grant to a steel company for loan repayment purposes if the company is unable to repay the loan because of financial hardship beyond its control, has demonstrated a good faith effort to be cost efficient, and such grant is in the U.S. national security interest.Insulates the Board's loan guarantee authority for steel companies from the authority of any other Federal department or agency, including the Office of Management and Budget.</summary>
</bill>
