<bill session="104" type="h" number="3602" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Dam Safety Program Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce the hazards of dam failures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411997"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402657" joined="1996-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1996-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1996-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403864" joined="1996-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1996-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404503" joined="1996-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1996-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hydraulic engineering"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/1996--Introduced.
National Dam Safety Program Act of 1996 - Requires the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, State dam safety agencies, and the National Dam Safety Review Board (established by this Act) to establish and maintain a coordinated national dam safety program. Sets forth the duties of the Director, including: (1) developing and implementing the program; (2) establishing goals, priorities, and target dates for such implementation; and (3) providing a method for cooperation and coordination with, and (as feasible) providing assistance to, interested governmental entities in all States. Establishes program objectives, including: (1) ensuring that new and existing dams are safe through the development of technologically and economically feasible programs and procedures for national dam safety hazard reduction; (2) encouraging acceptable engineering policies and procedures used for dam site investigation, design, construction, operation and maintenance, and emergency preparedness and establishment and implementation of effective dam safety programs in each participating State based on State standards; and (3) developing public awareness projects, technical assistance materials, and mechanisms with which to provide technical assistance for dam safety to the non-Federal sector. Sets forth provisions regarding program components, including Federal and non-Federal elements, and three functional activities (leadership, technical assistance, and public awareness). Requires the Director to: (1) develop an implementation plan which shall demonstrate dam safety improvements through FY 2001 and recommend appropriate roles for Federal agencies, State and local governments, individuals, and private organizations; and (2) submit a biennial report to the Congress describing the status of the program and the progress achieved by the Federal agencies during the previous two years in implementing the Federal Guidelines for Dam Safety. Authorizes establishment of the Board, which shall be responsible for monitoring participating State implementation of the requirements of the assistance program. Authorizes appropriations. Sets forth an apportionment formula. Requires the Director to: (1) provide, at the request of any State that has or intends to develop a dam safety program, training for State dam safety staff and inspectors; and (2) undertake a program of technical and archival research. Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to maintain and periodically publish updated information on the inventory of dams.</summary>
</bill>
