<bill session="106" type="h" number="3171" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Health Museum Site Selection Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Health Museum Site Selection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Administrator of General Services to convey a parcel of land in the District of Columbia to be used for construction of the National Health Museum, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400583" joined="2000-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, Hazardous Materials and Pipeline Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-03-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-04-06T16:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. LaTourette asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Transportation have until midnight on April 6 to file a report on H.R. 3171. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13T19:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 106-590.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-04-13T19:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="320">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 320.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW08" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, Hazardous Materials and Pipeline Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1623"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1623"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Asbestos abatement"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2000--Reported to House amended.
National Health Museum Site Selection Act - Authorizes the Administrator of General Services to identify a parcel of excess real property in the District of Columbia to be conveyed to the National Health Museum, Inc., subject to the written concurrence of the Museum, to provide a site for the construction and operation of a new building to serve as the Museum.Prohibits any part of the property from being used for lobbying activities for 99 years.Sets forth provisions regarding the purchase price for the property and requires that the net proceeds from the conveyance be deposited into, administered, and expended as part of the Federal Buildings Fund.Conditions such conveyance on the Administrator receiving satisfactory assurances that the Museum: (1) will establish, operate, and maintain a satellite museum on Ellis Island, New Jersey, for the same purposes and subject to the same limitations as the Museum and will, within a prescribed period, commence construction of such satellite museum and renovation of a National Park Service (NPS) facility and will pay operation and maintenance costs of such facility; or (2) has entered into an agreement to take occupancy of an NPS facility that has been renovated by the NPS and will pay all rents for such facility.Provides for reversion of the property to the United States and repayment of the Museum if construction and operation requirements are not met or if use or status restrictions are violated.Permits the Museum, after the conveyance of property under this Act, to: (1) demolish or renovate any existing or future improvement on the property; (2) build, own, operate, and maintain new improvements on the property; (3) finance and mortgage the property on customary terms and conditions; and (4) manage the property.Requires the United States to cooperate with the Museum on any zoning or other administrative matter relating to the development or improvement of the property, or the demolition of any improvement.Requires the costs of remediation of any environmental hazards existing on the property before the date of the conveyance of the property under this Act, including all asbestos-containing materials, to be borne by the United States.Requires the Museum to submit annual reports on the Museum's status to the Administrator and appropriate congressional committees.</summary>
</bill>
