<bill session="105" type="h" number="1381" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Environmental Policy and Conflict Resolution Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental and Native American Public Policy Act of 1992 to establish the United States Institute for Environmental Conflict Resolution to conduct environmental conflict resolution and training, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400226"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="1997-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="399"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/1997--Introduced.
Environmental Policy and Conflict Resolution Act of 1997 - Amends the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental and Native American Public Policy Act of 1992 to include in the Board of Trustees of the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation the chairperson of the President's Council on Environmental Quality. Revises the purposes and authority of the Foundation to include establishment of the United States Institute for Environmental Conflict Resolution to assist the Government in implementing environmental assessment provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Establishes in the Treasury a United States Institute for Environmental Conflict Resolution Revolving Fund, for establishment and operation of the Institute, to be administered by the Foundation. Establishes procedures for use by a Federal agency of the Foundation and the Institute to provide assessment, mediation, or related services in connection with a dispute or conflict related to the environment, public lands, or natural resources. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
