<bill session="105" type="h" number="4321" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-08-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financial Information Privacy Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Financial Information Privacy Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect consumers and financial institutions by preventing personal financial information from being obtained from financial institutions under false pretenses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1998-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400578" joined="1998-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1998-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1998-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1998-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1998-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1998-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1998-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-08-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-08-21T19:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Banking and Financial Services. H. Rept. 105-701, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-21">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than Sept. 25, 1998 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(j), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-14">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Commerce for a period ending not later than Sept. 25, 1998 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jusrisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(e), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-25T19:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Commerce. H. Rept. 105-701, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-25T19:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-25T19:51:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="430">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 430.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank fraud"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Investment advisers"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/1998--Reported to House amended, Part II.
Financial Information Privacy Act of 1998 - Amends the Consumer Credit Protection Act to: (1) specify the types of enterprises constituting a financial institution within its purview (including any broker or dealer, investment adviser or investment company, and any insurance company); and (2) authorize the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to prescribe regulations clarifying or describing the types of institutions which shall be treated as financial institutions for purposes of this Act. (Sec. 2) Declares it a violation of this Act to obtain or solicit customer information of a financial institution relating to another person under false pretenses. Exempts from such proscription: (1) law enforcement agencies; (2) financial institutions engaged in testing security procedures, investigating misconduct or negligence, or recovering customer information obtained or received under false pretenses; (3) investigations of insurance fraud by an insurance entity; and (4) customer information of financial institutions available as a public record under Federal securities laws. Grants the FTC, certain banking regulatory agencies, and the States enforcement powers under this Act (including the power to require payment of damages as restitution by the violating party to the damaged person). Directs the FTC to notify the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) whenever it initiates an investigation of a financial institution subject to SEC oversight. Subjects violations of this Act to Federal civil and criminal penalties. Requires each Federal banking agency and the SEC or self regulatory organizations, as appropriate, to review regulations and guidelines applicable to financial institutions under their respective jurisdictions, and prescribe revisions as necessary to ensure policies, procedures, and controls relating to the deterrence and detection of the activities proscribed by this Act. Requires the Comptroller General to report to the Congress on: (1) the efficacy and adequacy of the remedies provided in this Act; and (2) recommendations for additional action to address threats to the privacy of financial information. Directs the FTC, the Attorney General, and the agencies referred to in this Act to report annually to the Congress on the number and disposition of all enforcement actions taken pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
