<bill session="104" type="h" number="2188" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish in the Department of the Interior the Essex National Heritage Area Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410887"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1995-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-28">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.4236.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="4236"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Essex National Heritage Area Title II: Essex National Heritage Area Commission Title I: Essex National Heritage Area - Establishes the Essex National Heritage Area for the purpose of preserving and interpreting the contributions to our national heritage of certain historic and cultural lands, natural waterways, and structures within Essex County in Massachusetts. Title II: Essex National Heritage Area Commission - Establishes the Essex National Heritage Area Commission in the Department of the Interior to: (1) coordinate activities of government and private entities to further historic preservation, cultural conservation, natural area protection, and compatible revitalization for the Area; (2) establish standards for projects and prepare programs for preservation of historic properties; (3) make loans and grants for conserving and protecting sites, buildings, resources, and objects which are included on or eligible for the National Register of Historic Places; and (4) implement the study report by the Essex Heritage Ad-Hoc Commission. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to assist the Commission in preparing studies and plans and in implementing the recommendations contained in such report. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into agreements with the Commission or with any property owner within the Area to facilitate public use and enjoyment of such resources or to otherwise further the Commission's objectives. Directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance to the Commission, upon request, and authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance to property owners, Massachusetts, the city of Salem and other participating municipalities, Federal or State entities, institutions, or persons to carry out this Act. Directs the Commission to assist in the establishment of a nonprofit management entity to continue the Commission's functions after it expires in ten years. Prohibits privately owned property from being included within the Area's boundaries unless the government of the county, city, or town in which the property is located agrees and notifies the Secretary. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
