<bill session="105" type="h" number="2759" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-08-03T16:26:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-08-03T16:26:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Professional Shortage Area Nursing Relief Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Health Professional Shortage Area Nursing Relief Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to the requirements for the admission of nonimmigrant nurses who will practice in health professional shortage areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T12:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 105-668.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-08-03T12:31:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="376">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 376.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6931-6935" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-08-03T16:26:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-08-03T16:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Physical therapy"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/1998--Passed House amended.
Health Professional Shortage Area Nursing Relief Act of 1998 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish a four-year nonimmigrant (H-1C visa) classification for nonimmigrant registered nurses in health professional shortage areas. Requires that an alien: (1) have a full foreign nursing license or has received U.S. nursing education; (2) have passed an appropriate examination or is a licensed nurse in the State of intended employment; and (3) be fully eligible to begin work in the petitioning facility. Requires the facility to file an employment attestation with the Department of Labor with respect to such alien (or aliens) evidencing that: (1) similarly employed nurse's wages and conditions will not be adversely affected; (2) the alien's wages will be the same as other similarly employed nurses; (3) steps are being taken to recruit U.S. nurses (as set forth by this Act); (4) no labor dispute is involved; (5) no more than one-third of the facility's registered nurses will be H-1C aliens; and (6) employment will not be performed at a facility other than the petitioning facility. Directs the Secretary of Labor to: (1) compile a public list of petitioning facilities; (2) establish a process for complaint receipt, investigation, and disposition (including civil monetary penalties) against a noncomplying facility; and (3) impose an attestation filing fee of up to $250. Limits: (1) aggregate fiscal year H-1C entrants to 500; and (2) fiscal year entrants in any one State to 25 and 50 in States with less or more than ten million inhabitants, respectively. Defines "facility" as a hospital: (1) in a health shortage area; (2) with at least 190 acute care beds; and (3) with at least 35 percent and 28 percent of its patients being Medicare and Medicaid patients, respectively. Repeals the nonimmigrant nursing program (H-1A visa). (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to recommend: (1) an alternative to the H-1C program as a permanent remedy to the registered nurse shortage; and (2) a more effective program enforcement system. (Sec. 4) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to exempt certain nurses and physical therapists from foreign health care worker certification requirements.</summary>
</bill>
