<bill session="106" type="h" number="1459" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Models of Safety and Health Excellence Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Labor to establish voluntary protection programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400318"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1999-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1999-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400588" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="2000-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2000-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1999-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400519" joined="1999-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="1999-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1999-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Industrial accidents"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/1999--Introduced.
Models of Safety and Health Excellence Act of 1999 - Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish and carry out voluntary protection programs to promote and recognize the achievement of worksites that demonstrate excellence in workplace health and safety. Authorizes the Secretary, in limited situations, to alter program application requirements to include nonstandard worksites such as short-term construction sites and mobile worksites. Directs the Secretary to encourage: (1) program participants to share occupational safety and health expertise with other employers; (2) the participation of small business in the programs, through outreach and assistance initiatives and program requirements that address the needs of small businesses. Authorizes the Secretary to provide for development of equivalent programs in State-plan States (under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSHA)). Sets forth program requirements for applications, on-site evaluations, information, and reevaluations. Exempts worksites participating in the program from inspections or investigations under OSHA, except inspections or investigations arising from employee complaints, fatalities, catastrophes, or significant toxic releases. Requires decisions regarding acceptance into, and continued participation in, the program to be based on the applicant's superior safety and health performance, as determined by, and in the sole discretion of, the Secretary or the Secretary's authorized representatives.</summary>
</bill>
