<bill session="105" type="h" number="2319" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Debit Card Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to safeguard consumers in connection with utilization of certain debit credit cards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400553"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1997-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1997-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1997-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Checking accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debit cards"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/1997--Introduced.
Consumer Debit Card Protection Act - Amends the Electronic Fund Transfer Act with respect to a financial institution which issues electronic fund transfer cards for consumer accounts without a means of unique individual identification. Requires such an institution to include on the card a prominent and conspicuous consumer protection warning that the card can be used without a code or unique identifier. Provides that, if a consumer applies for a card requiring a code or other unique identifier, the institution issues a card without such an identifier, and the consumer refuses to accept it, the institution shall promptly issue the consumer a card which does require such a code or identifier to access a consumer account. Declares that a signature shall not be treated as a unique identifier. Repeals guidelines governing consumer reimbursement and maximum liability for losses caused by the consumer's failure to timely report unauthorized electronic fund transfers. Limits consumer liability to a $50 maximum in all circumstances. Excepts a consumer from liability for unauthorized electronic fund transfers if the only required form of identification is a signature. Reduces from ten to three business days the period within which a financial institution may provide a provisional recredit of a consumer's account upon timely notice of error. Mandates provisional recredit of a consumer's account, including interest, upon receipt of notice of an error involving an electronic fund transfer initiated by the use of a card without a means of access which uniquely identifies the consumer. Modifies the loss or theft of card notification information required on monthly account statements as a precondition for consumer liability for unauthorized transfers. Precludes consumer liability for fees for insufficient funds due to an unauthorized electronic fund transfer executed by the use of a card lacking a protective device to serve as a unique identifier of the rightful consumer. Requires prompt recrediting of the consumer's account for any fee imposed before receipt of the consumer's notice of an unauthorized electronic fund transfer.</summary>
</bill>
