<bill session="106" type="h" number="4870" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-19T12:52:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-09-19T12:52:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Intellectual Property Technical Amendments Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Intellectual Property Technical Amendments Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Intellectual Property Technical Amendments Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical corrections in patent, copyright, and trademark laws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2000-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-20">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-07-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-14T17:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 106-853.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-14T17:22:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="508">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 508.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-19T12:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Coble moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-19T12:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7762-7765" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-19T12:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4870.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-09-19T12:52:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7762-7765" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-09-19T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Chief financial officers"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Inventions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Patent agreements"/>
    <term name="Patent licenses"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2000--Passed House amended.
Intellectual Property Technical Amendments Act of 2000 - Amends Federal patent and trademark law, as amended by the Intellectual Property and Communications Omnibus Reform Act of 1999 (IPCORA) and the American Inventor's Protection Act (AIPA), to rename: (1) the Director of the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (PTO) the Commissioner of such Office; (2) the Commissioner for Patents the Assistant Commissioner for Patents; and (3) the Commissioner for Trademarks the Assistant Commissioner for Trademarks. Amends other specified law to reflect these changes.(Sec. 2) Amends IPCORA to specify the PTO Commissioner as the officer authorized to revise trademark services fees for inflation.(Sec. 3) Specifies third-party requesters as the persons who may invoke inter partes reexamination of a patent in light of new evidence (prior art) affecting its patentability. Makes this specification retroactive to the enactment of IPCORA.(Sec. 4) Amends IPCORA and the Patent and Trademark Efficiency Act to permit the PTO Deputy Commissioner to be a career or non-career appointee in the Senior Executive Service.Makes the PTO Deputy Commissioner a member of both the Trademark Trial and Appeal Board and the Board of Patent Appeals and Interferences.Exempts members of the Public Advisory Committee from the current prohibition against PTO employees' having an ownership interest in patents.Repeals the requirement for a PTO officer's attestation signature on a patent grant.(Sec. 5) Amends IPCORA and the Domestic Publication of Foreign Filed Patent Applications Act of 1999 to declare that the right to obtain a reasonable royalty based on an international application designating the United States commences on the date of the application's publication (currently, on the date the PTO receives a copy of the application) under the pertinent treaty.(Sec. 6) Revises certain requirements with respect to the prior art effect of published international applications. Declares that the PTO will only rely on information published in English in patent applications as it makes the essential determination of novelty during the examination of a patent application. Makes November 29, 2000, the effective date of specified AIPA amendments establishing the early publication of patent applications, including amendments made by this Act.(Sec. 8) Amends the Trademark Act of 1946, as amended by IPCORA and the Anti-Cybersquatting Consumer Protection Act, with respect to certain damages for willful dilutions of famous marks.Provides for service on the Commissioner of any notices or process in proceedings affecting a mark registered by an applicant, or an assignee of the mark, not domiciled in the United States if the registrant or assignee does not designate by a document filed in the PTO the name and address of a person resident in the United States on whom such notices or process may be served.Allows a foreign applicant for a trademark duly registered in the applicant's country of origin, when registering the mark on the principal or supplemental U.S. register, to submit a true copy or a photocopy of the foreign registration as an alternative to a certification or a certified copy.(Sec. 9) Makes a clerical amendment to the Patent and Trademark Fee Fairness Act of 1999.</summary>
</bill>
