<bill session="105" type="h" number="3163" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Trade Dress Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Trademark Act of 1946 to provide protection for trade dress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-02-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E117"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/1998--Introduced.
Trade Dress Protection Act - Amends the Trademark Act of 1946 to add to the list of trademarks that may be refused registration on the principal register on account of their nature those marks that comprise any matter that, as a whole, is functional. Authorizes trade dress which functions as a mark to be registered and protected (except as expressly excluded by existing law) without the need to show that it has become distinctive if the relevant public is likely to identify the source of the product or service by reference to the subject matter claimed as trade dress. Revises a provision regarding registration on the supplemental register to authorize registration of a mark that: (1) consists of any symbol, name, word, slogan, phrase, surname, geographical name, numeral, device, color, label, any matter that is not functional, or any combination of the foregoing; and (2) is capable of distinguishing the applicant's goods or services. Defines "trade dress" as the total image or overall appearance of a product or service. Prohibits registration or protection of trade dress that is functional. Defines "functional," with respect to matter seeking protection under the Act, to mean that the matter is of such superior design that to afford it protection would significantly hinder effective competition. Places the burden of proving that matter is not functional in a civil action for trade dress infringement for unregistered trade dress on the person asserting trade dress protection.</summary>
</bill>
