<bill session="108" type="h" number="3030" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-02-04T18:02:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-02-04T18:02:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Services Block Grants Improvement bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving the Community Services Block Grant Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Improving the Community Services Block Grant Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Improving the Community Services Block Grant Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Community Service Block Grant Act to provide for quality improvements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2003-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2003-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2003-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2003-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1726"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-09-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Subcommittee on Education Reform Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 20.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-10-10T10:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 108-310.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-10-10T10:14:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="186">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 186.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-02-03T18:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 513 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3030 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and the Workforce now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T12:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 513 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T12:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 513.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H319-359" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H325-326" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T12:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3030 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and the Workforce now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T12:59:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 513 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T12:59:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Tom Latham to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T12:59:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3030.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T13:33:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Woolsey amendment in the nature of a substitute under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T15:27:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Woolsey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Woolsey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T15:29:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Scott (VA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T15:35:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Scott (VA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Scott (VA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T15:35:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Scott (VA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T16:06:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T16:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the George Miller (CA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T17:06:00-05:00">
      <text>LIMITING DEBATE - By unanimous consent, debate was limited on the George Miller of California amendment to 30 minutes, to be equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T18:02:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3030.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T18:02:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-02-04T18:02:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04T18:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Education Reform" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="513"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="1786"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Church and social problems"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h459"/>
    <amendment number="h460"/>
    <amendment number="h461"/>
    <amendment number="h462"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>2/4/2004--Passed House amended.
Improving the Community Services Block Grant Act of 2004 - Amends the Community Services Block Grant Act (CSBGA) to reauthorize appropriations and revise the program. (Sec. 2) Revises CSBGA program purposes and goals to include a focus on reducing poverty and expanding opportunities for individuals and families to become economically self-sufficient. Requires eligible entities to develop and meet locally determined goals as well as State goals, standards, and performance requirements. Extends through FY 2009 the authorization of appropriations for CSBGA programs. Authorizes additional appropriations for FY 2004 under CSBGA for a program of assistance relating to unemployment, which would provide an additional six months of extended temporary unemployment compensation benefits to eligible individuals. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to make grants to States from such CSBGA funds to provide financial and employment support to individuals who: (1) cannot find employment; (2) have exhausted their State unemployment benefits; and (3) can no longer receive Federal extended temporary unemployment compensation after the week of December 20, 2003. Requires eligibility criteria and benefit amounts under this new program to be the same as those for such individuals before December 20, 2003, under the Federal extended temporary unemployment compensation program (which expired as of such date). Directs the Secretary to use a specified portion of funds under CSBGA for training and technical assistance to assist States in correcting programmatic deficiencies of eligible entities. Provides for carryover into the next fiscal year of unexpended funds of eligible entities that were granted by a State for the previous fiscal year. Revises requirements for opportunities for providing youth mentoring activities to encourage education and academic achievement and youth crime prevention. Includes initiatives to improve economic conditions and mobilize new resources in rural areas to eliminate obstacles to the self-sufficiency of families and individuals in rural communities among the activities for which State plans must assure use of CSBGA grant funds. Requires State plans to include assurances that States will: (1) take swift action to improve performance, or when appropriate, terminate the funding of low-performing eligible entities that do not meet locally determined goals, or State goals, standards and performance requirements; and (2) provide a justification to the Secretary if they continue to fund persistently low-performing eligible entities. Includes dissemination of best practices and assistance in developing reporting and electronic data systems among authorized activities of the Secretary in providing training and technical assistance to States. Requires States to: (1) measure performance of local entities with regard to locally determined goals; and (2) provide information on the timeliness of the distribution of block grant funds to eligible entities and on the availability of such funds as timely advance payments for activities approved in local plans. Requires eligible entities to develop locally determined goals, including: (1) leveraging and mobilizing community resources; (2) fostering coordination of Federal, State, local, private and other assistance; and (3) promoting community involvement. Requires eligible entities to demonstrate to the State that they have met such local goals to continue their eligibility for funding. Provides for coordination of CSBGA reporting requirements with all HHS programs managed by eligible entities in order to consolidate and reduce the number of reports required about individuals, families and uses of grant funds. Sets forth local grantee accountability and reporting requirements. Prohibits eligible entities from discriminating on the basis of religion against current or potential program beneficiaries. Revises CSBGA requirements relating to community economic development (CED) grants. Revises authorized activities under CED grants to include financial assistance for construction or substantial rehabilitation of buildings and facilities, and for loans or investments in private business enterprises owned by community development corporations (CDCs). Directs the Secretary to establish procedures for allowing: (1) funds or intangible assets acquired by CED grants to become the sole property of a CDC after 12 years if the CDC agrees to use such funds or property in ways consistent with the purposes and uses of the original grant; and (2) a CDC to carry out replacement activities which are substantially similar to, serve the same impact area, and have the same goals and objectives as the original activities for which a grant is made, if such original activities cannot be carried out due to no fault of the CDC. Includes water and wastewater facility needs among those to be addressed by rural community development assistance. Extends through FY 2009 the authorization of appropriations, under CSBGA, for: (1) community food and nutrition programs; and (2) national or regional programs designed to provide instructional activities for low-income youth.</summary>
</bill>
