<bill session="105" type="hr" number="41" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to establish a Citizens' Commission on Congressional Ethics, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400428"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1997-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1997-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-02-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E168"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Legislative and Budget Process.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU02" subcommittee="Legislative and Budget Process" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional office operations"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/1997--Introduced.
Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to add rule LII establishing the Citizens' Commission on Congressional Ethics to: (1) recommend to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct administrative actions to establish or enforce standards of official conduct for Members, officers, and employees of the House; (2) investigate alleged violations of the Code of Official Conduct or of any law by a Member or House employee in performance of duties and submit a written recommendation to the Committee on appropriate action; and (3) report to the appropriate Federal or State authorities, with the approval of the House, any substantial evidence of such violation which may have been disclosed in an investigation by the Commission or the Inspector General. Prohibits the Commission from making a report or recommendation relating to the official conduct of a Member, officer, or employee or investigating such conduct without approval by an affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the Commission. Amends: (1) rule VI to add to the duties of the Inspector General of the House of Representatives responsibilities for audits and investigations of the financial operations of the House and activities to detect and prevent fraud and abuse in such operations; and (2) rule X to eliminate the duties of the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct relating to recommendations, studies, investigations, reports, and functions designated by the Ethics in Government Act of 1978. Prohibits an advisory opinion from being made by the Committee relating to the official conduct of a Member, officer, or employee of the House, unless approved by the affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the Commission. Amends rule XLIV to require statutory financial disclosure reports for certain Federal personnel to be filed with the Citizens' Commission on Congressional Ethics instead of the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</summary>
</bill>
