<bill session="105" type="h" number="3542" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">O&amp;C Lands Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the Bureau of Land Management's authority to make sales and exchanges of certain Federal lands in the State of Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-30">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Railroad land grants"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Salmon fisheries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Telegraph"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/1998--Introduced.
O&amp;C Lands Protection Act - Establishes specified limitations on the sale and exchange out of Federal ownership by the Secretary of the Interior of O&amp;C and public domain lands within the Bureau of Land Management's (BLM) Medford, Roseburg, Eugene, Salem, and Coos Bay districts and the Klamath Resource Area of the Lakeview District (geographic area) in Oregon. Defines "O&amp;C lands" as certain lands originally granted in Oregon for purposes of establishing railroad and telegraph lines that revested in the United States. (Sec. 3) Bars the Secretary from selling or exchanging out of Federal ownership any O&amp;C or public domain lands within the geographic area located within: (1) a congressionally designated wilderness area; (2) the national wild and scenic river system; or (3) an area designated to be of critical environmental concern. Sets forth provisions regarding prices and procedures for making such land sales. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) use the O&amp;C Lands Protection Fund (established by this Act) to purchase non-Federal lands located within the geographic area that are contiguous to other O&amp;C or public domain lands; and (2) give first priority to acquiring lands adjacent to streams, riparian areas, or wildlife corridors within such area used by endangered or threatened species. (Sec. 4) Sets forth procedures for exchanges as well as requirements for the value of exchanged lands. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to: (1) determine annually whether there has been a net reduction in the acreage of O&amp;C lands during the preceding fiscal year as a result of disposal of lands by the United States; (2) designate an equivalent number of acres of public domain lands within the geographic area for treatment as O&amp;C lands, if there was a reduction; and (3) designate such public domain lands that are stocked with timber in volumes per acre that are not less than the average volumes found on the O&amp;C lands and public domain lands in the area that were disposed of during the preceding fiscal year. (Sec. 6) Establishes the O&amp;C Lands Protection Fund to be available for purchasing lands, making equalization payments, and making distributions to the State of Oregon and the counties within the geographic area. (Sec. 7) Allocates revenues received by the United States from the sale of timber and other surface resources from public domain lands within such area to the State of Oregon, the affected counties, and the Salmon Habitat Restoration Fund. Establishes the Salmon Habitat Restoration Fund for specified activities within the geographic area.</summary>
</bill>
