<bill session="104" type="h" number="3671" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United Houma Nation Recognition and Land Claims Settlement Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the recognition of the United Houma Nation and to provide for the settlement of land claims of the United Houma Nation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400397"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Native American and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII14" subcommittee="Native American and Insular Affairs" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Constitutions"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/1996--Introduced.
United Houma Nation Recognition and Land Claims Settlement Act of 1996 - Grants Federal recognition to the United Houma Nation and establishes a trust relationship with the Tribe. Ratifies prior transfers of real property (and improvements thereon) or natural resources located anywhere within the United States from, by, or on behalf of the Tribe. Extinguishes aboriginal title, rights, interest, and claims by the Tribe and other Indians. Bars the United States from asserting any future claim arising by or on behalf of the Tribe from the transfer or conveyance of any real property (and improvements thereon) or natural resources before the enactment of this Act. Requires the Tribe to submit to the Secretary of the Interior its base membership roll. Allows the Tribe to elect to organize a tribal government under the Indian Reorganization Act and adopt any new constitution or other organic law in accordance with such Act.</summary>
</bill>
