<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="920" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:52-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="1350" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="1995-12-06">offered</status>
  <sponsor id="400569"/>
  <offered datetime="1995-12-06"/>
  <description>Amendment clarifies provisions relating to restricting certain vessels from participation in noncontiguous trade routes; designates the Secretary of Defense as the official to request a vessel for the National Defense Reserve Fleet; repeals current law prohibiting the Secretary of Transportation from requiring performance bonds from contractors for repair and maintenance of vessels in the Ready Reserve Fleet; grants reemployment rights to merchant seamen of a vessel used by the U.S. in time of war or national emergency; and extends the Transportation Department's authority to provide maritime insurance to vessels until commercial insurance can be obtained.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment printed in House Rpt. 104-375, to make a number of changes to the provisions of the bill that establishes a new Maritime Security Fleet, and to make other changes to maritime law. Specifically, the amendment would clarify provisions relating to restricting certain vessels from participation in noncontiguous trade routes; designate the Secretary of Defense as the official to request a vessel for the National Defense Reserve Fleet; repeal current law prohibiting the Secretary of Transportation from requiring performance bonds from contractors for repair and maintenance of vessels in the Ready Reserve Fleet; grant reemployment rights to merchant seamen of a vessel used by the U.S. in time of war or national emergency; extend the Transportation Department's authority to provide maritime insurance to vessels until commercial insurance can be obtained; and other purposes.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-12-06T14:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Bateman.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-06T14:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Bateman amendment (A001) modified by unanimous consent. Modification restores language inadvertently omitted from the text.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-06T15:03:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the Bateman amendment (A001) as modified Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
