<bill session="108" type="hr" number="655" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-03T14:12:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-06-03T14:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Condemning the crackdown on democracy protestors in Tiananmen Square, Beijing, in the People's Republic of China on the 15th anniversary of that tragic massacre.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="2004-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="2004-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2004-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2004-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-02T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-02T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3684-3689" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-02T18:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 655.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-02T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-03T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3746-3747" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2004-06-03T14:12:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="228" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 400 - 1 (Roll no. 228).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/2/2004 H3684" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-06-03T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Political conventions"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Public demonstrations"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2004--Passed House without amendment.
States that the House of Representatives: (1) expresses sympathy to the families of those killed, tortured, and imprisoned as a result of their participation in the democracy protests of June 3-4, 1989, in Tiananmen Square, Beijing, in the People's Republic of China, and to all those persons who have suffered for their efforts to keep that struggle alive, and to all the people of China who lack fundamental human rights; (2) commends all persons who are peacefully advocating for democracy and human rights in China; (3) calls upon those nations participating in the 2008 Olympic Games in Beijing to urge China to fully comply with the United Nations Declaration on Human Rights; (4) calls upon the Communist Government of China to honor its pledge of a `high degree of autonomy' made at the time of the Hong Kong reversion in 1997 by permitting immediate elections for the Legislative Council of Hong Kong and by leaving all revisions of Hong Kong law to a legislature elected by universal suffrage; and (5) condemns the human rights abuses by the Communist Government of China, and calls on that Government to reevaluate the official verdict on the June 4, 1989, Tiananmen pro-democracy activities and order formal investigations into the reported killing, torture, and imprisonment of democracy activists, establish a June Fourth Investigation Committee, release all prisoners of conscience, provide just compensation to the families of persons killed in such protests, allow the return of persons exiled for their activities in 1989, release Dr. Yang Jianli, and end the harassment and detention of all Chinese citizens exercising their legitimate freedoms of expression, association, and religion.</summary>
</bill>
