<bill session="106" type="h" number="2682" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Highway-Rail Grade Crossing Safety Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Motor Carrier Safety Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to enhance the safety of motor carrier operations and the Nation's highway system, including highway-rail crossings, by amending existing safety laws to strengthen commercial driver licensing, to improve compliance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1999-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Ground Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW10" subcommittee="Ground Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1559"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bus drivers"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Driver education"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Highway research"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic regulations"/>
    <term name="Traffic signs and signals"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Truck drivers"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Vandalism"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Motor Carrier Safety Title II: Highway-Rail Grade Crossing Safety Title I: Motor Carrier Safety - Motor Carrier Safety Act of 1999 - Amends Federal transportation law to direct the Secretary of Transportation, in prescribing regulations on minimum standards for testing and ensuring the fitness of an individual operating a commercial motor vehicle, to require that such individual has received training, including in-vehicle training, in the safe operation of a motor vehicle of the type the individual operates or will operate.(Sec. 102) Requires a State, in order to avoid withholding of its apportionment of Federal-aid highway funds, to comply with certain commercial driver's license requirements, including to: (1) record on a driver's commercial driver's license record each conviction for a moving traffic violation, including one committed in a non-commercial motor vehicle; (2) not issue a commercial driver's license to an individual within three years after the date the individual was convicted of any drug- or alcohol-related traffic violation, including one committed in a non-commercial motor vehicle; and (3) not issue a special license or permit to a commercial driver's license holder that permits the driver to drive a commercial motor vehicle during a period in which the individual is disqualified from operating a commercial motor vehicle, or the individual's driver's license is revoked, suspended, or canceled.Requires the Secretary, if a State is not in substantial compliance with specified Federal commercial driver's license requirements, to transfer up to five percent of the State's apportionment of Federal-aid highway funds to amounts made available to such State for enforcement of Federal and State programs for improving motor carrier safety, including commercial motor vehicle safety and hazardous materials transportation safety.(Sec. 103) Directs the Secretary, in prescribing regulations for determining the safety fitness of an owner or operator of a commercial motor vehicle, to require that no owners or operators beginning commercial motor vehicle operations after enactment of this Act will be determined fit unless they have attended a program that educates them on at least safety, size and weight, and financial responsibility regulations administered by the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to assess a fee to defray the cost of the program.(Sec. 104) Amends the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century to prohibit the redistribution to a State of its unused apportionment of funds for Federal-aid highway and highway safety construction programs during a fiscal year, if the State that fails to reduce the number of fatalities in a year resulting from commercial motor vehicle crashes by at least five percent.(Sec. 105) Directs the Secretary, after notice and opportunity for comment, to issue regulations requiring the installation and use of on-board recorders or other technologies on commercial motor vehicles to manage driver hours of service.(Sec. 106) Directs the Secretary to study and report to Congress on methods used to compensate drivers of commercial motor vehicles, and how they may affect safety and compliance with State and Federal motor carrier safety requirements (including hours of service regulations), including ways safety could be improved through changes in driver compensation. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 107) Requires the Secretary to expend a specified amount from certain Federal-aid highway funds each fiscal year to carry out public information and education programs to prevent crashes involving commercial motor vehicles.(Sec. 108) Requires the Secretary to amend a specified regulation to require the periodic updating of the Motor Carrier Identification Report, Form MCS-150, by each motor carrier conducting operations in interstate or foreign commerce. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 109) Amends Federal transportation law to subject to civil and criminal penalties, to the same extent as the motor carrier or driver committing such violation, any person who knowingly aids, abets, commands, or induces a violation of Federal regulations pertaining to qualifications, hours of service, safety, and equipment standards with respect to motor carriers (including migrant worker motor carriers).(Sec. 110) Redefines "imminent hazard" for which a commercial motor vehicle may be ordered out of service to mean any violation, or series of violations, of specified Federal commercial motor carrier safety regulations that could result in a highway crash if not discontinued within 24 hours.(Sec.111) Directs the Secretary to carry out a pilot program with one or more States to develop innovative methods (including use of photography and other imaging technologies) of improving compliance with traffic laws, including those pertaining to highway-rail grade crossings. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 112) Directs the Secretary to conduct research on heavy vehicle safety, including measures to improve braking and stability, measures to improve vehicle compatibility in crashes between heavier and lighter vehicles, and measures to improve the performance of motor vehicle drivers. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 113) Directs the Secretary to carry out a program, in cooperation with the States, to improve the collection and analysis of data on crashes involving commercial vehicles. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 114) Authorizes appropriations for: (1) grants to States for the development and enforcement of Federal and State regulations on commercial motor vehicle safety; and (2) the establishment and operation of motor carrier, commercial motor vehicle, and driver information systems and data analysis programs to support safety regulatory and enforcement activities.Title II: Highway-Rail Grade Crossing Safety - Highway-Rail Grade Crossing Safety Act of 1999 - Amends Federal rail transportation law to promote the establishment of emergency notification systems utilizing toll-free telephone numbers that the public can use to convey to railroad carriers (either directly or through public safety personnel) information about malfunctions of automated warning devices or other safety problems at highway-rail grade crossings.(Sec. 203) Amends railroad trespassing and vandalism provisions to require the Secretary to evaluate and review current local, State, and Federal laws regarding, among other things, violations of highway-rail grade crossing signals, and develop model prevention strategies and enforcement laws to be used for the consideration of State and local legislatures and governmental entities.Requires the Secretary to develop and make available to State and local governments model State legislation providing for civil or criminal penalties, or both, for violations of highway-rail grade crossing signals.(Sec. 204) Directs each railroad carrier to report to the Secretary, with periodic updates, certain information concerning each highway-rail crossing through which such carrier operates.</summary>
</bill>
