<amendment session="105" chamber="h" number="19" updated="2013-07-17T07:51:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="1" sequence="4"/>
  <status datetime="1997-03-19">offered</status>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <offered datetime="1997-03-19"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to prohibit employers from soliciting employees to take compensatory time; require the Secretary of Labor to define what constitutes an employee decision to accept it; prohibit employers from offering compensatory time unless the employer offers all employees 24 hours of leave that may be used for family, educational activities or medical care; prohibit compensatory time to employees who work less than 35 hours per week, work less than 12 months, are seasonal, or are employed in the construction, agricultural, garment, or any industry designated by the Secretary of Labor; provide that an employer may not deny compensatory time where the leave is protected by the Family and Medical Leave Act; limit the maximum hours accrued to 80 hours annually; specify that employers may not condition benefits or availability of overtime upon an employee's decision to accept, reject, or use compensatory time; and create a commission on workplace flexibility.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute to prohibit employers from directly or indirectly soliciting employees to take comp. time; require the Secretary of Labor to define what consitutes a knowing decision by the employee to accept comp. time; prohibits employers from offering comp. time, unless the employer provides all employees 24 hours of leave that may be used for family leave; prohibit offering comp. time for employees working less than 35 hours per week or employees working in construction, agriculture, or garment industries; limits the amount of comp. time an employee can accrue to a maximum of 80 hours annually. The amendment would specifically prohibit employers from conditioning employment benefits or availability of overtime upon an employees decision to accept or reject comp. time.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-03-19T15:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Miller (CA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-19T15:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Miller (CA) amendment (A004) modified by unanimous consent. Modifications to make technical corrections to the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-19T17:03:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the Miller (CA) amendment (A004) as modified Failed by recorded vote: 193 - 237 (Roll no. 58).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
