<bill session="108" type="h" number="3541" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Implements of Torture Export Control Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide authority to prevent human rights violations by controlling certain exports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400231"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2461"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2003--Introduced.
Implements of Torture Export Control Act of 2004 - Prohibits the Secretary of Commerce from approving crime control and detection instruments and equipment for export (except to any North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) member or major non-NATO ally) unless pursuant to an individual export license. Prohibits the Secretary from approving the export of such instruments, and any equipment especially susceptible to abuse as implements of torture, to any country if its government, or any group supported by or acting on behalf of that government, has repeatedly engaged in acts of torture during the 12-month period preceding the date of the application to export the item. Authorizes the Secretary, notwithstanding such prohibitions, to approve the export of any such item if the Secretary of State determines that the end user has not engaged in acts of torture. Prohibits the export to all destinations of: (1) any leg irons, handcuffs, and thumbcuffs with sharp or serrated edges; (2) saps, blackjacks, brass knuckles, and other easily concealed devices designed to administer severe blows to the body; (3) electroshock stun belts; (4) items specially designed as implements of torture; (5) batons or clubs fitted with spikes or other hard protuberances; and (6) components produced for incorporation into these items and the technology used for the development or production of these items. Requires the Secretary shall establish and publish in the Federal Register a list of crime control and detection instruments, and equipment especially susceptible to abuse as implements of torture. Requires the Secretary to: (1) ensure that all appropriate agency heads are fully consulted before an individual export license for such an item is granted; and (2) approve or deny an export license application for such instruments or equipment only in concurrence with the recommendations of the Secretary of State.</summary>
</bill>
