<bill session="108" type="h" number="1266" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the credit for the production of fuel from nonconventional sources and the credit for the production of electricity to include landfill gas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2003-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2003-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2004-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="358"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biodegradation"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2003--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) provision concerning the credit for producing fuel from a nonconventional source to provide, in general, that in the case of a facility for producing qualified fuel from landfill gas which is placed in service after June 30, 1998, and before January 1, 2008, the provision shall apply to fuel produced at such facility during the five-year period beginning on the later of: (1) the date such facility was placed in service; or (2) enactment.Amends the IRC provision concerning electricity produced from certain renewable sources to: (1) include landfill gas as a qualified energy resource; and (2) include, in the case of a facility using landfill gas to produce electricity, as a qualified facility any such facility owned by the taxpayer which is originally placed in service before January 1, 2008.</summary>
</bill>
