<bill session="107" type="h" number="4077" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide an apportionment to a primary airport that falls below 10,000 passenger boardings in a calendar year as a result of the discontinuance of air carrier service at the airport, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2002--Introduced.
Amends Federal aviation law to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to grandfather, that is, apportion airport development and noise compatibility program funds to a primary airport sponsor in a fiscal year in an amount equal to that apportioned to such sponsor in the previous fiscal year if the Secretary finds: (1) passenger boardings at such airport are below 10,000 in the calendar year used to calculate the apportionment as a result of the discontinuance of air carrier service to and from the airport in any of the three calendar years preceding the calendar year used for such calculations; and (2) the airport had at least 10,000 passenger boardings in any of such three preceding calendar years.</summary>
</bill>
