<bill session="105" type="h" number="4412" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cigars are No Safe Alternative Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To impose restrictions on the sale of cigars.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1554-1555"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Carbon monoxide"/>
    <term name="Carcinogens"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Nicotine"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Passive smoking"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Smoking and youth"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
    <term name="Tobacco research"/>
    <term name="Tobacco tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1998--Introduced.
Cigars Are No Safe Alternative Act - Prohibits any person from selling or distributing a cigar to any individual under 18. Requires that cigar retailers: (1) ensure that all cigars are located in areas where customers do not have direct access; and (2) sell cigars only in face-to-face exchanges. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to impose restrictions on the sale, advertising, distribution, and marketing of cigars directed at youth as appropriate to limit sale to individuals 18 or over. Prohibits advertising cigars on any form of electronic communication. Directs the Secretary to encourage cigar manufacturers to end the practice of paying for, or participating in, the placement of cigars in movies and on television where a substantial segment of the audience is under 18. Mandates health warnings on the labels of cigars and cigar packaging. Requires a study and report to the Congress and the President on: (1) the health effects of occasional cigar smoking, nicotine dependence demonstrated by cigar smokers, biological uptake of toxic and carcinogenic constituents of cigars, and environmental cigar smoke exposure; and (2) the yields of tar, nicotine, carbon monoxide, and any other additive designated by the Secretary. Requires cigar manufacturers to report to the Secretary on those yields. Requires a study and report to the Congress and the President by the Federal Trade Commission on current cigar sales, advertising, and marketing practices. Directs the Secretary to monitor trends in youth access to and use of cigars and, if cigars are inappropriately accessible to, or becoming an attractive alternative to smoking cigarettes for, children and adolescents, to notify the Congress and make recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
