<bill session="106" type="h" number="5507" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Informed Voter Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to promote the disclosure of information on the financing of campaigns for Federal elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400590"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business and politics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Facsimile transmission"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor union political activities"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Mass media"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Public opinion polls"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Union dues"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/2000--Introduced.
Informed Voter Act of 2000 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to require disclosure of specified information to the Federal Elections Commission (FEC) by each person making a disbursement for electioneering communications in an aggregate amount of over $10,000 during any calendar year.Requires each person providing a broadcast station with any communication mentioning a clearly defined candidate for Federal office to disclose certain information to the station. Requires broadcast stations to retain and make public such information.Requires each corporation and labor organization to disclose certain disbursement information to the FEC regarding disbursements of over $50,000 in the aggregate during a calendar year for activities otherwise exempt from contribution prohibitions.Requires a political committee of a State political party required to report on its disbursements to an entity of the State or local government to file a copy of the report with the FEC when it submits the report to such an entity.Requires certain reports, designations, or statements, which are required to be filed with the FEC by a political committee other than an authorized committee, for both the reporting period and the calendar year, to disclose the receipts and disbursements of any account of the committee whose funds are used for purposes which not otherwise subject to FECA limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements.Requires any person who conducts a Federal election poll by telephone or electronic device to disclose to each respondent the identity of the person paying the expenses of the poll.Revises requirements for the recordkeeping and reporting of secondary payments.Requires each political committee which receives a contribution of $500 or more between the 90th day before a Federal general election and the close of the polls on election day to file and preserve required information, within 48 hours after receipt of the contribution, using electronic mail, the Internet, or such other method of instantaneous transmission as the FEC may permit.Requires the identification of registered lobbyists and foreign agents.</summary>
</bill>
