<bill session="104" type="h" number="865" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Self-Sufficiency Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to offer States the option of replacing the Job Opportunities and Basic Skills Training (JOBS) program with a program that would assist all recipients of aid to families with dependent children in achieving self-sufficiency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408364"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E297-298"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, Commerce, and Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2493"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-24">
      <text>See H.R.4.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG26" subcommittee="Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="4"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compulsory education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Dropout prevention"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment subsidies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unmarried fathers"/>
    <term name="Unmarried mothers"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Self-Sufficiency Program Title II: Other Provisions Title III: Related Amendments Title IV: Effective Date Self-Sufficiency Act of 1995 - Title I: Self-Sufficiency Program - Amends part A (Aid to Families With Dependent Children) (AFDC) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) to grant States the option of establishing a self-sufficiency program in lieu of a job opportunities and basic skills (JOBS) training program. Requires any State that chooses such option to require increasing percentages of AFDC recipients to participate in the self-sufficiency program, reaching 100 percent participation by the end of ten years. Makes exceptions for recipients in specified circumstances. Sets forth reductions in AFDC payments to recipients who fail without good cause to participate in the self-sufficiency program. (Sec. 101) Sets forth general requirements for a State self-sufficiency plan. Requires a State to make an initial assessment of the educational, child care, and other supportive services needs as well as the skills, prior work experience, and employability of each program participant, including a review of the family circumstances and the needs of any child of the participant. Specifies the contents of a participant's self-sufficiency plan, including an employment goal. Requires the State to require the participant to negotiate and enter into an agreement on a specific self-sufficiency plan. Requires a State agency to inform AFDC applicants and recipients of education, employment, and training opportunities and support services (including child care and health coverage transition options). Authorizes States to make appropriate services and activities available under such program. Authorizes States, upon mutual agreements with participants in the program, to use amounts that would otherwise be expended for food stamp benefits to provide jobs for, subsidize wages of, or make cash payments to such participants. Requires establishment of procedures for resolution of disputes involving an individual's participation in the self-sufficiency program. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop performance standards for the program. Sets forth certain coordination requirements, including ones relating to program funding. Entitles States operating self- sufficiency plans to half of the resulting savings. (Sec. 102) Requires the guarantee of child care to participants in State self-sufficiency programs. Increases the Federal matching rate by ten percentage points for child care provided by States with self-sufficiency programs. (Sec. 103) Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to repeal the requirement that families in States with self-sufficiency programs must have received AFDC for a minimum period before becoming eligible for transitional Medicaid benefits or transitional child care benefits. (Sec. 105) Provides for transitional Medicaid benefits and transitional child care benefits in States with self-sufficiency programs without regard to type of income that would otherwise result in ineligibility for benefits. (Sec. 106) Eliminates certain exceptions from the requirement that minor parents and pregnant minors without children live with a responsible adult in States with self-sufficiency programs. Title II: Other Provisions - Provides for disregard, in the determination of AFDC payments, of persons who become family members after the initial receipt of AFDC in a State with a self-sufficiency program. (Sec. 202) Provides for enhanced AFDC payments for participants in a self-sufficiency program. (Sec. 203) Requires a State to make a lump-sum diversion payment, equal to three times the appropriate monthly AFDC payment, to any eligible family not yet receiving AFDC if the caretaker relative will be employed by the end of the three-month period that begins with the date the family will become an AFDC recipient. Requires reduction of any subsequent payments to such family to recover such diversion payment. Provides for three months of child care for a family receiving a diversion payment. (Sec. 205) Requires a State plan to make two-parent families ineligible for AFDC until 30 days after either parent's loss of employment. (Sec. 206) Increases the earned income disregard in States with a self-sufficiency program. Eliminates the time limitation on such disregard. Increases from $1,000 to $2,000 the asset limitations in such a State. (Sec. 208) Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to conform with this Act, providing for an employment cash-out of food stamp benefits. (Sec. 209) Gives States with self-sufficiency program plans the option of imposing penalties for failures to comply with school attendance or child immunization requirements of State law. Title III: Related Amendments - Denies welfare benefits to illegal aliens. Grants States the option to deny welfare benefits to aliens who are lawfully present in the United States. (Sec. 302) Requires provision to consumer reporting agencies of information on overdue child support obligations of absent parents. (Sec. 303) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for quarterly payments of the earned income credit. Title IV: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
