<bill session="107" type="hr" number="379" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing that certain actions should be taken with respect to the actions of OPEC and other oil-exporting countries, and with respect to decreasing the dependency of the United States on foreign sources of oil.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400544"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1134, E474"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-04-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Boycott"/>
    <term name="Business cycles"/>
    <term name="Cartels"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy demand"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Kuwait"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Norway"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Qatar"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="United Arab Emirates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2002--Introduced.
Urges the President to: (1) express to oil exporting countries that are not Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) members, such as the Republic of Mexico, that decisions to restrict crude oil supply in the world market as requested by the OPEC cartel adversely affect the national security of the United States and the world economy; (2) encourage U.S. allies in the Persian Gulf region, including OPEC members Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Qatar, and the United Arab Emirates, to reconsider their announcements to reduce and to hold the cartel's crude oil output at current levels despite increased demand in the United States and abroad; and (3) encourage the oil exporting countries allied to the United States, including non-OPEC states such as Mexico and Norway and OPEC members Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Qatar, and the United Arab Emirates, to increase oil production and exports to the United States to offset shortfalls in exports resulting from Iraq's boycott of oil shipments. Urges the Senate to pass H.R. 4 instituting a comprehensive national energy policy that would bolster U.S. national security by reducing dependence on foreign sources of energy, thereby resulting in lower prices for U.S. consumers.</summary>
</bill>
