<bill session="106" type="h" number="4735" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wartime Parity and Justice Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To allow certain individuals of Japanese ancestry who were brought forcibly to the United States from countries in Latin America during World War II and were interned in the United States to be provided restitution under the Civil Liberties Act of 1988, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400021"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="2000-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="2000-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="2000-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2000-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2000-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400302" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2000-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2000-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2000-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Central America"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Concentration camps"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Japanese Americans"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2000--Introduced.
Wartime Parity and Justice Act of 2000 - Allows certain individuals of Japanese ancestry who were brought forcibly to the United States from countries in Latin America during World War II and interned in the United States to be provided restitution under the Civil Liberties Act of 1988.(Sec. 3) Declares that the United States apologizes to such individuals for the fundamental violations of their basic civil liberties and constitutional rights. Urges the President to transmit to each such individual a personal letter of apology on behalf of the United States.(Sec. 4) Places upon the Attorney General responsibility to identify and locate eligible individuals under this Act within 12 months. Authorizes any eligible individual to notify the Attorney General that the individual is eligible and provide documentation to that effect within six years. Directs the Attorney General to make a final determination of eligibility within one year after locating or receiving notification from an individual.Authorizes judicial review of a denial of compensation. Permits an individual covered by this Act who has accepted payment on a related claim against the United States before this Act's enactment to receive an appropriately reduced payment under this Act.(Sec. 5) Directs that: (1) individuals covered by this Act not be considered to have been present in the United States unlawfully during the evacuation, relocation, or internment period; and (2) each U.S. department or agency correct any records that indicate that such individuals were in the United States unlawfully.(Sec. 6) Directs: (1) the appropriate agencies to disclose to the public all information relating to the forcible removal of individuals from Latin America and their internment in the United States during that period; and (2) the President to share such information with other countries and to encourage those countries to make that information available to people in those countries.(Sec. 7) Reestablishes in the Treasury the Civil Liberties Public Education Fund to be available for such restitution.(Sec. 8) Establishes the Civil Liberties Public Education Fund Board of Directors which shall be responsible for making disbursements from the Fund: (1) to sponsor research and public education activities; and (2) for reasonable administrative expenses.</summary>
</bill>
