<bill session="105" type="h" number="1120" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Revitalization and Brownfield Cleanup Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assist local governments in assessing and remediating brownfield sites, to amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to encourage State voluntary response programs for remediating such sites, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="1997-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1997-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="402284" joined="1997-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1997-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1997-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1997-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1997-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1997-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="406047" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1997-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1997-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1998-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1997-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1997-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1997-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1997-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1997-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1997-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1997-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="1997-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400613" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="1997-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1997-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-09">
      <text>See H.R.2727.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2727"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Brownfields"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Factories"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Brownfield Remediation and Environmental Cleanup Title II: State Voluntary Response Programs Title III: Innocent Landowners and Prospective Purchaser Liability Community Revitalization and Brownfield Cleanup Act of 1997 - Title I: Brownfield Remediation and Environmental Cleanup - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program to provide grants to local governments to inventory and conduct site assessments of brownfield sites. Defines a "brownfield site" as a parcel of land that contains or contained abandoned, idled, or under-used commercial or industrial facilities, the expansion or redevelopment of which is complicated by the presence or potential presence of hazardous substances, pollutants, or contaminants. (Sec. 103) Directs the Administrator to establish a program of grants to local governments for capitalization of loan programs for brownfield site cleanup by the locality or owner or prospective purchaser. (Sec. 104) Makes amounts in the Hazardous Substance Superfund (the Fund) available to carry out the grant programs of this Act. Authorizes appropriations from the Fund. (Sec. 105) Requires reports to the Congress regarding the site assessment and loan capitalization programs. (Sec. 106) Imposes funding limitations, including a restriction on use of funds to meet Federal cost-sharing requirements and a prohibition on the use of grants to pay fines or penalties. (Sec. 109) Authorizes appropriations to carry out the site assessment and loan capitalization programs. Title II: State Voluntary Response Programs - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to add provisions requiring the Administrator to provide technical and other assistance to States to establish and expand qualifying State voluntary response programs, comprised of elements including public participation opportunities, oversight and enforcement authorities, and certification mechanisms. Title III: Innocent Landowners and Prospective Purchaser Liability - Amends CERCLA, with respect to defenses to liability of an owner of after-acquired property, to deem a person to have made (under current law, "undertaken") appropriate inquiry into the property's previous ownership and uses if the person establishes that an environmental site assessment was conducted which meets specified requirements (compliance with an American Society for Testing and Materials standard or with standards issued by the President) and the person fulfills certain responsibilities concerning information compilation, exercise of appropriate care with respect to hazardous substances at the facility, and cooperation with those conducting response actions. (Sec. 302) Absolves from liability for response actions bona fide prospective purchasers to the extent liability at a facility for a release or threat thereof is based solely on ownership or operation of a facility. Gives a lien upon a facility to the United States for unrecovered response costs in any case in which there are such unrecovered costs for which the owner is not liable by reason of this Act and the facility's fair market value has increased above that which existed 180 days before the action was taken. (Sec. 303) Adds CERCLA provisions governing owner-operator status of persons owning or operating property contiguous to a release site.</summary>
</bill>
