<bill session="108" type="h" number="2607" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Federal Contractor Safeguard Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the contract consolidation requirements in the Small Business Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2003-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2003-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1367-1368"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="633"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2003--Introduced.
Small Business Federal Contractor Safeguard Act - Amends the Small Business Act to modify contract consolidation requirements.Replaces definitions of "bundled contracts" and "bundling of contract requirements" with definitions of "consolidated contract" and "multiple award contract."Prohibits a Federal contracting agency from executing a procurement strategy that includes a consolidated contract valued at more than $2 million unless such strategy: (1) identifies benefits anticipated from consolidation and alternative contracting approaches that would involve a lesser degree of consolidation; and (2) includes a determination that the consolidation is necessary and the benefits justify its use. Provides that a procurement strategy that includes a consolidation valued at more than $5 million shall also: (1) be supported by market research demonstrating that such contract will result in cost savings, quality improvements, reduction in acquisition cycle times, or better terms and conditions; (2) include an assessment of impediments to participation by small businesses as prime contractors that result from such consolidation; (3) specify actions designed to maximize small business participation as subcontractors; and (4) not be justified by savings in administrative or personnel costs unless such savings are substantial in relation to the total cost of the procurement.Allows a small business, if an agency head solicits offers for a consolidated contract, to submit an offer that provides for the use of a particular team of subcontractors. Requires equal evaluation of such an offer.</summary>
</bill>
