<bill session="106" type="h" number="4303" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">MTBE Elimination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the use of, and provide for remediation of water contaiminated by, methyl tertiary butyl ether.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400581"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="2000-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="2000-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400517" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2000-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400519" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2000-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="2000-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater pollution"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Oxygenates"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Reformulated gasoline"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2000--Introduced.
MTBE Elimination Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) should provide technical assistance, information, and matching funds to help local communities test drinking water supplies and remediate drinking water contaminated with methyl tertiary butyl ether (MTBE).Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to prohibit, three years after the enactment of the MTBE Elimination Act, the use of MTBE as a fuel additive.Requires persons selling oxygenated gasoline containing MTBE at retail to be required under regulations promulgated by the Administrator to label the fuel dispensing system with a notice that specifies that the gasoline contains MTBE and provides other information concerning MTBE as determined appropriate by the Administrator.Directs the Administrator to establish a schedule that provides for an annual phased reduction in the quantity of MTBE that may be used as a fuel additive during the three-year period beginning on this Act's enactment date.Requires the Administrator to establish an MTBE research grants program within EPA. Authorizes grants to eligible grantees to pay the Federal cost share of research on: (1) the development of more cost-effective and accurate MTBE groundwater testing methods; (2) the development of more efficient and cost-effective remediation procedures for water sources contaminated with MTBE; or (3) the potential effects of MTBE on human health. Makes eligible for such grants Federal research agencies, national laboratories, colleges or universities, certain private research organizations, and State environmental research facilities. Authorizes appropriations.Directs the Administrator to promulgate rules requiring a .5 pounds per square inch Reid vapor pressure allowance for all reformulated gasoline containing 3.5 percent oxygen by weight. Provides that any additional volatile organic compound emissions resulting from the use of such gasoline should be deemed to be fully offset and not calculated in determining compliance with certain Clean Air Act provisions dealing with reasonable further progress plans or demonstrations.</summary>
</bill>
