<bill session="106" type="h" number="2637" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer and Community Choice in Access Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect consumer and community choice in access to Internet providers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1999-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Internet service providers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/1999--Introduced.
Consumer and Community Choice in Access Act of 1999 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to authorize the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to require cable operators that provide interconnection with the Internet using that cable system's facilities to offer such interconnection on terms and conditions that are fair, reasonable, and nondiscriminatory and to provide such interconnection with the facilities and equipment of any Internet service provider, whether or not affiliated with such cable operator. Directs a cable operator to designate channel capacity for the provision of other cable services (currently, for a commercial use, which includes only video programming). Provides that, until the FCC establishes open access or interconnection standards and obligations for cable providers, a service that provides high-speed data service and that seeks to obtain channel capacity for such service may be treated as seeking channel capacity for a commercial use. Subjects a telecommunications service that is provided by a cable system to Federal regulation as a common carrier service.</summary>
</bill>
