<bill session="105" type="h" number="449" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the orderly disposal of certain Federal lands in Clark County, Nevada, and to provide for the acquisition of environmentally sensitive lands in the State of Nevada.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300040"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-04-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <calendar datetime="1997-04-23T17:36:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="49">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 49.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-04-23T17:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-68.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-23T18:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-23T18:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1746-1750" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-23T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-04-23T18:37:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-04-23T18:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-25">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior and Office of Management and Budget.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-06">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Public Lands. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-06-24">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-08-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Murkowski under the authority of the order of Jul 31, 98 without amendment. With written report No. 105-291.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-08-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="528">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 528.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-02" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11368, S11373" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-02">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1998-10-05">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-10-19">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-10-19" type="public" number="105-263">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-263.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Forests and Public Land Management" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="94"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental degradation"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Recreation centers"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/1997--Passed House amended.
Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1997 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) to dispose of certain Federal lands within the area under the jurisdiction of the Director of the Bureau of Land Management in Clark County, Nevada. Allows the State of Nevada or the unit of local government in whose jurisdiction the lands are located (Clark County, Las Vegas, North Las Vegas, or Henderson, Nevada) to elect to obtain the lands for local public purposes pursuant to the Recreation and Public Purposes Act (RPPA). Requires the Secretary, upon application by a unit of local government or regional governmental entity (the Southern Nevada Water Authority, the Regional Flood Control District, and the Clark County Sanitation District), to issue right-of-way grants (valid in perpetuity) on Federal lands in Clark County for all facilities and systems needed for: (1) the impoundment, storage, treatment, transportation, or distribution of water (other than water from the Virgin River) or wastewater; or (2) flood control management. Waives rental or cost recovery fees with respect to such grants. Directs the Secretary to make such lands available to Clark County in accordance with the RPPA for the construction of youth activity facilities. Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) withdrawal of such lands from mining laws and from operation under the mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws; and (2) joint selection of such lands for sale or exchange by the Secretary and the respective unit of local government. Provides for allocation of proceeds from the land sales and exchanges to: (1) the general education program of Nevada; (2) the Southern Nevada Water Authority; and (3) a special account in the Treasury for the acquisition of environmentally sensitive land in Nevada, capital improvements in Federal areas in Clark County and the Spring Mountains National Recreation Area, development of a multispecies habitat conservation plan, parks, trails, and natural areas in Clark County, and reimbursement of costs incurred by BLM local offices in arranging sales or exchanges. Requires the Secretary to transfer the airport environs overlay district lands identified in the Interim Cooperative Management Agreement between the United States Department of the Interior-Bureau of Land Management and Clark County, dated November 4, 1992, to Clark County upon request, without consideration, and subject to specified conditions, including conditions governing proceeds from the sale or lease of such property by Clark County. Allows the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture to acquire environmentally sensitive land with the owner's consent. Provides that such acquired land that is within the boundaries of a unit of the National Forest System, the National Park System, the National Wildlife Refuge System, the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, the National Trails System, the National Wilderness Preservation System, or any other system or national conservation or recreation area established by Act of Congress shall: (1) become part of the unit or area without further action by the respective Secretary; and (2) be managed in accordance with all laws and regulations and land use plans applicable to the unit or area. Includes lands acquired by the Secretaries under this Act within the definition of entitlement lands with respect to Federal payments to a local unit of government in which such land is located (payments in lieu of taxes). Authorizes the Secretary, upon request by a grantee of lands within Clark County, Nevada, that are subject to a lease or patent issued under the RPPA, to transfer the reversionary interest in such lands to other non-Federal lands on an equal value basis. Requires the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, to make available at less than fair market value land in Nevada, in accordance with the RPPA, for purposes of affordable housing (housing that is assisted under the United States Housing Act of 1937) only to State and local governmental entities (including local public housing authorities). Amends the Red Rock Canyon National Conservation Area Establishment Act of 1990 to modify the boundaries of the Area.</summary>
</bill>
