<bill session="108" type="h" number="3461" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To bar Federal agencies from accepting for any identification-related purpose a State-issued driver's license, or other comparable identification document, unless the State has in effect a policy requiring presentation of acceptable forms of identification prior to issuance of the license or document, and the State requires the license or document, if issued to a nonimmigrant alien, to expire upon the expiration of the alien's authorized period of stay in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and the Census.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO20" subcommittee="Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and the Census" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Border Security, and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/6/2003--Introduced.
Prohibits Federal agencies from accepting for any identification-related purpose a State-issued driver's license or other comparable identification document unless the application process for licenses or documents include presentation by applicants as evidence of identity: (1) two documents, with at least one containing a clear photograph of the applicant and at least one which is a primary document (as defined in this Act); or (2) three documents, if at least one is a primary document. Requires all documents to presented in English. Prohibits Federal agencies from accepting for any identification-related purpose any State-issued driver's license or other comparable identification document unless the State requires such licenses or documents issued to nonimmigrant aliens to expire on a date that is not later than: (1) the expiration of the alien's authorized U.S. stay; or (2) five years after such document's issuance in any case in which the alien's lawful stay is modified after U.S. admission, or does not expire on a fixed date. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to make grants to assist States in complying with the requirements described in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
