<bill session="105" type="h" number="3528" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Alternative Dispute Resolution Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Alternative Dispute Resolution Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Alternative Dispute Resolution Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Alternative Dispute Resolution Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Alternative Dispute Resolution Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Alternative Dispute Resolution Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 28, United States Code, with respect to the use of alternative dispute resolution processes in United States district courts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 105-487.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-04-21T13:12:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="281">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 281.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Coble moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2066-2069, H2076" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-04-21T18:25:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="101" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 405 - 2 (Roll No. 101).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Oversight and Courts.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Reported to Senate by Senator Hatch with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-07-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="514">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 514.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11808-11810" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07">
      <text>Amendment SP 3784 proposed by Senator McCain for Senator Grassley.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-07">
      <text>Amendment SP 3784 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1998-10-07" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Coble moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-10T16:53:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10457-10459" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-10T16:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-10">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-10-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-10-30" type="public" number="105-315">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-315.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Oversight and the Courts" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Trial practice"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3784"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/7/1998--Passed Senate amended.
Alternative Dispute Resolution Act of 1998 - Replaces Federal judicial code arbitration provisions with alternative dispute resolution (ADR) provisions. Directs each U.S. district court to: (1) authorize the use of ADR processes in all civil actions; (2) devise and implement its own ADR program to encourage and promote the use of ADR in its district; (3) examine the effectiveness of existing ADR programs and adopt appropriate improvements; and (4) retain or designate an employee or judicial officer who is knowledgeable in ADR practices and processes to implement, administer, oversee, and evaluate the court's ADR program. Authorizes the Federal Judicial Center and the Administrative Office of the United States Courts to assist the district courts in the establishment and improvement of ADR programs. (Sec. 4) Directs each district court to: (1) require that litigants in all civil cases consider the use of an ADR process at an appropriate stage in the litigation; and (2) provide litigants in all civil cases with at least one ADR process. Allows any district court that elects to require the use of ADR in certain cases to do so only with respect to mediation, early neutral evaluation, and, if the parties consent, arbitration. Authorizes each court to exempt from requirements of this section cases in which arbitration would not be appropriate. Requires each court to provide for the confidentiality of ADR processes and to prohibit disclosure of confidential dispute resolution communications. (Sec. 5) Requires each district court that authorizes the use of ADR processes to adopt appropriate processes for making neutrals available for use by the parties for each category of process offered. Sets forth provisions regarding neutral selection, qualifications, and training. (Sec. 6) Authorizes a district court to allow the referral to arbitration of any civil action pending before it, when the parties consent, except where: (1) the action is based on an alleged violation of a right secured by the Constitution; (2) jurisdiction is based on Federal civil rights and elective franchise provisions; or (3) the relief sought consists of money damages exceeding $150,000. Directs the district court to establish interim procedures to ensure that consent to arbitration is freely and knowingly obtained and that no party or attorney is prejudiced for refusing to participate in arbitration. (Sec. 7) Empowers ADR arbitrators to: (1) conduct arbitration hearings; (2) administer oaths and affirmations; and (3) make awards. Requires district courts to establish standards for arbitrator certification. Entitles arbitrators in an ADR program to the immunities and protections that the law accords to persons serving in a quasi-judicial capacity. (Sec. 8) Makes Federal Rule of Civil Procedure 45 (relating to subpoenas) applicable to subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses and the production of documentary evidence at an arbitration hearing. (Sec. 9) Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) filing procedures and the effect of an arbitration award and judgment; (2) the sealing of such award until the court enters its final judgment or the action has otherwise terminated; and (3) filing deadlines, restoration to the court docket, and the exclusion of evidence of arbitration with respect to a trial de novo of arbitration awards. (Sec. 10) Directs the district court to establish the amount of compensation that each neutral shall receive for services rendered. (Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
