<bill session="106" type="h" number="3049" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">DEED Act (Debt Emancipation to Enable Democracies Act of 1999)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Debt Emancipation to Enable Democracies (DEED) Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To cancel the bilateral debt owed to the United States by the heavily indebted poor countries, to prohibit United States funding of the International Monetary Fund until debt owed to the International Monetary Fund by the heavily indebted poor countries has been canceled, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400513"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1999-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Equality before the law"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/1999--Introduced.
Debt Emancipation to Enable Democracies (DEED) Act of 1999 - Directs the President to cancel all amounts owed to the United States by an eligible heavily indebted poor country (HIPC) and Haiti as a result of concessional and nonconcessional loans made, guarantees issued, or credits extended under any provision of law. Sets forth eligibility requirements for cancellation of debt for a HIPC.(Sec. 4) Provides that cancellation of debt shall not be considered assistance for purposes of any law limiting assistance to a country.(Sec. 5) Prohibits funds appropriated in this Act from being made available to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) until it: (1) has canceled all debts owed to the IMF by an eligible HIPC and Haiti; (2) has terminated the Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility; and (3) the Secretary of the Treasury has certified to specified congressional committees that such debts have been canceled, and the IMF has ceased linking loans to an eligible HIPC and Haiti to implementation of structural adjustment policies.(Sec. 6) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) to issue insurance, guaranties, or reinsurance, make loans, acquire securities, or enter into risk sharing arrangements for an eligible HIPC and Haiti with respect to which the United States and the IMF have provided debt cancellation under this Act, only if the President certifies to Congress that the government of such country is using funds available because of such debt cancellation for poverty reduction in the country.(Sec. 7) Sets forth certain notification requirements with respect to each eligible HIPC and Haiti.(Sec. 8) Authorizes a U.S. citizen to bring an action in any U.S. district court seeking compliance by the United States with the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
