<bill session="108" type="h" number="5350" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhancing Nutrition in Medical Education Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants for the integration of innovative curricula on nutrition in medical education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1922"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Diet"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Eating disorders"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Herbs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Nutritionally induced diseases"/>
    <term name="Obesity"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2004--Introduced.
Enhancing Nutrition in Medical Education Act of 2004 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to schools of medicine to integrate innovative curricula on nutrition into medical education. Requires the Secretary to ensure that such curricula focus on preventive health measures, including : (1) education on the causes, treatment, and prevention of obesity; (2) office education and counseling to ensure an appropriate diet for mostly healthy people; (3) prevention and treatment of common nutritional deficiencies; (4) the appropriate and inappropriate use of herbs and supplements; (5) office recognition and treatment of common eating disorders; and (6) identification of special dietary needs, eating disorders, and appropriate routes of referral for medical nutrition therapy. Requires grantees to: (1) develop innovative curricula; (2) integrate such curricula into the medical education at the school; (3) evaluate the results achieved with the curricula; (4) establish a multidisciplinary planning committee to develop the curricula; and (5) report to the Secretary on the developed curricula and results achieved. Requires the Secretary to prepare a consolidated report on the curricula and results achieved by grantees and to disseminate such report to schools of medicine.</summary>
</bill>
