<bill session="107" type="h" number="5599" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-15T14:12:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-15T14:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To apply guidelines for the determination of per-pupil expenditure requirements for heavily impacted local educational agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400066" joined="2002-10-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-15T14:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Culberson moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-15T14:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7900-7901" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-15T14:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5599.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-10-15T14:12:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7900" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-15T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Impact aid"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/15/2002--Passed House without amendment.
Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to revise impact aid provisions for certain heavily impacted local educational agencies (LEAs), under the program of payments for eligible federally connected children.Requires that procedures under specified Federal regulations be applied in determining whether an LEA with an enrollment of less than 350 students has a per-pupil expenditure that is less than the average per-pupil expenditure of a comparable LEA in the same State.Directs the Secretary of Education to deem the LEA serving the Bonesteel-Fairfax school district, 26-5, in Bonesteel, South Dakota, to be eligible in FY 2003 for a basic support payment for heavily impacted LEAs.Requires an application filed by Central School District, Sequoyah County, Oklahoma, for such a payment for federally connected students for FY 2003, to be treated as timely and processed by the Secretary if it is received within 30 days after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
