<bill session="106" type="h" number="1695" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-27">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ivanpah Valley Airport Public Lands Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Ivanpah Valley Airport Public Lands Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Ivanpah Valley Airport Public Lands Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Ivanpah Valley Airport Public Lands Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Ivanpah Valley Airport Public Lands Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Ivanpah Valley Airport Public Lands Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the conveyance of certain Federal public lands in the Ivanpah Valley, Nevada, to Clark County, Nevada, for the development of an airport facility, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400372" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1999-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-10-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T17:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-471.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-11-16T17:24:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="269">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 269.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-03-08T22:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 433 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1695 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T10:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 433 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T11:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 433.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H765-773" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T11:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1695 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T11:15:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 433 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T11:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ray LaHood to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T11:15:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1695.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T11:48:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Hansen.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T12:23:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1695.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T12:23:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T12:24:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H770" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-03-09T13:38:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="37" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 420 - 1 (Roll no. 37).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09T13:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-13">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-08-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/26/2000 with amendments. With written report No. 106-394.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-08-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="770">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 770.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-10-05" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9975-9976, S9981-9982" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9981-9982" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-17T13:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gibbons moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-17T13:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-10-17T13:41:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9960-9961" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9960" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-17T13:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-17">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-10-27">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-10-27" type="public" number="106-362">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-362.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="433"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Desert conservation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Private aviation"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h590"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/5/2000--Passed Senate amended.
Ivanpah Valley Airport Public Lands Transfer Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) to convey to Clark County, Nevada, certain Federal public lands in Ivanpah Valley, Nevada, for the development of an airport facility and related infrastructure. Prohibits such conveyance from being made until: (1) the County has conducted an airspace assessment, using the airspace management plan required by this Act, to identify any potential adverse effects on access to the Las Vegas basin under visual flight rules that would result from the construction and operation of a commercial or primary airport, or both, on the land to be conveyed; (2) the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) certifies to the Secretary that such assessment is thorough and that alternatives have been developed to address each adverse effect identified in such assessment; and (3) the County has entered into an agreement with the Secretary to retain ownership of Jean Airport, located at Jean, Nevada, and to maintain and operate such Airport for general aviation purposes.Requires the Secretary to deposit payments received from the County as consideration for the conveyance of each parcel into the special account established under the Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act. Allows such funds to be expended only for the acquisition of private inholdings in the Mojave National Preserve and for the protection and management of the petroglyph resources in the County. Prohibits interest earned on amounts deposited from being invested and expended as required under such Act.Prohibits the Secretary from expending funds pursuant to this Act until: (1) the provisions of this Act regarding all actions required under the National Environmental Policy Act with respect to initial planning and construction have been completed; and (2) a final Record of Decision pursuant to such Act has been issued which permits development of an airport at the Ivanpah site.Requires such payments to be refunded to the County and such lands to revert to the United States if the FAA and the County determine that an airport should not be constructed on the conveyed lands.Withdraws the conveyed lands from mineral entry under the Mining Law of 1872 and the Mineral Leasing Act.Directs the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary, prior to such conveyance, to develop an airspace management plan for the Ivanpah Valley Airport that shall, without adversely impacting safety considerations, restrict aircraft arrivals and departures over the Mojave Desert Preserve in California.Requires: (1) prior to construction of an airport facility on the conveyed lands, all actions required under the National Environmental Policy Act with respect to initial planning and construction to be completed by the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary as joint lead agencies; and (2) any such actions to specifically address any impacts on the purposes for which the Mojave National Preserve was created.</summary>
</bill>
