<bill session="106" type="h" number="1452" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State and Local Government Economic Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create United States money in the form of noninterest bearing credit in accordance with the 1st and 5th clauses of section 8 of Article I of the Constitution of the United States, to provide for noninterest bearing loans of the money so created to State and local governments solely for the purpose of funding capital projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400228"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2000-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2000-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1999-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="1999-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1999-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400519" joined="1999-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="2000-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400329" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1999-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Checking accounts"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Money supply"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/1999--Introduced.
State and Local Government Economic Empowerment Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to have money available for purposes of this Act (i.e., the creation of non-interest-bearing Government credit funds in measured or limited increments for the purpose of funding capital and environmental projects in the public interest) in an amount equal to the product of: (1) the U.S. population, as determined by the Secretary of Commerce on the basis of the 1990 census; and (2) $1,400. Requires that the money be created by having the Secretary and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System enter into a loan agreement whereby: (1) the Board shall lend the U.S. Treasury a sum up to $360 billion at the rate of not more than $72 billion per annum (on a cumulative basis) in each of the five years commencing 60 days after this Act's enactment date; and (2) the Secretary shall pay an annual fee to the Board to cover administrative costs that the Board incurs in acting as the agent of the Administrator appointed by the Secretary. Treats any amount made available pursuant to this Act as money created in the sovereign and exclusive capacity of the United States to create money. Specifies that: (1) money created under this section shall not be treated as revenue when it is created or made available to the Administrator, nor when the loans are repaid; (2) the money created and the interest-free loan program established under this Act shall not be treated as budget authority, shall not be subject to apportionment or sequestration other than in accordance with this Act, and shall not be taken into account in the determination of the baseline for any fiscal year; and (3) the disbursement of money created under this Act shall not be treated as an outlay or a budget outlay. (Sec. 5) Entitles each State, county, township, incorporated municipality, school district, and Indian tribe to obtain a loan from the Administrator, unless such governmental unit is delinquent in repaying a prior loan, subject to specified limitations. (Sec. 6) Directs the Administrator to issue an interest-free loan from the money created to any such government unit if the Administrator obtains assurances that the proceeds will be used solely for the purpose of: (1) funding capital projects of such unit, including the construction of or improvements to school facilities, streets, water and sewer systems, and public and environmental facilities; or (2) the cleanup of toxic waste sites or other environmental improvements.</summary>
</bill>
