<bill session="104" type="h" number="2269" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Security Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To guarantee the provision of minimum child support benefits and to reform the child support enforcement system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400289"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, Banking and Financial Services, Agriculture, and Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG26" subcommittee="Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Garnishment"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/6/1995--Introduced.
Child Security Act of 1995 - Establishes a monthly child support assurance benefits program with payments made by the Secretary of Health and Human Services following prescribed guidelines. Excludes such payments from consideration as income for purposes of determining eligibility for: (1) housing benefits; or (2) food stamps. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to establish a national registry of child support orders whose functions shall include maintenance of abstracts of child support orders accessible by the Secretary of the Treasury. Amends Part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require the States to have statutorily prescribed procedures to ensure that child support orders are immediately transmitted to such registry, including the social security account number of each parent with rights or obligations under the order. (Sec. 4) Amends the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prescribe child support enforcement guidelines through wage withholding and income tax collection. Establishes the Office of the Child Advocate in the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to assist in problem resolution relating to child support enforcement by the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), and to advise on administrative practices and potential legislative changes. (Sec. 5) Prescribes guidelines for: (1) HHS distribution of child support payments collected by the IRS; and (2) the assignment of rights to past-due support. (Sec. 7) Instructs the Secretary to: (1) establish the National Child Support Guideline Commission to develop recommendations for uniform national child support guidelines; and (2) transmit Commission recommendations to the Congress. (Sec. 8) Amends part D of SSA title IV to require State plans to provide for the uniform termination of child support obligations after specified ages. (Sec. 9) Mandates that HHS: (1) promulgate a methodology to determine State staffing needs relating to child support enforcement; and (2) develop a plan detailing the steps that the State must take to meet such requirements. Mandates that State Medicaid plans require the operation of a State program for: (1) child support enforcement; and (2) Aid to Families With Dependent Children (AFDC). Increases from three percent to five percent the amount deducted from Federal assistance payments as a penalty for noncompliance. (Sec. 11) Instructs the Secretary to authorize five States to conduct five-year social services demonstration projects giving priority in job opportunities and basic skills (JOBS) training programs under part F of SSA title IV to parents unable to support their children financially.</summary>
</bill>
