<bill session="106" type="h" number="2067" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Personnel Home of Record Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require that, for purposes of the 2000 census, members of the armed forces on active duty be allocated to their home of record, and overseas military dependents be allocated to their last United States residence or, alternatively, to the same place as the member of the armed forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400351"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1999-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1999-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1164-1165"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Census.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO13" subcommittee="Census" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/1999--Introduced.
Military Personnel Home of Record Act of 1999 - Requires the Secretary of Commerce to ensure that, for purposes of the 2000 census: (1) members of the armed forces on active duty shall be allocated to their home of record, legal residence, or last permanent duty station in the United States, in that order of priority; and (2) any dependents of such a member assigned to a permanent duty station outside of the United States who are residing with such member shall be allocated to their last State or U.S. territory of residence, except that, if such dependent never resided in the United States (or a U.S. territory) and is a U.S. citizen, such dependent shall be allocated in the same manner as applies to such member.</summary>
</bill>
