<bill session="106" type="h" number="4124" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Retiree Health Care Options Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the access to military treatment facilities for retired members of the uniformed services, and their dependents, who are over 65 years of age, to provide for Medicare reimbursement for health care services provided to such persons, to permit such persons to enroll in the Federal Employees Health Benefits program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400404"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400079" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2000-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400547" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="2000-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, Commerce, and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Drugstores"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance portability"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mail-order business"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medigap"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Enrollment of Retirees in TRICARE Prime and Medicare Reimbursement Title II: FEHBP Option for Retirees Title III: Other Matters Military Retiree Health Care Options Act - Title I: Enrollment of Retirees in TRICARE Prime and Medicare Reimbursement - States that the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) may not prohibit the enrollment of Medicare-eligible military retirees in the managed care option of the TRICARE program (a Department of Defense (DOD) managed health care program) solely on account of age or entitlement to hospital insurance benefits under part A of Title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act.(Sec. 103) Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS Secretary) to jointly establish a program (subvention program) that, beginning October 1, 2000, provides DOD with reimbursement from the Medicare program for health care services provided to Medicare-eligible retirees and certain military dependents: (1) through the TRICARE program to increase the number of retirees able to enroll in the TRICARE managed care option; and (2) in a military medical treatment facility. Requires program enrollment to be voluntary. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) waive enrollment fees; (2) modify existing TRICARE program contracts to incorporate enrollment provisions; and (3) establish cost-sharing requirements for enrollees.(Sec. 104) Provides for the determination of DOD reimbursement amounts for individuals enrolled in Medicare part A and individuals not enrolled in Medicare part B.(Sec. 105) Requires the Secretary to maintain current DOD health-care efforts for Medicare-eligible retirees in order to avoid imposing added costs to the Medicare program. Requires specified estimates of prior efforts and future targets with respect to DOD health care provided under the subvention program.Directs the Comptroller General to determine and report to the two Secretaries and Congress annually on the extent, if any, to which costs of the Secretary under the TRICARE program and the HHS Secretary under the Medicare program have increased as a result of the subvention program. Requires the Secretaries to take necessary action to offset any added costs.(Sec. 106) Requires the Secretary to reimburse subvention program participants for any late enrollment penalties imposed under the Medicare part B program.(Sec. 107) Provides that, in the case of a Medicare-eligible uniformed services retiree who seeks to enroll in a Medicare supplemental policy, the issuer of such policy may not: (1) deny the issuance or effectiveness of such policy; or (2) discriminate in the policy's price.Makes eligible for: (1) the subvention program an individual who was eligible to enroll under Medicare part B and who did not enroll in the Medicare program during his or her initial enrollment period; and (2) the Medicare supplemental program an individual who was eligible to enroll under Medicare part B.Title II: FEHBP Option for Retirees - Revises provisions concerning a demonstration project which includes certain covered military retirees and their beneficiaries within the Federal Employees Health Benefits program (FEHBP) to: (1) make such program permanent (currently terminates December 31, 2002); (2) remove certain reporting requirements; and (3) remove provisions concerning the application of Medigap protections to demonstration project enrollees.(Sec. 202) Requires the health and dental care benefits provided under the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services (CHAMPUS) and TRICARE Standard to be the same as those provided for the highest level of benefits under the service benefit plan of the FEHBP.Title III: Other Matters - Directs the Secretary to: (1) expand and make permanent the DOD demonstration project for providing pharmaceuticals by mail to permit Medicare-eligible uniformed services retirees and certain military dependents to participate in such project. Prohibits fees for project participation.(Sec. 302) Directs the Secretary to issue to covered beneficiaries under the TRICARE program an enrollment card for nationwide TRICARE program participation.</summary>
</bill>
