<bill session="106" type="h" number="5659" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Personal Social Security Account Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Social Security Act provide for personal Social Security accounts and to maintain the solvency of the old-age, surviors, and disability insurance program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400590"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-12-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2185"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/14/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Personal Social Security Accounts Title II: Maintaining the Solvency of the Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance Program Personal Social Security Account Act of 2000 - Title I: Personal Social Security Accounts - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to create a new OASDI part B (Personal Social Security Accounts) program similar to the Thrift Savings Program for Federal employees for eligible individuals.Directs the Commissioner of Social Security to establish in the Personal Social Security Account Fund, which this Act establishes, a personal social security account for each eligible individual: (1) born after December 31, 1945; (2) credited for any calendar year with four quarters of coverage; and (3) who has requested such an account. Provides for: (1) deposit in such accounts of specified percentages of an individual's annual income, as well as transfers from the Social Security trust funds; (2) investment of account amounts; and (3) distribution of account balances, in either a lump sum or equal annual installments, when the account holder reaches the old-age insurance entitlement age.Title II: Maintaining the Solvency of the Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance Program - Amends SSA title II to provide for: (1) modification of indexing initial old-age or disability insurance benefits; (2) reduction of such benefits by reason of a transfer to an eligible individual's personal Social Security account; and (3) borrowing authority for the Social Security trust funds taking into account the present value of future benefit reductions.</summary>
</bill>
