<bill session="106" type="h" number="1120" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the standards for responding to import surges under section 201 of the Trade Act of 1974, to establish mechanisms for import monitoring and the prevention of circumvention of United States trade laws, and to strengthen the enforcement of United States trade remedy laws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400238"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1999-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1999-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="1999-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Antidumping"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Cartels"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Industrial productivity"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel prices"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Monopolies"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Steel"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade associations"/>
    <term name="U.S. International Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/1999--Introduced.
Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to repeal the requirement that the cause of serious injury (or threat) be substantial to the domestic industry producing an article like or directly competitive with an article that is being imported into the United States in such increased quantities with respect to the President's taking action to facilitate efforts by such industry to make a positive adjustment to the import competition. Defines "cause" to mean a cause that contributes significantly to serious injury (or threat) to the domestic industry but need not be equal to or greater than any other cause.(Sec. 1) Revises certain factors the International Trade Commission (ITC) must consider when investigating to determine whether an article is being imported into the United States in such increased quantities as to be a substantial cause of serious injury (or threat) to the domestic industry producing an article like or directly competitive with the imported article. Repeals, similarly, the requirement that such injury be substantial.Directs the ITC, when a petition filed by an industry (or a request by the President, United States Trade Representative (USTR), a resolution of specified congressional committees, or on the ITC's own motion) requesting a positive adjustment to import competition alleges that critical circumstances exist, to make a serious injury (or threat) determination with respect to such competition not later than 45 days (currently 60 days) after such petition or request is filed. Requires the President within 20 days (currently, 30 days) after receiving an affirmative determination to provide provisional relief to prevent or remedy such injury. Requires with respect to the implementation of such provisional relief that it will not have an adverse impact on the United States substantially out of proportion to the benefits of such action.Requires provisional relief recommended by the ITC to take effect upon the enactment of a joint resolution of Congress within the 60 day (currently, 90 day) period beginning on the date that the President reports to Congress on what action, if any, is to be taken.(Sec. 2) Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to authorize an entity (including a trade association, firm, certified or recognized union, or group of workers which is representative of a domestic industry that produces an article that is like or directly competitive with an imported article) to file a request to monitor to such imports, based on a petition that alleges that an article is being imported into the United States in such increased quantities as to cause serious injury (or threat) to the domestic industry. Requires the President to determine whether to monitor within 45 days after receiving a request.(Sec. 3) Authorizes the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in order to facilitate the early identification of potentially disruptive import surges, to grant an exception to the publication dates established for the release of data on U.S. international trade in goods and services in order to permit public access to preliminary international trade import data, if the Director notifies Congress of the early release of such data.(Sec. 4) Amends the Customs Procedural Reform and Simplification Act of 1978 to authorize appropriations to establish a Steel Import Monitoring and Enforcement Support Center in the Customs Service.(Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Commerce, and the ITC to establish a suffix to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States for merchandise that is subject to countervailing duty orders or antidumping duty orders.(Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary of Commerce to monitor, and report to Congress on, imports (including steel mill products and other import-sensitive products) on a monthly basis for import surges and potential unfair trade through 2000.(Sec. 7) Directs the ITC to investigate, collect information, and report to specified congressional committees on anticompetitive practices in international steel trade. Requires the ITC's findings to be included in the National Trade Estimate report.(Sec. 8) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
