<bill session="105" type="h" number="2076" updated="2012-11-01T22:48:27-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to repeal the requirement that States provide for voter registration by mail and to require applicants for voter registration to provide a Social Security number and actual proof of United States citizenship, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400154"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>06/26/1997--Introduced.
Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to: (1) repeal the requirement for States to provide for voter registration in Federal elections by mail; (2) require applicants registering to vote to provide certain additional information; (3) permit a State, at its option, to remove certain registrants from the official list of eligible voters in Federal elections; (4) permit States to require individuals (other than illiterate or disabled individuals) voting in a Federal election to produce a valid photographic identification and provide their signature before receiving a ballot; and (5) repeal the requirement that States permit certain registrants to vote at the polling place for the former address.</summary>
</bill>
