<bill session="104" type="hr" number="489" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-31T18:11:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-07-31T18:11:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2823) to amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to support the International Dolphin Conservation Program in the eastern tropical Pacific Ocean, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T16:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-708, by Mr. Goss.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-25T16:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2823 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. In lieu of the amendment recommended by the Committee on Resources now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature printed in the Congressional Record and numbered 1 pursuant to clause 6 of rule XXIII. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-07-25T16:38:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="259">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 259.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31T17:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9424-9431" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31T17:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-07-31T18:11:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-07-31T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="2823"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/1996--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 2823 (yellowfin tuna fishing and dolphin protection).</summary>
</bill>
