<bill session="104" type="h" number="165" updated="2012-11-01T22:43:38-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make Members of Congress ineligible to participate in the Federal Employees' Retirement System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405317" joined="1995-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on House Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSGO09" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Civil Service"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>01/04/1995--Introduced.
Makes a Member of Congress ineligible to participate in the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS), with the exception of any individual who, as of the enactment of this Act, satisfies the mandatory requirements for being considered eligible for an annuity. States that nothing in this Act shall prevent appropriate refunds from being made on account of an individual becoming ineligible to participate in FERS. Requires a Member who becomes ineligible to participate in FERS to be treated in the same way as if separated from service. Makes provisions of this Act inapplicable with respect to: (1) any former Member of Congress who, as of the enactment of this Act, is entitled to a FERS annuity; or (2) any individual who, as of the enactment of this Act, is entitled to any annuity as a survivor of a former Member of Congress.</summary>
</bill>
