<bill session="105" type="h" number="3851" updated="2012-11-01T22:49:11-05:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Let the Public Decide Campaign Finance Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to provide for expenditure limitations and public financing for House of Representatives general elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400300"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSRU" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Checkoff"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional powers"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Independent candidates"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Primaries"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Special elections"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Third parties (U.S. politics)"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>05/13/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Expenditure Limitations and Public Financing for House of Representatives General Elections Title II: Amendments to Internal Revenue Code of 1986 Title III: Ban on Use of Soft Money by House Candidates Title IV: Independent Expenditures Title V: Provisions Relating to House of Representatives Primary Elections Title VI: Consideration of Constitutional Amendment Let the Public Decide Campaign Finance Reform Act - Title I: Expenditure Limitations and Public Financing for House of Representatives General Elections - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to set forth specified expenditure limitations for House of Representatives general elections. Establishes in the Treasury the Grassroots Good Citizenship Fund (Fund), which shall provide public funding for House candidates' expenditures. Authorizes certain additional amounts from State and national party committees. Title II: Amendments to Internal Revenue Code of 1986 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) authorize taxpayers to designate specified overpayments and contributions for the Fund; and (2) increase corporate tax rates and use the amounts from such increase for the Fund. Title III: Ban on Use of Soft Money by House Candidates - Amends FECA to prohibit the use of non-regulated funds (soft money) by House candidates. Title IV: Independent Expenditures - Amends FECA to ban independent expenditures in House elections. Redefines "independent expenditure" to mean an expenditure for a communication, with exceptions, which: (1) is made during the 90-day period ending on the date of a general election for Federal office and which identifies a candidate for election for such office by name, image, or likeness; or (2) contains express advocacy and is made without the participation of, or consultation with, a candidate. (Sec. 402) Bars the use of funds not subject to FECA requirements (soft money) for expenditures made by: (1) an authorized committee of a candidate for Federal office or a political party committee; (2) a person who has made contributions to a candidate where the expenditure is in support of the candidate or in opposition to another candidate for the same office during the election cycle; (3) a person or a political committee controlled by such person who is required to register as a lobbyist or foreign agent under Federal law; (4) a person who has communicated with a candidate regarding activities that influence the candidate's election to Federal office where the expenditure is in support of the candidate or in opposition to another candidate for the same office during the election cycle; and (5) a person authorized to raise or expend funds on behalf of the candidate or the candidate's authorized committees or who serves as an agent of such committees in an executive or policymaking position and who is, or has been, engaged in such activities in the same election cycle. Title V: Provisions Relating to House of Representatives Primary Elections - Amends FECA to set forth specified House limitations for: (1) expenditures for elections other than general elections; and (2) acceptance of contributions from large donor multicandidate political committees. Title VI: Consideration of Constitutional Amendment - Provides for the consideration of a specified constitutional amendment if any provision or amendment of this Act is found unconstitutional.</summary>
</bill>
