<bill session="106" type="h" number="180" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Integrity in Voter Registration Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require each individual registering to vote in elections for Federal office to provide the individual's Social Security number and to permit a State to remove a registrant who fails to vote in two consecutive general elections for Federal office from the official list of eligible voters in elections for Federal office on the ground that the registrant has changed residence, if the registrant fails to respond to written notices requesting confirmation of the registrant's residence.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1999-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E39-40"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
Integrity in Voter Registration Act of 1999 - Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require applicants registering to vote in Federal elections to provide their social security numbers. Authorizes a State to remove a registrant's name from the official list of eligible voters for such elections on the grounds of changed residence if the registrant has not: (1) voted in an election during the period beginning on the day after the date of the second previous general Federal election held prior to being sent a specified notice; (2) voted in any of the first two general Federal elections after being sent a notice; and (3) responded to such notices.</summary>
</bill>
