<bill session="105" type="h" number="4670" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Women and Children's Resources Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program of formula grants to the States for programs to provide pregnant women with alternatives to abortion, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400320"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism counseling"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Childbirth"/>
    <term name="Church and social problems"/>
    <term name="Church and state"/>
    <term name="Churches"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contraceptives"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse in pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Nonmarital births"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Prenatal care"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sexual abstinence"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/1998--Introduced.
Women and Children's Resources Act - Mandates annual grants to States for programs to provide: (1) information, education, and counseling on alternatives to abortion and on sexual abstinence, pregnancy testing and follow-up services, and prenatal and postpartum health; and (2) related services, items, and assistance. Makes eligible persons who are: (1) pregnant, the parent or guardian of an infant under 12 months old, or the partner of those individuals; and (2) under a specified income level. Prohibits the programs from performing or making referrals for abortions or providing or making referrals for information, education, or counseling that presents abortion as a pregnancy option. Requires States to carry out the programs through nonprofit private entities, but excludes entities with activities during the preceding five years that present abortion as an option. (Sec. 4) Allows a State to contract with religious organizations on the same basis as any other nongovernmental provider without impairing the religious character of the organization and without diminishing the religious freedom of beneficiaries. Requires that programs be implemented consistent with the establishment clause of the Constitution. Prohibits the Federal and State Governments from discriminating against an organization on the basis that the organization has a religious character. Prohibits a contracting religious organization from discriminating against an individual on the basis of religion, religious belief, or refusal to actively participate in a religious practice. Declares that these provisions do not preempt any provision of a State constitution or State statute restricting the expenditure of State funds in or by religious organizations. (Sec. 6) Sets forth a formula for the allotment of funds to the States. (Sec. 10) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
