<bill session="108" type="hc" number="239" updated="2013-07-14T19:03:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress that the global diamond industry, as represented by the World Diamond Council, should provide transition development assistance to communities in Sierra Leone, Angola, and the Democratic Republic of Congo, where the illicit trade in conflict diamonds for arms fueled civil war, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400423"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2004-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Angola"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democratic Republic of Congo"/>
    <term name="Diamonds"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Jewelry trade"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Psychotherapy"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sierra Leone"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
    <term name="Trade associations"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Warranties"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2003--Introduced.
Conflict Diamonds Resolution - Urges the global diamond industry, as represented by the World Diamond Council, to: (1) establish a fund that supports demobilization centers and rehabilitation training programs for excombatants in the civil wars in Sierra Leone, Angola, and the Democratic Republic of Congo, particularly child soldiers, provides health care treatment, education, training, and other needs of women and girls victimized in those wars by rape, forced domestic servitude, and other gender-related abuses, helps strengthen governmental and nongovernmental health care infrastructure to support HIV/AIDS programs in such countries, supports economic development and civil society-building programs in those countries, and supports diamond training in the latest technologies to African workers; (2) establish a program through which humanitarian assistance from the diamond industry can be made available to the amputees of, and others permanently disabled by, the civil wars in such countries; (3) continue deliberations with the United Nations, governments, charitable organizations, and nongovernmental organizations in the Kimberly Process to develop a diamond certification system for rough diamonds to stem the trade in conflict diamonds; and (4) support the activities of all reconciliation processes (including the Truth and Reconciliation Commission of Sierra Leone) that will play a critical role in healing the wounds of war and promoting a lasting peace in Sierra Leone, Angola, and the Democratic Republic of Congo. Urges the Secretary of State to assist the World Diamond Council in establishing and administering the fund, and to report to the appropriate congressional committees on progress made by the Council toward addressing the goals and objectives of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
