<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="1017" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:54-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2406" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="1996-05-08T17:45:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400594"/>
  <offered datetime="1996-05-08"/>
  <description>Amendment includes technical and clarifying changes; replaces the single block grant for Federally assisted housing with two block grants, one for capital needs and the other for operating expenses; increases to 30 percent the portion of public housing units reserved for families with incomes at or below 30 percent of the area median income; requires that 50 percent of assistance provided under the new tenant-based rental assistance voucher program be received by families making 60 percent or less of area median income; caps at 30 percent of income the maximum rent that may be charged to current residents earning 30 percent or less of area median income; establishes a 30 percent rent cap for all current elderly and disabled tenants; provides for the deregulation of 300 housing authorities; allows public housing authorities to convert their housing assistance to tenant-based vouchers under certain circumstances; establishes a commission to analyze the costs of public housing to facilitate cost comparisons; requires housing authority board members who are residents of public housing to be elected by their neighbors; allows a housing authority to enter into contracts with tenants to facilitate a movement from housing assistance into self-sufficiency; and establishes a demonstration program to allow 100 housing authorities to design programs that m.ve tenants from public housing into private home ownership markets.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment made in order by the rule to make numerous technical and clarifying changes in the bill and to do the following: Increase from 25% to 30% the portion of public housing units to be reserved for families at or below 30% of the median income of the area; require that 50% of assistance provided under the rental assistance voucher program be reserved for families making at or less than 60% of the median income of an area; place a cap of 30% of income on the amount of rent charged to current residents; deregulate 300 local housing authorities over a three year period to remove restrictions on rental prices; allow local public housing authorities to convert their public housing assistance to tenant-based vouchers and to establish an independent National Commission on Housing Assistance Program Cost to analyze the total costs of federally assisted housing.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-05-08T17:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Lazio.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1996-05-08T17:45:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Lazio amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
