<bill session="106" type="h" number="2831" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Medical Services Efficiency Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure Medicare reimbursement for certain ambulance services, and to improve the efficiency of the emergency medical system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400529"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2000-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1999-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities, Resource Conservation and Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG23" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Resource Conservation and Credit" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Ambulances"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to rural areas"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Medicare Coverage of Certain Ambulance Services Title II: State Emergency Medical Services Agency Participation in Certain Federal Programs Title III: Federal Commission for Emergency Ambulance Services Title IV: Study and Report Regarding Consolidation of Federal Authority Over Emergency Medical Services Emergency Medical Services Efficiency Act of 1999 - Title I: Medicare Coverage of Certain Ambulance Services - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to ensure Medicare reimbursement for ambulance services rendered because of the sudden onset of a medical condition manifested by symptoms believed to be serious but whose ultimate diagnosis results in the conclusion that the ambulance services were not necessary.Title II: State Emergency Medical Services Agency Participation in Certain Federal Programs - Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to include State emergency medical services agencies among the entities eligible for financial assistance with regard to telemedicine and distance learning services in rural areas.Amends the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 to allow a State emergency medical services agency to participate in the Informatics, Telemedicine, and Education Demonstration Project as part of an eligible health care provider telemedicine network (consortium).Title III: Federal Commission for Emergency Ambulance Services - Establishes the Federal Commission for Emergency Ambulance Services to study and report to the President and Congress on all matters relating to emergency ambulance services, including any existing or proposed Federal department or agency rules that impact such services, together with recommendations for improving such matters. Provides for Commission funding.Title IV: Study and Report Regarding Consolidation of Federal Authority Over Emergency Medical Services - Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to the President and Congress on the consolidation of Federal authority over emergency medical services in a single Federal agency, together with appropriate recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
