<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="933" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="4137" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2008-02-07T14:03:00-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-02-07"/>
  <description>Amendment makes technical changes to the bill, as well as changes to the provisions on college costs to a more consumer friendly approach, while keeping the focus on accountability; revises the definition of the state funds that count toward meeting the State Maintenance of Effort requirement; revises a technical amendment to Pell grant funding; modifies the Cohort Default Rate provisions to provide for a transition period before the new sanctions are imposed and provides for targeted technical assistance to schools in danger of losing their federal student aid as a result of high Cohort Default Rates; provides assurances that students will be aware of lower-cost federal student aid options before turning to more expensive private loans and a means to help students avoid potentially compromising their federal aid eligibility by inadvertently relying on private student loans or borrowing excess amounts of private student loans; and includes studies.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 110-523 to make technical changes to the bill, as well as changes to the provisions on college costs to a more consumer friendly approach, while keeping the focus on accountability; revises the definition of the state funds that count toward meeting the State Maintenance of Effort requirement; revises a technical amendment to Pell grant funding; modifies the Cohort Default Rate provisions to provide for a transition period before the new sanctions are imposed and provides for targeted technical assistance to schools in danger of losing their federal student aid as a result of high Cohort Default Rates; provides assurances that students will be aware of lower-cost federal student aid options before turning to more expensive private loans and a means to help students avoid potentially compromising their federal aid eligibility by inadvertently relying on private student loans or borrowing excess amounts of private student loans; and includes studies.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-07T13:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. George Miller.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H736-751" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H736-749" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2008-02-07T14:03:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Miller, George amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
