<bill session="108" type="h" number="2652" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Internet Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to the sale of prescription drugs through the Internet.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2003--Introduced.
Internet Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prohibit any person from introducing a prescription drug into interstate commerce or delivering such a drug for introduction into commerce pursuant to a sale if: (1) any part of the sales transaction for the drug is conducted through an Internet site; and (2) such site, or any other Internet site used by such person for purposes of sales of a prescription drug, fails to meet specified requirements regarding inclusion of a page (and links thereto) providing the identities of the seller and the persons serving as pharmacists or medical consultants and the States in which the seller and such persons are authorized to dispense drugs or provide consultations.Provides that a State that has in effect requirements for Internet sites that are no less stringent and that has adequate procedures for their enforcement shall have primary enforcement responsibility for any violation involving such a purchase made from within the State.</summary>
</bill>
