<bill session="105" type="h" number="4336" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish an initiative for food and other assistance for individuals in Indonesia and Southeast Asia who are affected by the Asian financial crisis.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-07-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6423-6424"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Business cycles"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/1998--Introduced.
Directs the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (AID) to establish an initiative for food and other assistance for individuals in Indonesia and Southeast Asia affected by the Asian financial crisis. Directs the Administrator of AID, in carrying out the food security elements of the initiative, to: (1) establish, where appropriate, agricultural commodity distribution technical assistance, agricultural research, extension, farmer-to-farmer, and food assistance programs; and (2) provide assistance to nongovernmental organizations, including private voluntary organizations and cooperatives, for programs (of up to four years in duration) to provide food assistance under this Act. Earmarks certain developmental and agricultural assistance and economic support fund assistance for the food security initiative, including assistance for: (1) food, medical, fuel, and other shortages in Indonesia and Southeast Asia; (2) developing political institutions and parties in Indonesia and Southeast Asia; (3) improvement of transparency and regulation of banking, financial, insurance, and securities institutions; and (4) support of legal and judicial reforms. Requires that at least 80 percent of the assistance to Indonesia be administered or distributed through indigenous nongovernmental or private voluntary organizations.</summary>
</bill>
