<bill session="104" type="hr" number="401" updated="2012-11-01T22:43:20-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-16T00:01:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-04-16T00:01:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Directing the Office of Compliance to provide educational assistance to employing offices of the House of Representatives regarding compliance with the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 and requiring employing offices of the House of Representatives to obtain the prior approval of the chairman and the ranking minority party member of the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives of the amount of any settlement payments made under such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-15T23:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-15T23:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (4/15/1996 CR H3341-3343)</text>
      <reference ref="4/15/1996 CR H3341-3343" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-15T23:57:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1996-04-16T00:01:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-16T00:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee-management relations in government"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>04/15/1996--Introduced.
Requires the Office of Compliance, through interpretive bulletins, advisory opinions, and other methods, to provide educational assistance to employing offices of the House of Representatives in the same manner and to no lesser an extent than such assistance is provided to other employees through the Department of Labor with respect to laws made applicable to such offices under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995. Prohibits the Office's employees who provide such assistance from participating in deciding complaints or petitions for review filed under such Act. Requires the joint approval of the chairman and the ranking minority party member of the House Committee on House Oversight regarding the amount of any settlement payment before a House employing office may enter into any settlement of a complaint under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
