<bill session="104" type="h" number="30" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Housing and Community Development Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Community Partnerships Against Crime Act of 1994</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">National Homeownership Fund Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Housing Assistance Amendments Act of 1994</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend and extend certain laws relating to housing and community development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404634"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation in crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Community policing"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Condominium (Housing)"/>
    <term name="Congregate housing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Displaced homemakers"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Eviction"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government National Mortgage Association"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Home equity loans"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Housing codes"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Housing for the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Housing management"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interagency Council on the Homeless"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Moderate income housing"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Prefabricated buildings"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public service employment"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Smoke detectors"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban housing"/>
    <term name="Urban renewal"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Vandalism"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Housing Assistance Subtitle A: Public and Indian Housing Subtitle B: Section 8 Rental Assistance Subtitle C: Homeownership Programs Subtitle D: Home Investment Partnerships Subtitle E: Supportive Housing Programs Subtitle F: Mortgage Insurance and Secondary Mortgage Market Title II: Community Development Title III: Homeless Assistance Subtitle A: Reorganization of Certain McKinney Act Housing Provisions Subtitle B: Other Housing Assistance Programs for the Homeless Under McKinney Act Subtitle C: Miscellaneous Homeless Housing Provisions Title IV: Rural Housing Programs Title V: Authorizations of Appropriations Housing and Community Development Act of 1995 - Title I: Housing Assistance - Subtitle A: Public and Indian Housing - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to revise public housing ceiling rent provisions. (Sec. 109) Authorizes: (1) the use of modernization funds for replacement housing; and (2) public housing agencies to leverage amounts for replacement and modernization. (Sec. 111) Revises public housing demolition and disposition provisions. (Sec. 112) Increases maximum planning grant amounts under the distressed housing revitalization program. Revises related implementation grant provisions. (Sec. 113) Applies specified public housing provisions to Indian housing. (Sec. 115) Community Partnerships Against Crime Act of 1994 - Amends the Anti-Drug Abuse Act of 1988 to include "adjacent premises" within the scope of the public housing drug-related crime elimination program. (Sec. 116) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to increase maximum amounts available and extend funding availability to a public housing agency for resident opportunity assistance (currently resident management technical assistance and training). Subtitle B: Section 8 Rental Assistance - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to merge the section 8 certificate and voucher rental assistance programs into a single rental assistance program. Sets forth program provisions. (Sec. 122) Authorizes incentives to refinance high interest rate mortgages for section 8 projects. (Sec. 124) Authorizes renewal of expiring section 8 contracts. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 125) Provides for the conversion of assistance for the Tamaqua Highrise housing project in Tamaqua, Pennsylvania, from a leased housing contract to tenant-based assistance. Deems specified dwelling units in Perth Amboy and New Brunswick, New Jersey, to be in compliance with certain rehabilitation requirements. Subtitle C: Homeownership Programs - National Homeownership Fund Act - Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to replace the current National Homeownership Trust Demonstration with a National Homeownership Fund program which shall make grants to States, housing finance agencies, and nonprofit housing intermediaries for first-time homebuyer assistance in the forms of: (1) downpayment assistance; (2) second mortgage assistance; (3) revolving loan fund capitalization; and (4) interest rate buydowns. (Sec. 133) Amends the Housing and Commodity Development Act of 1992 to revise non-federally owned or assisted housing eligibility for residential lead-based paint reduction assistance. Extends authorization of appropriations for Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) lead exposure research. (Sec. 134) Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to extend the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation affordable housing program. Subtitle D: Home Investment Partnerships - Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to increase the eligible uses of HOME investment partnerships. Subtitle E: Supportive Housing Programs - Amends the Housing Act of 1959 to permit supportive housing for the elderly assistance to be used for elder cottage housing units. Redefines "frail elderly." Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to repeal the elder cottage housing unit demonstration program. (Sec. 152) Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to make public housing agencies eligible sponsors under the supportive housing for persons with disabilities program. (Sec. 153) Revises: (1) meal fee and matching amounts under the revised congregate services program; and (2) contribution amounts under the supportive housing assistance for elderly independence program. Subtitle F: Mortgage Insurance and Secondary Mortgage Market - Amends the National Housing Act to extend multifamily housing mortgage loan provisions. (Sec. 162) Revises refinancing provisions for HUD-held mortgages. (Sec. 163) Authorizes the delegation of single family mortgage insuring authority to direct endorsement mortgages. Title II: Community Development - Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to extend community development block grant (CDBE) assistance for colonias. (Sec. 205) Authorizes a colonias assistance program, including model programs. (Sec. 206) Increases eligible activities under the youth build program. Gives priority to applicants supplementing grant amounts. Title III: Homeless Assistance - Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Housing Assistance Amendments Act of 1994 - Subtitle A: Reorganization of Certain McKinney Act Housing Provisions - Amends the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act to establish a flexible grant program including: (1) homelessness prevention; (2) emergency shelter; (3) supportive housing; (4) safe havens; (5) shelter plus care; and (6) innovative homeless initiatives. Subtitle B: Other Housing Assistance Programs for the Homeless Under McKinney Act - Amends the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act to establish a program of section 8 assistance for shelter plus care single room occupancy dwellings. Authorizes appropriations. Subtitle C: Miscellaneous Homeless Housing Provisions - Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to provide for the elimination of unfit transient facilities. Title IV: Rural Housing - Amends the Housing Act of 1949 to authorize appropriations for specified rural housing and related programs. (Sec. 402) Makes Indians eligible for rural housing programs. (Sec. 404) Revises rural homeownership loan and rental housing provisions. (Sec. 407) Extends set-aside authority for underserved areas. Increases set-asides for colonias. Revises underserved area designation criteria. (Sec. 409) Reduces the maximum term of rural rental housing loans. Extends non-profit set-aside authority. Authorizes mortgage modifications, including an expedited refinancing procedure. (Sec. 410) Authorizes the optional conversion of rental assistance payments to operating subsidies for migrant farmworker projects. (Sec. 413) Authorizes loan guarantees through FY 1996 for multifamily rural rental housing. Sets forth related provisions. Title V: Authorization of Appropriations - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to increase aggregate low-income housing budget authority. Sets forth obligations for specified housing programs. (Sec. 502) Authorizes appropriations for lower-income housing. (Sec. 503) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to authorize appropriations for Indian housing loan guarantees. (Sec. 504) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to: (1) extend set-asides for new construction of projects for disabled families; (2) reduce annual emergency modernization funds; and (3) authorize appropriations for family investment centers. (Sec. 507) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to authorize appropriations for federally assisted multifamily housing. (Sec. 508) Amends the Anti-Drug Abuse Act of 1988 to authorize appropriations for the community partnerships against crime program. (Sec. 509) Amends the Housing and Urban-Rural Recovery Act of 1983 to authorize appropriations for the early childhood development program. (Sec. 511) Amends the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 to extend and authorize appropriations for specified housing counseling programs. (Sec. 513) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to authorize appropriations for supportive housing for the elderly and for persons with disabilities. (Sec. 514) Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to: (1) authorize appropriations for congregate and supportive services; (2) increase budget authority for section 8 assistance under the United States Housing Act of 1937; (3) authorize appropriations for housing opportunities for persons with AIDS; and (4) authorize appropriations for the National Homeownership Fund. (Sec. 518) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 to authorize appropriations for low-income housing preservation, including technical assistance and capacity building set-asides. (Sec. 519) Amends the Housing and Community Development Amendments of 1978 to authorize appropriations for the flexible subsidy program. (Sec. 520) Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to authorize appropriations for: (1) the home investment partnerships program; and (2) the youth build program. (Sec. 521) Amends the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993 to authorize appropriations for the community investment demonstration program. (Sec. 523) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to authorize appropriations for: (1) community development block grants; (2) real property loan guarantees; (3) special purpose grants; and (4) economic development grants. (Sec. 525) Amends the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation Act to authorize appropriations for the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation. (Sec. 526) Amends the Housing and Urban-Rural Recovery Act of 1983 to authorize appropriations for the John Heinz neighborhood development program. (Sec. 527) Authorizes appropriations for colonias assistance. (Sec. 528) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to: (1) extend loan and mortgage insurance authority under the New Towns demonstration program for emergency relief of Los Angeles; (2) authorize appropriations for second mortgage assistance; and (3) authorize appropriations for community development assistance. (Sec. 529) Amends the National Housing Act to extend FHA mortgage insurance authority. (Sec. 530) Amends the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act to extend GNMA mortgage guarantee authority. (Sec. 532) Amends the Housing and Urban Development Act to authorize appropriations for housing research and development. (Sec. 533) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to authorize appropriations for residential lead-based paint hazard reduction, including technical assistance and capacity building, and research set-asides. (Sec. 534) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 to authorize appropriations and specified set-asides for the fair housing initiatives program. (Sec. 535) Authorizes appropriations for: (1) the National American Indian Housing Council and (2) the Housing Assistance Council. (Sec. 537) Amends the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act to: (1) authorize appropriations for the flexible block grant program; (2) increase budget authority for section 8 assistance for single room occupancy dwellings; (3) authorize appropriations for section 8 assistance for shelter plus care single room occupancy dwellings; (4) authorize appropriations for the rural homelessness program; (5) extend and authorize appropriations for the Interagency Council on the Homeless; and (6) authorize appropriations for the Federal Emergency Management Agency food and shelter program.</summary>
</bill>
