<bill session="106" type="h" number="2732" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Instant Notification System Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require State and local law enforcement authorities and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms to be immediately notified when the national instant criminal background check system determines that a person is ineligible to receive a handgun.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400518"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="1999-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1999-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
The National Instant Notification System Act of 1999 - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to require the national instant criminal background check system, if it determines that receipt of the firearm by the person would violate such Act or State law, to immediately notify the State and local law enforcement authorities willing to accept the information and the appropriate field office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms of: (1) the determination (including why the receipt would constitute such a violation); (2) identifying information about the person; and (3) the location of the licensee involved. Specifies that neither a government nor an employee of a government responsible for providing a notice or information under this Act shall be liable in an action at law for damages for failure to so provide the notice or information.</summary>
</bill>
