<bill session="108" type="h" number="2432" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-18T19:29:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-18T19:29:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Paperwork and Regulatory Improvements Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Paperwork and Regulatory Improvements Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Paperwork and Regulatory Improvements Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Paperwork Reduction Act and titles 5 and 31, United States Code, to reform Federal paperwork and regulatory processes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2003-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="2003-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400200" joined="2003-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="2003-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2003-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2003-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="2003-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400362" joined="2003-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2003-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1221-1222"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy Policy, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy Policy, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-05-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-05-14T19:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 108-490, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-14T19:54:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on The Budget Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than May 14, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-14T19:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on The Budget discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-14T19:56:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="277">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 277.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>PERMISSION TO FILE REPORT - Mr. Murphy asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Government Reform be permitted to file a supplemental report on H.R. 2432. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Government Reform, H. Rept. 108-490, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17T22:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 645 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2728, H.R. 2729, H.R. 2730, H.R. 2731 and H.R. 2432.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 645 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 645.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3141-3160" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3152-3153" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2728, H.R. 2729, H.R. 2730, H.R. 2731 and H.R. 2432.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T17:10:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 645 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T17:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Robert B. Aderholt to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T17:11:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2432.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T18:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ose amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Waxman amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2432.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T19:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3160" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T19:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-05-18T19:29:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="188" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 373 - 54 (Roll no. 188).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T19:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T19:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 645, H.R. 2432 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSGO01" subcommittee="Energy Policy, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="645"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="hr" number="645"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2728"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Apples"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commodity Credit Corporation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal budget process"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h530"/>
    <amendment number="h531"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/18/2004--Passed House amended.
Paperwork and Regulatory Improvements Act of 2004 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Paperwork Reduction Act to: (1) require the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), in consultation with the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) and the Office of Tax Policy of the Department of the Treasury and the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration, in minimizing the Federal information collection burden, to conduct a review of the collections of information by the IRS to identify actions that it can take to reduce the information collection burden imposed on small business concerns, consistent with current Federal law requiring the task force on information collection and dissemination to examine the feasibility of requiring Federal agencies to consolidate requirements regarding collections of information with respect to small business concerns within and across such agencies; and (2) include the results of such review in the annual report submitted to Congress for FY 2006 on the major activities respecting Federal information policy. (Sec. 4) Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to repeal specified exemptions from Paperwork Reduction Act requirements and certain other rulemaking requirements. Makes the repeal of such exemptions effective 180 days after the enactment of this Act. (Sec. 5) Amends the Truth in Regulating Act of 2000 to make permanent the authority of a chairman or ranking member of a congressional committee to request the Comptroller General to perform a regulatory analysis of an economically significant rule upon agency publication. (Sec. 6) Amends the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2001 to instruct the Director of OMB, in carrying out requirements for the accounting statement and associated report submitted to Congress with the Federal budget submitted to the President, to require each agency annually to submit to OMB an estimate of the total annual costs and benefits of Federal rules and paperwork to the extent feasible for the agency and each agency program. Requires the Director, after consultation with the head of each agency, to designate at least three agencies (or offices within an agency) to participate in a study on regulatory budgeting for FY 2006 and 2007, including three regulatory agencies or offices from among the Department of Labor, the Department of Transportation, the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Environmental Protection Agency. Requires such study to address the preparation of regulatory budgets and such budgets to include the presentation of the varying estimated levels of benefits that would be associated with the different estimated levels of costs with respect to the regulatory alternatives under consideration by the agency (or office within the agency). Includes in the accounting statement and associated report submitted to Congress for calendar year 2006 a presentation of the different levels of estimated regulatory benefits and costs with respect to the regulatory alternatives under consideration for at least one of the major regulatory programs of each of the designated agencies. Requires the Director, after consultation with the Committees on the Budget and on Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committees on the Budget and on Governmental Affairs of the Senate, to include in such statement and report submitted to Congress for calendar year 2009 a report on the study which: (1) assesses the feasibility and advisability of including a regulatory budget as part of the Federal budget submitted to the President; (2) describes any difficulties encountered by OMB and the participating agencies in conducting such study; and (3) recommends, to the extent the President considers necessary or expedient, proposed legislation regarding regulatory budgets. Requires such report to also be submitted directly to such congressional committees.</summary>
</bill>
