<bill session="104" type="h" number="3805" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sports Relocation Reform Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish procedures and remedies governing the relocation of certain professional sports teams, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400549"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1996-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1996-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1996-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="1996-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Basketball"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Football"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hockey"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Location of industries"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Stadiums"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting of sports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/1996--Introduced.
Sports Relocation Reform Act of 1996 - Authorizes any U.S. professional sports league to establish a rule: (1) authorizing the league membership to decide whether or not a member team may be relocated; and (2) requiring that any person seeking to change the home territory of a member team obtain league approval. Makes the antitrust laws inapplicable to the enforcement or application of any such rules. Outlines procedural requirements for requests for approval of a proposed relocation, requiring each league to establish rules and procedures governing such requests. Outlines criteria to be considered during such process, including fan loyalty and the extent to which the requesting team has entered into good faith negotiations of terms and conditions required to continue to play in the current territory. Requires the league to conduct hearings in which interested parties are afforded an opportunity to submit written testimony and exhibits. Provides for judicial review through a civil action filed in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia, with an exception for a team located in the District of Columbia area. Authorizes such Court to remand the matter for further consideration by the league and enjoin any relocation until the league has completed such reconsideration. Prohibits multiple lawsuits by other interested parties.</summary>
</bill>
