<bill session="104" type="h" number="2323" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State and Local Government Interstate Waste Control Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize State and local governments to prohibit or restrict the receipt of out-of-State municipal solid waste, to authorize local governments to control and direct the movement of certain solid waste, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400307"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="1995-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="402657" joined="1995-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1996-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1995-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1995-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1995-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404996" joined="1995-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1995-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="1996-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1995-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1995-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400520" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400374" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="411247" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1995-11-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compost"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Newspapers"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court decisions"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Interstate Waste Title II: Flow Control State and Local Government Interstate Waste Control Act of 1995 - Title I: Interstate Waste - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit a landfill or incinerator from receiving out-of-State municipal solid waste (OSW) for disposal or incineration unless the waste is received pursuant to a new (entered into on or after enactment of this Act) or existing host community agreement or an exemption from this prohibition (which may be limited by the State, as provided in this Act). Requires owners or operators to make specified information regarding the landfill or incinerator (facility) available prior to seeking authorization from an affected local government to receive such waste pursuant to a new host community agreement. Sets forth other formal requirements for the authorization process, including those for notification of the State, contiguous local governments, and contiguous Indian tribes. Requires, for an exemption, that the owner or operator provide either information establishing that: (1) the owner or operator of the facility received before enactment of this Act a State permit specifically authorizing acceptance of the waste; or (2) the facility received shipments of such waste during 1993, and such information is in such documented form as would result in criminal penalties under State law in case of false or misleading information. Authorizes States to establish limits on the amount of OSW received annually for disposal at each facility pursuant to an exemption for documented shipments (under paragraph (2), above) and affected local governments to limit the amount received at a particular facility pursuant to such an exemption. Sets the limitation amount for any facility that began receiving documented OSW before enactment of this Act at the amount received during 1993. Authorizes States that imported more than 750,000 tons of such waste in 1993, in lieu of this freeze, to establish limits for calendar years after 1996 that are percentages of the waste received during 1993, beginning with 85 percent in 1997 and declining to 50 percent after 2000. Allows any comprehensive solid waste management plan approved under Federal or State law and any implementation of such plan through the State permitting process to take into account local regional needs for solid waste disposal capacity. Allows an affected local government to determine that there is no need for a new landfill or incinerator or major modification at an existing facility under its jurisdiction, but prohibits a plan from expressly prohibiting importation of solid waste from out of State. Declares that prohibitions, limitations, and the planning and permitting processes under, and laws and regulations implementing, this Act shall not be considered to impose an undue burden on or to otherwise impair, restrain, or discriminate against interstate commerce. Requires owners or operators of facilities to annually report to Governors of the States in which the facilities are located the amount of OSW received during the preceding year. Title II: Flow Control - Authorizes States and political subdivisions to exercise flow control authority for municipal solid waste and recyclable materials voluntarily relinquished by the owner or generator (recyclables), directing such waste and materials to particular waste management or recyclables facilities designated and in operation on May 15, 1994, if: (1) the waste and recyclables are generated within the jurisdictional boundaries of the State or subdivision, determined as of May 15, 1994; and (2) such authority is imposed through the adoption or execution of a law, regulation, or other legally binding provision or official act of the State or subdivision that was in effect on May 15, 1994, or would have been in effect on such date but for the issuance of an injunction or other court order based on a ruling that the law or provision violated the Commerce Clause of the Constitution. Permits the exercise of such authority for only the classes or categories of waste or recyclables to which flow control authority was applicable on May 15, 1994, or immediately before the effective date of an injunction or other court order referred to above and only if the facility received municipal solid waste in those classes or categories prior to May 15, 1994, or the effective date of the injunction or court order. Authorizes States and political subdivisions to exercise such authority with respect to facilities other than those designated and in operation on May 15, 1994, if, in addition, the State or subdivision has taken one or more of specified actions (relating to permits, execution of contracts and agreements, and presentation of revenue bonds) prior to such date to commit to the designation of such facilities. Sets limits on the duration of flow control authority. Permits States or political subdivisions, upon the request of a municipal solid waste or recyclables generator, to authorize the diversion of waste generated by such generator to a solid waste facility other than the designated facility. Prohibits a State or local government from requiring any generator or transporter to transport, or deliver for transportation, such waste or materials to any site listed on the National Priorities List established under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, unless the generator or transporter has been indemnified by the government against all liability under that Act with respect to such materials. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to study and report to the Congress on the extent to which the Supreme Court decision in C &amp; A Carbone v. Clarkstown, New York has affected the ability of public and private entities to secure or retain financing for solid waste management facilities or services and is likely to interfere with the implementation of State solid waste management plans, recycling, or composting.</summary>
</bill>
