<bill session="108" type="h" number="5387" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wauconda Technical and Environmental Remediation Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide remedial actions and other assistance to affected residents near the Wauconda Sand and Gravel Superfund Site.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400085"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Vinyl chloride"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wells"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2004--Introduced.
Wauconda Technical and Environmental Remediation Act of 2004 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) provide bottled water to individuals living within a 1.5-mile radius of the Wauconda Sand and Gravel Superfund site in Lake County, Illinois (Wauconda residents) who are served by residential wells with any contamination of vinyl chloride; and (2) increase testing and monitoring of such wells. States that nothing in this Act may be construed to relieve the Administrator, other Federal agency heads, or potentially liable parties of legal liability with respect to site cleanup. Directs the Administrator to: (1) study possible long-term solutions to remediate the site and provide a clean drinking water source for Wauconda residents; and (2) recommend and implement a long-term solution to provide a clean drinking water source for such residents. Requires the Administrator to work with the heads of other appropriate Federal and State agencies to seek a comprehensive resolution to the short- and long-term environmental and health problems related to the site.</summary>
</bill>
