<bill session="104" type="h" number="2149" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-01T18:27:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-05-01T18:27:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ocean Shipping Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Ocean Shipping Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce regulation, promote efficiencies, and encourage competition in the international ocean transportation system of the United States, to eliminate the Federal Maritime Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1995-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1995-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1995-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1995-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Prior to Introduction and Referral (Feb 2, 95).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held and Forwarded to Full Committee an Original Measure by the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Prior to Introduction.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-08-02">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29T15:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Coble asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Transportation have until midnight on Oct. 6 to file a report on H.R. 2149. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-01T16:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 104-303.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-11-01T16:20:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="156">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 156.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-04-30T19:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 419 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2149 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without installowed. The rule provides for the consideration of a manager's amendment to be printed in part 1 of the report of the Committee on Rules to accompany the resoulution, which is considered as read, may amend portions of the bill not yet read for amendment, is debatable for 10 minutes. If adopted, the amendment is considered as part of the base text for further amendment purposes. Additionally, the rule waives clause 7 of rule XVI (germaneness) against the manager's amendment printed in part 1 of the report. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 419 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 419.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4335-4355" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2149 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without instruction is allowed. The rule provides for the consideration of a manager's amendment to be printed in part 1 of the report of the Committee on Rules to accompany the resolution, which is considered as read, may amend portions of the bill not yet read for amendment, is debatable for 10 minutes. If adopted, the amendment is considered as part of the base text for further amendment purposes. Additionally, the rule waives clause 7 of rule XVI (germaneness) against the manager's amendment printed in part 1 of the report. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 419 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ralph Regula to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 419, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Shuster amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01T18:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2149.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-05-01T18:27:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="144" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 182 (Roll no. 144).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="419"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1081"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1356"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Business intelligence"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Maritime Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freight forwarders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ownership"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine insurance"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Merchant marine"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Shipping agreements"/>
    <term name="Shipping conferences"/>
    <term name="Shipping rates"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tugboats"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1002"/>
    <amendment number="h1003"/>
    <amendment number="h1004"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/1/1996--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Ocean Shipping Reform Title II: Controlled Carriers Amendments Title III: Elimination of the Federal Maritime Commission Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions Ocean Shipping Reform Act of 1995 - Title I: Ocean Shipping Reform - Amends the Shipping Act of 1984 to include as one of its purposes the granting of authority to carriers and shippers to develop transportation arrangements to meet their specific needs. (Sec. 102) Redefines the term "conference," with respect to an association of ocean carriers permitted, pursuant to an approved agreement, to engage in concerted activity, to change "common tariff," which they all utilize, to "common schedule of transportation rates, charges, classifications, rules, and practices." Defines ocean freight forwarder and shippers' association. (Sec. 103) Revises the scope of the Shipping Act of 1984, with respect to certain agreements by or among ocean common carriers, to: (1) substitute "ocean freight forwarders" for "non-vessel-operating common carriers" in exclusive, preferential, or cooperative working arrangements with ocean common carriers covered by the Act; and (2) cover agreements that discuss any matter related to ocean transportation contracts, and enter ocean transportation contracts and agreements related to those contracts. Repeals coverage of agreements to regulate or prohibit the use of service contracts. (Sec. 104) Revises provisions relating to individual and independent actions on certain matters by members of a shipping conference agreement. (Sec. 106) Repeals the mandate for an automated tariff filing and information system. Revises provisions relating to: (1) schedules of transportation rates, terms, and conditions of common carriers and conferences for transportation services not governed by an ocean transportation contract; (2) ocean transportation contracts between one or more common carriers and a conference and one or more shippers; and (3) prohibited acts by persons or common carriers with respect to the provision of ocean transportation services. (Sec. 109) Amends the Foreign Shipping Practices Act of 1988 with respect to actions that the Federal Maritime Commission (FMC) may take against foreign carriers whose practices in a foreign country result in conditions that adversely affect U.S. carriers in the oceanborne trade, and do not exist for foreign carriers of that country in the United States. (Sec. 110) Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to request the Secretary of the Treasury to refuse or revoke any clearance required for a common carrier vessel if such carrier fails to supply certain information in an FMC investigation or adjudicatory proceeding. (Sec. 114) Revises certain license and bond requirements with respect to ocean freight forwarders. Prohibits a conference or group of two or more ocean common carriers in foreign commerce that is authorized to agree upon the compensation paid to an ocean freight forwarder from: (1) denying to any member of such group or conference the right to take independent action on compensation paid to an ocean freight forwarder; or (2) agreeing to limit such compensation to less than 1.25 percent of the aggregate of all rates applicable and assessed under a common schedule of transportation rates against the cargo concerned. (Sec. 117) Requires marine terminal operators to make available to the public any schedules of rates, regulations, and practices, including limitations of liability, pertaining to receiving, delivering, handling, or storing property at its marine terminal. Title II: Controlled Carriers Amendments - Revises provisions concerning the unjustness and unreasonableness of controlled carrier rates. (Sec. 201) Declares that the rate standards, information submissions, remedies, reviews, and penalties under the Shipping Act of 1984 shall apply to ocean common carriers that are not controlled, but which have been determined by the Secretary to be structurally or financially affiliated with nontransportation entities or organizations (government or private) in such a way as to affect their pricing or marketplace behavior in an unfair, predatory, or anticompetitive way that disadvantages U.S. carriers. Requires the Secretary to prescribe regulations governing submission of price and other information to enable the Secretary to determine whether prices charged by controlled and non-controlled carriers are unfair, predatory, or anticompetitive. Prohibits disclosure or publication of such information (except for administrative, judicial, or congressional purposes) if the information does not result in a finding of violation or in an enforcement action. (Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary to develop, and submit to the Congress, a negotiation strategy to persuade foreign governments to divest themselves of ownership and control of ocean common carriers. (Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary to report annually to the Congress on: (1) certain actions of the Secretary under the Foreign Shipping Practices Act of 1988 and the Shipping Act of 1984; and (2) the effect on U.S. maritime employment of the laws and practices of foreign governments and foreign carriers, or other persons providing maritime services in a foreign country, that adversely affect the operations of U.S. carriers in U.S. oceanborne trade. Title III: Elimination of the Federal Maritime Commission - Terminates, and transfers to the Secretary, all functions of the FMC on September 30, 1997. Authorizes appropriations to the FMC for FY 1997. Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions - Directs the Secretary of the Navy to transfer six specified obsolete Navy tugboats to the Northeast Wisconsin Railroad Transportation Commission.</summary>
</bill>
