<bill session="106" type="h" number="2309" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Independent Medical Review Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require group health plans and health insurance issuers to provide independent review of adverse coverage determinations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/1999--Introduced.
Independent Medical Review Act of 1999 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to require group health plans and health insurance issuers to provide for independent review of adverse coverage determinations.Requires group health plan claims procedures to include procedures for a fair, de novo determination of medical necessity by the independent review organization without regard to the definition used by the plan, as well as notifications to participants or beneficiaries of their rights to: (1) appeal adverse determinations to utilization review agents of the plan; (2) appeal adverse determinations of such utilization review agents to independent review organizations (with procedures for such appeal); and (3) obtain immediate review by an independent review organization in cases of life-threatening conditions (with procedures for obtaining such review).Sets forth requirements for: (1) procedures for appeals of adverse decisions to the plan's utilization review agent; (2) the independent review process; and (3) certification of independent review organizations by the Secretary of Labor.Treats the independent review organization's determination as the final decision of the plan, but allows a court to vacate or modify such determination under certain circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
