<bill session="106" type="hj" number="43" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Disapproving the certification of the President under section 490(b) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 regarding foreign assistance for Mexico during fiscal year 1999.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="1999-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1999-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/1999--Introduced.
Disapproves the President's determination contained in the foreign assistance certification submitted to the Congress on February 26, 1999, that Mexico has cooperated fully with the United States to achieve full compliance with the goals and objectives established by the United Nations Convention Against Illicit Traffic in Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances. Makes the requirement to withhold U.S. assistance and to vote against multilateral development bank assistance contained in the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 inapplicable with respect to Mexico until March 1, 2000, if at any time after the date of this Act's enactment the President submits to Congress a determination and certification consistent with that Act that the vital national interests of the United States require that the assistance be provided for Mexico and that the United States not vote against multilateral development bank assistance for Mexico. Deems this Act to have been enacted within 30 calendar days after February 26, 1999, for purposes of certification provisions.</summary>
</bill>
