<bill session="105" type="h" number="3144" updated="2012-11-01T22:48:59-05:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Caring for Children Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide additional tax relief to families to increase the affordability of child care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="409087" joined="1998-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1998-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, Government Reform and Oversight, House Oversight, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Child care block grants"/>
    <term name="Child care workers"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community centers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>02/03/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Tax Relief to Increase Child Care Affordability Title II: Encouraging Quality Child Care Subtitle A: Dissemination of Information About Quality Child Care Subtitle B: Increased Enforcement of State Health and Safety Standards Subtitle C: Removal of Barriers to Increasing the Supply of Quality Child Care Subtitle D: Quality Child Care Through Federal Facilities and Programs Caring for Children Act - Title I: Tax Relief to Increase Child Care Affordability - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the percentage of dependent care expenses (if the expenses are incurred to enable the taxpayer to be employed (employment-related expenses)) allowed as a credit. Deems a taxpayer who has one or more children under the age of four to have employment-related expenses of specified amounts, notwithstanding provisions limiting expenses to the amount of earned income. (Sec. 102) Mandates a program to promote employer use of dependent care assistance programs. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 103) Allows a credit to employers for employer-provided child care expenses, including acquisition, construction, and other property expenses and operating costs. Terminates the credit after a specified date. Title II: Encouraging Quality Child Care - Subtitle A: Dissemination of Information About Quality Child Care - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, directly or through a competitive contract, to collect and disseminate information on health and safety in various child care settings and findings in the field of early childhood learning and development. (Sec. 202) Mandates grants to develop distance learning child care training technology infrastructures and model technology-based training courses for child care providers and child care workers. Authorizes appropriations. Subtitle B: Increased Enforcement of State Health and Safety Standards - Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to require that the State plan for the use of funds under the Act provide the percentage of child care provider inspections required under State law. Mandates changes in State allotments based on State health and safety standards and inspections. Subtitle C: Removal of Barriers to Increasing the Supply of Quality Child Care - Authorizes appropriations to carry out the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990. (Sec. 222) Establishes a grant program, based on State populations, to assist States in providing funds to encourage the establishment and operation of employer operated child care programs. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the program on a specified date. (Sec. 223) Mandates a report by the Comptroller General to the Congress on whether, and if so the extent to which, concerns regarding legal liability inhibit the availability and affordability of child care. Subtitle D: Quality Child Care Through Federal Facilities and Programs - Mandates regulations requiring child care centers in executive, legislative, or judicial facilities to comply with State and local licensing requirements. Provides for enforcement.</summary>
</bill>
