<bill session="105" type="h" number="3303" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-22T14:22:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-06-22T14:22:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY1999-2001, Department of Justice</title>
    <title type="popular">Department of Justice FY1999-2001 Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriation Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1999, 2000, and 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriation Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1999, 2000, and 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1999, 2000, and 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1999, 2000, and 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for the Department of Justice for fiscal years 1999, 2000, and 2001; to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 1999 and 2000 to carry out certain programs administered by the Department of Justice; to amend title 28 of the United States Code with respect to the use of funds available to the Department of Justice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1998-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-04-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-05-12T13:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 105-526.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-05-12T13:36:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="298">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 298.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-06-22T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hyde moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-22T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4884-4891" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-22T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-06-22T14:22:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-06-22T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-17">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-17">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Reported to Senate by Senator Hatch with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="586">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 586.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Attorneys general"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Automobile insurance"/>
    <term name="Automobile theft"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Farm produce"/>
    <term name="Federal Prison Industries, Inc."/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to rural areas"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International claims"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="National socialism"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Presidential protection"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Probation officers"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Rape victim services"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Undercover operations"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/1998--Reported to Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Authorizations of Appropriations Subtitle A: Specific Provisions Subtitle B: General Provisions Title II: Authorizations of Appropriations for Programs Title III: Permanent Enabling Provisions Title IV: Miscellaneous Department of Justice Appropriations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1999, 2000, and 2001 - Title I: Authorizations of Appropriations - Subtitle A: Specific Provisions - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1999 through 2001 to the Department of Justice (DOJ) for: (1) general administration; (2) administrative review and appeals; (3) the Office of Inspector General; (4) general legal activities; (5) the Antitrust Division; (6) United States Attorneys; (7) the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); (8) the United States Marshals Service; (9) the Drug Enforcement Administration; (10) the Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS); (11) fees and expenses of witnesses; (12) interagency crime and drug enforcement; (13) the Federal Prison System; (14) the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission; (15) the Community Relations Service; (16) the Assets Forfeiture Fund; (17) Federal Prisoner Detention; and (18) the United States Parole Commission. (Sec. 102) Limits the funds available to Federal Prison Industries which may be used for administrative expenses and the employment of experts and consultants. Subtitle B: General Provisions - Directs the Attorney General to appoint 200 additional assistant U.S. attorneys by September 30, 2000, from attorneys who are incumbents of full-time DOJ litigation positions in Washington, D.C. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Authorizations of Appropriations for Programs - Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to authorize appropriations for FY 1999 and 2000 for: (1) expeditious deportation for denied asylum applicants; (2) appointing Federal victim's counselors (under the Violence Against Women Act of 1994); (3) improving border controls; (4) expanded special deportation proceedings; (5) training programs to assist probation and parole officers and other personnel who work with released sex offenders in the areas of case management, supervision, and relapse prevention; (6) the Missing Alzheimer's Disease Patient Alert Program; (7) the Motor Vehicle Theft Prevention Program; and (8) rural domestic violence and child abuse enforcement assistance. (Sec. 202) Amends the Antiterrorism and Effective Death Penalty Act of 1996 to authorize appropriations for FY 1999 and 2000 for metropolitan fire and emergency services training in responding to terrorist attacks and for research and development to support counter-terrorism technologies. (Sec. 203) Extends through FY 2000 the authorization for the Attorney General to transfer real or personal property of limited or marginal value to a State or local government agency or its designated contractor or transferee for use to support drug abuse treatment, drug and crime prevention and education, housing, job skills, and other community-based public health and safety programs. Specifies that such transfer shall be subject to satisfaction by the recipient involved of any outstanding lien against the property transferred. (Sec. 204) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to increase the authorization of appropriations for FY 1999 and 2000, and to authorize appropriations for FY 2001, for the State Criminal Alien Assistance Program to compensate States for the costs of incarcerating undocumented criminal aliens. Title III: Permanent Enabling Provisions - Amends the Federal judicial code to authorize the Attorney General to use funds available to carry out the activities of DOJ for: (1) certain general uses (including certain motor vehicle purchases, insurance, unforeseen emergencies of a confidential character, payment of interpreters and translators, payment of rewards, the purchase of evidence, uniform allowances, and certain expenses with respect to DOJ employees' dependents and families); (2) certain specific uses (such as for aircraft and boats, and purchase of ammunition and firearms by specified agencies); (3) subsistence and medical expenses of persons in the custody of the United States Marshals Service; (4) witness fees and expenses; (5) INS administration and law enforcement; and (6) Federal Prison System activities. Prohibits the use of such funds to pay compensation for individuals employed as attorneys who are not duly licensed and authorized to practice under the law of a State, U.S. territory, or the District of Columbia. Permits the use by the recipient of funds paid as reimbursement to a governmental unit in DOJ, to another Federal entity, or to a unit of State or local government. (Sec. 302) Directs the Attorney General to report to each House of Congress in any case in which the Attorney General: (1) establishes a policy to refrain from enforcing any provision of a Federal statute because of the Attorney General's position that such provision is unconstitutional; or (2) determines that DOJ will contest, or will refrain from defending, in any proceeding any Federal statutory provision because of such a position. (Sec. 303) Authorizes the Attorney General to appoint officials to assist in the protection of the person of the Attorney General. Title IV: Miscellaneous - Repeals open-ended authorizations of appropriations for the National Institute of Corrections and for the Marshals Service. (Sec. 404) Specifies that nothing in this Act or its amendments shall be construed to modify or supersede the application or operation of the Public Buildings Act of 1959. (Sec. 405) Rewrites Federal provisions regarding the Counterterrorism Fund. Provides that amounts appropriated to the Fund shall be available for: (1) current purposes pursuant to reprogramming procedures applicable to general Department of Justice appropriations; and (2) Federal departments and agencies for costs incurred in connection with counterterrorism technology research and development and providing training and related equipment to State and local law enforcement agencies for prevention and response capabilities against bombs and against chemical, biological, nuclear, and cyber attack. (Sec. 406) Amends the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 to provide that, with respect to provisions regarding relief from liability and punishment under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, the Walsh-Healy Act, and the Davis-Bacon Act for failure to pay minimum wage or overtime compensation, the use of an employer's vehicle for travel by an employee and activities performed by an employee which are incidental to the use of such vehicle for commuting shall not be considered part of the employee's principal activities if the use (including, without limitation, driving) of the employer's vehicle is subject to an agreement on the part of the employer and the employee or his or her representative (current law), or is required or permitted by the employer.</summary>
</bill>
