<bill session="104" type="h" number="2156" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Insurance Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to change the name of the Servicemen's Group Life Insurance Program to Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance, to merge the Retired Reservists' Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance Program into the Veterans' Group Life Insurance Program, to extend Veterans' Group Life Insurance coverage to members of the Ready Reserve of a uniformed service who retire with less than 20 years of service, to permit an insured to convert a Veterans' Group Life Insurance policy to an individual policy of life insurance with a commercial insurance company at any time, and to permit an insured to convert a Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance policy to an individual policy of life insurance with a commercial company upon separation from service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400504"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1995-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="407838" joined="1995-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Compensation, Pension, Insurance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-04">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.2843.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Compensation, Pension, Insurance, and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2843"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/1995--Introduced.
Veterans' Insurance Reform Act of 1995 - Redesignates the Servicemen's Group Life Insurance program as the Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance (SGLI) program. Merges the Retired Reservists' Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance program into the Veterans' Group Life Insurance (VGLI) program. Extends the VGLI program to members of the Ready Reserve who retire with less than 20 years of service. Authorizes an insured under: (1) the VGLI program to convert such policy to an individual policy of life insurance with a commercial insurance company at any time; and (2) the SGLI program to convert to such an individual policy upon separation from service.</summary>
</bill>
