<bill session="107" type="h" number="4917" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-24T16:12:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-09-24T16:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Los Padres National Forest Land Exchange Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Los Padres National Forest Land Exchange Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for an exchange of lands with the United Water Conservation District of California to eliminate private inholdings in the Los Padres National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-07-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-07-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-04T17:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-636.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-09-04T17:04:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="385">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 385.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T16:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T16:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6503-6504" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T16:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4917.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-09-24T16:12:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6503" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/4/2002--Reported to House without amendment.
Los Padres National Forest Land Exchange Act of 2002 - Authorizes an exchange of approximately 340 acres held by the United Water Conservation District of California and approximately 420 acres of National Forest System lands. Allows the Secretary of Agriculture to reserve easements in the conveyance of National Forest System lands for access roads and trails, including perpetual unrestricted rights of pedestrian access to the Potholes trailhead of Los Padres National Forest.Requires the Secretary to provide reasonable access to privately owned inholdings in the District lands acquired under this Act. Stipulates that the District must construct a gravel parking area for the Potholes trailhead, subject to the following requirements: (1) the District may reasonably regulate vehicular access to the trailhead; and (2) foot traffic to the trailhead shall be perpetual and unrestricted.States that all special use authorizations and term easements issued by the Secretary with respect to the lands being conveyed by the Secretary shall not be renewed or reauthorized after the enactment of this Act.Exempts water rights from this land exchange. Permits the District and the Secretary to equalize this exchange through a cash payment. Adds the District lands acquired under this Act to the Los Padres National Forest.</summary>
</bill>
