<bill session="104" type="h" number="290" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Management and Conflict of Interest Reform Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To institute management reforms and eliminate conflicts-of-interest on boards of directors of depository institutions and depository holding companies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400210"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Bank directors"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Bank management"/>
    <term name="Bank mergers"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Management and Conflict of Interest Reform Amendments of 1995 - Amends the Depository Institution Management Interlocks Act to include foreign banks within the administrative and enforcement purview of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. Prohibits an outside counsel or outside accountant of a depository institution or a depository holding company from serving as a member of the board of directors of such institution, holding company, or any of its subsidiaries, affiliates, or holding companies. Requires each depository institution and depository holding company to provide to each member of its board of directors and each member of the board of directors of any depository institution or depository holding company it controls: (1) a list of the names and principal places of business of each individual or company which directly or indirectly owns, controls, or has power to vote five percent or more of any class of voting securities of such institution or holding company; and (2) a notice of any proposed change in control of the parent depository institution or depository holding company. Requires a majority of the voting members of the board of directors of depository institutions and depository holding companies to be outside directors.</summary>
</bill>
