<bill session="105" type="h" number="749" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act to provide for improved notification and consent, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1997-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="110"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Excavation"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/1997--Introduced.
Amends the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act to allow the intentional removal or excavation of Native American human remains from Federal or tribal lands for purpose of study if consent is obtained from lineal descendants or each appropriate Indian tribe or Native Hawaiian organization. Requires a Federal agency or instrumentality that receives notice of a discovery of Native American cultural items on lands it manages to notify each appropriate Indian tribe or Native Hawaiian organization. Requires the committee established to monitor and review the inventory and identification process and repatriation activities to compile an inventory of, and develop a process for, the disposition of funerary objects. Requires that amounts collected as penalties under the Act be used to supplement enforcement appropriations. Authorizes: (1) a reward for furnishing information leading to a civil penalty; and (2) reduction of a penalty amount if the violator agrees to pay certain restitution to the aggrieved parties.</summary>
</bill>
