<bill session="105" type="h" number="4306" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To eliminate the spending cap adjustments for International Monetary Fund funding increases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400607"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Special drawing rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/1998--Introduced.
Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to remove specified increases in the U.S. quota of the International Monetary Fund Eleventh General Review of Quotas or increases in amounts available for New Arrangements to Borrow under the Bretton Woods Agreements Act from the list of amounts for which discretionary spending limits, allocations, and budgetary aggregates are to be adjusted to reflect new budget authority and outlays flowing from reported or amended legislation. Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) to make a parallel amendment eliminating such increases from the list of matters which trigger adjustments to discretionary spending limits.</summary>
</bill>
