<bill session="105" type="h" number="2539" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the use of United States funds to provide for the participation of certain Chinese officials in international conferences, exchanges, programs, and activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Antennas"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clergy"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International propaganda"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Refugee policy"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Prohibition on Use of Funds for the Participation of Certain Chinese Officials in Conferences, Exchanges, Programs, and Activities Title II: Authorization of Appropriations for Increased Funding for Radio Free Asia and Voice of America Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions Title I: Prohibition on Use of Funds for the Participation of Certain Chinese Officials in Conferences, Exchanges, Programs, and Activities - Prohibits certain U.S. agencies from funding the travel and per diem expenses of certain nationals of the People's Republic of China for participation in conferences, exchanges, programs, and activities. Title II: Authorization of Appropriations for Increased Funding for Radio Free Asia and Voice of America - Authorizes appropriations for International Broadcasting Activities for FY 1998 and 1999 in addition to sums previously authorized. Details allocation of such additional appropriations for Radio Free Asia. Instructs the Director of the United States Information Agency and the Board of Broadcasting Governors to seek to ensure that funds made available for broadcasting to nations whose people do not fully enjoy freedom of expression do not decline in proportion to amounts made available for broadcasting to other nations. (Sec. 202) Directs the President to report to the Congress on a plan to achieve continuous broadcasting of Radio Free Asia and Voice of America in multiple major dialects and languages to the People's Republic of China. (Sec. 203) Reduces authorization of appropriations for FY 1998 and 1999 for Migration and Refugee Assistance. Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1998 and 1999 to support personnel in the United States Embassy in Beijing as well as in selected American consulates to monitor political repression in the People's Republic of China. Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the President should make freedom of religion one of the major objectives of U.S. foreign policy with respect to China; (2) the Department of State should raise the issue of individuals imprisoned or otherwise harassed by the Chinese Government on religious grounds and request a complete and timely response from the Chinese Government regarding the individuals' whereabouts and condition, the charges against them, and the sentence imposed; and (3) the goal of official communications should be the expeditious release of all religious prisoners in China and the end of religious harassment and repression.</summary>
</bill>
