<bill session="106" type="h" number="4391" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mobile Telecommunications Sourcing Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Mobile Telecommunications Sourcing Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Mobile Telecommunications Sourcing Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Mobile Telecommunications Sourcing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 4 of the United States Code to establish nexus requirements for State and local taxation of mobile telecommunication services.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend title 4 of the United States Code to establish sourcing requirements for State and local taxation of mobile telecommunication services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2000-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2000-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-05-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-10T16:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 106-719.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-10T16:36:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="403">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 403.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-11T10:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gekas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-11T10:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5741-5744" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-11T10:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4391.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-07-11T10:22:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5741-5743" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-07-11T10:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-11T10:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-07-14" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6812-6813" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2000-07-14">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2000-07-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-07-28">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-07-28" type="public" number="106-252">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-252.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1755"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental tax relations"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone rates"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2000--Passed House amended.
Mobile Telecommunications Sourcing Act - Amends Federal provisions concerning tax authority to deem mobile telecommunications services provided in a taxing jurisdiction as provided by the customer's home service provider. Subjects charges for such services to taxation by the taxing jurisdiction whose territorial limits encompass the customer's place of primary use, regardless of where the services originate, terminate, or pass through. Prohibits any other taxing jurisdiction from imposing any tax, charge, or fee for such services.Authorizes a State or designated database provider to provide an electronic database to a home service provider which designates for each street address the appropriate taxing jurisdiction as identified by a nationwide standard numeric code. Requires the database provider to provide notice of the availability of such database, as well as subsequent revisions thereto. Holds harmless from any fee liability a home service provider that uses such database. Holds a provider harmless from any such liability in the absence of such a database if the provider employs an enhanced zip code to assign each street address to a specific taxing jurisdiction and exercises due diligence to ensure that each address is assigned to the correct taxing jurisdiction. Requires one specific taxing jurisdiction to be assigned when an enhanced zip code overlaps boundaries of different taxing jurisdictions. Terminates the authority to use the enhanced zip code on the later of: (1) 18 months after the nationwide standard numeric code has been approved; or (2) six months after a State or designated database provider provides such database.Authorizes a taxing jurisdiction, or a State acting on behalf of such jurisdiction, to: (1) determine the place of primary use for purposes of appropriate taxing authority; and (2) if necessary, notify a home service provider to change the assignment of a taxing authority to reflect the appropriate place of primary use. Requires the home service provider to obtain and maintain the customer's place of primary use for taxing purposes. Provides transition provisions and special rules.</summary>
</bill>
