<bill session="108" type="h" number="2061" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Youth Anti-Drug Media Campaign Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make improvements with respect to the Drug-Free Media Campaign Act of 1998 and to authorize such Campaign through fiscal year 2008.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2003-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mass media"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2003--Introduced.
National Youth Anti-Drug Media Campaign Reauthorization Act of 2003 - Amends the Drug-Free Media Campaign Act of 1998 to require the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy to conduct a national youth anti-drug media campaign, the purposes of which shall include: (1) increasing the awareness of adults of the impact of drug abuse on young people; and (2) encouraging parents and other adults to discuss with young people the dangers associated with drug use (current law requires the Director to conduct a national media campaign to reduce and prevent drug abuse among young people).States that the Director shall approve the strategy of the campaign and all advertising.Directs the Director to request that the Partnership for a Drug-Free America: (1) recommend strategies addressing national, regional, and local drug threats; and (2) create all advertising to be used in the media campaign, with certain exceptions.Modifies provisions pertaining to the use of funds, including to state that no funds other than out-of-pocket production costs and talent reuse payments may be used for the creative development of advertisements except in specified circumstances.Requires the receipt of no cost matches relating to substance abuse prevention prior to any disbursal of funds for advertising time or space. Declares that any donated advertising material shall not be subject to sponsorship identification provisions in the Communications Act of 1934.Requires the Director to carry out an examination of campaign records and an audit of the costs of the campaign, in accordance with the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949.</summary>
</bill>
