<bill session="107" type="h" number="4919" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-24T16:16:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-09-24T16:16:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tonto and Coconino National Forests Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Tonto and Coconino National Forests Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the exchange of certain lands in the Coconino and Tonto National Forests in Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400173"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="2002-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T12:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-674.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-09-24T12:06:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="416">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 416.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6504-6506" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4919.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-09-24T16:16:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6504-6505" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="5032"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2002--Passed House amended.
Tonto and Coconino National Forests Land Exchange Act - Title I: Tonto and Coconino National Forests Land Exchange - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to certain private land owners specified lands in the Tonto National Forest in exchange for the conveyance by such land owners of certain lands adjacent to the Montezuma Castle National Monument and certain lands within the Coconino National Forest. Requires that the values of Federal and non-Federal lands be equalized.Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to certain private land owners specified lands northeast of Payson, Arizona, in exchange for the conveyance by such land owners of certain lands within the Tonto National Forest. Requires that the values of Federal and non-Federal lands be equalized. Terminates all special use cabin permits on the Federal land upon execution of the exchange.Deletes from an exchange Federal land parcels that cannot be transferred due to hazardous materials, threatened or endangered species, cultural or historic resources, or wetland and flood plain problems and requires making appropriate adjustments to equalize land values being exchanged.Provides that the land acquired by the Secretary become part of the Tonto or Coconino National Forest, as appropriate. Provides for: (1) the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer all or a portion of the lands acquired adjacent to the Montezuma Castle National Monument to the administrative jurisdiction of the National Park Service; and (2) the incorporation of such lands in the Montezuma Castle National Monument.Title II: Mendocino National Forest Land Conveyance - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to the owner of Faraway Ranch in Lake County, California ("the recipient"), by quitclaim deed, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to specified National Forest System (NFS) lands in Mendocino National Forest in Lake County. Directs the recipient to pay the Secretary an amount equal to the fair market value of the NFS lands. Assigns all transaction costs associated with the conveyance to the recipient. Requires the funds received by the Secretary to be used for the acquisition of land and interests in land for NFS purposes in California and for reimbursement of costs incurred by the Forest Service in making the conveyance. Withdraws, subject to valid existing rights, the lands being conveyed from all forms of location, entry, and patent under the public land laws and the mining and mineral leasing laws of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
