<bill session="104" type="h" number="998" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Expanded Training Opportunities Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title III of the Job Training Partnership Act to provide employment and training assistance for certain individuals who work at or live in the community of a plant, facility, or enterprise that is scheduled to close or undergo significant layoffs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400585"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Plant shutdowns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/21/1995--Introduced.
Expanded Training Opportunities Act - Amends the Job Training Partnership Act to revise provisions for employment and training assistance for dislocated workers. Provides for employment and training assistance for certain individuals employed at or living in the community of a plant, facility, or enterprise scheduled to close or undergo significant layoffs. Includes skills enhancement to improve employment prospects among authorized retraining services for dislocated workers. Includes in-house training and retraining programs for workers in companies undergoing restructuring among authorized demonstration programs.</summary>
</bill>
