<bill session="108" type="h" number="4444" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Worker Reemployment Accounts Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to establish a Personal Reemployment Accounts pilot grant program to assist Americans in returning to work.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2004-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2004-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400375" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="2004-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="hr" number="656"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="444"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment subsidies"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2004--Introduced.
Worker Reemployment Accounts Act of 2004 - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to authorize the Secretary of Labor to establish and implement a national demonstration project on personal reemployment accounts (PRAs). Directs the Secretary to make competitive grants for such project to States or local boards or consortia to provide PRAs to eligible individuals. Makes eligible for a PRA, in a designated State or local area, individuals who: (1) are identified as likely to exhaust unemployment compensation and in need of job search assistance to make a successful transition to new employment (or if their unemployment can be attributed in substantial part to unfair competition from Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated); (2) are receiving regular unemployment compensation under any Federal or State unemployment compensation program administered by the State; and (3) are eligible for at least 20 weeks of regular unemployment compensation. Allows PRAs to be used to purchase intensive services, training services, or supportive services through the one-stop delivery system on a fee-for-service basis, or through other providers, consistent with specified safeguards. Provides cash reemployment bonuses, consisting of the balance of their PRAs, to recipients who obtain full-time employment before the end of the 13th week of unemployment for which compensation is paid.</summary>
</bill>
