<bill session="108" type="h" number="4394" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Accountability and Responsibility in Contracting Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make ineligible for Federal contract awards any expatriated corporations and any companies that do business with, or own foreign subsidiaries that do business with, state sponsors of terrorism or foreign terrorist organizations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2004-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400181" joined="2004-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2004-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2004-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2004--Introduced.
Accountability and Responsibility in Contracting Act - Prohibits any acquiring corporation or any subsidiary of any such a corporation that enters into a corporate expatriation transaction (as defined by this Act) from being eligible to be awarded a Federal contract for a three-year period, unless the acquiring corporation reorganizes as a domestic corporation under the applicable incorporation laws of a State. Prohibits any entity and any entity with a foreign subsidiary doing business with a state sponsor of terrorism or foreign terrorist organization from being eligible to be awarded a Federal contract for a period of: (1) three years for a first offense; (2) ten years for a second offense; and (3) 15 years for any offense after a second offense. Directs each executive agency to require certification from a current contractor that the contractor, the contractor's domestic parent company and all other domestic subsidiaries of the parent did not do business, and did not own a foreign subsidiary that did business, during the ten-year period ending on this Act's enactment with such a state sponsor or organization. Directs each executive agency to require certification from a potential contractor, that the potential contractor, the potential contractor's domestic parent company, and all other domestic subsidiaries of the parent is not doing business, and does not own a foreign subsidiary that is doing business, or has done business within the last ten years, with such a state sponsor or organization. Permits citizens to file complaints with executive agencies regarding Federal contractors and requires annual reporting on the complaints to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
