<bill session="108" type="h" number="4114" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Migratory Bird Treaty Reform Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Migratory Bird Treaty Reform Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Migratory Bird Treaty Act to exclude non-native migratory bird species from the application of that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400149"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="2004-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E510"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-06-03T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-520.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-06-03T15:28:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="299">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 299.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="2547"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Animal breeding"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Exotic animals"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife reintroduction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2004--Reported to House amended.
Title I: Exclusion of Nonnative Species from Migratory Bird Treaty Act - Migratory Bird Treaty Reform Act of 2004 - (Sec. 102) Amends the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (MBTA) to clarify that the MBTA's prohibition on taking, killing, or possessing migratory birds applies only to native migratory bird species whose occurrence in the United States results from natural biological or ecological conditions. Excludes from coverage under the MBTA bird species occurring as the result of human assisted introduction unless the species: (1) was native to the United States and extant in 1918; (2) became extinct throughout its range thereafter; and (3) was reintroduced as part of a Federal program. (Sec. 103) Requires the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to publish a list of all non-native, human introduced bird species to which the MBTA does not apply that belong to biological families of migratory birds covered under any migratory bird conventions with Great Britain (for Canada), Mexico, Russia, or Japan. Title II: Conservation of Neotropical Migratory Birds - Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Improvement Act of 2004 - (Sec. 202) Amends the Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Act (NMBCA) to increase the Federal share of costs for projects funded under that Act. Prescribes the form of payment for such projects undertaken in the United States and Canada versus Latin America and the Caribbean. Establishes the Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Fund. Increases the amount of funds that the Secretary may expend to administer the NMBCA. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer to the Fund amounts that were in the Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Account immediately before the enactment of this Act. Authorizes appropriations. Requires not less than 75 percent of such appropriations to be used for projects outside the United States. Prohibits expenditures for projects in Canada during a fiscal year unless the amount available to carry out NMBCA exceeds $10 million for that year.</summary>
</bill>
