<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="328" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:46-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="4" sequence="21"/>
  <status datetime="1995-03-24">offered</status>
  <sponsor id="400554"/>
  <offered datetime="1995-03-24"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to transform the Aid to Families with Dependent Children (AFDC) program into a program that moves recipients from welfare to work by providing a public sector or subsidized private sector job paying minimum wage for at least two years; increase funding in the JOBS Program participation requirements by five percent per year over seven years, rising from 15 percent in fiscal year 1997 to 50 percent in fiscal year 2003, resulting in a $14.9 billion authorization in additional JOBS funding over the five years; take steps to expand child care services for poor families; and finance the spending increases by raising the top corporate income tax rate by 1.25 percent to 36.25 percent.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute to transform the AFDC program into a program that successfully moves recipients from welfare to work. It significantly increases the funding for education, job training, employment services, and child care for welfare recipients--in order to help them move into the workforce. It requires states to have an increasing percentage of their AFDC caseload participate in JOBS programs over seven years, rising from 15% in FY 1997 to 50% in FY 2003. It imposes a work requirement and rewards states that move recipients from welfare to unsubsidized employment. It contains provisions to ensure that welfare recipients are better off economically by taking a job than by staying on welfare. It contains no changes in School Lunch, WIC, and other child nutrition programs; Food Stamps; SSI; and benefits for legal immigrants. Finally, it finances its spending increases for education, job training, and child care programs by raising the top corporate tax rate by 1.25% to 36.25%.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-24T10:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A021) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mrs. Mink.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-24T12:46:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the Mink amendment (A021) Failed by recorded vote (3/5 required): 96 - 336 (Roll No. 267).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
