<bill session="104" type="h" number="1140" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tuberculosis Prevention and Control Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402750" joined="1995-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1995-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1996-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1995-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1995-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1995-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Extended care facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis research"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/1995--Introduced.
Tuberculosis Prevention and Control Amendments of 1995 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations for grants for the prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis. Includes services regarding incarceration in the purposes for which the grants may be expended. Increases the amount authorized to be reserved for emergency grants for geographic areas with high numbers or substantial increases in the number of cases. Authorizes appropriations for grants for bulk purchases of medications and other supplies regarding tuberculosis. Authorizes appropriations for expenditures (directly or through grants) for research, demonstration projects, public information and education, education of health professionals, support of centers, and collaboration with international organizations and foreign countries. Authorizes grants for the establishment and operation of not more than five centers to train health professionals regarding tuberculosis, including regarding screening and referral and provision of facilities and equipment. Mandates, directly or through contracts, evaluation of the centers. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes appropriations for conducting or supporting research and research training on tuberculosis. Authorizes grants for: (1) construction or modernization of outpatient medical facilities located apart from hospitals and providing services for medically underserved populations; (2) conversion of existing facilities into outpatient medical facilities or long-term care facilities for such populations; (3) renovation of inpatient facilities; and (4) construction or renovation of facilities to provide services regarding incarceration. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
