<bill session="104" type="h" number="3298" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Voyageurs National Park Intergovernmental Council Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of the Voyageurs National Park Intergovernmental Council, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecotourism"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Snowmobiles"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
    <term name="Winter sports facilities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/1996--Introduced.
Voyageurs National Park Intergovernmental Council Act of 1996 - Establishes the Voyageurs National Park Intergovernmental Council which shall: (1) prepare and submit to the Secretary of the Interior comprehensive draft amendments and proposed revisions to the management plan for the Park providing for a broad range of sustainable land and water uses and scenic and recreational activities compatible with governing local, State, and Federal laws and regulations; (2) analyze the economic and environmental costs and benefits of implementing sustainable practices for the Park; and (3) establish an ongoing process of assessing the effect of local, State, and Federal actions, plans, ordinances, regulations, laws, and land use decisions on the long-term sustainability of the economic and environmental values and resources of the region. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Secretary to implement amendments to the management plan for the Park, including amendments providing for recreational opportunities involving boats, aircraft, snowmobiles, hiking, and skiing on all major lakes and bays. Directs the Secretary: (1) to receive the Council's draft amendments, recommend revisions, and adopt the revised amendments that are consistent with the public interest and applicable laws; (2) if the Secretary decides not to adopt the Council's revised amendments, to appoint, and revise the management plan based on amendments submitted by, a management plan board; or (3) if the Council declines to submit revised amendments, to make necessary and appropriate amendments and implement the plan.</summary>
</bill>
