<bill session="113" type="h" number="1503" updated="2013-07-17T16:00:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">No Hungry Kids Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal a certain rule relating to nutrition standards in the national school lunch and school breakfast programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400220"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412429" joined="2013-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2013--Introduced.
No Hungry Kids Act - Nullifies the rule published by the Department of Agriculture on January 26, 2012, establishing nutrition standards for the school lunch and breakfast programs. (This rule is summarized as requiring most schools to increase the availability of fruits, vegetables, whole grains, and fat-free and low-fat fluid milk in school meals; reduce the levels of sodium, saturated fat and trans fat in meals; and meet the nutrition needs of school children within their calorie requirements.) Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to prohibit the Secretary of Agriculture's minimum nutritional requirements for school lunches from being construed as establishing a calorie maximum for individual school lunches or prohibiting a child from eating a lunch provided by the child's parent or legal guardian.</summary>
</bill>
