<bill session="104" type="h" number="2445" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Economic Growth and Price Stability Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to focus on price stability in establishing monetary policy to ensure the stable, long-term purchasing power of the currency, to repeal the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="1995-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="1996-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1995-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="1995-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Economic and Educational Opportunities, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="1266"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Full employment policies"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Open market operations"/>
    <term name="Price regulation"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Standard of living"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/1995--Introduced.
Economic Growth and Price Stability Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Reserve Act to repeal the mandate of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Open Market Committee to maintain long run growth of monetary and credit aggregates in order to promote maximum employment, stable prices, and moderate long-term interest rates. Replaces such mandate with a mandate to: (1) establish an explicit numerical definition of "price stability"; and (2) maintain a monetary policy that effectively promotes long-term price stability. Repeals the mandate of the Board and the Committee to report biannually to the Congress on national economic trends, taking into account unemployment, investment and productivity. Replaces such mandate with a mandate to consult semiannually with the Congress and report on their plans and the time required to achieve price stability. Repeals the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 (Humphrey-Hawkins Act). Amends the Employment Act of 1946 and the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to reflect the provisions of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
