<bill session="105" type="h" number="2206" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-06T18:39:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-10-06T18:39:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Veterans Health Programs bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Health Programs Improvement Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Veterans Health Programs Improvement Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans Health Programs Improvement Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs for homeless veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1997-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1997-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1997-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1997-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1997-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="1997-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1997-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6966"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-09-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-10-02T10:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 105-293.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-10-02T10:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="167">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 167.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T14:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Stump moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T14:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8362-8367, H8397" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Stearns objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-10-06T18:39:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="1687"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2197"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism treatment"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Blood"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Dentists"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled veterans"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Eviction"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Group homes"/>
    <term name="Gulf War syndrome"/>
    <term name="Halfway houses"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Homeless veterans"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing management"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mentally ill"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Occupational therapy"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf War"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Post exchanges"/>
    <term name="Radiation victims"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists in government"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soldiers' homes"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Supervisors"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1997--Passed House amended.
Veterans Health Programs Improvement Act of 1997 - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in providing care and services to veterans suffering from serious mental illness, including homeless veterans, to provide: (1) outreach services; (2) care, treatment, and rehabilitative services (including the use of halfway houses); and (3) therapeutic transitional housing assistance and outpatient care. Authorizes the Secretary to operate residences and facilities as therapeutic housing, with specified conditions, including the requirement of a house manager at each residence and payments by residents to cover board expenses. Directs the Secretary to operate a program to expand and improve the provision of veterans' benefits to homeless veterans. Requires the establishment of at least eight sites as centers for the provision of comprehensive services to homeless veterans. Directs the Secretary to coordinate such services with other Federal departments and agencies, State and local governments, and nongovernmental organizations. Requires assessments of the needs of homeless veterans living in each area served by the Department of Veterans Affairs. Amends the Homeless Veterans Comprehensive Service Programs Act of 1992 to extend through FY 1999 the homeless veterans comprehensive service grant program. Amends the Veterans' Benefits Improvements Act of 1994 to require additional information on program effectiveness in a required report concerning assistance provided to homeless veterans. Extends permanently a program for the furnishing of noninstitutional alternatives to veterans' nursing home care. Authorizes (current law requires) the Secretary to furnish appropriate health-related services solely through contracts with public and private agencies and to designate Department health-care employees to furnish case management services to veterans furnished such services. Amends the Veterans Health Care Act of 1992 to require counseling to Persian Gulf War veterans to include verbal counseling along with the provision of written materials. Authorizes the Secretary to provide hospital care and services to a veteran who was exposed to a toxic substance, radiation (current law), or other conditions (currently, an environmental hazard) while performing military service. Directs the Secretary to carry out a program of demonstration projects to test new approaches to treating, and improving treatment satisfaction of, Persian Gulf veterans who suffer from undiagnosed and ill-defined disabilities. Requires the program to be established no later than July 1, 1998, at up to ten geographically dispersed Department medical centers. Provides funding. Excludes from Federal personnel reduction requirements employees of the Veterans Health Administration who: (1) provide or supervise others who provide care and services to patients; or (2) conduct research. Allows a drug, pharmaceutical or biological product, or hematology-related product listed on the Federal pharmaceutical supply schedule to be procured or ordered from such schedule only by or for the following entities: (1) any agency or instrumentality of the Government; or (2) any other entity specified in Federal law or regulation effective before July 1, 1997, as eligible to procure such products from such schedule. Redesignates the Wm. Jennings Bryan Dorn Veterans' Hospital in Columbia, South Carolina, as the Wm. Jennings Bryan Dorn Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center.</summary>
</bill>
