<bill session="105" type="h" number="1765" updated="2012-11-01T22:48:11-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Pension Reform Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide that, for purposes relating to retirement, Members of Congress and congressional employees shall be treated in the same manner as are employees in the executive branch generally.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400599"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400078" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1997-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1997-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400383" joined="1997-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Civil Service"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional pensions"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>06/03/1997--Introduced.
Congressional Pension Reform Act of 1997 - Provides for the deduction and withholding of seven percent (currently, eight and seven and one-half percent, respectively) of the basic pay of a Member of Congress or congressional employee under the Civil Service Retirement System, thus making such deduction and withholding equivalent to that of a Federal employee. Makes provisions regarding immediate retirement, entitlement to annuities, and deferred retirement for Federal employees applicable to Members. Removes specified provisions regarding annuities, reduced annuities, and deferred retirement for Members. Removes a provision that entitles a Member to an annuity if he or she serves in nine Congresses. Continues the applicability of existing provisions regarding immediate Member annuities and deferred retirement with respect to Members serving on or after this Act's effective date who, as of the day before such effective date, satisfy the existing age and service requirements for entitlement to immediate annuities or deferred retirement. Revises the formula for computing annuities of Members and congressional employees with at least five years of service to restrict creditable service to service performed before this Act's enactment date. Makes similar amendments with respect to the computation of Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS) annuities for Members and congressional employees. Makes the reduction in annuity for Federal employees retiring before age 55 applicable to Members as well. Repeals provisions that provide for a different reduction formula for Members. Repeals provisions concerning: (1) annuities for surviving spouses of Members entitled to deferred annuities; (2) the treatment of annuities during periods of reemployment; and (3) eligibility for annuities of Members or survivors. Makes deductions and withholding and the formula for Government contributions under FERS for Members and congressional employees conform to those of Federal employees.</summary>
</bill>
