<amendment session="105" chamber="h" number="156" updated="2013-07-17T07:51:35-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="1757" sequence="28"/>
  <status datetime="1997-06-11T16:02:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <offered datetime="1997-06-04"/>
  <description>Amendment prohibits population planning assistance to any foreign organization until the organization certifies that it will not perform abortions except where the life of the mother would be endangered or in cases of rape or incest; certifies that it will not engage in any activity to alter the laws or policies of any foreign country concerning the circumstances under which abortion is permitted, regulated, or prohibited; and prohibits any funds to the United Nations Population Fund unless the President certifies that it has terminated all activities in the People's Republic of China or during the 12 months preceding such certification there have been no coerced abortions associated with the family planning policies of the People's Republic of China.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to restrict assistance to foreign organizations that perform or actively promote abortions and prohibiting the use of any funds authorized in the bill to be made available for the United Nations Population Fund in any fiscal year unless the President certifies that UNFPA has terminated all activities in the People's Republic of China, and during the 12 months preceding such certification there have been no abortions as the result of coercion associated with the family planning policies of the national government or other governmental entities.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-06-04T22:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A028) offered by Mr. Smith (NJ).</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1997-06-05T15:57:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="168">
      <text>On agreeing to the Smith (NJ) amendment (A028) Agreed to by recorded vote: 232 - 189 (Roll no. 168).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Serrano demanded a separate vote on the Smith (NJ) amendment (A028).</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1997-06-11T16:02:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="194">
      <text>On agreeing to the Smith (NJ) amendment (A028) Agreed to by recorded vote: 234 - 193 (Roll no. 194).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
