<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1098" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="5876" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2008-06-24T17:20:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-06-24"/>
  <description>Amendment makes changes to the definition of "covered program". It expands the definition to include public residential programs; strikes the exclusion of psychiatric residential treatment facilities and the exclusion of foster care group homes; strikes the requirement for the Secretary of HHS to make unannounced site inspections of covered programs at least once every two years and strikes Section 5. The amendment also requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the activities of the national toll-free hotline; directs the Secretary to conduct a study on the outcomes of residential programs and amends one of the standards to require a timeline about notifying parents.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 110-717 to make three changes to the definition of "covered program." It expands the definition to include public residential programs, and it strikes the exclusion of psychiatric residential treatment facilities and the exclusion of foster care group homes. The amendment strikes the requirement for the Secretary of HHS to make unannounced site inspections of covered programs at least once every two years, and it strikes Section 5. The amendment requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the activities of the national toll-free hotline, directs the Secretary to conduct a study on the outcomes of residential programs, and amends one of the standards to require a timeline about notifying parents.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. George Miller.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5959-5961" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5959" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2008-06-24T17:20:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="444">
      <text>On agreeing to the Miller, George amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 422 - 0 (Roll no. 444).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
