<bill session="106" type="h" number="1045" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Radiation Exposure Compensation Improvement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Radiation Exposure Compensation Act to provide for partial restitution to individuals who worked in uranium mines, mills, or transport which provided uranium for the use and benefit of the United States Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400534" joined="1999-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-03-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1062"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="367"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Brain diseases"/>
    <term name="Breast cancer"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Colon cancer"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Digestive diseases"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Leukemia"/>
    <term name="Liability for nuclear damages"/>
    <term name="Lung cancer"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Men"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Mine wastes"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Ovarian cancer"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radiation victims"/>
    <term name="Radioactive fallout"/>
    <term name="Radon"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Respiratory diseases"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Stomach diseases"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Thyroid diseases"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Urology"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
    <term name="X-rays"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/1999--Introduced.
Radiation Exposure Compensation Improvement Act of 1999 - Amends the Radiation Exposure Compensation Act to add to the definition of "affected area" the parts of Arizona, Utah, and New Mexico comprising the Navajo Nation Reservation that were subjected to fallout from nuclear weapons testing in Nevada. Modifies the definition of "specified disease." Amends provisions regarding claims relating to uranium mining to expand their applicability to include any individual employed to transport or handle uranium ore. Includes as eligible such individuals in currently-specified States and in any other State in which uranium was mined, milled, or transported. Includes as a uranium mine above-ground mines, open pit mines, and uranium mills. Expands the dates between which exposure must have taken place. Increases the amount of compensation provided, decreases the required period of exposure, eliminates the distinction between smokers and nonsmokers, and expands the compensable conditions to include any condition associated with uranium mining, milling, or transport. Mandates compensation for individuals employed in uranium mining, milling, or transport and who: (1) were, without the individual's knowledge or informed consent, intentionally exposed to radiation for research by the Federal Government; or (2) in the course of the individual's employment suffered death, injury, or disability but were barred from the worker's compensation system or civil actions available to similarly situated employees in nonuranium mines or mills. Modifies and establishes various definitions. Changes procedures and requirements regarding the determination and payment of claims, including setting forth certain requirements relating to Native Americans. Declares that payment of an award under any provision of the Act does not preclude an award under any other provision of the Act, but that no individual may receive more than one award for any compensable cancer or other disease. Allows claims to be filed for 20 years after the enactment of this Act and applies the amendments made by this Act to any claim pending or commenced after a specified date. Mandates a report to the Congress that: (1) summarizes medical knowledge on adverse health effects on residents of communities adjacent to uranium mills or mill tailings, above ground uranium mines, or open pit mines; (2) summarizes information on the availability and accessibility of medical care for individuals with malignancies and other compensable diseases relating to exposure to uranium as a result of mining and milling; (3) summarizes reclamation efforts regarding uranium mines, mills, and mill tailings in Colorado, New Mexico, Arizona, Wyoming, and Utah; and (4) makes recommendations for further actions to ensure health and safety regarding such efforts.</summary>
</bill>
