<bill session="104" type="h" number="3809" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Debt Collection Act Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the ability of the United States Government to collect debts owed to it, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1996-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1996-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1996-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1996-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Collection agencies"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/1996--Introduced.
Debt Collection Act Amendments of 1995 - Amends Federal law to require the head of an executive or legislative agency (who, currently, is merely authorized) to: (1) contract with a collection service to recover indebtedness owed to the United States; (2) collect such indebtedness from Federal employees in installment deductions; (3) disclose certain information to a consumer reporting agency when trying to collect a claim; and (4) collect such a claim by administrative offset. Requires the head of a Federal agency to report promptly to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) any debt that has been paid in full. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow the IRS to disclose address information in accordance with any law granting a Federal claim against a taxpayer. Directs the Comptroller General to report to the Congress after annual audits of each Federal agency on: (1) the amount of debt owed to the agency; (2) the amount that is delinquent; and (3) action taken by the agency to recover such debt. Repeals the termination date of the pilot debt collection project of the Department of Justice. Requires the Attorney General to include in the annual report to the Congress on activities to recover indebtedness the total cost of the pilot project and the total amount of debt recovered under it. Requires that recovered funds be used to reduce the Federal deficit. Requires a percentage of recovered funds to be used by the agency in collecting indebtedness. Prohibits the head of a Federal agency from making a loan until the loan applicant has been prescreened to determine creditworthiness. Requires the IRS to disclose address information to a Federal agency for use in collecting a claim. Prohibits the head of a Federal agency from making a loan to a loan applicant who owes a delinquent debt to the Federal Government, including the IRS. Allows the use of administrative charges by the Secretary of the Treasury for improving credit management techniques.</summary>
</bill>
