<bill session="106" type="h" number="1074" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-07-26T18:44:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-07-26T18:44:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regulatory Right-to-Know Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Regulatory Right-to-Know Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Regulatory Right-to-Know Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide Governmentwide accounting of regulatory costs and benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400567" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1999-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1999-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1999-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1999-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400603" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="1999-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400530" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400374" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400410" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="1999-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="1999-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E411-412"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-20">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-05-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-06-07T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 106-168.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-06-07T16:22:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="93">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 93.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-07-21T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 258 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1074 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Shall be in order to consider as an original bill the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Government Reform now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. Provides for consideration of only those amendments pre-printed in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-22T18:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 258 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T15:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 258.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6365-6379" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T15:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1074 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Shall be in order to consider as an original bill the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Government Reform now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. Provides for consideration of only those amendments pre-printed in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T15:02:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 258 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T15:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ray LaHood to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T15:02:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1074.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the enbloc amendment offered by Mr. McIntosh.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Hoeffel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T16:43:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS ON AMENDMENT - The Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Hoeffel by voice vote and announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McIntosh demanded a recorded vote. Pursuant to H. Res. 258, further proceedings on the amendment were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1074 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T18:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1074.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-07-26T18:44:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="336" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 254 - 157 (Roll no. 336).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-07-26T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-07-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO01" subcommittee="National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="258"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="746"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Industrial productivity"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h344"/>
    <amendment number="h345"/>
    <amendment number="h346"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/26/1999--Passed House amended.
Regulatory Right-to-Know Act of 1999 - Directs the President, acting through the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, to submit annually to the Congress an accounting statement and associated report containing an estimate of the total annual costs and benefits of Federal regulatory programs in the aggregate; by agency, agency program, and program component; and by major rule. Requires the Director, in addition, to include in the accounting statement: (1) an analysis of impacts of Federal rules and paperwork on Federal, State, local, and tribal government, the private sector, small business, wages, consumer prices, economic growth, as well as on public health, public safety, the environment, consumer protection, equal opportunity, and other public policy goals; (2) an identification and analysis of overlaps, duplications, and potential inconsistencies among such programs; and (3) recommendations to reform inefficient or ineffective regulatory programs or program components, including recommendations for addressing market failures that are not adequately addressed by such existing programs or program components. Requires the Director, in estimates contained in any submission, to quantify the net benefits or net costs of each program component, each major rule, and each option for which costs and benefits were included in any regulatory impact analysis issued for any major rule. Requires the Director to include in each submission a table stating the number of major and nonmajor rules issued by each agency in the preceding fiscal year.Requires the accounting statement, at a minimum, to: (1) cover expected costs and benefits for the fiscal year for which the statement is submitted and the four following fiscal years; (2) cover previously expected costs and benefits for the two preceding fiscal years, or the most recent revision of such costs and benefits; and (3) with respect to each major rule, include the estimates of costs and benefits for each of the fiscal years referred to that were included in the regulatory impact analysis that was prepared for such major rule.Prohibits the application of certain requirements under this Act with respect to the first and second accounting statements.Requires the Director to: (1) issue guidelines to agencies to standardize most plausible measures of costs and benefits, the means of gathering information used to prepare the accounting statements under this Act, including information required for impact analyses, and the format of information provided for accounting statements, including summary tables; and (2) review agency submissions for consistency with such guidelines.Requires the Director: (1) before submitting the statement and report and before preparing final guidelines, to provide public notice and an opportunity to comment and to consult with the Director of the Congressional Budget Office; and (2) to include an appendix to the report or guidelines, respectively, addressing public and peer review comments.Directs the Director to arrange for two or more persons that have nationally recognized expertise in regulatory analysis and regulatory accounting to provide peer review of each accounting statement and associated report and the guidelines before such statement, report, or guidelines are final. Requires the Director to ensure that: (1) the persons that provide peer review are fairly balanced with respect to the points of view represented; (2) no such person has a conflict of interest that is relative to the functions to be performed in the review; and (3) the comments provided by those persons are not inappropriately influenced by any special interest and are the result of independent judgment.Directs the head of each Federal banking agency and the National Credit Union Administration, and not the Director, to exercise all authority and carry out all duties otherwise vested under this Act in the Director with respect to that agency, other than the authority and duty to submit accounting statements and reports as required by this Act.Prohibits applying any provision of this Act to any matter relating to monetary policy that is proposed or promulgated by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee.</summary>
</bill>
