<bill session="104" type="h" number="2614" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-05T14:56:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-12-05T14:56:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commemorative Coin Authorization and Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform the commemorative coin programs of the United States Mint in order to protect the integrity of such programs and prevent losses of Government funds, to authorize the United States Mint to mint and issue platinum and gold bullion coins, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1995-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1995-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1995-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="1995-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1995-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1995-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1995-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1995-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held and Forwarded to Full Committee by the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy Prior to Referral by a Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05T14:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Castle moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05T14:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13946-13948" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05T14:47:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-12-05T14:56:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-05T14:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Platinum"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Commemorative Coin Program Reform Title II: Platinum and Gold Bullion Coins Title III: Mint Managerial Staffing Reform Commemorative Coin Authorization and Reform Act of 1995 - Title I: Commemorative Coin Program Reform - Amends Federal law regarding the Numismatic Public Enterprise Fund to mandate inclusion of any surcharge imposed upon the sale of any numismatic item. Sets forth conditions on payment of surcharges to recipient organizations. Repeals the requirement that the Comptroller General submit a financial accounting statement to the Congress on the payment of surcharges and on the use and expenditure of surcharge proceeds by a recipient organization. (Sec. 102) Decreases from five years to four years the terms of office for members of the Citizens Commemorative Coin Advisory Committee ( the Committee). Mandates that the Chairperson of such Committee be elected by its members from among such members. Requires the Committee to report to the Congress on recommendations for development of a multiyear commemorative coin program involving circulating coins which would supersede other commemorative coin programs for the year the commemorative circulating coin program is in effect. Title II: Platinum and Gold Bullion Coins - Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) mint and issue platinum bullion coins; and (2) continue to mint and issue American Eagle gold coins in two or more versions simultaneously. Title III: Mint Managerial Staffing Reform - Amends Federal law to repeal the requirement that each mint have a presidentially appointed superintendent and assayer and the Philadelphia mint have a presidentially appointed engraver.</summary>
</bill>
