<bill session="106" type="h" number="1538" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Educational Opportunities Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Children's Education Tax Credit Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Helping Empower Low-Income Parents (HELP) Scholarships Amendments 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide flexibility to certain local educational agencies that develop voluntary public and private parental choice programs under title VI of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="1999-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1999-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1999-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1999-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1999-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-04-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E752"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Church schools"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Home schooling"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School choice"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State aid to education"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tuition tax credits"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1999--Introduced.
Educational Opportunities Act of 1999 - Title I: HELP Scholarships - Helping Empower Low-Income Parents (HELP) Scholarships Amendments of 1999 - Amends title VI (Innovative Education Program Strategies) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to allow any State that has enacted or will enact a law establishing a voluntary public and private school parental choice scholarship program in compliance with specified ESEA requirements to reserve an additional 15 percent from its annual title IV allotment for use exclusively for such parental choice programs. Requires State educational agencies (SEAs), except in the case of such programs, to distribute 90 percent (currently 85 percent) of title VI funds to local educational agencies (LEAs).(Sec. 105) Includes such parental choice programs among State and local uses of title VI funds.Requires such parental choice programs to be located in an area designated as an empowerment zone or enterprise community.(Sec. 106) Directs the Comptroller General to make contracts for annual evaluation of each parental choice program. Requires the Secretary of Education to reserve certain funds for such evaluations.Provides that title VI funds to establish a parental choice program shall be considered assistance to the student and shall not be considered as assistance to any school that chooses to participate in such program.Prohibits the Secretary from exercising any direction, supervision, or control over curricula, program of instruction, administration, or personnel of any school that chooses to participate in a parental choice program.Title II: Education Tax Credit - Children's Education Tax Credit Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish a tax credit (of up to $1,000) for the qualified educational expenses (tuition, attendance fees, books, supplies, equipment, but excluding meals and lodging) paid by a taxpayer for the education at an eligible zone educational institution of each individual with respect to whom the taxpayer is allowed a deduction as a dependent.(Sec. 202) Provides for: (1) the inclusion of certain home schooling expenses; and (2) adjustments for certain scholarships.Defines "eligible zone educational institution" as a secondary school, an elementary school, or any private, parochial, religious, or home school that: (1) provides elementary or secondary education; and (2) is located in an area designated as an empowerment zone or enterprise community.</summary>
</bill>
