<bill session="107" type="h" number="4873" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">J. Dennis Hastert Scholar Athlete Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a scholarship program to recognize scholar athletes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="College sports"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2002--Introduced.
J. Dennis Hastert Scholar Athlete Act of 2002 - Amends part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to make grants to States to award scholarships for one to four years of study at institutions of higher education to individuals who have demonstrated outstanding academic and athletic achievement and show promise of continuing that achievement.Authorizes the Secretary to enter into agreements with States to assure that the scholarship program is administered to comply with specified requirements.Specifies student eligibility requirements based on promise of academic and athletic achievement.Authorizes State educational agencies to establish selection criteria with an emphasis on sports that are a part of the Olympic Games or are not significant revenue generators at particular institutions.</summary>
</bill>
