<bill session="108" type="h" number="1584" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-04-25">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Diamond Trade Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Clean Diamond Trade Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Clean Diamond Trade Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Clean Diamond Trade Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To implement effective measures to stop trade in conflict diamonds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2003-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="2003-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crane moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H2895-2901" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1584.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T17:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H2911" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-04-08T17:47:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="118" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 419 - 2, 1 Present (Roll no. 118).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H2895-2897" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T17:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5112-5113" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2003-04-10" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11T13:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2003-04-11T13:07:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H3332-3334" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H3332-3333" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11T13:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2003-04-14">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2003-04-25">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2003-04-25" type="public" number="108-19">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-19.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="1415"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="760"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Diamonds"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Jewelry trade"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s529"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/25/2003--Public Law.
(This measure has not been amended since it passed the Senate on April 10, 2003. The summary of that version is repeated here.)Clean Diamond Trade Act - (Sec. 4) Directs the President to prohibit the importation into, or exportation from, the United States of any rough diamond, from whatever source, that has not been controlled through the Kimberley Process Certification Scheme (KPCS). Prescribes criteria for waiver of such prohibition.(Sec. 5) Directs the President to require the appropriate Government agency to conduct annual reviews of the standards, practices, and procedures of any entity in the United States that issues Kimberley Process Certificates for the exportation from the United States of rough diamonds to determine whether they accord with the KPCS.(Sec. 6) Makes the importing authority under this Act the U.S. Bureau of Customs and Border Protection (BCBP) and the exporting authority the Bureau of the Census.(Sec. 7) Declares that the Congress supports the policy that the President shall take appropriate steps to promote and facilitate the adoption of the KPCS by the international community.(Sec. 8) Sets forth civil and criminal penalties for violation of this Act. Authorizes the BCBP and the U.S. Bureau of Immigration and Customs Enforcement to enforce this Act and the laws and regulations governing exports of rough diamonds, including with respect to the validation of the Kimberley Process Certificate by the exporting authority.(Sec. 9) Authorizes the President to direct the appropriate Federal agencies to make available technical assistance to countries seeking to implement the KPCS.(Sec. 10) Urges the President to work with states, customs territories, or regional economic integration organizations identified by the Secretary of State (Participants) to strengthen the KPCS through the adoption of measures for: (1) sharing statistics on rough diamonds production and trade; and (2) monitoring the effectiveness of the KPCS in stemming trade in diamonds whose importation or exportation is not controlled through the KPCS.Urges the executive branch continue to: (1) keep and publish statistics on imports and exports of rough diamonds; (2) make them available for analysis by interested parties and by Participants; and (3) take a leadership role in negotiating a standardized methodology among Participants for reporting such statistics.(Sec. 11) Directs the President to establish a Kimberley Process Implementation Coordinating Committee to coordinate the implementation of this Act.(Sec. 12) Prescribes annual reporting requirements.(Sec. 13) Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress within two years after enactment of this Act on the effectiveness of its provisions in preventing the prohibited importation or exportation of rough diamonds.(Sec. 14) Authorizes the President to delegate the duties and authorities under this Act to appropriate Federal officers, departments, or agencies.</summary>
</bill>
