<bill session="108" type="h" number="5295" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-10-08T23:07:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-08T23:07:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Employees Dental and Vision Benefits Enhancement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Federal Employees Dental and Vision Benefits Enhancement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part III of title 5, United States Code, to provide for the establishment of programs under which supplemental dental and vision benefits are made available to Federal employees, retirees, and their dependents, to expand the contracting authority of the Office of Personnel Management, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2004-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08T23:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Government Reform discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08T23:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Murphy asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08T23:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9033-9037" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-10-08T23:07:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9033-9036" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08T23:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="4844"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="2657"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Eye care"/>
    <term name="Eyeglasses"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Hearing"/>
    <term name="Hearing aids"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="United States Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2004--Passed House without amendment.
Federal Employees Dental and Vision Benefits Enhancement Act of 2004 - Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish and administer programs through which current and retired Federal employees and their family members and dependents may obtain enhanced dental and vision benefits to supplement those available under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program (FEHB). Authorizes OPM to prescribe reasonable minimum standards for enhanced dental and vision benefits. Allows a full range of dental benefits, including diagnostic, preventive, emergency care, restorative, oral and maxillofacial surgery, endodontics, periodontics, prosthodontics, and orthodontics. Allows for diagnostic and preventive vision benefits, including eyewear. Requires Federal employees to be responsible for 100 percent of the premiums for dental and vision coverage offered under this Act. Imposes requirements for studies, reports, and audits relating to the dental and vision benefit programs established under this Act. Extends the enhanced dental and vision benefits provided by this Act to employees of the U.S. Postal Service. Expresses the sense of Congress that Federal employee health insurance benefits should be sufficient to promote the health and productivity of such employees and to support the recruitment and retention of a highly qualified workforce. Urges Congress to evaluate such supplemental dental and vision plans to determine the options for, and feasibility of, providing an employer contribution. Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to report to Congress on options: (1) for extending health insurance coverage under FEHB to unmarried dependent college students under age 25; and (2) for extending hearing benefits to Federal employees and annuitants, their relatives, and other appropriate classes of individuals.</summary>
</bill>
