<bill session="104" type="h" number="2347" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To seek international sanctions against the Castro government in Cuba, to plan for support of a transition government leading to a democratically elected government in Cuba, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Banking and Financial Services, the Judiciary, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-19">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.927.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Rules and Organization of the House.</text>
      <committee name="House Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Rules of the House" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="927"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="American property in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="CIS countries"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debt agreements"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Export subsidies"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Expropriation"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import quotas"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="International propaganda"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="National self-determination"/>
    <term name="Naval bases"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Raw materials"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Russian Republic"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trading with the enemy"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Seeking Sanctions Against the Castro Government Title II: Assistance to a Free and Independent Cuba Title III: Protection of Property Rights of United States Nationals Against Confiscatory Takings By the Castro Regime Title IV: Exclusion of Certain Aliens Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1995 - Title I: Seeking Sanctions Against the Castro Government - Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the President should instruct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations to seek within the Security Council a mandatory international embargo against the Cuban Government; and (2) efforts by any state to make the nuclear facility at Cienfuegos operational will have a detrimental impact on U.S. assistance to and relations with such state. (Sec. 102) Reaffirms a provision of the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992 that states that the President should encourage foreign countries to restrict trade and credit relations with Cuba. Urges the President to take steps to apply sanctions described by such Act against countries assisting Cuba. Declares that the President should instruct the Secretary of the Treasury and the Attorney General to enforce the Cuban Assets Control Regulations. Amends the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992, with respect to sanctions against a country that provides assistance to Cuba, to include as such assistance any exchange, reduction, or forgiveness of Cuban debt owed to a country in return for a grant of an equity interest in a property, investment, or operation of the Government of Cuba or of a Cuban national (debt-for-equity swap). (Sec. 103) Prohibits any U.S. national, permanent resident alien, or U.S. agency from knowingly extending any loan or other financing to a foreign national, U.S. national, or permanent resident alien, in order to finance transactions involving property confiscated by the Cuban Government the claim to which is owned by a U.S. national. Terminates such prohibition upon termination of the economic embargo of Cuba. Sets forth penalties for violation of such prohibition. (Sec. 104) Directs the Secretary to instruct the U.S. executive directors of the international financial institutions to oppose the admission of Cuba as a member of such institutions until the President submits a determination that a democratically-elected government is in power in Cuba. Urges the President to support Cuba's membership in such institutions during the period that a transition government is in power, subject to the membership's taking effect after a democratically-elected government is in power. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to withhold U.S. payments from institutions that approve assistance to Cuba over the opposition of the United States. (Sec. 105) Urges the President to instruct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the Organization of American States (OAS) to vote to oppose ending the suspension of Cuba from the OAS until the President determines that a democratically-elected government is in power there. (Sec. 106) Directs the President to report to the appropriate congressional committees on progress towards the withdrawal of personnel of any independent state of the former Soviet Union from the Cienfuegos nuclear facility. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to make ineligible for assistance any independent state of the former Soviet Union that is providing assistance for, or engaging in nonmarket based trade with, Cuba. Withholds from assistance provided for an independent state an amount equal to the assistance and credits provided by such state in support of intelligence facilities in Cuba. Authorizes the President to waive the requirement to withhold such assistance if specified conditions are met. (Sec. 107) Requires the Director of the U.S. Information Agency to convert television broadcasting to Cuba under the Television Marti Service to ultra high frequency broadcasting. Repeals the Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act and the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act upon the determination that there is a democratically-elected government in Cuba. (Sec. 108) Directs the President to report annually to the appropriate congressional committees on assistance and commerce received by Cuba from other foreign countries. (Sec. 109) Authorizes the President to furnish assistance to individuals and independent nongovernmental organizations to support democracy-building efforts for Cuba. Directs the President to take steps to encourage the OAS to create a special emergency fund for the purpose of deploying human rights observers, election support, and election observation in Cuba. Urges the President to instruct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the OAS to encourage other OAS member states to join in calling for the Cuban Government to allow the immediate deployment of independent OAS human rights monitors throughout Cuba and on-site visits to Cuba by the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights. Urges the President to provide not less than $5 million of the U.S. voluntary contribution to the OAS for the purposes of the special fund. (Sec. 110) Directs the President to withhold the allocation of assistance, with specified exceptions, for any country in an amount equal to the sum of assistance and credits, if any, provided by such country in support of the completion of the Cuban nuclear facility at Juragua, near Cienfuegos, Cuba. (Sec. 111) Directs the President to instruct all U.S. Government officials who engage in official conduct with the Cuban Government to raise on a regular basis the extradition of or rendering to the United States of all persons residing in Cuba who are sought by the U.S. Department of Justice for crimes committed in the United States. Title II: Assistance to a Free and Independent Cuba - Requires the President to develop a plan for providing economic assistance to Cuba at such time that a transition or a democratically-elected government is in power. Limits assistance for a transition government to humanitarian assistance necessary for the successful completion of the transition to democracy, remittances by individuals to their relatives of cash or goods, and military adjustment assistance. Expands assistance to include development and agricultural assistance and export financing (as well as other specified assistance) when a democratically-elected government is in power. (Sec. 202) Requires the President to take steps to obtain the agreement of other countries, international financial institutions, and multilateral organizations to provide comparable assistance to Cuba. Requires the President, upon transmittal to the Congress of a determination that a democratically-elected government is in power, to report to appropriate congressional committees on: (1) acts, policies, and practices that constitute significant barriers to, or distortions of, U.S. trade in goods or services or foreign direct investment with respect to Cuba; and (2) U.S. policy objectives regarding trade relations with a democratically-elected government in Cuba, including possible reciprocal extension of nondiscriminatory trade treatment (most-favored-nation treatment), designation of Cuba as a beneficiary developing country under the Generalized System of Preferences under the Trade Act of 1974 or as a beneficiary country under the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act, and negotiations regarding free trade such as Cuba's accession to the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA). (Sec. 203) Requires the President, upon determining that a democratically-elected government is in power in Cuba, to designate a United States-Cuba Council to: (1) ensure coordination between the U.S. Government and private sector in responding to change and promoting market-based development in Cuba; and (2) establish periodic meetings between the U.S. and Cuban private sectors for the purpose of facilitating bilateral trade. (Sec. 204) Authorizes the President to suspend the U.S. economic embargo against Cuba upon determining to the appropriate congressional committees that a democratically-elected government is in power in Cuba. Requires the President to notify the Congress of any action taken to suspend the economic embargo against Cuba. Declares that such suspension shall cease to be effective upon enactment of a joint resolution disapproving such action. (Sec. 205) Sets forth conditions under which a government in Cuba will be considered transitional or democratic. Title III: Protection of Property Rights of United States Nationals Against Confiscatory Takings By the Castro Regime - Makes any person, including any agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, that traffics in confiscated property liable for money damages to any U.S. national who owns the claim to such property. Grants U.S. district courts exclusive jurisdiction over such actions. (Sec. 303) Requires district courts to accept as conclusive proof of ownership a certification of a claim to ownership that has been made by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission pursuant to the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949. Amends such Act to authorize district courts, for fact-finding purposes, to refer to the Commission questions of the amount and ownership of a claim by a U.S. national resulting from the confiscation of property by Cuba, whether or not the U.S. national qualifies as such at the time of the confiscation. (Sec. 304) Bars certain ineligible U.S. nationals, or Cuban nationals, from having a claim in the compensation paid to a U.S. national by virtue of a claim certified by the Commission. Title IV: Exclusion of Certain Aliens - Directs the Secretary of State to exclude from the United States aliens (or their spouses, minor children, or agents) involved in the confiscation of property, or the trafficking in confiscated property, owned by a U.S. national. Provides for case-by-case waiver of this exclusion in the national interest of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
