<bill session="106" type="h" number="4600" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Children's Internet Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require schools and libraries to implement filtering or blocking technology for computers with Internet access as a condition of universal service discounts under the Communications Act of 1934.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400319"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="2000-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400584" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2000-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400547" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400588" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="2000-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2000-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400530" joined="2000-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2000-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2000-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="School boards"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2000--Introduced.
Children's Internet Protection Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to make an elementary or secondary school having computers with Internet access, or a library with one or more computers with Internet access, ineligible to receive universal services at discount rates unless the authority responsible for the administration of such school or library certifies to the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) that it: (1) has selected a technology for such computers which filters or blocks access to material that is obscene, child pornography, and material that is harmful to minors during computer use; and (2) is enforcing a policy to ensure the operation of such technology during any use of such computers by minors. Allows such authority to: (1) use a technology which filters other material deemed inappropriate for minors; and (2) disable such technology during adult use. Requires schools and libraries with filtering technology already installed to certify compliance with this Act during each annual program application cycle. Requires schools and libraries without such technology to certify during the first program year that they are undertaking the procurement of such technology, and for the second program year to certify that they are in compliance with such requirements. Makes any school or library which is unable to certify compliance in the second program year ineligible for universal services funding for that and any subsequent year until such school or library achieves certification (with a waiver if State or local rules or regulations or bidding requirements prevent the making of such certification).Makes each covered school or library not in compliance with such requirements ineligible for funding under the universal services support program and subject to enforcement actions by the FCC.Allows discounted universal service rates to be: (1) available only for services covered by FCC regulations on priorities for funding telecommunications services (including the Internet) that assign priority for available funds for the poorest schools; and (2) used for the purchase or acquisition of appropriate filtering or blocking products, but not for the purchase of unrelated software or other technology.</summary>
</bill>
