<bill session="105" type="hr" number="424" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:20-05:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Travel Reform Rule of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Requiring members, officers, and employees of the House of Representatives to submit reports on travel to the Clerk of the House which include information on the source of funds used to pay for such travel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404996"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1998-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="1998-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-05-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E798)</text>
      <reference ref="CR E798"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSRU" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Airline rates"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional allowances"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Military transportation"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>05/07/1998--Introduced.
Comprehensive Travel Reform Rule of 1998 - Requires each Member, officer, and employee of the House of Representatives to report to the Clerk of the House on the following categories of travel undertaken by the individual: (1) travel for which payment is made from the Members' representational allowance or from the accounts of a House committee or office, other than travel undertaken by a Member (or by his or her employee or an employee of a committee on which the Member is the chair or ranking minority member) between the Member's district and the District of Columbia; (2) travel within a foreign country for which payment is made by the foreign government; and (3) travel in support of the official business of such individual for which payment is made from any source other than described above. Sets forth the contents of such reports and includes within them (for travel paid for by certain nonprofit organizations) a copy of the organizations' contributions and expenditures filed with the IRS and a copy of their schedule of contributions of $5,000 or more received by them during a taxable year. Requires the report within 30 (currently, 60) days after the completion of the travel involved. Makes conforming amendments to rule XI (committee travel expenses) and rule LI (gift ban) of the Rules of the House. Requires the Clerk to notify the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of any Member, officer, or employee who reports after the applicable deadline or whose report fails to meet the requirements of this Act. Provides for: (1) quarterly compilations of such travel reports as well as annual reports of all House travel to be published in the Congressional Record; and (2) availability of such reports on the Internet. Prohibits a Member, officer, or employee from accepting any of the travel described in this Act for which: (1) first class airfare is provided; or (2) the total costs of meals and lodging exceed the amount of the maximum per diem rate set forth in applicable Federal law for other government employees. Exempts travel expenses incurred on behalf of either the spouse or a child of the Member, officer, or employee from restrictions on privately-funded gifts for spouse or family member travel only if the travel is not offered or enhanced because of the official position of the Member, officer, or employee and is customarily provided to others in similar circumstances. Allows the total expenditure for travel under this Act for an individual to exceed the published per diem rate applicable for Federal employees who are not Members, officers, or employees of the House only if the Member or officer involved authorizes the expenditure of a greater amount before the travel occurs. Prohibits a Member, officer, or employee of the House from accepting any official travel paid by private sources unless the travel is preauthorized by the Committee.</summary>
</bill>
