<bill session="104" type="h" number="1806" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Legal Services Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for the Legal Services Corporation Act and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401547" joined="1995-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403864" joined="1995-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1995-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1995-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1995-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1220-1221"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Attorney-client privilege"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bar associations"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election districts"/>
    <term name="Embezzlement"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Eviction"/>
    <term name="Executives"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Judicial districts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor disputes"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal Services Corporation"/>
    <term name="Legal advertising and soliciting"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to prisoners"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to the poor"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legal research"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Political activities"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Rights of institutionalized persons"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State legislative districts"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Welfare reform"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/1995--Introduced.
Legal Services Reform Act of 1995 - Revises the Legal Services Corporation Act, including authorizing appropriations for the Legal Services Corporation for FY 1996 through 2000. (Sec. 4) Prohibits the use of Corporation funds for redistricting activity. (Sec. 5) Applies to the Corporation: (1) Federal criminal laws against theft, fraud, and embezzlement with respect to Corporation funds; (2) the Federal criminal statute against obstructing a Federal audit; and (3) certain provisions of the False Claims Act. (Sec. 6) Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) restrictions on solicitation of clients; and (2) procedural safeguards for litigation. (Sec. 8) Revises lobbying restrictions, including requiring the Corporation to ensure that Corporation funds are not used to pay for publicity or propaganda intended to support or defeat legislation. (Sec. 9) Directs the Corporation to require each recipient of financial assistance to maintain records of time spent on cases. (Sec. 10) Requires the board of directors of each nonprofit organization furnishing legal assistance and receiving Corporation funds to set specific priorities for the types of matters it handles. (Sec. 11) Revises financing provisions to require that non-Federal funds received by the Corporation be accounted for and reported as receipts and disbursements separate and distinct from Corporation funds. (Sec. 12) Prohibits the use of Corporation funds in certain cases involving eviction from public housing for drug violations. (Sec. 13) Requires all Corporation grants and contracts to be awarded under a competitive bidding system. Sets forth provisions governing such system. (Sec. 14) Authorizes the Corporation to provide assistance to substate regional planning and coordination agencies composed of substate areas whose governing boards are controlled by locally elected officials. Repeals provisions authorizing the Corporation to provide certain research and training and technical assistance and to serve as an information clearinghouse. Prohibits a financial assistance recipient, or any client of such recipient, from claiming or collecting attorney fees from nongovernmental parties to litigation initiated by such client with the assistance of such recipient. Directs the Corporation to create a fund to pay defendants or clients under specified circumstances involving retaliation or harassment. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 15) Sets forth restrictions on the use of Corporation funds for: (1) abortion litigation; (2) class actions against the Federal Government or any State or local government; and (3) legal assistance to aliens. (Sec. 18) Revises provisions regarding: (1) the support or conduct of training programs; and (2) fee-generating cases. (Sec. 19) Directs the Corporation to study the feasibility of using client copayments to assist in setting service priorities. Authorizes the Corporation to adopt a permanent system of client copayments for its legal assistance programs. (Sec. 21) Prohibits the use of Corporation funds involving: (1) efforts to reform welfare; and (2) prisoner litigation. (Sec. 23) Directs the President (currently, the board) to appoint the president of the Corporation. (Sec. 24) Prohibits the creation or use of "alternative corporations." (Sec. 25) Limits pay for officers and employees of the Corporation to the rate of level III (currently, V) of the Executive Schedule. (Sec. 26) Requires the Corporation to maintain its principal office in the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area (currently, in the District of Columbia). (Sec. 27) Specifies that "attorney client privilege" protects only a communication made in confidence to an attorney by a client for the purpose of seeking legal advice and does not protect from disclosure to Federal auditors.</summary>
</bill>
