<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="112" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:17-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="1279" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2005-05-11">offered</status>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-05-11"/>
  <description>Amendment, as modified, excludes property crimes from the crime of violence definition for Gang Crimes; makes changes to 18 U.S.C. 1952, Interstate and Foreign Travel in Aid of Racketeering Enterprises, to retain the existing interstate commerce requirement, to add conspiracies as possible violations, and to increase penalties for violations; clarifies the crime of violence definition under 18 U.S.C. 16(b) to include an act that by its nature creates a substantial risk that physical injury may result to a person or property of another; and makes other technical and clarifying changes to the bill.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 109-76 to excludes property crimes from crime of violence definition for Gang Crimes under revised 18 USC 521 Gang Crime; Replaces current text with revised changes to existing 18 USC 1952, Interstate and Foreign Travel in Aid of Racketeering Enterprises, to retain existing interstate commerce requirement, to add conspiracies as possible violation, and to increase penalties for violations; Inserts existing statute text which was inadvertently omitted from introduced and reported versions of H.R. 1279, modifies crime of violence definition under 18 USC 16(b) to clarify that act, by its nature, creates substantial risk that physical injury may result to person or property of another; clarifies exception to ban on possession of handguns by juveniles under 18 USC 922(x) to permit juvenile to possess firearm while in the presence of parent or guardian who is not prohibited from possessing such a firearm by Federal, State or local law, and does not require that juvenile have written authorization from such parent or guardian; includes other technical and grammatical changes.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Sensenbrenner.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3146-3147" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3146-3147" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Sensenbrenner amendment (A001) modified by unanimous consent. Modification seeks to strike that portion of the amendment which proposes to insert material on page 20.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3147" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the Sensenbrenner amendment (A001) as modified Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3147" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
