<bill session="106" type="h" number="2086" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-15T14:56:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-02-15T14:56:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Networking and Information Technology bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize funding for networking and information technology research and development for fiscal years 2000 through 2004, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="1999-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2000-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1999-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400577" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1999-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2000-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400592" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2000-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="1999-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="1999-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1999-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="1999-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1186"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-09-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 41 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T17:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 106-472, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-16T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Ways and Means Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Feb. 29, 2000.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-10T10:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 422 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2086 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15T13:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 422 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15T13:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 422.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H392-408" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15T13:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2086 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15T13:15:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 422 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15T13:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Paul E. Gillmor to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15T13:15:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2086.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - During the amendment process under this open rule, debate time for all amendments will be governed by the 5 minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15T14:55:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2086.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15T14:55:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15T14:56:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H398-400" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-02-15T14:56:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15T14:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="422"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2046"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Encryption"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development tax credit"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Supercomputers"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h573"/>
    <amendment number="h574"/>
    <amendment number="h575"/>
    <amendment number="h576"/>
    <amendment number="h577"/>
    <amendment number="h578"/>
    <amendment number="h579"/>
    <amendment number="h580"/>
    <amendment number="h581"/>
    <amendment number="h582"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>2/15/2000--Passed House amended.
Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Act - Amends the High-Performance Computing Act of 1991 to authorize appropriations for FY 2000 through 2004 for research and development activities of the following departments and agencies in connection with the High-Performance Computing Program (establishing goals and priorities for, and engaging in, Federal high-performance computing research, development, networking, and related activities): (1) the National Science Foundation (NSF); (2) the National Aeronautics and Space Administration; (3) the Department of Energy (DOE); (4) the National Institute of Standards and Technology; (5) the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and (6) the Environmental Protection Agency.Directs the National Institutes of Health to conduct research toward the advancement and dissemination of computational techniques and software tools in support of its mission of biomedical and behavioral research. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2000 through 2004 to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the NSF, and DOE for such activities.Earmarks specified amounts of such authorized funds for: (1) long-term basic research on networking and information technology, including grants for information technology research centers; and (2) grants for the development of major research equipment. Authorizes federally funded research and development centers to apply for and be awarded such latter grants.Directs NSF to provide grants under the Scientific and Advanced Technology Act of 1992 for information technology education and training grants and internship grants. Requires matching funds. Earmarks funds for such grants for FY 2000 through 2004.Directs NSF to establish a research program to develop, demonstrate, assess, and disseminate effective applications of information and computer technologies for elementary and secondary education. Earmarks funds for such grants for FY 2000 through 2004.Authorizes the United States Geological Survey to participate in or support such networking and information technology research and development.Authorizes NSF to enter into an arrangement for the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study of privacy on the Internet. Requires NSF to report to Congress on Council findings, conclusions, and recommendations. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) such study; and (2) FY 2001 and 2002 for support by such departments and agencies of the Next Generation Internet Program (research, development, and demonstration of advanced networking technologies to increase Internet capabilities and performance).Requires a previously-established advisory committee on high-performance computing to: (1) conduct periodic evaluations of high-performance computing and networking and information technology research and development programs; and (2) report at least once every two fiscal years to specified congressional committees on its findings and recommendations.Directs NSF to study and report to Congress comparing the availability of encryption technologies in foreign countries to such technologies subject to export restrictions in the United States.Requires the NSF Director to conduct a study of, and report to Congress on: (1) high-speed, large bandwidth capacity computer access to all U.S. public elementary and secondary schools and libraries; and (2) accessibility to information technologies by individuals who are elderly, disabled, or elderly and disabled.Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress on the effects of this Act on lower income families, minorities, and women.Prohibits funds appropriated pursuant to this Act from being expended by an entity unless it agrees to comply with the Buy American Act. Expresses the sense of Congress that, in the case of equipment and products purchased by such entities with such financial assistance, such entities should purchase only American-made equipment and products.</summary>
</bill>
