<bill session="108" type="h" number="4965" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Black-Market Elimination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To impose sanctions on foreign entities that engage in certain nuclear proliferation activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2004-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2004-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2004-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400442" joined="2004-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2004-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2004-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2004-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2004-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2004-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2004-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Commercial blacklisting"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Military aircraft"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military technology"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Rockets (Ordnance)"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
    <term name="Warships"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2004--Introduced.
Nuclear Black-Market Elimination Act - Authorizes the President to prohibit, for at least three years, any transaction or dealing by a U.S. person or within the United States with any foreign person or entity that the President determines sells, transfers, brokers, finances, assists, delivers or otherwise provides or receives, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act: (1) nuclear enrichment or reprocessing equipment, materials, or technology to any country for which an additional protocol with the International Atomic Energy Agency for the application of safeguards is not in force, or to any country that the President determines is developing, constructing, manufacturing, or acquiring a nuclear explosive device; or (2) designs, equipment, or specific information to assist in the development, construction, manufacture, or acquisition of a nuclear explosive device by a non-nuclear weapon state. Authorizes the President to provide assistance for up to three years under the Arms Control Act and the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as well as a drawdown of defense equipment and services under the latter Act, to any country that cooperates with the United States and U.S. allies to prevent the transport and transshipment of items of proliferation concern in its national territory or airspace or in vessels under its control or registry. Prohibits the United States from transferring any excess defense article that is a vessel or aircraft to a country that has not provided written assurances that it will support and assist U.S. efforts to interdict items of proliferation concern. Prohibits the President from providing, in any fiscal year, more than 75 percent of U.S. assistance to Pakistan unless Pakistan meets certain requirements, including fully sharing with the United States all information relevant to the A.Q. Khan proliferation network, and providing full access to A.Q. Khan, his associates, and any material that bears upon their activities and contacts. Provides for a national security waiver of such requirements, but prohibits its exercise in two successive fiscal years. Requires the President to: (1) identify proliferation network host countries to appropriate congressional committees; and (2) suspend all arms sales licenses to such countries.</summary>
</bill>
