<bill session="105" type="h" number="2108" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-08-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dutch John Federal Property Disposition and Assistance Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Dutch John Federal Property Disposition and Assistance Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To dispose of certain Federal properties located in Dutch John, Utah, and to assist the local government in the interim delivery of basic services to the Dutch John community, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-08-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-15T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-714.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-15T13:10:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="410">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 410.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="890"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="890"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Church property"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community facilities"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Mormons"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Postal facilities"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/1998--Reported to House amended.
Dutch John Federal Property Disposition and Assistance Act of 1998 - Provides for the transfer or disposal of certain Federal properties at Dutch John, Utah. Transfers lands designated for disposal from the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary), acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, to the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation (BLM), and, if appropriate, the Postal Service. Removes such lands from inclusion in the Ashley National Forest and the Flaming Gorge National Recreation Area. Directs: (1) the Secretary of the Interior to transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain lands acquired for the Central Utah Project to the Secretary; and (2) the Secretary to transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain lands in the Ashley National Forest to the Secretary of the Interior. Incorporates lands transferred to the Secretary into the Ashley or Uinta National Forests. Directs the Secretary to transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain lands to the Postal Service. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to conduct appraisals to determine the fair market value of properties designated for disposal. Conveys specified infrastructure facilities, land, and public schools to Daggett County, and certain facilities of the Utah Division of Wildlife Resources to the Division, without consideration. Sets forth requirements for the purchase of disposed residential properties. Bases priority in purchasing on seniority of reclamation lease or residency in Dutch John. Limits households to one residential lot. Sets forth requirements for the purchase of unoccupied lots, special use lands, and church land. Transfers all water rights to the Dutch John municipal water system to the County, subject to certain conditions. Requires the Secretary to consider issuance of a special use permit affording Flaming Gorge Reservoir public shoreline access and use within the vicinity of Dutch John in conjunction with commercial visitor facilities provided under such a permit. Directs the Secretary, before transfer or disposal of any land that contains cultural resources and may be eligible for listing on the National Register of Historic Places, to prepare a memorandum of agreement, for review and approval by the Utah Office of Historical Preservation and the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, that contains a strategy for protecting or mitigating adverse effects on cultural resources. Conveys such land to the County upon completion of actions required under the agreement. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to provide training and transitional operating assistance to County personnel designated as successors to operators of conveyed infrastructure facilities. Provides for annual payments to the County, for up to 15 years, for purposes of defraying administrative transition costs. Makes available a limited amount of electric power and energy from the Colorado River Storage Project for the Dutch John community. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
