<bill session="104" type="h" number="1227" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-23T15:35:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-05-23T15:35:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Minimum Wage Increase bill</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Employee Commuting Flexibility Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Minimum Wage Increase Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 relating to the payment of wages to employees who use employer owned vehicles.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400567" joined="1996-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400568" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1995-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="1996-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1995-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1995-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404367" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1995-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1995-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="1995-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1995-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1995-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400242" joined="1995-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="407669" joined="1995-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400510" joined="1995-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1995-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1996-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="1996-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="1996-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E590"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-03-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-05-20T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Economic and Educational. H. Rept. 104-585.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-05-20T14:57:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="289">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 289.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21T22:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 440 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3448 and H.R. 1227 with 5 hours of general debate. Providing for the consideration of H.R. 3448 and H.R. 1227 in the House. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means to H.R. 3448 now printed in the bill shall be considered as read and all points of order against the amendment (except those arising under sec. 425(a) of the Budget Act, shall be waived. The bill and amendment shall be debatable for one hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motion except a motion to recommit with or without instructions. The yeas and nays shall be considered as ordered on passage and on any conference report. After disposition of H.R. 3448, it shall be in order without intervening point of order to consider the bill H.R. 1227 in the House. The amendment in the nature of a substitut...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 440 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T20:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Armey asked unanimous consent that during consideration of the bill H.R. 1227 pursuant to H. Res. 440, notwithstanding the order of the previous question, it may be in order after 30 minutes of the 90 minutes provided for initial debate on the bill, as amended pursuant to the rule, for the Chair to postpone further consideration of the bill until the following legislative day, on which consideration may resume at a time designated by the Speaker. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T20:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 440.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5478-5485" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T20:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3448 and H.R. 1227 with 5 hours of general debate. Providing for the consideration of H.R. 3448 and H.R. 1227 in the House. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means to H.R. 3448 now printed in the bill shall be considered as read and all points of order against the amendment (except those arising under sec. 425(a) of the Budget Act, shall be waived. The bill and amendment shall be debatable for one hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motion except a motion to recommit with or without instructions. The yeas and nays shall be considered as ordered on passage and on any conference report. After disposition of H.R. 3448, it shall be in order without intervening point of order to consider the bill H.R. 1227 in the House. The amendment in the nature of a substitut...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T20:24:00-04:00">
      <text>After disposition of H.R. 3448, it shall be in order without intervening point of order to consider the bill H.R. 1227 in the House. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Economic Opportunities now printed in the bill, as modified by the amendment printed in sec. 3 of the report accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and any further amendment without intervening motion except:</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T20:24:00-04:00">
      <text>90 minutes of debate on the bill; an amendment printed in part 2 of the report accompanying this resolution, which shall be separately debatable for one hour, and on which the question shall be divided between the proposed subsection 3(d) and the remainder of the proposed section 3; and one motion to recommit with or without instructions. In the engrossment of the bill H.R. 3448, the text of H.R. 1227 shall be added to the bill and, H.R. 1227 shall be</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T20:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the House proceeded with 30 minutes of the 90 minutes of general debate provided by the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T21:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the bill would be postponed until Thursday, May, 23, 1996. When consideration continues, there will be an additional period of one hour for general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-22T21:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Further consideration suspended, leaving H.R. 1227 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23T09:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5503-5544" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23T09:02:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The House continued with general debate on the bill. At the time debate resumed, 60 minutes of general debate remained from last evening.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23T10:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Riggs moved to consider the Riggs amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23T11:03:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to consider the Riggs amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 267 - 161 (Roll no. 191).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 90 minutes of debate on the Riggs amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 440, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Goodling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 440, the amendment will be divided into two parts on the question of its adoption. The Speaker will first put the question on agreeing to sections A, B, and C of the Goodling amendment. The Speaker will then put the question on the remaining section D, which would exempt small businesses with gross annual sales under $500,000 from the minimum wage provisions of the Fair Labor Standards Act.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-05-23T15:35:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="195" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 281 - 144 (Roll no. 195).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Laid on the table. See H.R. 3448 for further action.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23T15:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 440, the House appended the text of H.R. 1227 as passed by the House to H.R. 3448. See H.R. 3448 for further action.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5544" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="440"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3448"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Computer programming"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing personnel"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Professions"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tipping"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1083"/>
    <amendment number="h1084"/>
    <amendment number="h1085"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/23/1996--Passed House amended.
Employee Commuting Flexibility Act of 1996 - Amends the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 to provide that an employer does not have to pay minimum wages or overtime compensation to an employee for or on account of such employee's use of employer-owned vehicles for traveling for commuting purposes, if such use is: (1) within the normal commuting area for the employer's business or establishment; and (2) subject to an agreement on the part of the employer and the employee or employee representative. Considers such commuting use, and activities incidental to it, as not part of the employee's principal activities, thus relieving the employer of liability and punishment, under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, Walsh-Healey Act, and Davis-Bacon Act, for failure to pay such wage or compensation for the time of such use. Minimum Wage Increase Act of 1996 - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to increase the minimum wage rate from the current $4.25 per hour to: (1) $4.75 per hour during the year beginning on June 30, 1996; and (2) $5.15 per hour after that year. Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exempt from minimum wage and overtime requirements certain computer professionals who are compensated at a rate of not less than $27.63 per hour. Revises provisions relating to the tip credit for determining the minimum wage for tipped employees. Allows an employer to pay less than the minimum wage (as increased by this Act, but not less than $4.25 per hour) to any employee who is less than 20 years old, during the first 90 consecutive calendar days after such employee is hired.</summary>
</bill>
