<bill session="104" type="h" number="1917" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">DeLauro-Lowey Water Pollution Control and Estuary Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide special funding to States for implementation of national estuary conservation and management plans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404634" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="406082" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="406284" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1995-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1995-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection groups"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Municipal politics and government"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/1995--Introduced.
DeLauro-Lowey Water Pollution Control and Estuary Restoration Act - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to extend the authorization of appropriations for the State water pollution control revolving fund program through FY 2002. Requires a specified percentage (increasing with each succeeding fiscal year) of such appropriations to be used for capitalization grants for estuary plans to qualified States. Prohibits a qualified State from submitting an estimate of needs unless the estimate is approved by each management conference that is implementing an approved estuary plan and of which the State is a member. Makes States that fail to submit approved need estimates ineligible for assistance. Directs States to establish separate Estuary Accounts in their water pollution control revolving funds, to be used for implementing approved estuary plans. Permits loans made with Account funds to be for terms of up to 40 years or for the useful life of a facility constructed with the loan, whichever is less, if the borrower demonstrates financial hardship. Establishes a State matching requirement for deposits into Accounts. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to make grants for the implementation of estuary conservation and management plans. Authorizes appropriations. Permits certain grants under the National Estuary Program to be used for interim actions adopted by management conferences to protect the water and sediment quality of estuaries. Extends the authorization of appropriations for management conferences, grants, conservation and management plans, and research under the National Estuary Program through FY 2002. Directs the Administrator to issue a guidance document establishing requirements for: (1) management conferences to follow in developing and monitoring conservation and management plans; and (2) the Administrator to follow in approving implementation strategies included in such plans and in approving interim actions to protect the water quality of the estuary for which a conservation and management plan is developed. Specifies that a management conference convened under the Act shall be convened for a period of at least five years. Authorizes the Administrator, upon approval of a plan and for purposes of monitoring or implementing the plan, to extend a conference for an additional five years if the affected Governors concur and the extension is necessary to meet specified Act requirements. Sets forth conditions under which management conferences may be terminated. Revises approval and implementation procedures for estuary conservation and management plans and establishes procedures for interim actions. Prohibits any activity located in U.S. waters or which serves new development in such waters from being included in a conservation and management plan or a State needs estimate unless specified Federal officials determine that: (1) the activity is essential to reduce the discharge of pollutants into navigable waters; and (2) there is no practicable alternative to the proposed activity that would have a less adverse impact on the aquatic habitat.</summary>
</bill>
