<bill session="108" type="h" number="2548" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 5 of subtitle I of title 40, United States Code, to enhance Federal asset management, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2003-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400200" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400304" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2003-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-07-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuum of care"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2003--Introduced.
Federal Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to direct the Administrator of General Services to: (1) establish, maintain, and apply current asset management principles to real and personal property; (2) establish performance measures to determine Federal real property management effectiveness; and (3) establish and maintain a single database of all Federal real property interests. Requires each Federal landholding agency to appoint a Senior Real Property Officer to monitor and administer real property assets. Authorizes landholding agencies to apply enhanced asset management tools, such as interagency transfers or exchanges, sales or exchanges with non-Federal sources, and subleases or outleases to other Federal agencies or non-Federal entities, for real property. Allows the Administrator to: (1) review any transaction undertaken by an agency utilizing such authority; and (2) disapprove such transaction if it does not reflect due diligence by the agency, is not in the best interest of the United States, or does not comply with property management requirements. Permits a building to be constructed or altered only: (1) in compliance with one of the nationally recognized model building codes and with other applicable nationally recognized codes; and (2) after consideration of all requirements (other than procedural requirements) of zoning laws and laws relating to landscaping, open space, minimum distance from the property line, maximum height historic preservation, and esthetic qualities and other similar laws of a State that would apply if it were not a building constructed or altered by a Federal agency. Sets forth special rules for consultation, review, and inspections by State and local government officials. Allows such officials to make recommendations concerning measures that are necessary to meet such codes and measures that should be taken in consideration of local conditions. Waives such provisions with respect to any building if their application would adversely affect national security. Prohibits agency actions involving use of enhanced asset management tools, determing real property to be excess, or disposing of excess real property with respect to specified Federal land and improvements in Los Angeles and Sepulveda, California. Provides for: (1) the crediting of monetary proceeds from the disposition of real and related personal property to existing agency accounts to pay for capital asset expenditures of that agency; (2) Federal agencies to retain from proceeds of sales of personal property amounts necessary for recovering full direct and indirect costs incurred in disposing of such property; and (3) implementation of such disposal and accounting requirements for FY 2003 through 2007. Authorizes the: (1) conveyance of surplus Federal property to non-profit organizations for preservation purposes and, generally, for public airport use; and (2) abandonment, destruction, or other disposal of property if it has no commercial value or if costs of continued care and handling would exceed its fair market value. Amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to revise procedures for the consideration of surplus real property for homeless assistance.</summary>
</bill>
