<bill session="108" type="h" number="4246" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">2005 BRAC Selection Criteria Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 to specify the criteria to be used by the Secretary of Defense in making recommendations in 2005 for the closure or realignment of military installations inside the United States under such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400434"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2004-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-25">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2004--Introduced.
2005 BRAC Selection Criteria Act - Amends the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 to add the following to the final criteria to be used by the Secretary of Defense in making recommendations in 2005 for the closure or realignment of military installations inside the United States: (1) the current and future mission requirements and the impact on operational readiness of the total force of the Department of Defense; (2) the availability and condition of land, facilities, infrastructure, and associated air and water space at both existing and potential receiving locations; (3) the ability to accommodate contingency, mobilization, and future total force requirements at both existing and potential receiving locations to support operations, training, maintenance, and repair; and (4) preservation of land, air, and water space, facilities, and infrastructure necessary to support training and operations of military forces determined by the Secretary to be surge (manpower) requirements. Requires the added criteria to be given priority in recommending installations for closure or realignment.</summary>
</bill>
