<bill session="108" type="h" number="4691" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to engage in a feasibility study relating to long-term water needs for the area served by the Fryingpan-Arkansas Project, Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400020" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2004-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-01">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water allocation (Policy)"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water rates"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2004--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, through the Bureau of Reclamation, to conduct a study to determine the most feasible method of meeting water supply and related storage requirements within the area served by the Fryingpan-Arkansas Project, Colorado (the Project), including the potential enlargement of Fryingpan-Arkansas facilities. Directs the Secretary to take into consideration the Preferred Storage Options Plan Report published September 21, 2000, by the Southeastern Colorado Water and Storage Needs Assessment Enterprise and Final PSOP Implementation Committee Report dated April 19, 2001 (PSOP Reports), the intergovernmental agreement dated May 27, 2004 among the Cities of Pueblo, Aurora, Fountain, and Colorado Springs, the Southeastern Colorado Water Conservancy District, and the Board of Water Works of Pueblo, Colorado, and the need to ensure compliance with the Arkansas River Compact as executed by the States of Colorado and Kansas on December 14, 1948. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into contracts with any entity, including those operating or participating in a water bank established pursuant to Colorado law, for the use of excess capacity in the Project for the purpose of diverting, storing, impounding, pumping, exchanging, or conveying non-project water for irrigation or domestic, municipal, or industrial purposes. Requires the Secretary to take into consideration the PSOP Reports and the need to ensure compliance with the Arkansas River Compact. Directs the Secretary to establish charges for the use of excess capacity. Sets forth provisions regarding the diversion, storage, impoundment, pumping, exchange, or conveyance of non-project water.</summary>
</bill>
