<bill session="105" type="h" number="4355" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Year 2000 Information Disclosure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage the disclosure and exchange of information about computer processing problems and related matters in connection with the transition to the Year 2000.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400607" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1998-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1998-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6875-6877"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-26">
      <text>For Further Action See S.2392.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="2392"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="2392"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Libel and slander"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Warranties"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Year 2000 computer problem"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/1998--Introduced.
Year 2000 Information Disclosure Act - Provides that, in any covered civil action based on an allegedly false, inaccurate, or misleading statement concerning Year 2000 computer compliance information (Y2K problem), the maker of such statement shall not be liable unless the claimant establishes that the statement: (1) was material; (2) where not a republication, was made with knowledge that it was false, inaccurate, or misleading, with an intent to mislead or deceive, or with a grossly negligent failure to determine or verify its accuracy; and (3) where it was a republication of a statement regarding a third party, was made with knowledge that it was false, inaccurate, or misleading and without disclosure that it was based on information supplied by another and that the maker has not verified the statement. Provides that, in any covered action in which the adequacy of notice about Year 2000 processing is at issue and no clearly more effective method of notice is practicable, the posting of notice by the entity purporting to have provided such notice on that entity's Year 2000 Internet website shall be presumed to be an adequate mechanism for providing such notice. Provides that, in any covered action arising under any Federal or State defamation law or law relating to trade disparagement or a similar claim, to the extent such action is based on an allegedly false Year 2000 statement, the maker shall not be liable unless the claimant establishes by clear and convincing evidence that the statement was made with knowledge that it was false or with reckless disregard of its truth. Prohibits in any covered action a Year 2000 statement from being interpreted or construed as an amendment to or alteration of a written contract or warranty, whether entered into by a public or private party (with exceptions). Authorizes a Federal entity, agency, or authority to expressly designate requests for the voluntary provision of information relating to Year 2000 processing as "Special Year 2000 Data Gathering Requests," thereby protecting information received from such requests from: (1) disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act; and (2) use by any Federal entity, agency, or authority in any civil action arising under any Federal or State law (with an exception). Provides exclusions from this Act. Makes this Act applicable to any Year 2000 statement made on or after July 14, 1998, through July 14, 2001.</summary>
</bill>
