<bill session="105" type="hj" number="44" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to require a balanced budget.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400300"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Capital budgets"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Deficit financing"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/1997--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Prohibits the United States from ever contracting any public debt except in the cases and manners provided in this article. Exempts the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund from any limitation imposed by this Article. Allows the United States to borrow money to repel invasion, suppress insurrection, or defend the United States in time of war, if the money raised is applied exclusively to the object for which the loan was authorized or to the repayment of such debt. Allows the United States to contract public debt to acquire, construct, develop, extend, enlarge, or improve land, waters, property, highways, railways, buildings, equipment, or facilities for public purposes or to make funds available for veterans' housing loans, if the President determines and the Congress concurs by a majority vote that to prevent an unacceptable reduction in economic growth that would raise unemployment or diminish family income, it is essential for the United States to provide for such needed capital investments by contracting public debt. Allows the United States to contract public debt to fund or refund the whole or any part of indebtedness incurred before this Article takes effect. Requires this article to take effect beginning with the later of FY 2002 or the second fiscal year beginning after its ratification.</summary>
</bill>
