<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1104" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="6052" sequence="3"/>
  <status datetime="2008-06-26T16:46:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="412197"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  <description>Amendment provides an exception to section 526 of the Energy Independence and Security Act (regarding procurement and acquisition of alternative fuels) by exempting contracts for generally available fuels that are not predominantly produced from noncontroversial petroleum sources if (1) the contract does not require the contractor to provide alternative fuels; (2) the purpose of the contract is not to obtain an alternative fuel; and (3) the contract does not provide incentives for a refinery upgrade or expansion to allow a refinery to use or increase its use of fuel from a nonconventional petroleum source.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 3 printed in House Report 110-734 to provide an exception to section 526 of the Energy Independence and Security Act (regarding procurement and acquisition of alternative fuels) by exempting contracts for generally available fuels that are not predominantly produced from noncontroversial petroleum sources if (1) the contract does not require the contractor to provide alternative fuels, (2) the purpose of the contract is not to obtain an alternative fuel, and (3) the contract does not provide incentives for a refinery upgrade or expansion to allow a refinery to use or increase its use of fuel from a nonconventional petroleum source.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26T15:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Mahoney (FL).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6135-6137, H6140" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6135-6136" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2008-06-26T16:46:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="465">
      <text>On agreeing to the Mahoney (FL) amendment (A003) Agreed to by recorded vote: 421 - 0 (Roll no. 465).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
