<bill session="105" type="hr" number="89" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-12T17:03:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-03-12T17:03:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Requesting the President to submit a budget for fiscal year 1998 that would balance the Federal budget by fiscal year 2002 without relying on budgetary contingencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="1997-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1997-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="1997-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-11T19:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 90 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 89 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the resolution in the House. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12T13:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 90 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12T13:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 90.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12T13:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 89 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the resolution in the House. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12T13:57:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 90, the House proceeded with two hours of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12T16:23:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H904-923" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12T16:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Spratt moved to recommit with instructions to Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12T16:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Spratt motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12T16:36:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12T16:37:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 202 - 225 (Roll No. 43).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H922-923" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1997-03-12T17:03:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="44" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 197 (Roll No. 44).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-03-12T17:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="90"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Budget Office"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economic forecasting"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/1997--Introduced.
Requests the President to submit a detailed plan to balance the Federal budget by FY 2002, as estimated by the Congressional Budget Office (CBO), that: (1) uses the most recent CBO economic and technical assumptions; (2) reduces the deficit through programmatic reforms rather than alternative budgetary procedures such as automatic spending cuts and the sunsetting of tax cuts; (3) realizes a significant proportion of its total savings in the first three years; and (4) offers sufficient Medicare reforms to forestall the imminent bankruptcy of the Medicare trust funds for a substantial period.</summary>
</bill>
