<bill session="104" type="h" number="2389" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safeguarding Medicare Integrity Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To combat fraud and abuse in the medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1995-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicaid fraud"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Preventing Fraud and Abuse Title II: Regulatory Relief Safeguarding Medicare Integrity Act of 1995 - Title I: Preventing Fraud and Abuse - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) make certain ongoing efforts to alert Medicare beneficiaries of any fraud or abuse committed against the Medicare program as well as of the toll-free telephone line for reporting such fraud and abuse; (2) provide an explanation of Medicare benefits with respect to each item or service for which payment may be made regardless of whether or not a deductible or co-payment may be imposed; and (3) issue special Medicare-related fraud alerts upon request after investigation. Directs the Secretary to establish certain incentive programs to: (1) encourage the reporting of Medicare fraud and abuse; and (2) collect information on program efficiency. (Sec. 103) Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to revise contracting requirements, allowing imposition of intermediate sanctions for specified program violations in lieu of contract termination under guidelines for the payment of health maintenance organizations and competitive medical plans. Applies such sanctions to any Medicare program violation. (Sec. 104) Amends SSA title XI (General Provisions and Peer Review) to direct the Secretary to establish a voluntary disclosure program for an individual or entity with information on acts or omissions of such individual or entity which constitute grounds for a sanction. Authorizes the Secretary to waive or mitigate any applicable sanction in the event of such a voluntary disclosure. (Sec. 105) Amends SSA title XI to revise current sanctions, increasing criminal fines and establishing a minimum period of exclusion for certain individuals and entities subject to permissive exclusion. (Sec. 106) Amends SSA title XVIII (Medicare) to create the Medicare Integrity Program for contracting with eligible entities to conduct various anti-fraud and abuse review and audit activities. Establishes the Anti-Fraud and Abuse Trust Fund in the Treasury, consisting of specified fines, penalties, and amounts transferred from the Federal Hospital Trust Fund and the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund, to carry out such activities. Provides for a direct appropriation of funds to carry out the program. Prohibits any agency or organization (including fiscal intermediaries and insurance carriers) from carrying out any such activities that have been contracted out. (Sec. 107) Permits Medicare carriers to carry out prior authorization for certain items of durable medical equipment. (Sec. 108) Directs the Attorney General to establish a Health Care Anti-Fraud Task Force within the Department of Justice to prosecute health care fraud offenses. (Sec. 109) Directs the Administrator of the Health Care Financing Administration (acting through the Office of Research and Development) to contract with a private entity to study for a report to Congress on the adequacy of private quality assurance programs and consumer protections used by eligible organizations with risk-sharing contracts under Medicare, including an analysis of the effectiveness of such organizations in protecting enrollees against the risk of insufficient provision of benefits which may result from utilization controls. Title II: Regulatory Relief - Amends SSA title XI to provide for regulatory relief with regard to: (1) the imposition of civil monetary and anti-kickback penalties (and associated exceptions); and (2) the effect and application of safe harbor exceptions. (Sec. 203) Provides for solicitation of proposals for and publication of modifications to existing safe harbors and addition of new ones. (Sec. 204) Directs the Secretary to issue advisory opinions regarding prohibited remuneration, inducements to reduce or limit Medicare or Medicaid services, or qualification of any activity or proposed activity for the imposition of specified sanctions. Prohibits advisory opinions with respect to fair market value of goods, services, or property, or to an individual's status as a bona fide employee.</summary>
</bill>
