<bill session="106" type="h" number="3483" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Derivatives Market Reform Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal securities laws to enhance oversight over certain derivatives dealers and hedge funds, reduce the potential for such entitles to increase systemic risk in the financial markets, enhance investor protections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2510-2511"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Derivative securities"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Holding companies"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Professional associations"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Stock exchanges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Derivatives Dealers Title II: Broker-Dealer Oversight Reforms Title III: Hedge Fund Reporting Derivatives Market Reform Act of 1999 - Title I: Derivatives Dealers - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to prescribe procedural guidelines for the mandatory registration of derivatives dealers. Grants the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) enforcement powers, including examination of such dealers' records.Title II: Broker-Dealer Oversight Reforms - Authorizes a national securities exchange and a registered securities association to adopt and implement rules governing members engaged in derivatives transactions.(Sec. 203) Requires SEC financial responsibility rules to include the mandatory maintenance of sufficient capital levels by any derivatives dealer that is a material person associated with a registered broker or dealer (after taking into account the financial activities, customary sources of capital, and the credit risk and aggregate leverage of such derivatives dealer).(Sec. 205) Sets forth recordkeeping and reporting requirements, for risk assessment purposes, with respect to persons associated with brokers and dealers of government or municipal securities, including disclosure of such persons': (1) monitoring of financial and operational risks to associated brokers and dealers; and (2) financial and securities activities, and customary sources of capital and funding.(Sec. 207) Requires the SEC to take all actions necessary to establish regulations pertaining to large trader reporting requirements.(Sec. 208) Grants rulemaking powers under this Act to: (1) the SEC; (2) the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System; and (3) other designated agencies. Amends the Market Reform Act of 1990 to reinstate certain annual reporting requirements.Title III: Hedge Fund Reporting - Amends the Investment Company Act of 1940 to require unregistered hedge funds to submit quarterly status reports to the SEC.(Sec. 301) Instructs the SEC to transmit copies of such reports to specified regulatory agencies and to the public.</summary>
</bill>
