<bill session="104" type="hr" number="130" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-06T15:07:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-04-06T15:07:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 483), to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to permit medicare select policies to be offered in all States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400327"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-04-05T23:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-103, by Ms. Pryce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-05T23:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 483 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of H.R. 1391 as an original bill for the purpose of amendment. No further amendment shall be in order except an amendment in the nature of a substitute to be offered by Representative Dingell, debatable for one hour, and shall not be subject to further amendment. It shall be in order for the Committee on Commerce to file a report on H. R. 483 at any time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-04-05T23:42:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="41">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 41.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06T13:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4366-4374" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06T14:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-04-06T15:07:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="298" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 253 - 172 (Roll no. 298).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06T15:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="483"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h340"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/6/1995--Passed House amended.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 483 (amending the Social Security Act to permit Medicare select policies to be offered in all States).</summary>
</bill>
