<bill session="106" type="h" number="3267" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fairness for the Military Reserve Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve benefits for members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces and their dependents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400573"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2000-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="2000-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-12-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Military aircraft"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/1999--Introduced.
Fairness for the Military Reserve Act of 1999 - Authorizes armed forces reserve and National Guard personnel traveling to perform annual training duty outside the continental United States to travel on a space-required basis between the member's home and place of duty if there is no available road or rail transportation.Directs the Secretary of Defense to prescribe regulations to allow the following persons to receive transportation on Department of Defense (DOD) aircraft on a space-available basis under the same terms and conditions that apply to members of the armed forces entitled to retired pay: (1) members of the Selected Reserve in good standing; (2) a former reserve member under 60 years of age who would be eligible for retired pay except for being under such age; and (3) dependents of the above. Limits the required identification for such travel.Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations authorizing a reserve member traveling to inactive duty training at least 50 miles from home to be eligible for billeting (housing) in DOD facilities on the same basis as active-duty personnel traveling under orders away from such member's duty station. Requires proof of the reason for such travel.Increases the maximum number of reserve retirement points that may be credited in a year for reserve service from 75 to 90 for years during and subsequent to the date of enactment of the Reserve Component Equity Act of 1999.Authorizes the Secretary of the military department concerned to provide civil legal services to reserve personnel (and their dependents) not otherwise entitled to such services, but only during a period following a release from active duty under a call or order to such duty for more than 29 days under a mobilization authority that is not in excess of twice the length of the duty period served.</summary>
</bill>
