<bill session="106" type="h" number="2810" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Violent Offender DNA Identification Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate the exchange by law enforcement agencies of DNA identification information relating to violent offenders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1999-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400588" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="1999-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="1999-10-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8577"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Burglary"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Courts-martial and courts of inquiry"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="DNA fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Forensic medicine"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military and naval offenses"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/1999--Introduced.
Violent Offender DNA Identification Act of 1999 - Requires the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to develop a voluntary plan to assist State and local forensic laboratories in performing deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) analyses of DNA samples collected from convicted offenders, aimed at eliminating the backlog of convicted offender DNA samples awaiting analysis in State or local forensic laboratory storage in an efficient, expeditious manner that will provide for their entry into the Combined DNA Indexing System (CODIS). Sets forth provisions regarding plan conditions and plan implementation. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 3) Revises the Antiterrorism and Effective Death Penalty Act of 1996 to authorize the Director of the FBI to expand CODIS to include information on DNA identification records and analyses related to criminal offenses under Federal law, the Uniform Code of Military Justice, and the District of Columbia (DC) Code.Modifies the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 (VCCLEA) to authorize the Director to establish an index of individuals convicted of criminal offenses, including specified qualifying offenses. Directs that the index include only information on DNA identification records and DNA analyses that undergo semiannual external proficiency testing and that meet other specified requirements.Requires the Director to establish a list of qualifying offenses, including each criminal offense under Federal law that constitutes a serious violent felony or burglary, and under the DC Code that would, if committed in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, constitute a serious violent felony or burglary, and certain standards and procedures.Requires: (1) the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to collect a DNA sample from each individual in the custody of the Bureau who has been convicted of a qualifying offense; and (2) the agency responsible for the supervision under Federal law of an individual on supervised release, parole, or probation to collect a DNA sample from each individual who has been convicted of a qualifying offense.Authorizes the Government of DC to collect a DNA sample from each individual in custody of DC as a result of a conviction for a qualifying offense. Requires that such DNA identifications records be automatically removed when the underlying conviction for the qualifying offense is vitiated or expunged by appeal or otherwise.Directs the Director of the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for DC, or the Trustee appointed under the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 as appropriate, to collect a DNA sample from each individual under Agency or Trustee supervision who is on supervised release, parole, or probation and who has been convicted of a qualifying offense.Directs the Secretary of Defense to prescribe regulations that specify categories of conduct punishable under the Uniform Code of Military Justice (qualifying military offenses) that are comparable to qualifying offenses, and sets forth standards and procedures for the analysis of DNA samples collected from individuals convicted of a qualifying military offense, their inclusion in an index, and the automatic removal of DNA identification records and analyses under specified circumstances.Sets criminal penalties for individuals from whom the collection of a DNA sample is required or authorized who fail to cooperate in the collection of that sample.Authorizes appropriations. Requires such cooperation as a condition of probation, supervised release, or release generally.Sets forth report and evaluation requirements.</summary>
</bill>
