<bill session="104" type="h" number="1252" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stormwater Management Improvement Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to improve stormwater management, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1995-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="404367" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1995-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1995-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E613"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/1995--Introduced.
Stormwater Management Improvement Act of 1995 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to apply permit requirements to stormwater discharges associated with commercial activity and to certain discharges from storm sewer systems serving populations between 50,000 and 100,000 in urbanized areas in which other discharges requiring permits are located. Exempts, with exceptions, a discharge composed entirely of stormwater from a municipal storm sewer system serving a population of between 50,000 and 100,000 individuals that is located in an urbanized area from permit requirements prior to October 1, 2001. Exempts, with exceptions, sources of discharges composed entirely of stormwater from municipal storm sewer systems from permit requirements (currently, such exemption is only available prior to October 1, 1994). Provides that permits issued for discharges from municipal storm sewers composed entirely of stormwater shall not require compliance with numeric effluent limitations and water quality standards shall not be applied or enforced as effluent limitations. Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue a consolidated permit for discharges from a storm sewer system owned by a municipality and the stormwater discharges from industrial or commercial sources owned by the same municipality. Requires the Administrator to establish permit requirements for stormwater discharges from commercial and light industrial sources. Authorizes the Administrator to exempt certain commercial and light industrial stormwater discharges from permit requirements. Exempts stormwater discharges from small industrial or commercial businesses (businesses with a maximum of 25 employees and defined as small business concerns pursuant to the Small Business Act) from permit requirements unless the discharge contributes to a violation of a water quality standard or is a significant contributor of pollutants. Directs the Administrator to establish an initiative to fund State and local demonstration programs and research to test innovative approaches to address the impacts of hydrologic and hydraulic changes, source controls, and water quality management practices and controls for runoff from municipal storm sewers. Authorizes appropriations. Makes municipalities subject to stormwater discharge permit requirements eligible for grants to train citizens in watershed monitoring activities to support municipal stormwater management programs.</summary>
</bill>
