<bill session="106" type="h" number="2825" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Lands Improvement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to dispose of all public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management that have been identified for disposal under the Federal land use planning process.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400116"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2000-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1999-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1999-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="1999-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1999-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="1999-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1837-1838"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Paleontology"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/1999--Introduced.
Federal Lands Improvement Act of 1999 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to dispose of all public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) that, as of the enactment date of this Act, have been identified for disposal under the Federal land use planning process under the Federal Land Policy and Management of 1976. Requires the disposal of at least one- third of such lands before the end of the next three years, two-thirds before the end of the next five years, and all such lands within seven years.Prohibits the disposal of: (1) lands located in wilderness areas or wilderness study areas; and (2) parcels of land if the cost of disposal exceeds the amount that would be received for such parcels.Requires the disposal of such public lands in parcels of 160 acres or less.Requires one-third of the proceeds to be deposited in a separate account established by this Act, one-third to be paid to the county in which the lands are located, and one-third to be deposited in the Treasury's general fund and utilized for reducing the public debt. Requires the separate account to be available to the Secretary for paying, subject to specified limitations: (1) costs incurred by the BLM in arranging the disposals; (2) the cost of acquisition from a willing seller of environmentally sensitive land in States in which such public lands are located ; (3) the cost of carrying out any necessary revision or amendment of a current BLM land use plan that relates to such public lands; (4) the cost of projects or programs to restore or protect wetlands, riparian areas, or cultural, historic, prehistoric, or paleontological resources on public lands, including petroglyphs; and (5) the cost of projects, programs, or land acquisition to stabilize or restore water quality for water located or used on public lands.Requires the Secretary to report to Congress each fiscal year on the use of such proceeds.</summary>
</bill>
