<bill session="106" type="h" number="2913" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Juvenile Accountability and Diversion Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to authorize grants to provide juvenile accountability coordinators to take a comprehensive approach to holding first- and second-time nonviolent juvenile offenders accountable for their actions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400186"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1917"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administration of juvenile justice"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child mental health services"/>
    <term name="Community service (Punishment)"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Delinquency prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Juvenile detention"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Prison alternatives"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/1999--Introduced.
Juvenile Accountability and Diversion Act of 1999 - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to authorize the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to make grants to units of local government for the purpose of employing juvenile accountability coordinators each of whom shall provide comprehensive services to juveniles (and their families) who come within the juvenile justice system and who are not alleged to have committed a serious crime.Directs the Administrator to take into consideration: (1) the per capita rate of offenses (other than serious crimes) committed by juveniles in the geographical area under the jurisdiction of each unit of local government that applies for a grant for that fiscal year; and (2) the economic resources available to such local governmental unit. Limits the aggregate amount of such grants to a particular unit of local government for a fiscal year to $300,000.Sets forth grant eligibility requirements, including assurances that: (1) the grant will be used only to employ, as part of the juvenile justice system administered by such local governmental unit, one or more qualified juvenile accountability coordinators, subject to specified requirements (including record-keeping requirements); and (2) if a juvenile complies with a diversion accountability plan, such local governmental unit will not adjudicate the offense with respect to which such plan is developed.Sets forth reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
