<bill session="104" type="hj" number="123" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Continuing Appropriation (third)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406863"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-18T12:27:00-05:00">
      <text>CONSIDERATION OF LEGISLATION - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 275, the Chair announced that a motion to suspend the rules and pass H.J. Res. 123 would be considered later in the day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-18T13:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Livingston moved to suspend the rules and pass the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-18T13:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13325-13332" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-18T13:36:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-11-18T14:44:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="818" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 416 - 0 (Roll no. 818).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-11-18T14:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-11-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="246">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 246.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S17485-17486" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Amendment SP 3061 proposed by Senator Dole.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Amendment SP 3061 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1995-11-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19T20:41:00-05:00">
      <text>CONSIDERATION OF LEGISLATION - Mr. Livingston asked unanimous consent that it be in order to take from the Speaker's table the joint resolution H.J. Res. 122, with the Senate amendment thereto, and to consider in the House a motion offered by the Chairman of the Committee on Appropriations to dispose of the Senate amendment, that the Senate amendment shall be considered as read, that the motion shall be debatable for ten minutes equally divided and controlled by the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee, and that the previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to final adoption without intervening motion. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19T20:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Livingston moved that the House agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19T20:42:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent request, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Livingston motion.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1995-11-19T20:43:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13343-13346" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19T20:43:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19T20:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1995-11-19">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1995-11-19" type="public" number="104-54">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-54.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Administrative Conference of the U.S."/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Budget reconciliation"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Interstate Commerce Commission"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban renewal"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3061"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/19/1995--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Continuing Appropriations Title II: (Unnamed) Title I: Continuing Appropriations - (Sec. 101) Makes further continuing appropriations for FY 1996 for continuing projects and activities, including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees, conducted in 1995 and for which appropriations or other authority would be available in the following Acts: (1) the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996; (2) the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 1996; (3) the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1996; (4) the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1996; (5) the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996; (6) the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996; (7) the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1996; (8) the Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 1996; (9) the Treasury, Postal Service, and General Government Appropriations Act, 1996; and (10) the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996. Sets the rates of such funding. Sets forth limitations on the use of such funds. (Sec. 106) Provides that, unless otherwise provided for in this joint resolution or in the applicable appropriations Act, appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this joint resolution shall be available until: (1) enactment of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution; (2) the enactment of the applicable appropriations Act by both Houses without any provision for such project or activity; or (3) November 20, 1995, whichever first occurs. States that for purposes of this resolution, the period of time covered by this resolution shall be considered to have begun on November 14, 1995. (Sec. 111) Provides in specified circumstances, except for section 106, for the maintenance of a minimum level of funding for projects or activities under any Act listed in section 101. Defines minimum level. (Sec. 112) Requires, except for section 106 and under specified conditions, that whenever the rate for operations for any continuing project or activity would result in a furlough of Government employees, that rate for operations may be increased to a minimum level that would enable the furlough to be avoided. (Sec. 113) Requires, except for sections 106, 111, and 112, that for those programs that had high initial rates of operation or complete distribution of funding at the beginning of FY 1995 because of distributions of funding to States, foreign countries, grantees, or others, similar distributions of funds for FY 1996 shall not be made and no grants shall be awarded for such programs funded by this resolution that would impinge on final funding prerogatives. (Sec. 115) Provides that section 132 of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act of 1988 (which provides that amounts appropriated for the Federal Payment to the District of Columbia shall not be subject to apportionment) shall not apply for this joint resolution. Provides for including in the apportionment for the Federal Payment to the District of Columbia an additional $15 million for certain capital construction loan repayments. (Sec. 116) Requires, except for section 106, that the authority and conditions for the application of appropriations of the Office of Technology Assessment as contained in House Report 104-212, shall be followed when applying the funding made available by this joint resolution. (Sec. 119) Requires, except for section 106, the Securities and Exchange Commission's Salaries and Expenses amount to include, in addition to direct appropriations, the amount it collects under the fee rate and offsetting collection authority. (Sec. 120) Requires that funding be made available for the necessary expenses of the Bureau of Mines for: (1) continuing limited health and safety and related research, materials partnerships, and minerals information activities; (2) mineral assessments in Alaska; and (3) terminating all other activities of the Bureau of Mines. (Sec. 121) Requires, except for section 106, that funds for the Environmental Protection Agency shall be made available in the appropriation accounts which are provided in H.R. 2099 as reported on September 13, 1995. (Sec. 122) Sets forth a special formula for determining the rate of operations for projects and activities that would be funded under the heading "International Organizations and Conferences, Contributions to International Organizations" in the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996. (Sec. 123) Provides, except for section 106, that the rate for operations of the following projects or activities shall be only the minimum necessary to accomplish orderly termination: (1) Administrative Conference of the United States; (2) Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations (with an exception); (3) Interstate Commerce Commission; (4) Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation; (5) Land and Water Conservation Fund, State Assistance; and (6) Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, Rural Abandoned Mine Program. Title II: - Waives parchment printing requirements of the enrollment of: (1) a continuing resolution; (2) a debt limit extension measure; and (3) a reconciliation bill. (Sec. 202) Sets forth the definitions of terms used in this joint resolution.</summary>
</bill>
