<bill session="106" type="hr" number="390" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives concerning the peace process in Angola.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1999-11-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1999-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA08" subcommittee="Africa" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Angola"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diamonds"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Land mines"/>
    <term name="Minesweeping"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations technical assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/1999--Introduced.
Supports: (1) the people of Angola in their re-commitment to national dialog in pursuit of peace; and (2) efforts to establish a nonpartisan Angolan Institute for Peace and Development. Affirms U.S. support for Angolan peace through continued direct engagement in the United States-Angola Bilateral Consultative Commission.Urges: (1) the National Union for the Total Independence of Angola (UNITA) to suspend hostilities and to pledge to fulfill its commitments under the Lusaka Protocol, and the Angolan Government to suspend hostilities; (2) the United Nations (UN) to swiftly reestablish its presence in Angola under its new mandate to promote human rights protection and humanitarian action; (3) the warring parties immediately to establish peace corridors to facilitate the movement of humanitarian assistance to feed the more than 1 million internally displaced Angolan people; and (4) the United States to support financially and diplomatically the efforts of the UN Committee on Sanctions to identify and rein in all violators of sanctions against diamond and arms sales.Calls upon: (1) the international community to remain actively engaged in support of national reconciliation, removal of land mines, economic development, and democratization in Angola; (2) the Angolan Government to continue to implement elements of the Lusaka Protocol aimed at accelerating the democratic transition; (3) all parties to recognize and support the broadening and the implementation of the movement for peace which is emerging from religious and civil society organizations in Angola; and (4) the UN to work with the Southern Africa Development Community to develop a monitoring regime to interdict all supplies to UNITA and restrict illegal arms and diamond trafficking.</summary>
</bill>
