<bill session="104" type="h" number="2916" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Towing Vessel Safety Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 46, United States Code, to ensure the safety of towing vessels.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1996-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1996-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="1996-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1996-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E125-126"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Maritime satellites"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Navigation satellites"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tugboats"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/1996--Introduced.
Towing Vessel Safety Act of 1996 - Amends Federal marine safety law to require the Secretary of Transportation, in prescribing regulations for towing vessels, to: (1) consider the characteristics and nature of the service of towing vessels; (2) consult with the Towing Safety Advisory Committee; and (3) require the installation of certain navigational safety equipment on each towing vessel (other than one used only for towing disabled vessels). Revises the marine casualty reporting deadline to require that marine casualties be reported as soon as practicable, but in no case later than within five days (currently, within five days). Increases from $1,000 to up to $25,000 the civil penalty for vessel owners and operators for failing to report marine casualties. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress on the feasibility of establishing a differential global positioning satellite navigation system and creating electronic charts for U.S. inland waterways. Revises antidiscrimination provisions to prohibit a vessel owner or operator from temporarily removing a seaman because he or she refuses in good faith to violate marine safety regulations. Requires towing vessels to be: (1) manned by a licensed master; and (2) operated by a licensed individual. Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations which establish licenses for masters and mates of such vessels, subject to specified conditions. Subjects towing vessels to Federal inspection laws, with specified exceptions. Increases civil penalties for violations of licensing (from $5,000 to $25,000) and manning (from $1,000 to up to $25,000) requirements committed by owners and operators of uninspected towing vessels.</summary>
</bill>
