<bill session="104" type="h" number="2576" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-11-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend authorities under the Middle East Peace Facilitation Act of 1994 until December 1, 1995, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Arab countries"/>
    <term name="Commercial blacklisting"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
    <term name="West Bank"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/2/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Middle East Peace Facilitation Act of 1994, as contained in the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995, and as amended by other Federal law, to extend, from November 1, 1995, through December 1, 1995, the President's authority to suspend specified prohibitions against foreign and United Nations assistance to the Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO), the receipt or expenditure of PLO funds, and PLO membership in the International Monetary Fund, upon certification to specified congressional committees that: (1) such waiver is in the national interest; and (2) the PLO continues to abide by commitments made in letters to Israel and the Foreign Minister of Norway and under the Declaration of Principles signed in September 1993. Amends the Middle East Peace Facilitation Act of 1995 (not enacted until February 12, 1996) to decrease from 18 months to 12 months the President's period of authority to suspend certain provisions of law with respect to the PLO.</summary>
</bill>
