<bill session="104" type="hr" number="542" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Concerning the implementation of the General Framework Agreement for Peace in Bosnia and Herzegovina.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1996-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Inspection (Arms control)"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National self-determination"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="War crime trials"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="Yugoslavia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/1996--Introduced.
Declares that the United States is committed to the goals enunciated in the General Framework Agreement for Peace in Bosnia, Herzegovina, and associated annexes. Urges: (1) the United States and the international community to oppose efforts to advocate secession and to support the work of the parties to the Agreement to establish democratic institutions and the rule of law in Bosnia and Herzegovina; (2) the signatories to such Agreement and those nations and organizations participating in its implementation to make it an urgent priority to bring to justice persons indicted by the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia; and (3) the latter entities to ensure implementation of the arms control and confidence building agreements reached as part of the Agreement, including the Agreement on Sub-Regional Arms Control, and to undertake the destruction of those weapons above agreed ceilings. Commends the members of the NATO-led Peace Implementation Forces in Bosnia and Herzegovina for their work in carrying out their mandate and in ensuring a calm and orderly election process.</summary>
</bill>
