<bill session="106" type="h" number="4642" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-13">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make certain personnel flexibilities available with respect to the General Accounting Office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="2000-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-19T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Burton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-19T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7799-7804" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-19T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4642.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-09-19T15:46:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7799-7801" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-09-19T15:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-04">
      <text>Senate Committee on Governmental Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-10-04" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9867" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-04">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2000-10-05">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-06">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-10-13">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-10-13" type="public" number="106-303">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-303.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="General Accounting Office"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Severance pay"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' preference"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2000--Passed House amended.
Amends Federal civil service provisions with respect to the Civil Service Retirement System and the Federal Employees' Retirement System to entitle certain officers and employees of the General Accounting Office (GAO) who separate from service voluntarily to annuities under such system, as applicable.Grants to the Comptroller General of GAO the authority to provide voluntary separation incentive payments to GAO employees. Sets forth the terms and conditions and requirements governing such authority.Amends provisions relating to GAO's personnel management system to require the Comptroller General to prescribe regulations, consistent with regulations issued by the Office of Personnel Management for the separation of employees during a reduction in force or other adjustment in force, which give effect to the following factors in descending order of priority: (1) tenure of employment; (2) military preference; (3) veteran's preference; (4) performance ratings; (5) length of service; and (6) other objective factors such as skills and knowledge that the Comptroller General considers necessary and appropriate to realign GAO's workforce to meet current and future mission needs, to correct skill imbalances, or to reduce high-grade, managerial, or supervisory positions. (Provides that the regulations relating to removal from the GAO Senior Executive Service in a reduction in force or other adjustment in force shall be consistent with requirements for competitive procedures for a reduction in force in the Senior Executive Service.) Requires such regulations to provide that a final decision by the GAO Personnel Appeals Board may be reviewed by the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.Prohibits an employee from being released due to a reduction in force unless such employee is given written notice at least 60 days before being released. Allows the Comptroller General, in writing, to shorten the period of advance notice for a particular reduction in force if necessary because of circumstances not reasonably foreseeable, except that such period may not be less than 30 days. Requires such regulations to include provisions under which, at the Comptroller General's discretion, the opportunity to separate voluntarily (in order to permit the retention of an individual occupying a similar position) shall be available to the same extent and in the same manner as with respect to the Department of Defense or a military department.Authorizes the Comptroller General to establish senior-level positions to meet GAO's critical scientific, technical or professional needs. Provides for the numerical limitation under the personnel system to apply to such senior-level positions. Permits the reassignment of an officer or employee in GAO's Senior Executive Service to any such senior-level positions as the Comptroller General determines necessary and appropriate.Permits: (1) the procurement of 15 temporary or intermittent experts and consultants for renewable terms of not more than three years (currently, for not more than three years); and (2) changes the rate of pay with respect to certain experts and consultants.Requires the Comptroller General to: (1) include in each annual report to Congress during a five-year period a review of all actions taken pursuant to this Act relating to retirement and reductions in force; and (2) submit to Congress within three years a report on the implementation and effectiveness of this Act, including any assessment or recommendation of the GAO Personnel Appeals Board or of any interested groups or associations representing GAO officers or employees.</summary>
</bill>
