<bill session="106" type="h" number="361" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Indian Federal Recognition Administrative Procedures Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for administrative procedures to extend Federal recognition to certain Indian groups, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="1999-01-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E81-82"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-15">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/1999--Introduced.
Indian Federal Recognition Administrative Procedures Act of 1998 - Establishes the Commission on Indian Recognition within the Department of the Interior which shall assume the Department's authority to recognize a petitioning Indian group's tribal status. Sets forth operating and petitioning procedures. Requires petitions to contain specific evidence establishing certain mandatory criteria, including that: (1) the petitioner has been identified as an American Indian entity on a substantially continuous basis since 1934; (2) a predominant portion of the petitioning group comprises a distinct community and has existed as a community since 1934; (3) the petitioner has maintained political influence or authority over its members as an autonomous entity from 1934 until the present; (4) a governing document or description of membership criteria is submitted; (5) the petitioner's membership consists of individuals who descend from a historical Indian tribe or from tribes which combined and functioned as a single autonomous political entity; and (6) the membership of the petitioning group is composed principally of persons who are not members of any acknowledged North American Indian tribe. Requires the Commission to publish an annual list of recognized Indian tribes. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award petition assistance grants. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
