<bill session="106" type="hr" number="485" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-04T11:02:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-05-04T11:02:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1106) to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to make grants to State agencies with responsibility for water source development for the purpose of maximizing available water supply and protecting the environment through the development of alternative water sources.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-05-02T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-603, by Mr. Goss.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-02T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1106 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-05-02T19:05:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="216">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 216.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-05-04T10:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2557-2558" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-04T10:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 485.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-04T11:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2000-05-04T11:02:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2557" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-05-04T11:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="106" type="h" number="1106"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/2000--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 1106 (alternative water sources).</summary>
</bill>
