<bill session="106" type="h" number="4800" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ronald Reagan Recognition Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Ronald Reagan Memorial Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of the Interior to identify appropriate lands within the area designated as Section 1 of the Mall in Washington, D.C., as the location of a future memorial to former President Ronald Reagan, to identify a suitable location, to select a suitable design, to raise private-sector donations for such a memorial, to create a Commission to assist in these activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="2000-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="2000-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="2000-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1143"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-09-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-22T12:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-884.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-22T12:40:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="534">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 534.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Reagan Administration"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2000--Reported to House amended.
Ronald Reagan Memorial Act of 2000 - Authorizes the Ronald Reagan Memorial Commission to establish the Ronald Reagan Memorial on specified Federal lands administered by the National Park Service in the District of Columbia. Requires the National Capital Memorial Commission and the Secretary of the Interior to assist Commission members: (1) in the preparation of a recommendation to Congress of a permanent location for the memorial; and (2) the selection of a design for the memorial and the grounds of the memorial.Requires the Secretary to erect a suitable marker designating the"Future Site of the Ronald Reagan Memorial" which shall be maintained at the location until the memorial is open to the public.Establishes the Ronald Reagan Memorial Commission to: (1) raise necessary funds from appropriate private sector sources to design, construct, and maintain the memorial; (2) determine and recommend to Congress a permanent location for the memorial; (3) select a design for the memorial; and (4) report to Congress and the President on a recommended location and final design for the memorial no later than February 6, 2002.</summary>
</bill>
