<bill session="106" type="hj" number="109" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-29">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Continuing Appropriation FY2001 (First)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400439"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-09-25T19:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 591 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 109 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 591 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 591.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8114-8123" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 109 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.J. Res. 109.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-09-26T16:53:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="493" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 415 - 2 (Roll no. 493).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8114-8115" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-09-26T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="831">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 831.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9406-9440" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-09-28" how="roll" result="pass" roll="259" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 0. Record Vote Number: 259.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-09-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-09-29">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-09-29">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-09-29" type="public" number="106-275">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-275.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="591"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Earth resources satellites"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Political leadership"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2000--Introduced.
Makes appropriations for FY 2001 for continuing projects or activities, including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees, which were conducted in FY 2000 and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority would be available in: (1) the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001; (2) the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001; (3) the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2001; (4) the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2001; (5) the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2001; (6) the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001; (7) the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001; (8) the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2001; (9) the Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001; (10) the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2001; and (11) the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001.Continues funding of projects or activities at the current rate of operations and sets forth limitations on such funding.(Sec. 106) Provides funding under this resolution until enactment into law of any covered appropriation or the applicable appropriations Act (without any provision for the covered appropriation) or October 6, 2000, whichever occurs first.(Sec. 115) Continues certain activities authorized by the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 and the Russian Leadership Program under the 1999 Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act through the date for which funding is provided under this resolution.(Sec. 117) Requires the rate for operations for decennial census programs that would be funded under the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001 to be the budget request.(Sec. 118) Authorizes the U.S. Geological Survey to sign a contract to maintain Landsat-7 flight operations consistent with the President's budget proposal to transfer flight operations responsibility from the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to the Geological Survey.(Sec. 119) Authorizes the obligation and expenditure in FY 2001 of funds previously appropriated to the American Section of the International Joint Commission in the Emergency Supplemental Act, 2000.</summary>
</bill>
