<bill session="105" type="h" number="4326" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oregon Public Lands Transfer and Protection Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Oregon Public Lands Transfer and Protection Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Oregon Public Lands Transfer and Protection Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Oregon Public Lands Transfer and Protection Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain Federal lands located within or adjacent to the Rogue River National Forest and to clarify the authority of the Bureau of Land Management to sell and exchange other Federal lands in Oregon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-07-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-12T16:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-810.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-10-12T16:02:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="454">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 454.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-12T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-12T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10598-10602" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-10-12T16:21:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-12T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-14" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12533" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-10-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-10-30" type="public" number="105-321">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-321.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="h" number="4526"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="2394"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Logging"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Railroad land grants"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h931"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/12/1998--Passed House amended.
Oregon Public Lands Transfer and Protection Act of 1998 - Provides for the transfer of: (1) specified lands in the Rogue River National Forest System, Oregon, from public domain status to the National Forest; and (2) other lands from the National Forest to public domain status. Restores the status of certain revested Oregon and California railroad grant lands (O&amp;C lands) and revokes the reservation of such lands as part of the National Forest. Adds certain other revested railroad grant lands to such National Forest. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of the Interior, in carrying out sales, purchases, and exchanges of Bureau of Land Management (BLM) lands located within six Oregon districts (the geographic area), to ensure that, upon the expiration of a ten-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and each ten-year period thereafter, the total number of acres of O&amp;C lands, Coos Bay Wagon Road grant lands, and public domain lands in the geographic area that are available for timber harvesting is not less than such number on the date of enactment of this Act. (Sec. 4) Transfers administrative jurisdiction over certain lands in Lake County, Oregon, located adjacent to or within the Hart Mountain National Antelope Refuge, from BLM to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service. Includes transferred lands within the Refuge. Withdraws such lands from the public land, mineral leasing, and mining laws. Requires BLM to retain jurisdiction over certain lands located south of the Refuge identified for cooperative management. Requires such lands that are within the Guano Creek Wilderness Study Area to be managed to maintain the values for which the Area was designated. Transfers administrative jurisdiction over other specified lands adjacent to or within the Refuge from the Fish and Wildlife Service to BLM. Removes such lands from the Refuge and designates them as public lands. (Sec. 5) Increases from 300 to 1,000 acres the area included within the Bandon Marsh National Wildlife Refuge, Oregon. (Sec. 6) Amends the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992 to authorize the Secretary to participate in the design, planning, and construction of the Willow Lake Natural Treatment System Project for the reclamation and reuse of wastewater within and outside of the service area of Salem, Oregon. Limits the Federal share of project costs to 25 percent. Prohibits the Secretary from providing funds for project operation and maintenance. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the Secretary, acting through BLM, to make available for sale at fair market value to Deschutes County, Oregon, a parcel of land in such County, to be used for private residential development and the provision of community amenities and services. Requires the amount paid to be deposited in a special account and used to purchase environmentally sensitive land to be utilized within the BLM land use planning process.</summary>
</bill>
