<bill session="105" type="h" number="974" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to restore the Department of Defense loan guarantee program for small and medium-sized business concerns that are economically dependent on defense expenditures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1997-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1997-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="1997-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-03-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H772"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E408-409"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="735"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Conversion of industries"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Diversification in industry"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/1997--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to support through the provision of loan guarantees programs sponsored by the Federal Government, regional entities, State and local governments, private entities, and nonprofit organizations that assist small and medium-sized businesses that are economically dependent on defense expenditures to acquire dual-use (military and commercial) capabilities. Provides for the transfer of such loan guarantee authority and funding from the Secretary to the appropriate Federal agency by way of a memorandum of understanding. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out the loan guarantee program during any fiscal year for which funds are specifically made available for such purpose. Requires competitive procedures to be used in the selection of appropriate businesses for the loan program, under specified criteria. Requires a borrower to demonstrate that, during any one of the past seven years, at least 25 percent of the borrower's sales were derived from: (1) contracts with the Department of Defense or defense-related activities of the Department of Energy; or (2) subcontracts in support of defense-related prime contracts. Provides for: (1) a maximum loan amount and a loan guaranty rate; and (2) a 60-40 allocation of loan funds to small and medium-sized businesses, respectively. Provides for the continued availability through FY 1999 of current funding for the loan guarantee program.</summary>
</bill>
