<bill session="107" type="h" number="2397" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Office of Personnel Management to conduct a study to determine the approximate number of Federal employees and annuitants who are eligible to participate in the health benefits program under chapter 89 of title 5, United States Code, but who are covered neither by such program nor by any other health insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2001-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Civil Service and Agency Organization.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service and Agency Organization" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2001--Introduced.
Directs the Office of Personnel Management to determine and report to Congress: (1) the approximate total number of Federal employees and annuitants who are eligible to participate in the Federal employees health benefits program, but who are covered neither by such program nor by any other health insurance; (2) the principal reasons why those individuals did not obtain health insurance under such program and the approximate number (and percentage) assignable to each reason; and (3) the approximate number (and percentage) of such employees employed in respective Government instrumentalities and paid at respective Federal pay levels.</summary>
</bill>
