<bill session="105" type="h" number="4118" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Children's Health Insurance Accountability Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act and part 7 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to establish standards for the health quality improvement of children in managed care plans and other health plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="1998-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1998-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="1998-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1199"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child mental health services"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled children"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Mental health services for youth"/>
    <term name="Pediatricians"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Youth"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/1998--Introduced.
Children's Health Insurance Accountability Act of 1998 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to mandate that a group health plan or health insurance issuer provide to children of enrollees and enrollees who are children: (1) access to primary care providers who specialize in pediatrics and pediatric specialty services; (2) access to a sufficient number, distribution, and variety of qualified participating health care providers; (3) emergency services coverage without a requirement for either prior authorization determination, or a participating provider; (4) pediatric specialty services without imposing cost-sharing in excess of that required for other specialty care, and nonparticipating pediatric specialty services without additional cost; and (5) coverage that includes special consideration for the provision of services to children with special health care needs. (Sec. 3) Prescribes guidelines for continuity of care in the event that a contract between a health insurance issuer and a heath care provider should be terminated. Mandates that group health plans that cover children and health insurance issuers that offer health insurance coverage for children: (1) establish and maintain an ongoing, internal quality assurance program that meets certain requirements; (2) conduct utilization review activities that comply with prescribed criteria; (3) establish an internal and external appeals and grievance system meeting specified requirements; and (4) disseminate benefits and processes to the public plan. Requires group health plans and issuers of both group and individual health insurance plans to comply with the children's health accountability requirements set forth in this Act. (Sec. 3) (sic) Makes conforming amendments to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to study and report to the Congress on: (1) unique characteristics of patterns of illness, disability, and injury in children; (2) development of measures of quality of care and outcomes related to the health care of children; and (3) access of children to primary mental health services and the coordination of managed behavioral health services. Directs the General Accounting Office to study and report to certain congressional committees on: (1) the structure and performance of certain health plans (especially non-governmental plans) serving the needs of children with special health care needs; and (2) a survey of health plan activities that address the health needs of adolescents, including quality measures and innovative practice arrangement.</summary>
</bill>
