<bill session="106" type="h" number="1097" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to simplify the $500 per child tax credit and other individual non-refundable credits by repealing the complex limitations on the allowance of those credits resulting from their interaction with the alternative minimum tax.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400291"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1999-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1999-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1999-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="1999-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E404-405"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/1999--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise limitations under subpart A (Nonrefundable Personal Credits) of part IV (Credits Against Tax) to prohibit the aggregate amount of credits allowed by such subpart for the taxable year from exceeding the sum of: (1) the taxpayer's regular tax liability for the taxable year; and (2) the tax imposed for the taxable year by alternative minimum tax provisions. Repeals provisions concerning: (1) with respect to the additional credit for families with three or more children, the reduction of the child tax credit for a taxpayer subject to the alternative minimum tax; and (2) the supplemental child credit. Reduces the income threshold amount for the phaseout of the child tax credit.</summary>
</bill>
