<bill session="104" type="h" number="3759" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-11T15:51:00-04:00">PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-09-11T15:51:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Exports, Jobs, and Growth Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Exports, Jobs, and Growth Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend the authority of the Overseas Private Investment Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409423"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404996" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="406082" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="407669" joined="1996-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1996-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-07-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1224"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-07-10">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-07-30T21:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on International Relations. H. Rept. 104-722.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-07-30T21:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="386">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 386.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-10T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Roth moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-10T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10157-10167" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-10T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-10T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed until Sept. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10179"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-11T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10197-10198" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="1996-09-11T15:51:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="412" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 157 - 260 (Roll no. 412).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-11T15:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communist countries"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Eastern Europe"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="International Development Cooperation Agency"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Overseas Private Investment Corporation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/1996--Reported to House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Overseas Private Investment Corporation Title II: Trade and Development Agency Title III: Export Promotion Programs within the International Trade Administration Title IV: Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee Exports, Jobs, and Growth Act of 1996 - Title I: Overseas Private Investment Corporation - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to increase the maximum per capita income levels of less developed countries eligible for Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) economic investment projects. Increases the ceilings on the maximum contingent liabilities outstanding at any one time for investment insurance and for the financing of investment guarantees issued by OPIC as well as of direct U.S. investment. Extends OPIC's authority to issue such insurance and guarantees through FY 2001. Revises the congressional purpose of OPIC to include increasing U.S. exports to less developed countries and countries in transition from nonmarket to market economies. Revises the composition of the OPIC Board of Directors. Title II: Trade and Development Agency - Authorizes appropriations for the Trade and Development Agency for FY 1997 and 1998. Title III: Export Promotion Programs Within the International Trade Administration - Amends the Export Administration Amendments Act of 1985 to authorize appropriations for the Department of Commerce export promotion programs for FY 1997 and 1998. Title IV: Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee - Amends the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to require the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee (TPCC) to develop a Federal trade promotion plan that, among other things, shall: (1) identify the means for providing more coordinated export promotion services to small and medium-sized businesses; and (2) establish a set of priorities to promote U.S. exports to, and free market reforms in, the Middle East that are designed to stimulate job growth both in the United States and the region. Requires the TPCC to: (1) identify areas of overlap and duplication among Federal export promotion activities and report on actions to eliminate such overlap and duplication; and (2) report to the Congress on actions taken to promote better coordination among State, Federal, and private sector export promotion activities. Requires the TPCC, in a specified annual report to the Congress, to describe the activities of TPCC departments and agencies to foster U.S. trade and investment which will facilitate private sector development in the Ukraine.</summary>
</bill>
