<bill session="108" type="hc" number="268" updated="2013-07-14T19:03:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-10-28T16:46:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-10-28T16:46:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the imposition of sanctions on nations that are undermining the effectiveness of conservation and management measures for Atlantic highly migratory species, including marlin, adopted by the International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas and that are threatening the continued viability of United States commercial and recreational fisheries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2003-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2003-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-10-28T14:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-327.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-10-28T14:21:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="114">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 114.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-10-28T16:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Saxton moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-28T16:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9843-9846" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-28T16:27:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 268.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-10-28T16:46:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9843" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-10-28T16:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishery products"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Tuna"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2003--Passed House amended.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that the President should: (1) direct the U.S. Commissioners to the International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas to seek the establishment of effective conservation, management, and enforcement measures for the species under consideration at the 2003 Commission meeting, including for Atlantic marlin; (2) continue to encourage members and nonmembers that fish in the Commission regulatory area to make every effort to end illegal, unregulated, and unreported fishing, including any fishing that is not in conformance with relevant conservation recommendations adopted by the Commission, including those concerning Atlantic marlin landing reductions; (3) make full use of all appropriate diplomatic mechanisms, relevant international laws and agreements, and other appropriate mechanisms to ensure conformance with conservation recommendations for all species under the Commission's management authority, including Atlantic marlin; and (4) continue to encourage the Commission to adopt conservation recommendations authorizing the use of enforceable measures to prevent those who fish in the Commission regulatory area from taking actions that would undermine the effectiveness of conservation and management recommendations of the Commission. Declares the sense of Congress, in addition, that when any vessels of a country are being used in the conduct of fishing operations in the Convention area in such a manner or in such circumstances as would tend to diminish the effectiveness of Commission conservation recommendations, then the President and the Secretary of Commerce, consistent with their statutory authorities and international obligations, should exercise their authorities under the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975 and under the Commission's rules that ensure conformance with Commission recommendations by member and nonmembers. Declares the sense of Congress, furthermore, that if nationals of a Commission member or nonmember, directly or indirectly, are conducting fishing operations in such a manner or in such circumstances as would tend to diminish the effectiveness of the Commission's fishery conservation programs, then the Secretary of Commerce, consistent with international obligations, should certify that fact under the Fishermen's Protective Act of 1967 (thus triggering the President's authority to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to prohibit the bringing or the importation into the United States of any products from the offending country for any appropriate duration, to the extent sanctioned by the World Trade Organization or the multilateral trade agreements).</summary>
</bill>
