<bill session="105" type="h" number="3625" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">San Rafael Swell National Heritage and Conservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">San Rafael Swell National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">San Rafael Swell National Heritage and Conservation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">San Rafael Swell National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the San Rafael Swell National Heritage Area and the San Rafael Swell National Conservation Area in the State of Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-03">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-07">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-07-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-08-07T12:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-685.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-08-07T12:12:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="387">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 387.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="All terrain vehicles"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecotourism"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Paleontology"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public schools"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/7/1998--Reported to House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: San Rafael Swell National Heritage Area Title II: San Rafael Swell National Conservation Area Subtitle A: Establishment of Conservation Area Subtitle B: Wilderness Areas Within Conservation Area Subtitle C: Other Special Management Areas Title III: General Management Provisions San Rafael Swell National Heritage and Conservation Act - Title I: San Rafael Swell National Heritage Area - San Rafael Swell National Heritage Area Act - Establishes the San Rafael Swell National Heritage Area in Utah. (Sec. 104) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to recognize a management entity for the Heritage Area to be known as the San Rafael Regional Heritage Council. Specifies eligibility requirements and general authorities of the Council. (Sec. 105) Directs the entity, within three years after enactment of this Act, to prepare (with appropriate public participation) and submit to the Secretary a Heritage Area management plan. Requires such plan to present comprehensive recommendations for the conservation, funding, management, and development of the Heritage Area. Requires the Secretary to approve or disapprove of such plan within 60 days after its receipt. (Sec. 106) Provides for implementation of an approved management plan which preserves the cultural, historical, natural, and recreational resources of the Heritage Area. (Sec. 107) Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical and financial assistance to the entity and, upon the entity's request, to units of government, nonprofit organizations, and other persons, to assist in plan preparation and implementation. Directs the Secretary to inform the public of the location and character of the Heritage Area. (Sec. 108) Outlines duties of other Federal agencies with respect to activities in the Heritage Area and their effect on plan implementation. Provides savings provisions. (Sec. 110) Authorizes appropriations for the Heritage Area. Prohibits Federal assistance provided under this title from exceeding 50 percent of required amounts. Title II: San Rafael Swell National Conservation Area - Subtitle A: Establishment of Conservation Area - Establishes the San Rafael Swell National Conservation Area to preserve and maintain heritage, tourism, recreational, historical, scenic, archaeological, paleontological, biological, cultural, scientific, educational, and economic resources. Withdraws the Federal lands within the Conservation Area from all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, as well as from entry, application, and selection under related laws. Prohibits any commercial sale of trees and forest products located within the Conservation Area. (Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary to prepare and begin implementation of a Conservation Area management plan. Directs the Secretary and the San Rafael Swell National Conservation Area Advisory Council (established under this title) to review such plan at least every ten years and make appropriate revisions. Requires such plan to be a multiple use, sustained yield management plan and to be consistent with the Heritage Area management plan. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) establish a visitors center to interpret the history and geological, ecological, natural, cultural, and other resources of the Conservation Area; and (2) provide for visitor use of the public lands in the Conservation Area. Prohibits the restriction of recognized agricultural practices or other activities on private land adjacent to or within the Conservation Area. (Sec. 204) Authorizes the Secretary to acquire lands and interests therein in order to further the purposes of this title and to utilize land exchanges to resolve land-use conflicts within the Conservation Area. (Sec. 205) Establishes the San Rafael Swell National Conservation Area Advisory Council to advise and assist the Secretary in Conservation Area management. (Sec. 207) States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit the Secretary from installing communications equipment in the Conservation Area for public safety purposes. Subtitle B: Wilderness Areas Within Conservation Area - Designates specified areas within the Conservation Area as wilderness areas and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS). (Sec. 222) Directs the Secretary to manage such areas and to prepare management plans for each area. (Sec. 223) Allows the continuation of current livestock grazing in such areas. Prohibits such grazing from being reduced, increased, or withdrawn, except based solely on scientific analyses of range conditions. (Sec. 224) Declares that certain public lands administered by BLM in Emery and Carbon counties, Utah, have been adequately studied for wilderness designation. Releases from wilderness consideration any such lands not already designated. Subtitle C: Other Special Management Areas - Establishes in the Conservation Area the San Rafael Swell Desert Bighorn Sheep Management area (Bighorn area) to provide for management of such sheep and their habitat, and related activities. Prohibits mechanized travel within the Bighorn area, with exceptions. Provides for Bighorn area management by the Secretary and the Utah Division of Wildlife Resources, including the public viewing of such animals in their natural habitat. Requires a management plan for the Bighorn area. (Sec. 232) Directs the Secretary to designate areas within the Heritage Area as semi-primitive nonmotorized use areas, with specified requirements. Requires a management plan for each area so designated. (Sec. 233) Directs the Secretary to designate areas within the Conservation Area as a scenic visual area of critical environmental concern in order to preserve the scenic value of the Interstate 70 corridor within the Conservation Area. Title III: General Management Provisions - Directs the Secretary to permit domestic livestock grazing in the Conservation Area and in semi-primitive areas outside the Conservation Area where such grazing was established prior to the enactment of this Act. (Sec. 302)Directs the Secretary to: (1) allow for the discovery, protection, and interpretation of cultural or paleontological resources within the Conservation Area or within designated wilderness or semi-primitive areas; and (2) assure nonexclusive access to traditional cultural and religious sites within such Area or areas for Native Americans. (Sec. 303) Authorizes the Governor of Utah to identify, describe, and notify the Secretary of any school and institutional trust lands the value or economic potential of which is diminished by the establishment of the Conservation Area or the designation of a wilderness or semi-primitive area. Provides for a Federal-State exchange of lands in such cases. (Sec. 304) States that nothing in this Act shall constitute an express or implied Federal reservation of water arising from designations made. Authorizes the United States to exercise appropriate water rights under Utah State law. States that this Act shall not affect the: (1) Colorado River or its water works; or (2) jurisdiction or responsibilities of Utah with respect to fish and wildlife management activities.</summary>
</bill>
