<bill session="105" type="h" number="296" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To privatize the Federal Power Marketing Administrations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400368"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1997-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1998-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1997-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="1997-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1997-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-11">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Bur Reclamation.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Investment banking"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Establishment of Corporations and Transfer of Facilities Title II: Privatization of Corporations Title I: Establishment of Corporations and Transfer of Facilities - Establishes the following Government corporations to operate, maintain, and market the electric power transmission and generation facilities transferred to them under this Act: (1) the Southeastern Power Corporation; (2) the Western Area Power Corporation; and (3) the Southwestern Area Power Corporation. Directs the President to appoint, with the advice and consent of the Senate, a Transition Manager for each such Corporation. Prescribes transition guidelines for the transfer of facilities and funds, and the termination of the Federal power marketing administrations. Amends the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act of 1993 to repeal the prohibition against the use of Federal funds for studies relating or leading to the possibility of changing from the currently required "at cost" to a "market rate," or any other noncost-based method for hydroelectric power pricing by the six Federal public power authorities, or other Federal authorities without specific congressional authorization. Title II: Privatization of Corporations - Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to retain the services of investment banking firms to serve jointly as co-lead managers of the public offering for each such Corporation and to establish a syndicate to underwrite the public offering. Prescribes preparation guidelines for such public offering, including the election of a Board of Directors and the private status of the Corporations subsequent to the sale of 60 percent of the Federal interest in each such Corporation.</summary>
</bill>
