<bill session="105" type="h" number="2156" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cultural Education Enhancement Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide financial assistance, directly and through States, to support jointly with government entities, educational institutions, businesses, and nonprofit public and private entities, opportunities for the people of the United States to participate in the arts and the humanities; and to increase understanding and appreciation of the cultural heritage of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400334"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1997-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Art and state"/>
    <term name="Artists"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Contractors"/>
    <term name="Cultural policy"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/1997--Introduced.
Cultural Education Enhancement Act of 1997 - Amends the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965 (NFAHA) to repeal, replace, and rename it the American Heritage Administration Act of 1997. Establishes in the executive branch the American Heritage Administration (AHA). Eliminates the following entities under the current NFAHA: the National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities, the National Endowment for the Arts (NEA), the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH), the National Council on the Arts, the National Council on the Humanities, the National Capital arts and cultural affairs grants programs, and the Federal Council on the Arts and the Humanities. Provides for appointment of an AHA Director by the President, with Senate advice and consent. Requires the AHA Director to establish and implement programs of: (1) direct grants (using recommendations of peer review advisory councils) to nonprofit groups for projects, productions, and workshops in the fields of arts education and humanities education; and (2) grants to eligible applicant States for use on projects and productions approved by State agencies for specified uses relating to the arts, humanities, and cultural heritage. Specifies additional conditions to: (1) financial assistance to support the arts; (2) all financial assistance under this Act; and (3) division and allotment of appropriated funds. Provides for compliance, enforcement, and evaluation activities. Authorizes appropriations. Sets forth conforming amendments to various Federal laws. Transfers all NEA and NEH property to AHA. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to transfer the affairs of NEA and NEH, as well as those of the National Council on the Arts, the National Council on the Humanities, and the Federal Council on the Arts and the Humanities, to AHA.</summary>
</bill>
