<bill session="105" type="h" number="1838" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coast Guard Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1998 and 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal years 1998 and 1999 for the Coast Guard, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1997-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="1997-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1997-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-23">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Prior to Referral (Mar 19, 97).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-08-07">
      <text>See H.R.2204.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2204"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air bases"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Dismissal wage"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Ice breaking operations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Military medals, decorations, etc."/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military posture"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Military vehicles"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in government"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Offshore structures"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution control"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution of the sea"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Warships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Authorizations Title II: Personnel Management Title III: Financial and Property Management Title IV: Reports and Investigations Title V: Marine Safety and Environmental Protection Coast Guard Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1998 and 1999 - Title I: Authorizations - Authorizes appropriations for the Coast Guard for: (1) operation and maintenance; (2) acquisition, construction, rebuilding, and improvement of aids to navigation, shore and offshore facilities, vessels, and aircraft; (3) research, development, testing, and evaluation; (4) retired pay, payments under the Retired Serviceman's Family Protection and Survivor Benefit Plans, and payments for medical care of retired personnel and their dependents; and (5) environmental compliance and restoration at Coast Guard facilities. (Sec. 102) Authorizes Coast Guard end-of-year strength and military training student loads. Title II: Personnel Management - Amends Federal law relating to the Coast Guard to remove the dollar limit on severance pay for regular warrant officers. (Sec. 202) Authorizes the Coast Guard Commandant to: (1) obtain research on personnel resource and training needs; and (2) employ special programs for recruiting minorities, including using grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts. Terminates those authorities on a specified date. Title III: Financial and Property Management - Authorizes the Commandant to rent or lease commercial vehicles to transport the next of kin of eligible retired Coast Guard military personnel to attend funeral services of the service member at a national cemetery. (Sec. 302) Authorizes the use of up to $25,000 to provide economic adjustment assistance for the City of Novato, California, for the cost of revising the Hamilton Reuse Planning Authority's reuse plan as a result of the Coast Guard's request for housing at Hamilton Air Force Base (or to reimburse the Department of Defense for providing that assistance). (Sec. 303) Requires, when the Coast Guard supply fund is reduced to delete items stocked, that the existing capital of the fund be reduced by the value of the materials transferred to other Coast Guard accounts. (Sec. 304) Authorizes honorary recognition of individuals and organizations that significantly contribute to Coast Guard programs, missions, or operations, including State and local governments and commercial and nonprofit organizations. Allows payment for plaques, medals, and similar items. Title IV: Reports and Investigations - Removes provisions requiring that reports be made public. (Sec. 402) Amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to remove a requirement of a biennial report to the Congress. Title V: Marine Safety and Environmental Protection - Amends the Ports and Waterways Safety Act and Federal law relating to vessels and seamen to define "navigable waters of the United States" to include all waters of the U.S. territorial sea as described in a specified Presidential Proclamation. Makes changes relating to U.S. navigable waters in provisions relating to the operation of vessels, uninspected vessel safety equipment, recreational vessels, uninspected commercial fishing industry vessels, and vessel pilots. Amends the Act of June 15, 1917 (relating to foreign relations, neutrality, foreign commerce, espionage, and enforcement of criminal laws) to define "navigable waters of the United States" to include all waters of the U.S. territorial sea as described in a specified Presidential Proclamation. (Sec. 502) Amends Federal law relating to vessels and seamen to revise the bases for suspension or revocation of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner's document.</summary>
</bill>
