<bill session="104" type="h" number="1706" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Quality Assurance in Drug Testing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish Federal standards to ensure quality assurance of drug testing programs for private employers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1996-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-24">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-24">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="153"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and athletes"/>
    <term name="Drugs and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Libel and slander"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/1995--Introduced.
Quality Assurance in Drug Testing Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to add a new title, title XXVII: Quality Assurance in Drug Testing. Prohibits any individual from performing a toxicological analysis unless such analysis is conducted in a laboratory certified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Requires the Secretary to establish a certification program. Requires employers, in order to implement and maintain a drug testing program, to: (1) establish a written anti-drug abuse policy; and (2) establish a drug-free awareness program. Permits an employer to require applicants for employment and employees to submit to and pass a drug test. Provides for employee protections, including limited confidentiality. Permits employers to take actions necessary to ensure a safe, drug-free work environment. Requires employers to provide information to employees concerning the existence and availability of various drug treatment programs. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a program for the certification of laboratories used for toxicological analysis; and (2) issue additional rules and regulations essential to the implementation of this Act. Requires the certification program to be enforced pursuant to procedures contained in provisions of title III of the Act concerning laboratory certification. Sets forth procedures for filing employee complaints. Preempts State and local laws, rules, regulations, orders, or standards. Permits Federal agencies with authority over regulated industries or Government contractors to issue regulations concerning drug and alcohol testing.</summary>
</bill>
