<bill session="105" type="h" number="4664" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Iraq Liberation Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program to support a transition to democracy in Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="h" number="4655"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Arab refugees"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Debt agreements"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indictments"/>
    <term name="Internal migration"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Opposition (Political science)"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crime trials"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/1998--Introduced.
Iraq Liberation Act of 1998 - Declares that it should be the policy of the United States to seek to remove the Saddam Hussein regime from power in Iraq and to replace it with a democratic government. Authorizes the President, after notifying specified congressional committees, to provide to the Iraqi democratic opposition organizations: (1) grant assistance for radio and television broadcasting to Iraq; (2) Department of Defense defense articles and services and military education and training; and (3) humanitarian assistance, with emphasis on addressing the needs of individuals who have fled from areas under the control of the Hussein regime. Prohibits assistance to any group or organization that is engaged in military cooperation with the Hussein regime. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the President to designate one or more Iraqi democratic opposition organizations that meet specified criteria as eligible to receive assistance under this Act. Urges the President to call upon the United Nations to establish an international criminal tribunal for the purpose of indicting, prosecuting, and imprisoning Saddam Hussein and other Iraqi officials who are responsible for crimes against humanity, genocide, and other criminal violations of international law. Expresses the sense of the Congress that once the Saddam Hussein regime is removed from power in Iraq, the United States should support Iraq's transition to democracy by providing humanitarian assistance to the Iraqi people and democracy transition assistance to Iraqi parties and movements with democratic goals, including convening Iraq's foreign creditors to develop a multilateral response to the foreign debt incurred by the Hussein regime.</summary>
</bill>
