<bill session="105" type="h" number="4085" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Significant Regulation Oversight Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require congressional approval of proposed rules designated by the Congress to be significant.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1998-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/1998--Introduced.
Significant Regulation Oversight Act of 1998 - Prohibits a significant rule from taking effect before the enactment of a joint resolution described in section four of this Act comprised solely of the text of the rule. Requires, before a proposed significant rule takes effect as a final rule, the agency proposing the rule to submit to each House of Congress a report containing: (1) a copy of the proposed rule; (2) a concise summary of such rule, its purpose, and anticipated effects; (3) a complete copy of any cost-benefit analysis report that has been prepared by the agency with respect to the rule; (4) an explanation of the specific statutory interpretation under which a rule is proposed; and (5) any other relevant information or requirements under any other Act and any relevant Executive order. Requires each House of the Congress to provide a copy of the report to the Chairman and ranking minority party member of each committee with jurisdiction over the subject matter of the report. States that if the Congress fails to enact a joint resolution as prescribed in this Act approving a proposed significant rule, no court or agency may infer any intent of the Congress from any action or inaction with regard to such rule or any related statute. (Sec. 4) Requires the majority leader of each House of the Congress to introduce (by request) a joint resolution comprised solely of the text of the proposed significant rule within three session days in the Senate or three legislative days in the House of Representatives after the date on which an agency submits the report containing the text of the proposed significant rule. Allows any Member of either House to introduce the resolution if it is not introduced in that House as provided in the preceding sentence. Outlines House and Senate committee and floor procedures for approval of the joint resolution. (Sec. 5) Allows any existing rule to be revised or revoked in accordance with this Act if a petition for review so requests. (Sec. 6) Defines "significant rule" for purposes as any rule proposed by an agency that is specified or described as such in the Act that authorizes the rule. (Sec. 7) States that nothing in this Act applies to any rule concerning monetary policy proposed or implemented by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee.</summary>
</bill>
