<bill session="108" type="h" number="4188" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 1606 of title 10, United States Code, to increase the amount of basic educational assistance for members of the Selected Reserve, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2004-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2004-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400132" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2004-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2004-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2004-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400375" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2004-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2004-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="2004-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2004-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E586"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2004--Introduced.
Revises the rates of basic educational assistance to be paid by the Secretary of the military department concerned to members of the Selected Reserve to make such rate: (1) for a program of education pursued on a full-time basis, specified percentages, increasing for each of FY 2005 through 2009 and beyond, of the monthly rate of veterans' basic educational assistance; (2) for a program pursued on less than a full-time basis, an appropriately reduced rate as determined by the Secretary concerned; and (3) for a program pursued on less than a half-time basis, no such payment if tuition assistance is otherwise available to the person from the military department concerned. Makes members of the Selected Reserve meeting certain other requirements eligible for basic educational assistance if they served a cumulative 24 months of active duty during any five-year period as a member of such Reserve. (Currently, in order to be so eligible, such members must have served two years of continuous active duty.)</summary>
</bill>
