<bill session="106" type="h" number="2033" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Political Candidate Personal Responsibility Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide that the lowest unit rate for campaign advertising shall not be available for communications in which a candidate attacks an opponent of the candidate unless the candidate does so in person.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400419"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1999-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Negative campaigning"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/1999--Introduced.
Political Candidate Personal Responsibility Act of 1999 - Prohibits a candidate for public office from receiving the lowest unit charge for advertising on television or radio (offered 45 days before a primary election and 60 days before a general election) unless the candidate certifies that he or she will not make any direct reference to another candidate for the same office, unless: (1) such reference meets requirements of this Act; and (2) a communication which contains such reference also contains a prominently displayed image (television) or the voice (radio) of the candidate during at least 75 percent of the broadcast time. States that a candidate meets the requirements of this Act if: (1) in the case of a television broadcast, the reference is made by the candidate in a personal appearance on the screen; and (2) in the case of a radio broadcast, the reference is made by the candidate in a personal audio statement during which the candidate and the office are identified.</summary>
</bill>
