<bill session="106" type="h" number="4507" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transit Rail Access Improvement and Needs Act for the 21st Century</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate the Surface Transportation Board as a forum for resolution of disagreements between mass transportation authorities and freight railroads regarding access to freight track and rights-of-way for fixed guideway transportation in consideration for just and reasonable compensation to freight railroads.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400548"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2000-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2000-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2000-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2000-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400334" joined="2000-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2000-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Ground Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW10" subcommittee="Ground Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad equipment"/>
    <term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
    <term name="Railroad maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Speed limits"/>
    <term name="Subways"/>
    <term name="Surface Transportation Board"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2000--Introduced.
Transit Rail Access Improvement and Needs Act for the 21st Century - Amends Federal transportation law to provide that if, after negotiation, a mass transportation authority cannot reach agreement with a rail carrier to use the carrier's trackage, and have related services provided, for fixed guideway transportation purposes, the Surface Transportation Board shall, upon the authority's or the carrier's application, and if necessary or useful: (1) order that the trackage be made available and the related services provided to the authority; and (2) prescribe reasonable terms and compensation, based upon the carrier's incremental cost of providing such trackage and services.Authorizes the mass transportation authority or the rail carrier to apply to the Board for an order establishing reasonable terms for the operation of additional trains by or for the authority over a rail line of the carrier, when the carrier and the authority cannot agree to terms.Authorizes a mass transportation authority, after notice to the rail carrier and a sufficient period for maintenance improvements, to apply to the Board for an order requiring the carrier to provide increased or improved maintenance on the trackage if the authority believes that maintenance on trackage operated by or for the authority has fallen below a safe or necessary level.Authorizes a mass transportation authority to apply to the Board for an order requiring the rail carrier to allow accelerated speeds and related improvements if the rail carrier refuses to allow them.Declares that, except in an emergency, fixed guideway transportation provided by or for a mass transportation authority pursuant to an order issued under this Act has preference over freight transportation in using a rail line, junction, or crossing, unless the Board orders otherwise.Declares that if, after negotiation, a mass transportation authority cannot reach agreement with a rail carrier to acquire an interest in a railroad right-of-way for the construction and operation of a segregated fixed guideway facility, the authority may apply to the Board for an order requiring the carrier to convey an interest to the authority.</summary>
</bill>
