<bill session="107" type="h" number="3994" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-21T18:23:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-05-21T18:23:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Afghanistan Freedom Support Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Afghanistan Freedom Support Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize economic and democratic development assistance for Afghanistan and to authorize military assistance for Afghanistan and certain other foreign countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2002-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="2002-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400181" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2002-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2002-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-03-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-04-25T12:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on International Relations. H. Rept. 107-420.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-04-25T12:17:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="250">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 250.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-05-15T08:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 419 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3994 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on International Relations now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-15T18:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 419 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 419.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2748-2778" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2758-2760" label="text of title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2760-2761" label="text of title II as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3994 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on International Relations now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 419 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Judy Biggert to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3994.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hyde amendment under the five minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Lantos amendment under the five minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T16:38:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Lantos amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lantos demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 419, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hoeffel amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T16:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson-Lee amendments en bloc under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson-Lee amendments en bloc under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson-Lee demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 419, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of the adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Waters amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Waters amendment, as modified, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Waters demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 419, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T17:22:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T18:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3994.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T18:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-05-21T18:23:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="182" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 390 - 22 (Roll no. 182).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-21T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 3394.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="107" type="hr" number="419"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="2712"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="2712"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Asian American ethnic groups"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Central banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Handicraft"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Heroin"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land mines"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Machinery in industry"/>
    <term name="Malaria"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Minesweeping"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Opium"/>
    <term name="Orphans"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Public works"/>
    <term name="Refugee policy"/>
    <term name="Refugee resettlement"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in government"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h484"/>
    <amendment number="h485"/>
    <amendment number="h486"/>
    <amendment number="h487"/>
    <amendment number="h488"/>
    <amendment number="h489"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/25/2002--Reported to House amended.
Afghanistan Freedom Support Act of 2002 - Title I: Economic and Democratic Development Assistance for Afghanistan - Sets forth principles governing the provision of assistance for Afghanistan, including reducing terrorism and narcotics control, the participation of women, Afghan self-reliance, stability, and coordination of international donors.(Sec. 104) Authorizes the President to provide assistance for Afghanistan for the following activities: (1) urgent humanitarian needs; (2) repatriation and resettlement of refugees and internally displaced persons; (3) counternarcotics efforts; (4) reestablishment of food security, rehabilitation of the agriculture sector, improvement in health conditions, and the reconstruction of basic infrastructure; (5) reestablishment of Afghanistan as a viable nation-state through support for the development and expansion of democratic and market-based institutions; and (6) support for the establishment of a market economy, private financial institutions, the development of a telecommunications infrastructure, and trade and commercial links. Conditions certain assistance, initially, on the convention of a Loya Jirga (traditional Afghan assembly), and later, on substantial progress toward a constitution and democratically elected government, unless the President certifies to Congress that the vital national interests of the United States require otherwise.(Sec. 105) Earmarks funds for assistance in the major opium producing regions, including areas within the Badakshan, Helmand, and Qandahar provinces, with the goal of eliminating poppy cultivation. Denies such assistance to regions where the Afghan Government does not actively, effectively, and vigorously participate in illicit narcotics suppression activities or where production is more than de minimis, unless the President certifies to Congress that the vital national interests of the United States require otherwise.(Sec. 106) Urges the President to: (1) designate within the Department of State a coordinator (with the advice and consent of the Senate) to design an overall strategy for coordinating such assistance and advancing U.S. interests in Afghanistan; and (2) utilize the expertise of Afghan-Americans. Declares that the administrative provisions of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 shall apply to the same extent as they apply to certain other economic assistance. Requires the Comptroller General and the Inspector General of the United States Agency for International Development to monitor and audit expenditures. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2002 through FY 2005.Title II: Military Assistance for Afghanistan and Certain Other Foreign Countries and International Organizations - Expresses the sense of Congress that, during the transition to broad-based, multi-ethnic, gender-sensitive fully representative government, the U.S. should support: (1) the development of a civilian-controlled and centrally-governed standing Afghanistan army that respects human rights; (2) the creation and training of a professional civilian police force that respects human rights; and (3) a multinational security force in Afghanistan.(Sec. 202) Authorizes the President to provide and direct the drawdown of defense articles and services and military education to the Government of Afghanistan. Permits the provision of counter-narcotics, crime control, police training services, and other specified support.(Sec. 203) Makes other foreign countries or international organizations eligible for such assistance if they are participating in certain military, peacekeeping, or policing operations in Afghanistan.(Sec. 204) Declares that such articles, services, and military education and training shall be made available to the Department of Defense without reimbursement except to the extent that funds are appropriated to the President for such purpose. Authorizes appropriations to the President of sums necessary to reimburse the applicable appropriation, fund, or account for such assistance.(Sec. 205) Authorizes the President to provide assistance under this title to an eligible foreign country or international organization notwithstanding any other provision of law upon notifying the appropriate congressional committees that to do so is important to the national security interest of the United States.(Sec. 206) Terminates authority under this title on December 31, 2004.</summary>
</bill>
