<bill session="105" type="h" number="179" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:27-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Sweep Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to reform the financing of campaigns for election to Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1997-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSIF" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" name="House Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Politicians' families"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>01/07/1997--Introduced.
Clean Sweep Act of 1997 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to require that the majority of a House of Representatives candidate's contributors (with respect to an election cycle) reside in the congressional district involved. Excepts contributions from a national, State, district, or local political party committee (including any subordinate committee thereof). (Sec. 3) Bans Federal election activities by political action committees. (Sec. 4) Limits contributions or loans of the personal funds of a House candidate (including funds of members of the candidate's immediate family) during a calendar year which in the aggregate exceed $50,000. (Sec. 5) Requires that amounts paid by the national, State, or local political party committee (including a subordinate committee thereof) for mixed political activities: (1) shall be subject to limitation and reporting requirements as if such payment were an expenditure; and (2) may be paid only from an account that is subject to the requirements of FECA. (Sec. 6) Sets forth provisions concerning eligibility and certification for reduced broadcast rates for House candidates who limit the total amount of expenditures made during an election cycle. Imposes a penalty upon a candidate who makes expenditures in excess of the limit. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to entitle certified candidates to receive free broadcast time from broadcasting stations within the candidate's State or an adjacent State, except where only one candidate qualifies to be on the ballot. Exempts certain licensees. (Sec. 7) Amends FECA to prohibit contributions by an individual who is not a citizen of the United States. (Sec. 8) Bans any contribution of U.S. or foreign currency to any candidate or political committee with respect to any Federal election campaign. (Sec. 9) Revises Federal law relating to mass mailings sent by House members. (Sec. 10) Directs the Committee on House Oversight to submit a report to the President and the Congress analyzing the effects of changes made by this Act on the first general elections for the House which are held after December 31, 1998.</summary>
</bill>
