<bill session="104" type="hr" number="299" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-22T12:50:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-12-22T12:50:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Rules of the House of Representatives regarding outside earned income.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1995-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1995-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1995-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1995-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1995-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1995-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1995-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="409633" joined="1995-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-21T20:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 322 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 299 with 30 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Providing for the consideration of H. Res. 299 in the House and waiving all points of order against a motion to amend the resolution printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T11:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 322 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T11:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 322.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15594-15599" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T11:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 299 with 30 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Providing for the consideration of H. Res. 299 in the House and waiving all points of order against a motion to amend the resolution printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T11:32:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 322, the House proceed with 30 minutes of debate on the Solomon amendment and the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T12:12:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment and the resolution pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-12-22T12:50:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="883" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 259 - 128, 2 Present (Roll no. 883).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-22T12:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="322"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Copyright royalties"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Publishers and publishing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h925"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/22/1995--Passed House amended.
Amends rule XLVII (regarding limitations on outside employment and earned income) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit a Member, officer, or employee of the House from receiving: (1) advance payments on copyright royalties; or (2) copyright royalties pursuant to a contract entered into on or after January 1, 1996, unless the contract is first approved by the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct and such royalties are received from an established publisher pursuant to usual and customary contractual terms. Allows any literary agent, researcher, or other individual (other than a House employee or a relative of a Member, officer, or employee) working on behalf of a Member, officer, or employee with respect to a publication to receive an advance payment of a copyright royalty directly from a publisher and solely for the benefit of that literary agent, researcher, or other individual.</summary>
</bill>
