<bill session="105" type="h" number="2296" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To withhold foreign assistance to Caribbean Basin Initiative countries that support membership for the Government of Cuba into the Caribbean Community (CARICOM) or the Central American Common Market (CACM), and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1997-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1997-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="1997-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1997-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1997-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Central America"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/1997--Introduced.
Directs the President to withhold foreign assistance funds (other than humanitarian assistance) to any Caribbean Basin Initiative (CBI) country that uses its voice or vote in the Caribbean Community (CARICOM) or the Central American Common Market (CACM) to support provisional or permanent membership for Cuba in CARICOM or CACM. Directs the President to deny temporary or permanent tariff treatment of products of a CBI country that is equivalent to treatment provided to products of a North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) country if such CBI country: (1) uses its voice or vote to support provisional or permanent membership for Cuba in CARICOM or CACM; or (2) enters into negotiations for a free trade area agreement with Cuba.</summary>
</bill>
