<bill session="107" type="hr" number="372" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-03-20T15:16:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-03-20T15:16:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the concurrent resolution (H. Con. Res. 353) establishing the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2003 and setting forth appropriate budgetary levels for each of fiscal years 2004 through 2007.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T00:46:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 107-380, by Mr. Goss.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T00:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides three hours of general debate, with two hours confined to the congressional budget equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Budget, and one hour on the subject of economic goals and policies equally divided and controlled by Representative Saxton of New Jersey and Representative Stark of California or their designees. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the concurrent resolution. rule provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the report of the Committee on Rules (H. Rept. 107-380) shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole. The rule permits the chairman of the Budget Committee to offer amendments in the House to achieve mathematical consistency. Provides that the concurrent resolution shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question of its adoption.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-03-20T00:46:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="133">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 133.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T12:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1020-1036" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T13:16:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 372.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T14:56:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 221 - 206 (Roll no. 75).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T14:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Slaughter moved to reconsider the vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T14:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Goss moved to table the motion to reconsider the vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T15:06:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to table the motion to reconsider the vote. Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 206 (Roll no. 76).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2002-03-20T15:16:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="77" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 206 (Roll no. 77).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1020" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T15:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Dreier moved to reconsider the vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T15:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Goss moved to table the motion to reconsider the vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T15:19:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to table the motion to reconsider the vote Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 213 - 206 (Roll no. 78).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-20T15:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider the vote tabled.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="107" type="hc" number="353"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2002--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule (closed) for the consideration of H. Con. Res. 353 (congressional budget).</summary>
</bill>
