<bill session="106" type="h" number="908" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Aviation Consumer Right To Know Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve consumers' access to airline industry information, to promote competition in the aviation industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2000-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2000-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2000-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2000-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1999-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2000-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2000-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1999-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airline rates"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Insect control"/>
    <term name="Travel agents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/1999--Introduced.
Aviation Consumer Right To Know Act of 1999 - Amends Federal aviation law to prohibit any air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent from selling air transportation in the United States for a flight that bears a designator code of another air carrier unless the air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent informs the person purchasing the air transportation that the carrier providing such transportation will be a carrier other than the carrier whose designator code is used to identify the flight and informs the person of the corporate name of the other carrier. Requires an air carrier, upon the request of any person (including a governmental entity), to disclose the number or percentage of seats that the carrier intends to make available on a specific date for use by a person redeeming an award under a frequent flyer program. Requires the air carrier to also: (1) provide the person full access to all fares for air transportation provided by it, regardless of the technology the person uses to access the fares; and (2) permit the person to purchase air transportation at any published fare. Prohibits an air carrier from: (1) prohibiting a person (including governmental entity) that purchases air transportation from only using a portion of the air transportation purchased (including using the air transportation purchased only for one-way travel instead of round-trip travel); and (2) assessing an additional fee or charge to the person, or any ticket agent that sold the air transportation to such person. Requires any announcement by an air carrier of a delay or cancellation of a flight, a diversion of a flight to an airport other than the airport at which the flight is scheduled to land, or a delay in deplaning at an airport to include an explanation of the reason for such delay, cancellation, or diversion and, in the case of a delay, the expected length of the delay. Prohibits an air carrier from providing false or misleading explanations. Prohibits an air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent from selling air transportation in the United States for a flight on which an insecticide is planned to be used in the aircraft while passengers are on board the aircraft unless such air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent first informs the person purchasing the air transportation of its use, including the name of the insecticide.</summary>
</bill>
