<bill session="106" type="hc" number="181" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress with respect to war crimes against United States military personnel and their families, and in particular to the war crimes committed in El Salvador against United States Army pilots David H. Pickett and Earnest Dawson, Jr.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400549"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="2000-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Amnesties"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army personnel"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="El Salvador"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military helicopters"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/1999--Introduced.
Expresses: (1) sincere appreciation for the military service of Lieutenant Colonel David H. Pickett, Private First Class Earnest Dawson, Jr., and Chief Warrant Officer Daniel Scott; and (2) deepest sympathy to the families of David H. Pickett and Earnest Dawson, Jr., for their tragic and wrongful deaths; (3) profound regret that the available remedies have failed to bring Ferman Hernandez and Serveriano Fuentes, the men responsible for executing Pickett and Dawson, to justice.Declares that: (1) the United States should improve the legal protections for its military personnel who serve in foreign lands and their families; and (2) the Government of El Salvador should amend its Constitution to permit the extradition of Hernandez and Fuentes to the United States for trial.Urges the President to: (1) continue efforts to obtain the extradition of Hernandez and Fuentes; (2) initiate changes to the Geneva Convention and other international agreements that would prevent amnesty from being used to deny redress for grave breaches of the Geneva Convention; (3) initiate other changes to the Geneva Convention and other relevant international agreements to ensure and improve the legal protections for U.S. military personnel serving in foreign lands and their families; (4) examine all status-of-forces agreements and similar agreements and obtain revisions to ensure that the legal protections for U.S. military personnel will not suffer another failure; (5) encourage other countries to enact laws substantially similar to the War Crimes Act of 1996; and (6) report to the Congress at least annually regarding the actions taken and the progress made.</summary>
</bill>
