<bill session="106" type="h" number="331" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to provide for public funding for House of Representatives elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign debates"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voter turnout"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/1999--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to add a new title V (Public Funding for House of Representatives Elections) outlining the following: (1) qualifications for public financing; (2) limitations on contributions to qualifying House candidates prohibiting such a candidate from accepting contributions other than contributions from individuals that total not more than $100 per individual per election cycle, with an 80 percent in-State contribution requirement; (3) rules restricting public funding to specified purposes, such as buying broadcast time; (4) limitations on the maximum amount of public funding, which is set at $750,000 for qualifying House candidates; (5) various specified requirements pertaining to television debates and radio and television advertising; (6) reporting requirements for political committees and authorization for the filing of certain State reports in lieu of any required FECA report; (7) provisions regarding soft money of persons other than political parties; and (8) rules for contributions through intermediaries and conduits. Prohibits a national committee of a political party, including the national congressional campaign committees of a political party, and any officers or agents of such party committees from soliciting or receiving any contributions, donations, or transfers of funds, or spending any funds, not subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of this Act. Imposes similar restrictions generally with regard to any amount expended or disbursed by a State, district, or local committee of a political party for any activity which might affect the outcome of a Federal election. Provides that: (1) no national, State, district, or local committee of a political party shall solicit any funds for or make any donations to any organization that is exempt from Federal income taxation; and (2) no candidate for Federal office, individual holding Federal office, or any agent of such candidate or officeholder, may solicit or receive any funds in connection with any Federal election unless such funds are subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
