<bill session="104" type="h" number="2046" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Aquaculture Employment Investment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to authorize grants to coastal States for development of State coastal zone management program changes to support adoption of procedures and policies to evaluate and facilitate siting of certain aquaculture facilities in the coastal zone, and to establish in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration a marine aquaculture development program to be known as the Nantucket Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="1995-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1449-1450"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Mariculture"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/1995--Introduced.
Aquaculture Employment Investment Act - Amends the Coastal Zone Management Act to add the adoption of procedures and policies relating to the siting of coastal zone aquaculture facilities to the list of coastal zone enhancement objectives. Establishes in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration a marine aquaculture development program, to be known as the Nantucket Program, to expand coastal economic opportunities through job training, technical assistance, and employment in marine aquaculture, transplant, and relay operations. Mandates grants to coastal communities to develop marine aquaculture training and support activities. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
