<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="799" updated="2013-07-17T08:17:19-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2401" sequence="10"/>
  <status datetime="2011-09-23T12:34:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400431"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-09-23"/>
  <description>Amendment provides that the Cross State Air Pollution Rule has no legal force or effect, and directs EPA to continue to apply the Clean Air Interstate Rule (CAIR) for at least 3 years until after the study in the underlying bill is complete. Amendment also requires that the proposed Utility Maximum Achievable Control Technology (MACT) rule has no legal force and effect and that any subsequent Utility MACT rule be issued no sooner than 1 year after the study in the underlying bill is complete. If reissuing the rule, EPA is required to ensure that MACT standards are achievable in practice and that the compliance period is at least 5 years.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 10 printed in House Report 112-213 to provide that the Cross State Air Pollution Rule has no legal force or effect, and directs EPA to continue to apply the Clean Air Interstate Rule (CAIR) for at least 3 years until after the study in the underlying bill is complete. The amendment also requires that the proposed Utility Maximum Achievable Control Technology (MACT) rule has no legal force and effect and that any subsequent Utility MACT rule be issued no sooner than 1 year after the study in the underlying bill is complete. If reissuing the rule, EPA is required to ensure that MACT standards are achievable in practice and that the compliance period is at least 5 years.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-23T10:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A010) offered by Mr. Whitfield.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6431-6434, H6442-6443" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6431-6433" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2011-09-23T12:34:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="737">
      <text>On agreeing to the Whitfield amendment (A010) Agreed to by recorded vote: 234 - 188 (Roll no. 737).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
