<bill session="107" type="h" number="5557" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-11-14">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Armed Forces Tax Fairness Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Armed Forces Tax Fairness Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Armed Forces Tax Fairness Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a special rule for members of the uniformed services and Foreign Service in determining the exclusion of gain from the sale of a principal residence and to restore the tax exempt status of death gratuity payments to members of the uniformed services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T21:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Weller moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T21:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7164-7167" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T21:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5557.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T22:11:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed until Oct. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-09T10:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7308-7309" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-10-09T11:01:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="451" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 412 - 0 (Roll no. 451).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/7/2002 H7164-7165" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-09T11:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-14">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11159-11160" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2002-11-14" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-11-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="5063"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military base conversion"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Service academies"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax rebates"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4961"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/14/2002--Passed Senate amended.
Armed Forces Tax Fairness Act of 2002 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Internal Revenue Code (the Code) to suspend, for members of the uniformed services or of the Foreign Service serving on "qualified official extended duty" (any extended duty while serving at a duty station which is at least 150 miles from the principal residence or while residing under Government orders in Government quarters), the five-year period utilized in determining exclusion of gain from the sale of such residence. Limits the extension of such period to not more than five years.(Sec. 3) Restores in full the tax-exempt status of death gratuity payments to members of the armed services.(Sec. 4) Excludes from gross income any fringe benefit qualifying as a "qualified military base realignment and closure fringe."(Sec. 5) Expands the applicability of rules concerning time for the performance of certain acts under the Code (filing, payment, and etc.) which may be postponed because of service in a combat zone to include service away from a service member's permanent duty station while participating in an operation designated by the Secretary of Defense as a contingency operation.(Sec. 6) Permits ancestors and lineal descendants of past or present members of the armed forces to be taken into account in determining whether a veterans' organization is exempt from tax.(Sec. 7) Includes dependent care assistance within the definition of a qualified military benefit which shall be excluded from gross income, thus excluding such assistance from gross income for uniformed service members and former members.(Sec. 8) Exempts distributions from an education individual retirement account from the ten percent additional tax for non-educational use: (1) if made for an account holder at the United States Military Academy, the United States Naval Academy, the United States Air Force Academy, the United States Coast Guard Academy, or the United States Merchant Marine Academy; and (2) to the extent that the distribution does not exceed the costs of advanced education.(Sec. 9) Suspends the tax-exempt status of a designated terrorist organization (as defined by this Act). Denies: (1) deductions for contributions made to such an organization; and (2) administrative or judicial challenge to such suspension or denial. Provides for refund or credit in a case of erroneous designation.(Sec. 10) Provides a business or trade deduction of up to $1,500 for itemizers and non-itemizers for unreimbursed overnight travel, meals, and lodging expenses of National Guard and Reserve members who must travel more than 100 miles from home and stay overnight as part of their official duties.(Sec. 11) Directs the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to establish user fees for ruling letters, opinion letters, determination letters, and similar requests. Exempts certain pension plan requests. Sets forth average fee determination provisions.(Sec. 12) Authorizes the IRS to enter into partial payment installment agreements with taxpayers.Requires review of such agreements at least every two years.</summary>
</bill>
