<bill session="105" type="h" number="3518" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Power Marketing Administration Reform Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a transition to market-based rates for power sold by the Federal Power Marketing Administrations and the Tennessee Valley Authority, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1998-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1998-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, DOE.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="2499"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Environmental degradation"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Power marketing administrations"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley Authority"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley development"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/1998--Introduced.
Power Marketing Administration Reform Act of 1998 - Requires the Secretary of Energy to develop and implement procedures to ensure that the Federal Power Marketing Administrations (FPMAs) utilize the same accounting principles and requirements as the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) applies to the electric operations of public utilities. (Sec. 4) Requires each FPMA and the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) to submit periodically for FERC review rates for the sale or disposition of Federal energy that will ensure recovery of all their costs in generating and marketing such energy. Prescribes rate mechanism and pricing guidelines. Establishes a fund within the Department of the Interior to: (1) mitigate damage to environmental resources attributable to power generation and sales facilities; and (2) restore the health of such resources, including fish and wildlife. Mandates project-specific mitigation plans for each power generation project. Establishes a fund within the Department of Energy for renewable resources. Prescribes expenditure guidelines. Mandates that public bodies and cooperatives be given a preference for future power allocations or reallocations of Federal power through a right of first refusal at market prices. Instructs the Secretary of Energy to require each FPMA to: (1) assign personnel and incur expenses solely for authorized power marketing, reclamation, and flood control activities, and not for diversification into ancillary activities; and (2) make annual public disclosures of its activities, including the full costs of power projects and marketing. Precludes an FPMA from entering into or renewing any power marketing contract for a term exceeding five years. (Sec. 5) Requires provision of FPMA transmission services on an open access basis, and at FERC-approved rates in the same manner as provided by any public utility under FERC jurisdiction. (Sec. 6) Grants FERC rate-making approval authority until a full transition is made to market-based rates, for: (1) rate schedules recommended by the Secretary of Energy; and (2) rate schedules for FPMA power sales. (Sec. 7) Amends: (1) the Department of Energy Organization Act to reflect the changes made by this Act; and (2) specified Federal law to repeal the prohibition against the use of appropriated funds for purposes relating to the possibility of changing from an "at cost" to a "market rate" or any other noncost-based method for pricing Federal hydroelectric power.</summary>
</bill>
