<bill session="104" type="h" number="3623" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Federal Communications Commission to revise its television duopoly rules to require public comment on certain local marketing agreements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400129"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-06-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1066"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television industry"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/1996--Introduced.
Requires the Federal Communications Commission to revise its television contour overlap (duopoly) rule to: (1) treat as an attributable interest any agreement to broker more than 15 percent of the broadcast time per week of a television station to any party (including all parties under common control) who owns, operates, or controls an overlapping television station; (2) require any such agreement to be a signed written instrument that is maintained in the public file of the stations that are parties to it and that is available for public inspection; and (3) permit, after notice and public comment, waivers of such rule for such agreements if the Commission determines that it is consistent with the public interest, convenience, and necessity. Requires two television stations to be treated as overlapping stations if the Grade B contours of such stations signal overlap.</summary>
</bill>
