<bill session="106" type="h" number="2761" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to enable each public secondary school to hire a director of school safety, discipline, and student assistance to develop or improve a safety plan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3998"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="High school students"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="School administrators"/>
    <term name="School discipline"/>
    <term name="School planning"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="School violence"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1999--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make competitive grants to State educational agencies (SEAs), and to specially designated local educational agencies (LEAs), to enable each public secondary school to employ a director to develop or improve a school safety plan.Sets forth application requirements for: (1) SEAs, for grants; (2) LEAs other than specially designated ones, for subgrants; and (3) specially designated LEAs in States which do not apply for such grants, for direct grants.Requires funds provided under this Act to be used only to hire an individual or entity as a director to develop or improve a public secondary school safety plan and implement security measures approved in the school safety plan.Requires such a director to have the authority to: (1) discipline, in accordance with the school safety plan, any student whose actions or words threaten the safety of any student, teacher, employee, or administrator of the school; and (2) refer any student to the appropriate law enforcement authority, family and children services, or any other agency or organization the director considers appropriate to meet school safety plan requirements.Amends the General Education Provisions Act to include, among those to whom certain educational records may be released without the written consent of students' parents, directors of school safety, discipline, and assistance in their developing and implementing school safety plans.</summary>
</bill>
