<bill session="105" type="h" number="3242" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">IMF Full Cooperation and Accountability for Taxpayers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ban the provision of Federal funds to the International Monetary Fund unless a joint resolution is enacted that approves a certification by the Attorney General and the Secretary of State that all countries eligible to receive IMF funds are cooperating fully with the congressional and Justice Department investigations into the financing of the 1996 presidential election campaign and have disclosed the identity of all commercial entities in the country that would benefit from the provision of the funds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400385"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1998-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1998-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1998-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1998-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1998-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1998-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/1998--Introduced.
IMF Full Cooperation and Accountability for Taxpayers Act - Prohibits any U.S. officer, employee, or agent from providing, directly or indirectly, Federal funds to, or for the benefit of, the International Monetary Fund (IMF) unless the Attorney General and the Secretary of State certify to the Congress, and by joint resolution the Congress has approved such certification, that each country eligible to receive IMF funds: (1) is cooperating fully with the congressional or Justice Department investigation into the financing of the 1996 presidential election campaign; and (2) has disclosed to the Attorney General the identity of any commercial entity within such country that would benefit from the provision of such funds. Requires a report to the Congress 30 days before such certification of all information to be contained in it of which the Attorney General and the Secretary are then aware.</summary>
</bill>
