<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="881" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2262" sequence="6"/>
  <status datetime="2007-11-01T13:52:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <offered datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to establish the Mineral Commodity Information Administration into a role in the Department of Interior. This administration would have the Minerals Information Team (MIT) to collect, analyze, and disseminate information on the domestic and international supply of, and demand for, minerals and mineral materials critical to the U.S economy and national security. The amendment would remove the MIT from under the U.S. Geological Survey and establish it as a stand-alone agency within the Department of the Interior and would increase MIT's staff in order to perform the new and expanded functions authorized in the amendment.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 7 printed in House Report 110-416 to establish the Mineral Commodity Information Administration into a role in the Department of Interior. This administration would have the Minerals Information Team (MIT) to collect, analyze, and disseminate information on the domestic and international supply of, and demand for, minerals and mineral materials critical to the U.S economy and national security. The amendment would remove the MIT from under the U.S. Geological Survey and establish it as a stand-alone agency within the Department of the Interior and would increase MIT's staff in order to perform the new and expanded functions authorized in the amendment.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-01T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Pearce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12425-12428" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H12425-12427" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2007-11-01T13:52:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="fail">
      <text>On agreeing to the Pearce amendment (A006) Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
