<bill session="104" type="h" number="122" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regulatory Sunset Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Regulatory Sunset Commission to review regulations of executive agencies, and to provide for the automatic termination of regulations that are not authorized by the Commission to continue in effect.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402454"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401587" joined="1995-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1995-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1995-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404503" joined="1995-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1995-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1995-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="410887" joined="1995-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E50"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO01" subcommittee="National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Regulatory reform"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Sunset Reviews Title II: Agency Role in Sunset Reviews Regulatory Sunset Act of 1995 - Title I: Sunset Reviews - Establishes the Regulatory Sunset Commission to review regulations of executive agencies and determine in accordance with specified criteria whether they should be terminated, authorized to continue in effect, or modified. Provides for limited judicial review of Commission determinations. Title II: Agency Role in Sunset Reviews - Requires the head of each agency to: (1) conduct thorough and systematic reviews of all agency regulations based on such criteria; (2) prepare and transmit to the Commission a report on agency regulations which includes recommendations of the actions to take; and (3) publish in the Federal Register the agency responses to Commission determinations. Establishes a Regulatory Review Officer within each executive agency (designated by the agency head) to: (1) further agency compliance with this Act; and (2) report directly to the agency head with respect to such function.</summary>
</bill>
