<bill session="105" type="h" number="362" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Fraud and Abuse Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve Federal enforcement against health care fraud and abuse.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO04" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care fraud"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medicaid fraud"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Health Fraud and Abuse Act of 1997 - Directs the Inspector General (IG) of each of the Departments of Health and Human Services, Defense, Labor, and Veterans Affairs and the Office of Personnel Management to conduct audits, civil and criminal investigations, inspections, and evaluations relating to the prevention, detection, and control of health care fraud and abuse in violation of any Federal law, with exceptions. Provides for the powers of IGs. Directs the IGs to: (1) jointly establish a program to prevent, detect, and control health care fraud and abuse that considers the activities of Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies, Federal and State agencies responsible for the licensing and certification of health care providers, and State agencies designated under this Act; and (2) develop an annual investigative plan. Requires the Governor of each State to designate State agencies that conduct, supervise, and coordinate audits, civil and criminal investigations, inspections, and evaluations. Authorizes each Governor to establish and maintain a State agency to act as a Health Care Fraud and Abuse Control Unit. Establishes: (1) the Health Care Fraud and Abuse Control Account in the Treasury; and (2) the Account Payments Advisory Board to make recommendations to the IGs regarding the equitable allocation of payments from the Account.</summary>
</bill>
