<bill session="108" type="h" number="912" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-03T14:13:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-03-03T14:13:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Charles "Pete" Conrad Astronomy Awards Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Charles "Pete" Conrad Astronomy Awards Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Charles "Pete" Conrad Astronomy Awards Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to establish an awards program in honor of Charles "Pete" Conrad, astronaut and space scientist, for recognizing the discoveries made by amateur astronomers of asteroids with near-Earth orbit trajectories.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-02-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11T15:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 108-418.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-02-11T15:18:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="240">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 240.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-03-03T10:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Rohrabacher moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-03T10:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H757-759" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-03T10:20:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 912.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-03T10:30:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-03T14:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H787-788" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-03-03T14:13:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="35" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 404 - 1 (Roll no. 35).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H758" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-03T14:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1855"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Asteroids"/>
    <term name="Astronauts"/>
    <term name="Astronomy"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2004--Passed House amended.
Charles "Pete" Conrad Astronomy Awards Act - Directs the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to establish the Charles "Pete" Conrad Astronomy Awards Program. Requires the Administrator to make awards based on the recommendations of the Minor Planet Center of the Smithsonian Astrophysical Observatory (Minor Planet Center). Directs the Administrator to make one annual award, unless there are no eligible discoveries or contributions, for each of the following categories: (1) the amateur astronomer or group of amateur astronomers who discovered the intrinsically brightest near-Earth asteroid among the near-Earth asteroids that were discovered by such astronomers or groups; and (2) the amateur astronomer or group of amateur astronomers who made the greatest contribution to the mission of the Minor Planet Center to catalogue near-Earth asteroids. Limits the amount of an award under such Program to $3,000. Bars any individual who is not a citizen or permanent resident of the United States at the time of such individual's discovery or contribution from receiving an award. Makes the Administrator's awards decisions under this Act final. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
