<bill session="107" type="h" number="2589" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-09-24T18:04:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-09-24T18:04:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Office of Multifamily Housing Assistance Restructuring Extension Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Office of Multifamily Housing Assistance Restructuring Extension Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Mark-to-Market Extension Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997 to reauthorize the Office of Multifamily Housing Assistance Restructuring, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400533"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2001-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-07-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-09-05T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 107-196.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-09-05T15:11:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="115">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 115.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Green (WI) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5949-5955" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2589.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T15:51:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T18:03:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Hefley asked unanimous consent that the proceedings in which the Yeas and Nays were ordered on the motion to suspend the rules and pass H.R. 2589 be vacated and that the Chair put the question on the motion de novo. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T18:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5989" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-09-24T18:04:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5949-5952" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-09-24T18:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-09-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="168">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 168.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="1254"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2001--Passed House amended.
Mark-to-Market Extension Act of 2001 - Title I: Multifamily Housing Mortgage and Assistance Restructuring and Section 8 Contract Renewal - Amends the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997 (Act) to: (1) require (currently, authorizes) the Secretary of Housing and Human Services to make annual funding for tenant and nonprofit participation available for the multifamily mortgage mark-to-market section 8 restructuring program; and (2) permit carryover of unused funds.Provides for: (1) consistency of rent levels under enhanced voucher assistance and rent restructurings; (2) eligible inclusions for renewal rents of partially assisted buildings; (3) eligibility of restructuring projects for miscellaneous housing insurance; (4) Office of Multifamily Housing Assistance Restructuring (Office) notice to displaced tenants; (5) restructuring exemption for certain older properties under the American Homeownership and Economic Opportunity Act of 2000; and (6) "look-back" project eligibility.Title II: Office of Multifamily Housing Assistance Restructuring - Amends the Act to extend: (1) the Office through October 1, 2004; and (2) the mark-to-market program through October 1, 2006 (with no termination date for section 8 contract renewals). Sets forth provisions relating to the Office, including its Director and oversight by the Federal Housing Commissioner. Reduces the limitation on subsequent employment from two years to one year.Title III: Miscellaneous Housing Program Amendments - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to extend the community development block grant public services cap exception through FY 2003.(Sec. 302) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to permit the use of section 8 enhanced vouchers for prepayments made in 1996 or thereafter.(Sec. 303) Amends the American Homeownership and Economic Opportunity Act of 2000 to permit prepayment and refinancing of loans for section 202 supportive housing.</summary>
</bill>
