<bill session="107" type="h" number="3005" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-12-06T16:36:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-12-06T16:36:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Fast Track Trade Authority bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bipartisan Trade Promotion Authority Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Bipartisan Trade Promotion Authority Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Bipartisan Trade Promotion Authority Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Bipartisan Trade Promotion Authority Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend trade authorities procedures with respect to reciprocal trade agreements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="2001-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="2001-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="2001-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2001-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2001-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-03">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-10-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 26 - 13.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-10-16T22:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 107-249, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-16T22:25:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Rules Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 17, 2001.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-17T13:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Rules discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-10-17T13:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="152">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 152.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-12-05T23:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 306 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3005 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Provides that the amendment recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in the House Report 107-323 shall be considered as adopted. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T13:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 306 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T13:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 306.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8981-9044" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T13:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3005 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Provides that the amendment recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in the House Report 107-323 shall be considered as adopted. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T13:43:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3005.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T15:23:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T15:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Rangel moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T15:24:00-05:00">
      <text>The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T15:36:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T15:58:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 162 - 267 (Roll no. 480).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9029-9044" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9029-9042" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-12-06T16:36:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="481" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 215 - 214 (Roll no. 481).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8981-8993" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T16:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-12">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Finance"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-12-18">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Finance"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-02-28">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Reported by Senator Baucus with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 107-139. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-02-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="319">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 319.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="107" type="hr" number="306"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="3009"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="3009"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Children's rights"/>
    <term name="Chile"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Expropriation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Full employment policies"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Patent agreements"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="Singapore"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standard of living"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff agreements"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trademark agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2002--Reported to Senate amended.
Bipartisan Trade Promotion Authority Act of 2002 - (Sec. 2) Sets forth the overall trade negotiating objectives of the United States for trade agreements (generally similar to the objectives of the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988 (OTCA)), including to: (1) further strengthen the system of international trading disciplines and procedures, including dispute settlement; (2) foster economic growth, raise living standards, and promote full employment in the United States and to enhance the global economy; (3) ensure that trade and environmental policies are mutually supportive and seek to protect and preserve the environment, while optimizing the use of the world's resources; (4) promote respect for worker rights and the rights of children consistent with core labor standards of the International Labor Organization and an understanding of the relationship between trade and worker rights; (5) seek provisions in trade agreements under which parties to such agreements strive to ensure that they do not weaken or reduce the protections afforded in domestic environmental and labor laws as an encouragement for trade; and (6) ensure that trade agreements afford small businesses equal access to international markets, equitable trade benefits, expanded export market opportunities, and provide for the reduction or elimination of trade barriers that disproportionately affect small business.Sets forth the principal U.S. negotiating objectives (generally similar to the principal OTCA negotiating objectives) regarding trade barriers and other trade distortions, trade in services, foreign investment, intellectual property, transparency, anti-corruption, improvement of the World Trade Organization (WTO) and other multilateral and bilateral trade agreements, foreign regulatory practices, electronic commerce, reciprocal trade in agriculture, labor and the environment, dispute settlement and enforcement of trade agreements, border taxes, and WTO extended negotiations.Requires the United States Trade Representative (USTR) to consult closely with Congress during trade negotiations.(Sec. 3) Sets forth the authority of the President (generally similar to the authority under OTCA) to enter into trade agreements with foreign countries regarding tariff and non-tariff barriers. States that a trade agreement may be entered into (before June 1, 2005; or June 1, 2007, if trade authorities procedures (or fast-track procedures) are extended under this Act) only if it makes progress in meeting the overall and principal trade negotiating objectives, and the President satisfies certain notification and consultation requirements set forth in this Act, including submission of the agreement for assessment by the International Trade Commission (ITC).Applies trade authorities procedures to bills implementing trade agreements if they consist of: (1) a provision approving a trade agreement entered into under this Act, and approving any statement of administrative action; and (2) if changes in existing laws or new statutory authority are required to implement such agreements, provisions necessary to implement them, either repealing or amending existing laws or providing new statutory law.(Sec. 5) Authorizes both Houses of Congress to adopt a procedural disapproval resolution denying trade authorities procedures to any trade agreement if the President has failed or refused to notify or consult with Congress about it. Denies the application of trade authorities procedures to any implementing bill with respect to any such agreement negotiated under the auspices of the WTO, unless the Secretary has reported to Congress the U.S. strategy for correcting instances in which dispute settlement panels and the Appellate Body of the WTO have added to obligations or diminished rights of the United States.(Sec. 6) Exempts from the notice and consultation requirements of this Act any tariff or nontariff agreement which results from negotiations commenced before enactment of this Act, and which: (1) is entered into under the auspices of the WTO regarding the rules of origin work program; (2) is entered into with Chile or Singapore; or (3) establishes a Free Trade Area for the Americas.(Sec. 7) Requires the convening of a Congressional Oversight Group to serve as advisor to the U.S. delegation in the negotiation of any tariff or nontariff trade agreement.(Sec. 8) Requires the President to submit an implementation and enforcement plan at the same time a final text of any tariff or nontariff trade agreement is submitted to Congress.(Sec. 11) Directs the ITC to report to specified congressional committees regarding the economic impact of specified trade agreements on the United States.(Sec. 12) Directs the USTR to pursue, and to report to Congress on, the identification of a small business advocate at the WTO Secretariat to examine the impact of WTO agreements on the interests of small- and medium-sized enterprises, address their concerns, and recommend ways to address those interests in trade negotiations involving the WTO.</summary>
</bill>
