<bill session="108" type="h" number="521" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Steel Industry National Historic Site Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Steel Industry National Historic Site Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Steel Industry National Historic Site in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400114"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2003-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400168" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400181" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400372" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="409888" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2003-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="2003-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-11-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17T16:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-360.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-17T16:29:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="210">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 210.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="280"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Industrial buildings"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2003--Reported to House amended.
Steel Industry National Historic Site Act - Establishes the Steel Industry National Historic Site in Pennsylvania as a unit of the National Park System. Requires the Historic Site to consist of the following properties (the properties) which relate to the former U.S. Steel Homestead Works: (1) the Battle of Homestead site; (2) the Carrie Furnace complex; and (3) the Hot Metal Bridge. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire only by donation the following property for inclusion within the Site: (1) any land or interest in land in the properties; (2) up to ten acres of land adjacent to or in the general proximity of such properties for the development of visitor, administrative, museum, curatorial, and maintenance facilities; and (3) personal property associated with and appropriate for interpretation of such Site. Prohibits anything in this Act from being construed to: (1) require any private property owner to permit public access (including Federal, State, or local government access) to the private property; or (2) modify any provision of Federal, State, or local law with regard to public access to or use of private property. Allows the Secretary, until such time as the Secretary has acquired the properties, to enter into a cooperative agreement with any interested individual, public or private agency, organization, or institution to further the historic purposes of the Site. Provides that, any payment made by the Secretary pursuant to a cooperative agreement shall be subject to an agreement that conversion, use, or disposal of the project so assisted for purposes contrary to the purpose of the Site shall result in a right of the United States to reimbursement of all funds made available to such a project or the proportion of the increased value of the project attributable to such funds at the time of such conversion, use, or disposal, whichever is greater. Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance for the: (1) preservation of historic structures within the Site; and (2) maintenance of the natural and cultural landscape of such Site. Requires the Secretary to prepare and submit to specified congressional committees a general management plan for the Site, which will incorporate or otherwise address substantive comments made during consultation with: (1) an appropriate official of each appropriate political subdivision of Pennsylvania that has jurisdiction over all or part of the lands included in the Site; (2) an appropriate official of the Steel Industry Heritage Corporation; and (3) private property owners in the vicinity of such Site.</summary>
</bill>
