<bill session="104" type="h" number="1184" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Truth in Lending Act Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to clarify the intent of such Act and to reduce burdensome regulatory requirements on creditors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300003" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="401587" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402524" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1995-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403015" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="1995-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1995-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400583" joined="1995-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="405317" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1995-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400225" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400265" joined="1995-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1995-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400601" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="409423" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="409618" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="409633" joined="1995-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1995-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance charges"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing codes"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/1995--Introduced.
Truth in Lending Act Amendments of 1995 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act pertaining to consumer credit cost disclosure to exclude from the determination of finance charges: (1) charges imposed by third parties not affiliated with the creditor (including settlement agents, attorneys, and escrow and title companies) if the creditor does not expressly require the imposition of such charges and does not retain them; (2) taxes levied on security instruments or evidences of indebtedness if payment is a precondition for recording such an instrument; (3) fees, for preparation of loan-related documents and attending or conducting settlement in extensions of credit secured by interest in real property; and (4) fees related to pest infestation on premises, structural inspections, and flood hazards. (Sec. 3) Excludes from a consumer's statutory right of rescission certain refinancings or consolidations of debt secured by a first lien. (Sec. 4) Increases the allowable tolerances for accuracy pertaining to the annual percentage rate disclosure requirements on consumer credit transactions. Provides that the disclosure for per diem interest shall be deemed to be accurate if it is based on information actually known to the creditor at the time that the disclosure documents are being prepared for the consummation of the transaction. (Sec. 5) Sets forth liability limitations for: (1) a creditor's treatment, for disclosure purposes, of specified taxes, fees, and charges other than finance charges; and (2) a creditor's finance charge disclosures within specified tolerance limits. (Sec. 7) Provides that the statute of limitations on a consumer's right of rescission is absolute and acts as a bar to any subsequent assertion of such rescission in State or Federal court. (Sec. 8) Narrows the civil liability guidelines for consumer credit disclosures to: (1) declare a creditor liable for actual damages sustained by a person to the extent such person demonstrates reliance on the inaccurate disclosure which prevented the person from accepting better credit terms actually available from another creditor; (2) revise the general rules for liability of a creditor's voluntary assignee for a violation apparent on the face of the disclosure statement; and (3) declare that a servicer of a consumer obligation shall not be treated as an assignee unless the servicer is the owner of the obligation.</summary>
</bill>
