<bill session="106" type="h" number="5476" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Internet Prescription Drug Consumer Protection Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to enhance consumer protection in the purchase of prescription drugs from interstate Internet sellers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="2000-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2000-10-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-10-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1808-1809"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Drugstores"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/17/2000--Introduced.
Internet Prescription Drug Consumer Protection Act of 2000 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require each interstate Internet seller to comply with requirements of this Act with respect to the sale or offer of prescription drugs. Requires the seller to: (1) post visibly on its web site home page its street address, the States in which it is authorized as a pharmacy, certain prescriber information, and a statement it will dispense prescription drugs only upon a valid prescription; and (2) disclose such information to State licensing boards.Authorizes each State to bring proceedings against an Internet seller on behalf of affected consumers (requiring notice of such proceedings to the Secretary of Health and Human Services and appropriate Federal agencies). Allows the President to intervene in such actions.Directs the Secretary to: (1) engage in activities to educate the public about the dangers of purchasing prescription drugs from unlawful Internet sources; and (2) recommend to Congress the coordination of activities of Federal agencies regarding Internet sellers that operate from foreign countries with the activities of such foreign governments.Authorizes the President to initiate a civil action to enjoin or restrain the alienation or disposal of property obtained as a result of, or traceable to, a violation of this Act.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
