<bill session="108" type="h" number="1798" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Upper Housatonic Valley National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Upper Housatonic Valley National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Upper Housatonic Valley National Heritage Area in the State of Connecticut and the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2003-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="2003-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-23">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-11-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17T16:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-365.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-17T16:33:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="215">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 215.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="280"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Social life and customs"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2003--Reported to House amended.
Upper Housatonic Valley National Heritage Area Act - Establishes the Upper Housatonic Valley National Heritage Area in Connecticut and Massachusetts. Designates the Upper Housatonic Valley National Heritage Area, Inc., as the Area's management entity (the entity), which shall: (1) submit to the Secretary of the Interior for approval a management plan which includes policies, strategies, and recommendations for conservation, funding, management, development, and interpretation of the Area; and (2) assist local governments, regional planning organizations, and nonprofit organizations in implementing the plan. Allows the entity, for purposes of preparing and implementing the plan for the Area, to make grants and enter into cooperative agreements to provide technical assistance to Connecticut and Massachusetts and other specified entities. Prohibits the management entity from using Federal funds received under this Act to acquire real property, but may use any other source of funding, including other Federal funding, intended for the acquisition of real property. Requires the management entity to submit the management plan within three years after funds are made available for this Act. Bars the entity, if the plan is not submitted to the Secretary by such deadline, from qualifying for Federal funding under this Act until it is submitted. Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical and financial assistance to the Area and enter into cooperative agreements with the management entity and other public or private entities to develop and implement the plan. Prohibits the preservation, conservation, or promotion of any privately owned property by the plan until the owner of that private property has been notified in writing and has given written consent to the management entity. Provides for any owner of private property included within the Area's boundary to have their property immediately removed from the boundary by submitting a written request to the entity. Authorizes appropriations. Limits: (1) the amount of funding for any fiscal year; (2) the total amount that may be appropriated for the Area under this Act; and (3) Federal matching funds provided under this Act to 50 percent of the total cost of any assistance or grant provided or authorized under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
