<bill session="104" type="hr" number="254" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-30T15:18:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-11-30T15:18:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making technical corrections in the Rules of the House of Representatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Rules"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-11-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Rules"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14T21:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Rules. H. Rept. 104-340.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-11-14T21:20:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="122">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 122.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-11-30T15:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Dreier asked unanimous consent that it be in order without intervening motion to consider H. Res. 254; that the amendment recommended by the Committee on Rules be considered as adopted; that the previous question be considered as ordererd on the resolution; only the amendment offered by the Chairman of the Rules Committee or his designee is permitted; and debate will be limited to one hour. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-30T15:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered pursuant to a previous agreement.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13844-13845" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-30T15:15:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-30T15:18:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-11-30T15:18:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-11-30T15:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting of congressional proceedings"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee staffing"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative calendars"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Unfunded mandates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h918"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/30/1995--Passed House amended.
Makes technical and conforming corrections in the Rules of the House of Representatives concerning the Journal (of congressional proceedings); the Office of the Inspector General; the Committee on National Security; the Committee on Small Business; special oversight functions of the Committee on Resources and the Committee on Commerce; the three-day layover for filing of supplemental, minority, or additional views, committee reports, appropriations hearings and reports, conference reports, and Senate amendments to measures reported in disagreement; committee broadcast rules; committee staffs; the Corrections Calendar; privilege for measures reported by the Committee on Ways and Means; unfunded mandate reform; and the gift rule ( excludes from gifts banned under such rule donations of products from the Member's State that are intended primarily for promotional purposes such as display or free distribution and that are of minimal value to any individual recipient; and items of nominal value such as a greeting card, baseball cap, or a T-shirt).</summary>
</bill>
