<bill session="104" type="h" number="2211" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dioxin Reduction and Incinerator Alternatives Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish certain requirements with respect to solid waste and hazardous waste incinerators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402750" joined="1995-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="402762" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1995-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1995-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1995-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1995-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1996-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1996-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1995-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1995-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1995-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1995-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1995-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1995-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1995-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1995-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Chlorine"/>
    <term name="Churches"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Compost"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Electric batteries"/>
    <term name="Electronics"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food contamination"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Household hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Plastics"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Price fixing"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Schools"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Synagogues"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Waste reduction"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Yard waste"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1995--Introduced.
Dioxin Reduction and Incinerator Alternatives Act of 1995 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit the issuance of permits for construction or expansion of municipal solid waste incinerators until 2001. Prohibits Federal agencies, State or local governments, or other waste management jurisdictions from issuing permits to such incinerators after December 31, 2000, unless the applicant demonstrates that: (1) an annual waste composition analysis of the solid waste generated within the area to be served by the facility is conducted; (2) specified percentages of certain waste categories are diverted to waste management methods other than incineration; (3) the facility will not interfere with diversion rates; (4) it is not feasible to manage the remaining solid waste through source reduction, reuse, or recycling; (5) the facility will not adversely affect the environment, human health, or the local economy and is not situated in a nonattainment area identified under the Clean Air Act; (6) the full cost of the facility over its entire life will be less costly than reducing, recycling, or composting waste; (7) the waste management jurisdiction conducts a public participation process; (8) the proposed construction or expansion is approved by the affected unit of local government; (9) firms operating the facility are in compliance with environmental and public health statutes, have paid outstanding fines for violations of such statutes, and make disclosure statements available; (10) an approved environmental impact statement is completed; (11) the facility is not located within one and a half miles of specified sites, including schools or churches, or of a drinking water source; (12) certain incinerator capacity studies have been completed; and (13) the facility will not have a disproportionate impact on minority or low-income communities. Requires ash from municipal solid waste incinerators to be managed in a monofill that contains only such ash and meets specified design requirements. Prohibits the use of such ash for any purpose. Prohibits the incineration of household hazardous waste, batteries, chlorinated plastics, consumer electronics, and yard waste in such incinerators. Prohibits the issuance of permits or prior approval for the construction or expansion of hazardous waste incinerators unless requirements similar to those for municipal solid waste incinerators have been met. Directs hazardous waste management permit applicants to demonstrate that the State in which the incinerator is located, and each State in which generators of hazardous waste to be incinerated at the facility are located, are implementing toxics use reduction programs. Applies this Act to any facility that burns hazardous waste.</summary>
</bill>
