<bill session="104" type="h" number="2110" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhanced Environmental Cleanup and Management Demonstration Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide leadership, improved efficiencies, and regulatory clarity for Department of Energy waste management and environmental restoration efforts at the Hanford Reservation and certain other Defense Nuclear Facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402010" joined="1995-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1995-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="1995-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1995-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1995-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1995-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="410067" joined="1995-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="410636" joined="1995-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="411550" joined="1995-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on National Security, and Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOE, EPA.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental engineering"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Metric system"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/1995--Introduced.
Enhanced Environmental Cleanup and Management Demonstration Act of 1995 - Subjects to this Act: (1) the Hanford Reservation in southeastern Washington; and (2) any Defense Nuclear Facility with an FY 1995 environmental management budget of $500 million or more whose host State Governor so requests (unless the President determines that such application is not in the national interest). (Sec. 5) Directs the President to appoint a Site Manager for the Hanford Reservation, and for any other Defense Nuclear Facility whose application is approved. Delineates the Site Manager's authority to oversee and direct facility operations, including environmental cleanup and management. Requests the Site Manager to select remedial actions for a Defense Nuclear Facility in accordance with the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA). Authorizes the Site Manager to exempt a Defense Nuclear Facility subject to this Act from the requirements of the Metric System Conversion Act of 1975. (Sec. 6) States that internal orders of the Department of Energy (DOE), with certain exceptions, are not applicable at a Defense Nuclear Facility subject to this Act after the Site Manager confirmation. Permits a Site Manager to adopt a new order only after finding that it is essential to the protection of human health or the environment, or to conduct critical administrative functions, and will not unduly interfere with efforts to bring a Facility into compliance with environmental laws. (Sec. 7) Prescribes parameters within which a host State may exercise the authorities vested in the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency under CERCLA to enforce compliance at any Facility subject to this Act with any requirement of an interagency agreement with DOE. Requires a host State to use monetary penalties or fines collected from the Federal Government for environmental law violations only for projects to protect the environment at or near the facility from threats resulting from the facility or to remedy contamination associated with it. (Sec. 8) Requires the Site Manager to integrate the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act with other State and Federal regulatory requirements. (Sec. 9) Establishes a Land Use Council for each Defense Nuclear Facility for which a Site Manager has been appointed to develop a future land use plan for all lands within the Defense Nuclear Facility boundaries managed under CERCLA, and listed on the National Priorities List. Prescribes plan contents. (Sec. 10) Directs the Site Manager to: (1) promote demonstration, certification, verification, and implementation of new environmental technologies at the Facilities; and (2) establish a program for testing environmental, waste characterization, and remediation technology at the site. Directs the Secretary to provide regulatory or contractual safe harbors to limit liability of companies using technology approved for use at a Facility for use at other DOE facilities. Sets forth indemnification requirements for agreements with private entities when source, special nuclear, or by-product materials are involved. (Sec. 11) Prescribes contracting strategies consistent with the Federal Acquisition Regulation and the Federal Acquisition Streamlining Act. Permits multiyear contracting. Requires the Site Manager to obtain the expertise necessary to implement performance oriented incentive based contracting and procurement practices. (Sec. 13) Requires each Facility Site Manager to report biennially to the Congress. (Sec. 14) Exempts certain small Federal structures at a Defense Nuclear Facility from the National Historic Preservation Act, unless the Site Manager deems them appropriate for protection under such Act, and that such action will not delay cleanup activities or increase cleanup costs. (Sec. 15) Requires the DOE Office of Environmental Health and Safety to enforce safety and health activities at Defense Nuclear Facilities. (Sec. 16) Authorizes the Site Manager to enter into contracts with private entities to service environmental management at a Facility, including design, construction and operation of treatment, storage, and disposal facilities. Prescribes local community and resident preference and economic diversification requirements for such contracts. (Sec. 19) Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) stable funding levels are essential to implement this Act; and (2) the Site Manager and the President are encouraged to seek funding levels not lower than those allocated during FY 1996.</summary>
</bill>
