<bill session="106" type="h" number="1204" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Environmental Equalization and Energy Security Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a tax on the importation of crude oil and petroleum products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400389"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400540" joined="1999-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1999--Introduced.
Environmental Equalization and Energy Security Act of 1999 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on imported crude oil and petroleum products (except those imported from Canada) equal to the applicable environmental equalization fee per barrel of crude oil, as determined by the Secretary of Energy. States that the fee shall be the amount of the Secretary's estimate: (1) in the case of crude oil, of the average amount per barrel of the price of domestic crude oil attributable to costs of complying with U.S. environmental laws and regulations; and (2) in the case of petroleum products, of the average amount per barrel of the price of domestic petroleum products attributable to such costs. Exempts from such tax: (1) the sale of crude oil or petroleum products for export or for resale by the purchaser to a second purchaser for export; and (2) the sale or use of any petroleum product during any period when the President determines that it is in the national interest not to impose the tax.</summary>
</bill>
