<bill session="105" type="h" number="2924" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Alaskan Native Claims Settlement Act to provide for selection of lands by certain veterans of the Vietnam era and by the Elim Native Corporation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-11-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2220-2221"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-25">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Eskimos"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Vietnam veterans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/7/1997--Introduced.
Amends the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA) to make certain Native Alaskans who are Vietnam veterans eligible, for up to one year after the enactment of this Act, for up to 160 acres apiece of nonmineral Alaskan land. Withdraws certain Alaska lands from disposition under the public land laws, entry or appropriation under the mining laws, and the operation of U.S. mineral leasing, subject to valid existing rights, for a one-year period, for selection by the Elim Native Corporation. Authorizes: (1) such Corporation to select 50,000 acres of such lands to satisfy its land entitlements under ANCSA; (2) the Secretary of the Interior to receive, adjudicate, and convey such lands to the Corporation, subject to valid existing rights and an easement reserved to the United States for the benefit of the public; and (3) the Secretary to withdraw, and the Corporation to select, certain additional adjacent lands withdrawn to fulfill the Corporation's land entitlements equal to the total acreage of the Norton Bay Reservation as withdrawn by executive order. Constitutes the Corporation's selection of such lands as full satisfaction of all Corporation claims under ANCSA and the extinguishment of the Norton Bay Reservation.</summary>
</bill>
