<bill session="106" type="h" number="4551" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Benefits for Seniors Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal the 1993 increase in tax on Social Security benefits and to develop and apply a Consumer Price Index that accurately reflects the cost-of-living for older Americans who receive Social Security benefits under title II of the Social Security Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400019"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer price indexes"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Demography"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
    <term name="Social security beneficiaries"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2000--Introduced.
Fair Benefits for Seniors Act of 2000 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to make inapplicable after December 31, 2000, an increase in the amount of social security benefits included in gross income enacted by the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993 (effectively repealing such increase).Establishes the Consumer Price Index Review Committee to study and report to Congress on: (1) improved, more accurate methods for determining a Consumer Price Index for the Elderly to ensure that the improved index accurately measures changes in expenditures for consumption typical for retirees who receive Old-Age and Survivors Insurance benefits under title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act (SSA), as well as an index implementation plan; and (2) an accurate consumer price index for individuals who receive SSA title II disability insurance benefits. Authorizes appropriations.Directs the Commissioner of the Bureau of Labor Statistics to establish a pilot program to test the accuracy of an operational Consumer Price Index for the Elderly, which indicates changes in such consumption expenditures.Provides for implementation of the Consumer Price Index for the Elderly. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
