<bill session="104" type="hc" number="194" updated="2012-11-01T22:45:38-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Establishing a commission to study compensation and other personnel policies and practices in the legislative branch.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1996-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1205)</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1205"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Equal pay for equal work"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Pay equity"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Position classification"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>06/27/1996--Introduced.
Establishes the Commission on Employment Discrimination in the Legislative Branch to: (1) employ a nongovernmental consultant with expertise in job evaluation to study and compare the compensation paid within and between job classifications in the Library of Congress and to analyze the Library's personnel policies and practices; (2) evaluate the Library's compensation system and personnel policies and practices for compliance with title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and make specific recommendations (other than recommendations that would result in a reduction in the rate of pay payable for any position) to the Congress for such necessary action to achieve that compliance; (3) develop a comprehensive plan for application of the principles of title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 throughout the legislative branch; and (4) make specific recommendations to the Congress for improvement of legislative branch personnel policies and practices.</summary>
</bill>
