<bill session="106" type="h" number="1420" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Individual Tax Simplification Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 of provide a revenue-neutral simplification of the individual income tax.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400291"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1999-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1999-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-04-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E647-648"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Adopted children"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Adoptive parents"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled children"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee stock options"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax simplification"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Tuition tax credits"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Simplification Relating to Nonrefundable Personal Credits Title II: Simplification of Capital Gains Tax Title III: Repeal of Certain Hidden Marginal Rate Increases; Repeal of Individual Minimum Tax Subtitle A: Repeals Subtitle B: Revenue Offsets Individual Tax Simplification Act of 1999 - Title I: Simplification Relating to Nonrefundable Personal Credits - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal the interaction of the alternative minimum tax with the partially refundable child care tax credit.(Sec. 102) Replaces the current three ranges for phaseout of the adoption, child, and Hope and Lifetime Learning tax credits with a single, uniform phaseout of such credits.Title II: Simplification of Capital Gains Tax - Mandates a deduction from gross income of 38 percent of a net capital gain for any taxable year for a taxpayer other than a corporation.Title III: Repeal of Certain Hidden Marginal Rate Increases; Repeal of Individual Minimum Tax - Subtitle A: Repeals - Repeals the overall limitation on itemized deductions, the phaseout of personal exemptions, and the alternative minimum tax on individuals.Subtitle B: Revenue Offsets - Establishes an additional income tax on a sliding scale from: (1) one percent for adjusted gross incomes in excess of $120,000 on a joint return; up to (2) 2.08 percent for income greater than $150,000 (where the minimum tax exemption begins to phase out under this Act).(Sec. 312) Increases the floor on miscellaneous itemized deductions from two percent to four percent for adjusted gross incomes greater than $100,000.</summary>
</bill>
