<bill session="104" type="h" number="3158" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pilot Small Business Technology Transfer Program Extension Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Pilot Small Business Technology Transfer Program Extension Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to extend the pilot Small Business Technology Transfer program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1996-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1996-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="410887" joined="1996-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-03-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-06-28T01:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Watts (OK) asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Small Business have until 4:00 p.m. on July 3 to file a report on H.R. 3158. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26T16:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 104-850, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-09-26T16:40:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="462">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 462.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Discharged from Union Calendar.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Science for a period ending not later than Oct. 11, 1996 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of the Committee on Science pursuant to clause 1(n), rule X.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development contracts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/1996--Reported to House amended.
Pilot Small Business Technology Transfer Program Extension Act of 1996 - Amends the Small Business Act to: (1) extend through FY 2000 the Small Business Technology Transfer (SBTT) Program under which specified portions of each Federal agency's research and development (R&amp;D) budget are reserved for small business cooperative R&amp;D; and (2) increase for FY 1997 and thereafter the portion reserved for small businesses under such program. Directs the Comptroller General to conduct an assessment of the ongoing implementation of the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Program and the pilot SBTT Program. Outlines issues to be addressed in such assessment, requiring a focus on programs implemented during the period beginning October 1, 1995, and ending September 30, 1999. Requires a report from the Comptroller General to the small business committees. Requires the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to convene and supervise an interagency task force on fostering commercialization of the results of projects being undertaken by small businesses through the SBIR and SBTT programs. Outlines task force duties and membership requirements. Requires: (1) public participation in task force activities; and (2) a notice and initial call for such participation by the Administrator. Directs the Administrator to report to the small business committees on the work of the task force, including recommendations for legislative or administrative action.</summary>
</bill>
