<bill session="105" type="hr" number="539" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that a national HIV surveillance system should be expeditiously implemented.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1998-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="410407" joined="1998-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/1998--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the States should move to implement human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) surveillance systems; (2) the Federal Government and the States should ensure that funds follow epidemiological HIV infection trends; (3) there are different approaches to carrying out HIV surveillance systems and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDCP) should respect the right of each State to determine the best approach in that State; (4) a State that elects to implement an HIV surveillance system should assess HIV surveillance data security and confidentiality and change laws to ensure confidentiality; (5) HIV surveillance systems should not be developed that deter people from using anonymous HIV counseling and testing and other HIV prevention programs; (6) States should work with HIV community planning groups reflective of the demographics of HIV infection and with other local medical and public health institutions to develop their own HIV surveillance programs; and (7) the CDCP should provide comprehensive guidance to States and provide increased funds and technical assistance to ensure the quality and efficiency of HIV surveillance systems selected by the States and facilitate the transition from monitoring only acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) cases to monitoring both HIV cases and AIDS cases.</summary>
</bill>
