<bill session="106" type="h" number="2694" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community of Care Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the availability of child care for children whose parents work nontraditional hours or shifts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Child care block grants"/>
    <term name="Child care workers"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/1999--Introduced.
Community of Care Act of 1999 - Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to establish a program of assistance for child care for nontraditional hours and varied shifts. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants for activities designed to increase the availability of child care for children whose parents work nontraditional hours or varied shifts. Requires such activities to include: (1) creating incentives for resource and referral agencies to engage in activities designed to increase the awareness of parents who work nontraditional hours or varied shifts about the availability of communities of care to provide child care for their children; (2) providing funds to increase compensation, including bonuses, to such communities of care and their employees; (3) providing start-up funds for such communities of care; (4) providing grants to resource and referral agencies, child care organizations, and nonprofit organizations for activities that encourage and recruit caregivers, eligible child care providers, and family child care providers to start new communities of care; and (5) creating other incentives to increase the number and availability of such communities of care. Defines a community of care as caregivers, eligible child care providers, or family child care providers that, alone or in cooperation with other such caregivers or providers, provide child care for an average of seven or more nontraditional hours daily or for children whose parents work varied shifts. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
