<bill session="104" type="h" number="586" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Omnibus Foster Care Improvement Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to require States to administer qualifying examinations to all State employees with new authority to make decisions regarding child welfare services, to expedite the permanent placement of foster children, to facilitate the placement of foster children in permanent kinship care arrangements, and to require State agencies, in considering applications to adopt certain foster children, to give preference to applications of a foster parent or caretaker relative of the child.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1995-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1995-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1995-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1995-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="1995-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Adoptive parents"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Foster parents"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/1995--Introduced.
Omnibus Foster Care Improvement Act of 1995 - Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require States to administer qualifying examinations to all State employees with new authority to make decisions regarding child welfare services. (Sec. 3) Prohibits the Secretary of Health and Human Services from making a payment of such assistance to a State unless the State has in effect procedures requiring the State agency, at the time a child is removed from a home and placed in foster care under State supervision, to locate any parent of the child who is not living at the home and evaluate that parent's ability to provide a suitable home for the child. (Sec. 4) Gives States the option of deeming as adoption the placement of a child who was under State-supervised foster care with a blood relative given legal custody of the child. (Sec. 5) Prohibits the Secretary, after a five-year interim period, from making a payment of such assistance to a State unless the State requires a State agency to give preference to applications of a foster parent or caretaker relative of the child in considering applications to adopt certain foster children.</summary>
</bill>
