<bill session="105" type="h" number="2947" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Walker River Basin Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage and to assist in the permanent settlement of all litigation and other claims to the waters of the Walker River Basin, Nevada, and to conserve and stabilize the water quantity and quality for fish habitat and recreation in the Walker River Basin, consistent with the Walker River Decree issued by the United States district court for the District of Nevada.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Eutrophication"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/1997--Introduced.
Walker River Basin Act of 1997 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, specified locally affected interests, and the State of California to initiate negotiations for the comprehensive and permanent settlement of all claims to waters of the Walker River in California and Nevada. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress on any legislation required under the terms of such settlement. Directs the Secretary to assist in the development and implementation of studies, pilot projects, or long-term projects necessary in the negotiation of such settlement. Makes the Federal share 75 percent of the total cost of any such study or project, with the remaining amounts allocated among the locally affected interests, California, and Nevada. Authorizes appropriations. Provides for the protection and administration of U.S. water rights in Walker River water. Provides a moratorium against any other claims concerning Walker River water for one year after the enactment of this Act and during the period of any required study or project. Prohibits: (1) information derived from a study or project from being used for purposes other than the negotiation of a settlement; and (2) the Secretary from undermining, contradicting, or diminishing the water rights confirmed under the Walker River Decree (a decree issued by the U.S. District Court for the District of Nevada).</summary>
</bill>
