<bill session="104" type="h" number="184" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Individual Privacy Protection Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the privacy provisions of title 5, United States Code, to improve the protection of individual information and to reestablish a permanent Privacy Protection Commission as an independent entity in the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402763"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Records management"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Individual Privacy Protection Act of 1995 - Amends the Privacy Act of 1974 to increase the minimum amount of civil damages against the United States when an agency fails to maintain a record on an individual with accuracy, relevance, timeliness, or completeness in order to assure fairness. Sets limits on such recoveries. Establishes an Individual Privacy Protection Board to: (1) study the data banks, automated data processing programs, and information systems of public and private organizations to determine standards and procedures in force for the protection of personal information; (2) recommend to the President and the Congress the extent to which provisions of the Privacy Act should be applied to such organizations; (3) develop guidelines and provide continuing assistance for, and investigate compliance with, individual records maintenance requirements; (4) review Federal law, Executive orders, regulations, directives, and judicial decisions and report on their consistency with the rights of privacy, due process of law, and other guarantees in the Constitution; and (5) comment on the implications for data protection of proposed Federal, State, or local statutes, regulations, or procedures. Provides penalties for violations of privacy rights.</summary>
</bill>
