<bill session="106" type="h" number="3133" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coral Reef Protection Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Commerce, through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, to provide financial assistance for coral reef conservation projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400615" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1999-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-10-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2160-2161"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-21">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-21">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1253"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1253"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Caribbean Sea"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Coral reef conservation"/>
    <term name="Coral reefs"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Pacific area"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Salvage"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/21/1999--Introduced.
Coral Reef Protection Act of 1999 - Declares that it is U.S. policy to conserve coral reefs and coral reef ecosystems.(Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to provide: (1) financial assistance for projects that provide for the restoration or conservation of coral reefs or coral reef ecosystems; and (2) technical assistance to any State or Federal agency with coral reef jurisdiction.(Sec. 7) Authorizes: (1) the conducting of activities that conserve coral reefs or coral reef ecosystems or that further public awareness and education; and (2) joint projects with any Federal, State, or local authority or financial assistance to any person for such activities.(Sec. 8) Prohibits a vessel that is otherwise qualified to be documented as a vessel of the United States from being documented if the owner has abandoned any vessel on a reef subject to U.S. jurisdiction and the vessel remains on the reef or was removed using funds under this Act or any other Act having environmental protection as its purpose, unless the owner has reimbursed the United States for the environmental damage and removal expenses.(Sec. 9) Makes any person who injures or creates a threat of injury to any coral, coral reef, or coral reef ecosystem jointly and severally liable to the United States for response costs and damages, related seizure, forfeiture, or storage costs, and related interests. Provides for vessel liability in rem and for related maritime liens on vessels. Declares that specified provisions relating to limitations on the liability of vessel owners, masters, and others do not limit the liability of any person or vessel under this title (sic).Authorizes the Secretary to undertake or authorize all necessary actions to prevent or minimize injury (or threat of injury) to any coral, coral reef, or coral reef ecosystem. Authorizes the Attorney General to commence a civil action against any person or vessel that may be liable under this section. Sets forth defenses and a time limit for commencing actions.(Sec. 10) Authorizes the Secretary to enter into an agreement with a foundation under which the foundation may use amounts available to carry out this section to build and support public-private partnerships that support research, management, or education regarding coral reef and reef ecosystem conservation and furthering this Act's purposes.(Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
