<bill session="107" type="h" number="1175" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Indian Tribal Federal Recognition Administrative Procedures Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for administrative procedures to extend Federal recognition to certain Indian groups, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2001-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-03-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E432-433"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-11">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8389-8390"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2001--Introduced.
Indian Tribal Federal Recognition Administrative Procedures Act of 2001 - Establishes the Commission on Indian Recognition as an independent establishment which shall assume the authority of the Department of the Interior to recognize a petitioning Indian group's tribal status.Sets forth operating and documented petitioning procedures, including an opportunity for Indian groups denied recognition to a hearing under specified circumstances. Requires documented petitions to contain detailed, specific evidence, including: (1) statements of facts establishing that the petitioner has been identified as an American Indian entity on a substantially continuous basis since 1871, that a predominant portion of the petitioner's membership comprises a community distinct from those communities surrounding it and has existed as a community from historical times to the present, and that and the petitioner has maintained political influence or authority over its members as an autonomous entity from historical times until the time of the petition; (2) a copy of the petitioner's governing document or description of the petitioner's membership criteria and the petitioner's governing procedures; and (3) a list of the petitioner's current members, a copy of each available former list of members based on the petitioner's defined criteria, and a description of the methods used in preparing those lists.Requires the Commission to publish an annual list of recognized Indian tribes.Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award petition assistance grants.</summary>
</bill>
