<bill session="105" type="h" number="1659" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-23">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument Completion Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument Completion Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument Completion Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument Completion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the expeditious completion of the acquisition of private mineral interests within the Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument mandated by the 1982 Act that established the Monument, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="1997-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1997-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="1997-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1997-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E966"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-23">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-06-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11T12:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-704.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-11T12:30:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="399">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 399.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Chenoweth moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8473-8474" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-09-23T14:52:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-09-23T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="600">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 600.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1998-10-07" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11813" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-07">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1998-10-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1998-10-13">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1998-10-23">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1998-10-23" type="public" number="105-279">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 105-279.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="638"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Volcanoes"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/1998--Passed House amended.
Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument Completion Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to acquire, by exchange, the mineral and geothermal interests of each company (Burlington Northern, Incorporated or the Weyerhaeuser Company) in the Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument in the State of Washington. Sets forth requirements and administrative procedures for such exchange, including requiring the Secretary, in exchange for all mineral and geothermal interests acquired from each company, to issue to each such company monetary credits with a value of $2.1 million that may be used for the payment of: (1) not more than 50 percent of the bonus or other payments made by successful bidders in any sales of mineral, oil, gas, or geothermal leases under the Mineral Leasing Act, the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, or the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 in the contiguous 48 States; (2) not more than ten percent of the bonus or other payments made by successful bidders in any sales of such leases under such Acts; (3) not more than 50 percent of any royalty, rental, or advance royalty payment made to the United States to maintain any mineral, oil, or gas, or geothermal lease in the 48 contiguous States issued under such Acts; or (4) not more than ten percent of any royalty, rental, or advance royalty payment made to the United States to maintain any mineral, oil, or gas, or geothermal lease in Alaska issued under such Acts. Requires the Secretary to accept credits in the same manner as cash for the payments. Requires that all amounts in the form of credits accepted by the Secretary for the payments be considered to be money received for the purpose of the Mineral Leasing Act and the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970. Directs the Secretary, not later than 30 days after the completion of the required exchange with a company, to establish an exchange account for that company for the monetary credits issued to it. Permits: (1) a company to transfer or sell any credits in the company's account to another person; and (2) such credits transferred or sold to be used only by a person that is qualified to bid on, or that holds, a mineral, oil, or gas lease under the Mineral Leasing Act, the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, or the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970. Terminates an account created for a company five years after creation. Requires the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees on: (1) all remaining privately held mineral interests within the boundaries of the Monument; and (2) a plan and a timetable by which the Secretary would propose to complete the acquisition of such interests.</summary>
</bill>
