<bill session="104" type="hr" number="302" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-13T22:13:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-12-13T22:13:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Relating to the deployment of United States Armed Forces in and around the territory of the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina to enforce the peace agreement between the parties to the conflict in the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="1995-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on National Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T20:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on International Relations discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T20:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on National Security discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T20:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 304.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14849-14860" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T20:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2770 with 1 hour of general debate. The resolution provides for 1 hour of general debate on the question of deploying troops to the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina. After general debate it shall be in order to consider in the House H.R. 2770, debatable for 1 hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill without intervening motion, except one motion to recommit. After disposition of or postponement of further proceedings on H.R. 2770, it shall be in order to consider in the House H. Res. 302, relating to the deployment of troops in the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina, debatable for 1 hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motion. After disposition or postponement of the resolution, it shall be in order to consider another resolution relating to Bosnia and Herzegovina, debatable for 1 hour.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T20:29:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T21:53:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-12-13T22:13:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="857" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 287 - 141, 1 Present (Roll No. 857).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13T22:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hr" number="304"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="sj" number="44"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Neutrality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/1995--Introduced.
Reiterates serious concerns and opposition to the President's policy that results in the deployment of 20,000 members of the U.S. armed forces on the ground in the territory of the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina. Calls for: (1) the President and the Secretary of Defense to rely on the judgment of, and ensure the provision of appropriate resources and support to, the commander of the U.S. armed forces that are deployed in and around the territory of the Republic in all matters affecting the safety, support, and well-being of such forces; and (2) the U.S. Government to be impartial and evenhanded with all parties to the conflict as necessary to assure the safety and protection of such forces.</summary>
</bill>
