<bill session="107" type="h" number="5584" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect certain lands held in fee by the Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians from condemnation until a final decision is made regarding a pending fee to trust application for that land, to provide an environmentally sound process for the expeditious consideration and approval of an electricity transmission line right-of-way through the Trabuco Ranger District of the Cleveland National Forest and adjacent Federal lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy facility sites"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/9/2002--Introduced.
Declares that specified lands held in fee by the Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians shall not be transferred or made available for condemnation until the Secretary of the Interior renders a final decision (and all appeals are exhausted) on the pending fee to trust application, or the application is withdrawn.Directs the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture (the "Secretaries") to issue the necessary grants, easements, permits, plan amendments, and other approvals to allow for the siting and construction of a high-voltage electricity transmission line in part of the Cleveland National Forest in California and adjacent lands under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management and the Forest Service.Forbids any portion of the transmission line from entering any identified wilderness area.Assigns primary responsibility for completing the environmental and other reviews necessary for the implementation of this Act to the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management. States that it is anticipated that this Act will make it unnecessary to construct regional transmission lines through heavily populated lands in the Temecula Valley.Subjects the right-of-way to such terms and conditions as the Secretaries set forth to protect historic, cultural, and natural resources under their respective jurisdictions.</summary>
</bill>
