<bill session="105" type="h" number="360" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Waste Export and Import Prohibition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit the international export and import of certain solid waste.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Glass recycling"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="OECD countries"/>
    <term name="Paper recycling"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Scrap metals"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Waste Export and Import Prohibition Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit: (1) solid waste exports from the United States to a foreign country not a member of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD); and (2) effective January 1, 1999, solid waste exports to or imports from an OECD member country. Specifies exceptions from the first prohibition for certain waste paper, textiles, and glass intended for recycling and not regulated as hazardous waste and an additional exception from the latter for certain scrap metals. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in the case of an export violation, to: (1) ensure that the exported waste is retrieved (if the recipient country is agreeable to retrieval), either pursuant to a compliance order issued under this Act or by direct retrieval; or (2) dispose of or clean up such waste (to the extent agreed to) if the country is not agreeable to retrieval. Sets forth procedures for issuance of compliance orders. Establishes civil and criminal penalties. Authorizes commencement of citizen lawsuits by foreign governments. Repeals existing prohibitions on the export of hazardous waste.</summary>
</bill>
