<bill session="104" type="h" number="2952" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Individual Social Security Retirement Account Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and title II of the Social Security Act to reduce social security taxes, to reduce old-age insurance benefits by a corresponding amount, and to provide for the establishment of individual social security retirement accounts funded by payroll deductions and employer contributions equal to the amount of the tax reduction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400604"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1996-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/1996--Introduced.
Individual Social Security Retirement Account Act of 1995 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reduce the social security taxes on employees and employers by the authorized tax reduction for any calendar year under this Act. Defines the "authorized tax reduction" under the Code as half the sum of the excess of the total unadjusted Old Age and Survivors Insurance (OASI) tax rate over the adjusted cost rate, plus the value of certain projected receipts for such calendar year of the Federal Old Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund. Requires the Commissioner of Social Security to determine, according to specified formulae, and publish by November 1 of each calendar year, the total unadjusted OASI rate and the adjusted cost rate for the following calendar year. Reduces the self-employment tax by the authorized tax reduction for such tax, defined as the full sum of the excess of the total unadjusted OASI tax rate over the adjusted cost rate, plus the value of certain projected receipts for such calendar year of the Federal Old Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund. Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to reduce an individual's monthly OASDI benefit by the authorized benefit reduction, determined according to a specified formula. Amends OASDI to require employers to have in effect a social security payroll deduction plan for employees. Requires such plan to provide for employers to deduct the prescribed social security employee contribution for transfer, together with the prescribed social security employer contribution, to an individual social security retirement account of the employee. Requires self-employed individuals to pay into such accounts the prescribed social security self-employment contribution. Sets forth penalties for failure to establish deduction plans, make appropriate deductions, and pay deductions and contributions into social security retirement accounts. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require amounts deducted from employee wages to be shown on employee wage receipts (W-2 forms). Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to exempt social security payroll deduction plans from provisions governing employee benefit plans. Provides for the tax treatment of individual social security retirement accounts in a manner similar to individual retirement accounts. Terminates the tax reduction provisions of this Act after the authorized tax reduction is zero percent for three consecutive calendar years commencing on or after January 1, 1997.</summary>
</bill>
