<bill session="106" type="hj" number="51" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Authorization for Use of Military Force Against the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia Resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Authorizing the use of United States Armed Forces against the regime in power in the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia to meet certain objectives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400569"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Albanians"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense burdensharing"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indictments"/>
    <term name="Kosovo"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="National self-determination"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="President as Commander-in-Chief"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Serbia"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crime trials"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="Yugoslavia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/1999--Introduced.
Authorization for Use of Military Force Against the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia Resolution - Authorizes the President to use U.S. armed forces in conjunction with the military forces of the member nations of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to: (1) end the ethnic cleansing and terrorization of the ethnic Albanian population of Kosovo by the present regime in the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia; and (2) establish a practical and enforceable agreement for the return of ethnic Albanian citizens of Kosovo. Requires the President to: (1) ensure that the U.S. contribution to any peacekeeping operation relating to the conflict in Kosovo does not exceed 4,000 ground troops or 14 percent of the total number of ground troops in such peacekeeping operation; (2) ensure that the costs incurred by the United States in connection with such operation shall not exceed the proportional amount contributed by the United States to the NATO Security Investment Program; (3) work to establish an agreement among member nations of NATO under which the costs incurred by each such member nation for such conflict shall be proportional to the amount contributed by each such member nation to the NATO Security Investment Program; and (4 ) ensure that any agreement for cessation of military action relating to such conflict does not exempt from prosecution any individual who has been or who may be indicted by the United Nations International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia.</summary>
</bill>
