<bill session="105" type="hr" number="142" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-07T14:33:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-05-07T14:33:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 478) to amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to improve the ability of individuals and local, State, and Federal agencies to comply with that Act in building, operating, maintaining, or repairing flood control projects, facilities, or structures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-05-06T21:44:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-88, by Mr. Linder.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-06T21:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 478 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Resources now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-05-06T21:45:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="28">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 28.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-05-07T13:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2281-2283" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-07T13:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-07T14:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1997-05-07T14:33:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="107" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 415 - 8 (Roll no. 107).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-05-07T14:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="478"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/1997--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 478 (flood control project compliance with the Endangered Species Act of 1973).</summary>
</bill>
