<bill session="104" type="h" number="2854" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-04-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Farm bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Freedom to Farm bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Agricultural Market Transition Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Agricultural Market Transition Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Canola and Rapeseed Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Commodity Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Food Security Commodity Reserve Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">National Kiwifruit Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">National Natural Resources Conservation Foundation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Popcorn Promotion, Research, and Consumer Information Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Agricultural Reform and Improvement Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Agricultural Market Transition Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Canola and Rapeseed Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Food Security Commodity Reserve Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">National Kiwifruit Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">National Natural Resources Conservation Foundation Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Options Pilot Programs Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Popcorn Promotion, Research, and Consumer Information Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Agricultural Market Transition Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Canola and Rapeseed Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Commodity Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Food Security Commodity Reserve Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">National Kiwifruit Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">National Natural Resources Conservation Foundation Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Popcorn Promotion, Research, and Consumer Information Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the operation of certain agricultural programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300003" joined="1996-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400568" joined="1996-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1996-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="1996-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="402524" joined="1996-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400079" joined="1996-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403864" joined="1996-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400127" joined="1996-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="1996-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404869" joined="1996-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="1996-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1996-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="1996-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="1996-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-17">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-01-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 17.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-01-30">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01T19:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Roberts asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider, and that all points of order against the bill and against its consideration be waived; and that the previous question be considered as ordered without intervening motion except: 1. One hour of debate; 2. one amendment, if offered, by Rep. De La Garza, to be available for one hour.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01T19:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The Chair announced that the unanimous consent request was in order without the prior approval of the Majority and Minority leaders.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-09T11:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Agriculture. H. Rept. 104-462, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-09T11:36:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Ways and Means Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Feb. 9, 1996.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-09T11:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-02-09T11:37:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="223">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 223.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-02-20T11:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Goss notified the House that the Committee on Rules planned to begin consideration of a rule providing for the consideration of the bill H.R. 2854 on February 22, 1996. Members wishing to offer amendments to the bill should submit 55 copies of their amendment to the Rules Committee no later than 3 p.m. on Tuesday, February 26, 1996. Amendments should be written to conform to the text of the bill as reported by the Committee on Agriculture on Friday, February 9, 1996 (H. Rept. 104-462).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-27T22:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 366 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2854 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill and provides for consideration in the Committee of the Whole. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Agriculture now printed in the bill. Allpoints of order against the committee substitute shall be waived. No amendment to the substitute shall be in order except those specified in the report accompanying this resolution and shall not be subject to further amendment. Said amendments shall be debated in the order and manner specified. All points of order against said amendments shall be waived. It shall be in order at any time for the Chairman of the...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T13:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Volkmer asked unanimous consent that, during the consideration of the bill for amendment, it be in order to consider amendment No. 4 immediately after consideration of the Solomon/Dooley amendment No. 7. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T13:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 366 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T13:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 366.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1415-1490" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T13:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2854 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill and provides for consideration in the Committee of the Whole. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Agriculture now printed in the bill. All points of order against the committee substitute shall be waived. No amendment to the substitute shall be in order except those specified in the report accompanying this resolution and shall not be subject to further amendment. Said amendment amendments shall be debated in the order and manner specified. All points of order against said amendments shall be waived. It shall be in order at any time for the C...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T13:12:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 366 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T13:12:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable C.W. Bill Young to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T13:12:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with two hours of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T15:36:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Roberts en bloc amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T15:50:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T15:51:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the Frank (MA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T16:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366,the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Chabot amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T17:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the Shays amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T18:47:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Miller (FL) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T20:39:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the Solomon amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T21:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Roberts moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T21:59:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T21:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2854 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-28T22:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Traficant asked unanimous consent that, during the further consideration of the bill for amendment in the Committee of the Whole, Mr. Traficant be permitted to offer a substitute to the amendment made in order pursuant to H. Res. 366 (amendment No. 15.) Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T09:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1509-1575" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T09:04:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T09:04:00-05:00">
      <text>The Chair announced the order of business to be the consideration of the Boehlert amendment, which was pending before the Committee of the Whole when it rose on February 28, 1996.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T09:05:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the Boehlert amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T10:12:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with thirty minutes of debate on the Roth amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the Livingston amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Dooley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T11:38:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with twenty minutes of debate on the Foley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T12:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the order of the House of Wednesday, February 28, 1995, Mr. Traficant was recognize to offer a substitute to the amendment made in order by H. Res. 366.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T12:28:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded withten minutes of debate on the Traficant amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T12:33:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 366, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Stenholm amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T13:48:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2854.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T13:49:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T13:49:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T13:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Stenholm moved to recommit with instructions to Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T13:51:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T13:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Roberts raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Roberts stated that the motion includes provisions in the proposed amendment which would extend reauthorization for various nutrition programs and were beyond the scope of the bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T13:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T14:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Stenholm moved to recommit with instructions to Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T14:03:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T14:26:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 156 - 267 (Roll no. 41).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1575" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-02-29T14:46:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="42" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 270 - 155 (Roll no. 42).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T14:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-29T14:47:00-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2854.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-02-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="338">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 338.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-03-12">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1889-1900" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-12">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 1541 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1996-03-12" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-03-12">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment asks for a conference, appoints conferees Lugar; Dole; Helms; Cochran; McConnell; Craig; Leahy; Pryor; Heflin; Harkin; Conrad.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1899" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T14:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Roberts asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T15:00:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2304" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T15:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T15:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Peterson (MN) moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T15:00:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Peterson (MN) motion to instruct conferees on the part of the House to insist on the House language regarding a program extension of the Conservation Reserve Program through the year 2002.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T15:04:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T15:24:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 412 - 0 (Roll no. 67).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1575" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T15:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T15:25:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Roberts, Emerson, Gunderson, Ewing, Barrett (NE), Allard, Boehner, Pombo, de la Garza, Rose, Stenholm, Volkmer, Johnson (SD), and Condit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-14T15:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-15">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-20">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-22T14:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Roberts asked unanimous consent that managers on the part of the House have until midnight on March 25 to file a conference report on H.R. 2854. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-25T14:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 104-494 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2716-2841" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-25">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement and official papers held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2996-3004" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-27T21:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 393 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2854. Upon the adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider the conference report to accompany the bill H.R. 2854. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. S. Con. Res. 49 is hereby agreed to.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3150-3158" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:SENATE" datetime="1996-03-28" how="roll" result="pass" roll="57" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 74-26. Record Vote No: 57.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3100-3101" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28T23:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 393 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28T23:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Roberts brought up conference report H. Rept. 104-494 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 393.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-28T23:24:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 393, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-29T00:18:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-29T00:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1996-03-29T00:37:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="107" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by recorded vote: 318 - 89 (Roll no. 107).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/28/1996 H3169" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1996-03-29">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1996-04-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1996-04-04">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1996-04-04" type="public" number="104-127">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-127.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="366"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="393"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1205"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="sc" number="49"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1541"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1541"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="104" type="s" number="1541"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Acreage allotments"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Agribusiness"/>
    <term name="Agricultural agreements"/>
    <term name="Agricultural chemicals"/>
    <term name="Agricultural colleges"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural estimating and reporting"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pests"/>
    <term name="Agricultural policies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural surpluses"/>
    <term name="Agricultural taxes"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative agriculture"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Antidumping"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank directors"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Bank fraud"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Bank mergers"/>
    <term name="Bank reserves"/>
    <term name="Barley"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Botanical gardens"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Butter"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="CIS countries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Capital formation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Casualty insurance"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Cheese"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Commodity Credit Corporation"/>
    <term name="Commodity prices"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Conservation tillage"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Corn"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Dairy products"/>
    <term name="Debt agreements"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of Indians"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Emblems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection groups"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Estuarine ecology"/>
    <term name="Estuarine pollution"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Export subsidies"/>
    <term name="Export trading companies"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Farm manure"/>
    <term name="Farm produce"/>
    <term name="Farm production quotas"/>
    <term name="Farm tenancy"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Feed grain program"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial deregulation"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Fish culture"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Food stamp fraud"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Food supply"/>
    <term name="Food supply insurance"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade policy"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Forests"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Fruit and fruit trade"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Germplasm resources"/>
    <term name="Goats"/>
    <term name="Golden parachutes"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government internships"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grain"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Grassland ecology"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Grocery trade"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Honey"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydrocarbons"/>
    <term name="Import quotas"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Industrialization"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legumes"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Livestock industry"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Marketing orders"/>
    <term name="Marketing research"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Methyl bromide"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="New Zealand"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Oils and fats"/>
    <term name="Oilseeds"/>
    <term name="Options (Contract)"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Peanuts"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Plant diseases"/>
    <term name="Plant genetics"/>
    <term name="Plant quarantine"/>
    <term name="Plumbing"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Poultry industry"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Produce trade"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Protection of animals"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public television"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Reforestation"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Regulatory reform"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="Rice"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="Rural electrification"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Saline water conversion"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Seeds"/>
    <term name="Service academies"/>
    <term name="Sharecropping"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Small farms"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Sorghum"/>
    <term name="Soybeans"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Sugar"/>
    <term name="Sugar and sugar trade"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court decisions"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Swine"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Tropical forests"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Underemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban forestry"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Usury"/>
    <term name="Variable rate mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
    <term name="Vegetables and vegetable trade"/>
    <term name="Venture capital"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wheat"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wind erosion"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
    <term name="Wool"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h930"/>
    <amendment number="h931"/>
    <amendment number="h932"/>
    <amendment number="h933"/>
    <amendment number="h934"/>
    <amendment number="h935"/>
    <amendment number="h936"/>
    <amendment number="h937"/>
    <amendment number="h938"/>
    <amendment number="h939"/>
    <amendment number="h940"/>
    <amendment number="h941"/>
    <amendment number="h942"/>
    <amendment number="h943"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/25/1996--Conference report filed in House.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Agricultural Market Transition Act Subtitle A: Short Title, Purpose, and Definitions Subtitle B: Production Flexibility Contracts Subtitle C: Nonrecourse Marketing Assistance Loans and Loan Deficiency Payments Subtitle D: Other Commodities Subtitle E: Administration Subtitle F: Permanent Price Support Authority Subtitle G: Commission on 21st Century Production Agriculture Subtitle H: Miscellaneous Commodity Provisions Title II: Agricultural Trade Subtitle A: Amendments to Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 and Related Statutes Subtitle B: Amendments to Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 Subtitle C: Miscellaneous Agricultural Trade Provisions Title III: Conservation Subtitle A: Definitions Subtitle B: Highly Erodible Land Conservation Subtitle C: Wetland Conservation Subtitle D: Environmental Conservation Acreage Reserve Program Subtitle E: Conservation Funding and Administration Subtitle F: National Natural Resources Conservation Foundation Subtitle G: Forestry Subtitle H: Miscellaneous Conservation Provisions Title IV: Nutrition Assistance Title V: Agricultural Promotion Subtitle A: Commodity Promotion and Evaluation Subtitle B: Issuance of Orders for Promotion, Research, and Information Activities Regarding Agricultural Commodities Subtitle C: Canola and Rapeseed Subtitle D: Kiwifruit Subtitle E: Popcorn Subtitle F: Miscellaneous Title VI: Credit Subtitle A: Farm Ownership Loans Subtitle B: Operating Loans Subtitle C: Emergency Loans Subtitle D: Administrative Provisions Subtitle E: General Provisions Title VII: Rural Development Subtitle A: Amendments to the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 Subtitle B: Amendments to the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act Subtitle C: Amendments to the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 Subtitle D: Miscellaneous Rural Development Provisions Title VIII: Research, Extension, and Education Subtitle A: Modification and Extension of Activities Under 1977 Act Subtitle B: Modification and Extension of Activities Under 1990 Act Subtitle C: Repeal of Certain Activities and Authorities Subtitle D: Miscellaneous Research Provisions Subtitle E: Research Authority After Fiscal Year 1997 Title IX: Miscellaneous Subtitle A: Commercial Transportation of Equine for Slaughter Subtitle B: General Provisions Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 - Title I: Agricultural Market Transition Act - Subtitle A: Short Title, Purpose, and Definitions - Agricultural Market Transition Act - Defines specified terms for purposes of this title. Subtitle B: Production Flexibility Contracts - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary) to enter into flexibility contracts through crop year 2002 with eligible agricultural owners and producers with respect to conservation, wetlands, and planting flexibility requirements. (Sec. 113) Obligates contracts sums for FY 1996 through 2002, with specified amounts for wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, upland cotton, and rice (with an additional rice allocation). Sets forth: (1) annual payment rate factors; and (2) limitations for fruits and vegetables. Subtitle C: Nonrecourse Marketing Assistance Loans and Loan Deficiency Payments - Directs the Secretary to make nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for crop years 1996 through 2002 to producers of wheat, feed grains, upland cotton, extra long staple cotton, rice, and oilseeds. Sets forth loan rate, term, and repayment provisions. (Sec. 136) Directs the Secretary to establish special marketing loan provisions for upland cotton, including: (1) cotton user marketing certificates; (2) a special import quota; and (3) a limited global import quota. (Sec. 137) Directs the Secretary to make FY 1996 through 2002 recourse loans for high moisture feed grains and seed cotton. Subtitle D: Other Commodities - Chapter 1: Dairy - Sets forth 1996 through 1999 milk price support levels. Provides for: (1) allocation of butter and nonfat dry milk purchase prices; and (2) 1995 and 1996 assessment refunds. (Sec. 142) Establishes a recourse loan program for commercial processors of eligible dairy products. (Sec. 143) Directs the Secretary to consolidate Federal milk marketing orders, including the inclusion of California as a separate marketing order. (Sec. 145) Limits maximum State milk manufacturing allowances. (Sec. 147) Declares congressional consent, with specified conditions, to the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact entered into by Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island, and Vermont (with provision for additional entry by Delaware, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Maryland, and Virginia). (Sec. 148) Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to extend the dairy export incentive program through 2002. (Sec. 149) Directs the Secretary to assist the dairy industry to establish an export trading company, and designate an entity if the industry is unable to establish one. Chapter 2: Peanuts and Sugar - Directs the Secretary to: (1) make nonrecourse loans available to quota peanut producers at $610 per ton and to additional peanut producers at appropriate rates; (2) make related warehouse storage loans available; (3) provide for marketing area pools for quota and additional peanuts, with separate pools for New Mexico-produced Valencia peanuts; (4) require that all domestic and export peanuts comply with specified quality standards; and (5) provide for a nonrefundable marketing assessment. Provides that: (1) net gains from each marketing pool shall be distributed only to pool producers; and (2) losses in quota pools shall be covered using a specified order of priority. Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 with regard to the peanut program to: (1) extend peanut quota provisions through crop year 2002; (2) eliminate the minimum national poundage quota; (3) eliminate seed peanuts from the national poundage quota determination; (4) create a temporary quota allocation for seed peanuts; (5) eliminate the Texas increased quota allocation; (6) permit under specified conditions quota sale, lease, or transfer to any county within a State in the fall or spring; (7) prohibit quotas to be held by public entities and nonproducer nonresident quota holders; and (8) authorize transfers of additional peanuts to the quota pool where natural disasters prevented quota poundage harvesting and marketing. (Sec. 156) Directs the Secretary to make recourse loans available to processors of domestically grown sugarcane and sugar beets at 18 cents per pound and 22.9 cents per pound, respectively. Requires reductions if foreign subsidy reductions exceed Uruguay Round Agreement commitments. Sets loan terms at the earlier of nine months or the end of the fiscal year, with supplemental loans available for loans made in the last three months of a fiscal year. Authorizes the Secretary to provide nonrecourse loans when the imported tariff rate quota for sugar imports exceeds 1,500,000 short tons raw value. Sets forth first processor sugarcane and sugar beet marketing assessment rates for FY 1996 through 2003, which shall be collected monthly and remitted to the Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC). Sets forth enforcement and reporting provisions. Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 to repeal marketing allotment provisions. Makes this section (other than assessment provisions) applicable to the 1996 through 2002 crops of sugarcane and sugar beets. Subtitle E: Administration - Amends the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act to place certain limits on CCC expenditures. (Sec. 163) Increases the CCC interest rate applicable to agricultural commodity loans by 100 basis points. (Sec. 164) States that unless fraudulently obtained, producers shall not be liable for loan deficiencies under this title. Subtitle F: Permanent Price Support Authority - Repeals and suspends specified price support provisions under the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 and the Agricultural Act of 1949. Subtitle G: Commission on 21st Century Production Agriculture - Establishes the Commission on 21st Century Production Agriculture which shall assess: (1) the changes in U.S. production agriculture resulting from this Act; and (2) the current and future condition of U.S. production agriculture and the appropriate role of the Government. Terminates the Commission upon submission of a required report. Subtitle H: Miscellaneous Commodity Provisions - Authorizes the Secretary to conduct an options pilot program for supported commodities through December 31, 2002. Repeals the Options Pilot Program Act of 1990. Directs the Secretary to provide risk management education. (Sec. 193) Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to authorize the Secretary, in consultation with insurance providers, to offer catastrophic risk protection in a State (or portion of a State) through local Department of Agriculture (Department) offices if sufficient coverage is otherwise unavailable. Provides for transfer of current policies to private insurers. Establishes a crop insurance pilot project. (Sec. 194) Amends the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to establish in the Department (as an independent office) the Office of Risk Management which shall have jurisdiction over the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation and related crop insurance matters. Obligates FY 1996 funding for the Office from specified appropriations for the Consolidated Farm Services Agency. (Sec. 195) Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to establish a revenue insurance pilot program. (Sec. 196) Directs the Secretary to operate a noninsured crop disaster assistance program through the Consolidated Farm Service Agency for food or fiber crops not covered by Federal crop insurance catastrophic risk protection. Title II: Agricultural Trade - Subtitle A: Amendments to Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 and Related Statutes - Amends the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 (Public Law 480) to include private entities within the scope of foreign agricultural assistance under such Act. Revises assistance priorities. (Sec. 203) Gives authority for project development and implementation to U.S. agricultural trade organizations (entities which promote the export and sale of U.S. commodities but do not directly profit from the specific commodity sales). (Sec. 204) Eliminates the minimum ten-year payment period. Reduces the discretionary payment deferment period from seven years to five years. (Sec. 206) Repeals the value-added food partial waiver of repayment provision. (Sec. 207) Prohibits the Administrator (Administrator) of the Agency for International Development (AID) from denying nonemergency assistance to an eligible organization in a country in which AID has no presence or is not involved in such country's development plan. Increases maximum annual set-asides for eligible organizations. (Sec. 208) Expands foreign currency local sales or barter arrangements to include countries in the same region as the recipient country. Increases minimum local sales levels from ten percent to fifteen percent. (Sec. 209) Extends minimum agricultural assistance and nonemergency assistance authorities through FY 2002 (at current FY 1995 levels). Prohibits waiver of such assistance minimums before the beginning of a fiscal year. (Sec. 210) Extends the Food Aid Consultative Group through December 31, 2002. Revises membership provisions. Requires meetings with the Administrator at least twice per year. (Sec. 212) Revises commodity determination provisions. (Sec. 214) Authorizes multi-year agreements to be made available under programs of: (1) agricultural commodity sales to developing countries; and (2) commodity donations to least developed countries. Requires multi-year contracts to be made available for the commodity donation program. (Sec. 215) Authorizes (currently requires) the CCC to acquire and make commodities available under such Act. Includes Canadian transshipment expenses within authorized costs. (Sec. 216) Includes commodity donations to least developed country programs within specified freight procurement provisions. (Sec. 217) Extends Public Law 480 sales or assistance authority through December 31, 2002. (Sec. 218) Repeals provisions regarding: (1) regulations; and (2) independent program evaluations. (Sec. 220) Eliminates certain set-asides for the credit sales and commodity donation to least developed countries programs. Revises specified transfer of funds provisions. (Sec. 222) Establishes a five-country micronutrient fortification pilot program. Terminates such program on September 30, 2002. (Sec. 224) Extends through FY 2002 and increases obligations for the farmer-to-farmer program. (Sec. 225) Amends the Agricultural Act of 1980 to cite title III of such Act as the Food Security Commodity Reserve Act of 1996. Replaces the food security wheat reserve with a commodity wheat reserve made up of not more than 4,000,000 metric tons of wheat, corn, rice, or sorghum to be used for emergency food assistance or urgent humanitarian relief. Permits: (1) U.S. processing of commodities; (2) commodity exchanges, including powered milk and vegetable oil; and (3) use of the CCC. Terminates program authority on September 30, 2002. (Sec. 226) Amends the Food Programs Act of 1985 to extend the Food for Progress program through FY 2002. (Sec. 228) Amends the Mutual Security Act of 1954 to repeal certain export sale foreign currency use provisions. Subtitle B: Amendments to Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 - Amends the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to direct the Secretary to develop an agricultural export strategy that: (1) takes into consideration new market opportunities such as those created by the North American Free Trade Agreement and the Uruguay Round Agreements; and (2) identifies priority markets. Directs the President to identify in the annual budget each overseas office of the Foreign Agricultural Service that provides U.S. exporters with priority market assistance. (Sec. 243) Amends the export credit guarantee program to: (1) provide for U.S. supplier credits; (2) set forth additional (discretionary) criteria for recipient eligibility; (3) eliminate the prohibition on CCC guarantee of foreign agricultural components; (4) permit third country bank credit guarantees; (5) revise processed and high-value products set-asides, including elimination of specified set-asides for the independent states of the former Soviet Union; and (6) extend program authority through FY 2002. (Sec. 244) Extends the market access program through FY 2002. Restricts the use of funds for non-generic activities. (Sec. 245) Directs the CCC to make funds available for FY 1996 through 2002 for the export enhancement program. (Sec. 246) Requires exporter-participants in the credit guarantee, market promotion, or export enhancement programs to maintain commodity arrival certificates. (Sec. 247) Eliminates certain nonprogram transaction compliance provisions. (Sec. 249) Establishes a trade compensation and assistance program which shall become effective if a unilateral suspension of U.S. agricultural exports to a country is not joined by other countries within a specified time. (Sec. 250) Authorizes the Foreign Agricultural Service to provide agricultural technical assistance and training. (Sec. 252) Establishes the foreign market development cooperator program. Authorizes FY 1996 through 2002 appropriations. Subtitle C: Miscellaneous Agricultural Trade Provisions - Establishes the Edward R. Madigan United States Agricultural Export Excellence Award. (Sec. 262) Amends the Tobacco Adjustment Act of 1983 to repeal specified tobacco reporting requirements. (Sec. 263) Amends the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1990 and the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988 to repeal certain export enhancement provisions (support level adjustment and triggered marketing loans). (Sec. 265) Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to repeal the "debt-for-health-and protection swap" (assistance for commercial debt swap). (Sec. 269) Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to revise certain congressional findings regarding U.S. trade policy and trade negotiations. (Sec. 271) Repeals to Agricultural Aid and Trade Missions Act. (Sec. 272) Amends the Agricultural Act of 1954 to eliminate certain agricultural attache reporting requirements. (Sec. 273) Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to repeal certain world livestock market price information requirements. (Sec. 274) Amends the Agricultural Act of 1956 to repeal: (1) certain CCC surplus stock reduction reporting requirements; and (2) certain surplus extra-long staple cotton sale requirements. (Sec. 277) Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to rename the program of promotion of agricultural exports to emerging democracies as the program of promotion of agricultural exports to emerging markets (as defined by this Act). Authorizes additional sums of direct credits or export credit guarantees for FY 1996 through 2002. Extends the Agricultural Fellowship Program through 2002. (Sec. 279) Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act to direct the Secretary to establish labeling standards for domestic and imported sheepmeat (lamb and mutton). (Sec. 280) Amends Federal law to repeal certain provisions with respect to sugar-related assistance for CBI (Caribbean Basin Initiative) beneficiary countries and the Philippines. (Sec. 281) Expresses the sense of the Congress with respect to multilateral disciplines on credit guarantees, including the composition of disciplines on the practices of foreign government trading entities, such as the Australian and Canadian Wheat Boards, and the Australian and New Zealand Dairy Boards. Title III: Conservation - Subtitle A: Definitions - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to define specified terms applicable to highly erodible cropland conservation. Subtitle B: Highly Erodible Land Conservation - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to revise the highly erodible land conservation program, including: (1) program ineligibility; (2) guideline technical requirements; (3) variance procedures; and (4) good faith exemptions. (Sec. 316) Requires notice of possible violations to be provided during on-site inspections. (Sec. 317) Directs the Secretary to conduct a wind erosion estimation pilot project. Subtitle C: Wetland Conservation - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to revise the wetland conservation program, including: (1) program ineligibility; and (2) wetland delineation. Subtitle D: Environmental Conservation Acreage Reserve Program - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to revise and extend the environmental conservation acreage reserve program (ECARP) through 2002. States that ECARP shall consist of: (1) the conservation reserve program; (2) the wetlands reserve program; and (3) the environmental quality incentives program. Considers prior conservation and wetlands program enrollments to be ECARP enrollments. Directs the Secretary to designate conservation priority areas. (Sec. 332) Extends the conservation reserve program through 2002. Reduces maximum acreage enrollment. Authorizes owner or operator early contract termination (with exceptions). (Sec. 333) Extends the wetlands reserve program. Caps maximum acreage enrollment and revises enrollment methods. (Sec. 334) Establishes an environmental quality incentives program for FY 1996 through 2002 to combine into a single program the functions of: (1) the agricultural conservation program; (2) the Great Plains conservation program; (3) the water quality incentives program; and (4) the Colorado River Basin salinity control program. (Sec. 335) Directs the Secretary to establish conservation farm option pilot programs for producers of wheat, feed grains, cotton, and rice enrolled in the agricultural market transition program. Obligates specified FY 1997 through 2002 appropriations for the program. (Sec. 336) Amends specified Acts to make conforming amendments (including elimination of certain program authorities) with respect to: (1) the agricultural conservation program; (2) the Great Plains conservation program; (3) the Colorado River Basin salinity control program; (4) the rural environmental conservation program; (5) other specified conservation and resource conservation programs; and (6) the agricultural water quality incentive programs. Subtitle E: Conservation Funding and Administration - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to extend funding through FY 2002 for: (1) mandatory expenses; and (2) the environmental quality incentives program, including livestock operations. Subtitle F: National Natural Resources Conservation Foundation - National Natural Resources Conservation Foundation Act - Establishes the National Natural Resources Conservation Foundation as a conservation-related nonprofit corporation. Authorizes FY 1997 through 1999 appropriations. Subtitle G: Forestry - Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to authorize FY 1996 through 2002 appropriations for the Office of International Forestry. (Sec. 373) Amends the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 to: (1) authorize FY 1996 through 2003 appropriations for the forestry incentives program; and (2) authorize a forest legacy grant program. Subtitle H: Miscellaneous Conservation Provisions - Amends the Agriculture and Food Act of 1981 to authorize FY 1996 through 2002 appropriations for the resource conservation and development program. (Sec. 385) Authorizes the Secretary during FY 1996 through 2002 to enter into flood risk reduction contracts with operators of frequently flooded farm areas. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 386) Directs the Secretary to establish a voluntary program of private grazing and conservation assistance through the Natural Resources Conservation Service. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 387) Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) a wildlife habitat incentives program; and (2) a farmland protection program. (Sec. 389) Establishes an 18-month moratorium on any Forest Service bypass flow decisions. Provides for the establishment of a Water Rights Task Force to study Federal water rights issues. (Sec. 390) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct (Florida) Everglades ecosystem restoration activities. Establishes in the Treasury the Everglades Restoration Account. (Sec. 391) Directs the Secretary to provide agricultural air quality research oversight. Title IV: Nutrition Assistance - Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to extend through FY 2002 the following food stamp programs and provisions: (1) the allocation among State agencies of funds authorized for employment and training programs under the Act; (2) authorization to conduct pilot or experimental projects; (3) the making of grants to increase program participation; (4) the authorization of appropriations; and (5) the Puerto Rico food assistance block grant. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) make payments to American Samoa for each of FY 1996 through 2002 financing 100 percent of expenditures for a nutrition assistance program extended under certain technical assistance provisions; and (2) make grants for community food projects. (Sec. 402) Reauthorizes, through FY 2002, the following programs: (1) the commodity distribution program and the commodity supplemental food program (allowing 20 percent of funds carried over to be available for administrative expenses) under the Agriculture and Consumer Protection Act of 1973; (2) the emergency food assistance program under the Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983; (3) the soup kitchens and food banks program under the Hunger Prevention Act of 1988; and (4) surplus commodity processing agreements with private companies. Title V: Agricultural Promotion - Subtitle A: Commodity Promotion and Evaluation - Provides for periodic evaluation of each industry-funded generic agricultural commodity program's promotional effectiveness. Subtitle B: Issuance of Orders for Promotion, Research, and Information Activities Regarding Agricultural Commodities - Commodity Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 1996 - Authorizes the Secretary to issue agricultural producer, handler, and importer commodity marketing orders. Authorizes appropriations. Subtitle C: Canola and Rapeseed - Canola and Rapeseed Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information Act - Directs the Secretary to issue an order to finance and implement a program of canola and rapeseed research, promotion, market development, and consumer information. Requires: (1) such order to establish a National Canola and Rapeseed Board; and (2) producer referenda. Authorizes appropriations. Subtitle D: Kiwifruit - National Kiwifruit Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information Act - Directs the Secretary to issue an order to finance and implement a program of kiwifruit research, promotion, market development, and consumer information. Requires: (1) such order to establish a National Kiwifruit Board; and (2) producer referenda. Authorizes appropriations. Subtitle E: Popcorn - Popcorn Promotion, Research, and Consumer Information Act - Directs the Secretary to issue an order to finance and implement a program of popcorn research, promotion, market development, and consumer information. Requires: (1) such order to establish a Popcorn Board; and (2) producer referenda. Authorizes appropriations. Subtitle F: Miscellaneous - Amends the Honey Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information Act of subject honey producers to certain recordkeeping requirements. Title VI: Credit - Subtitle A: Farm Ownership Loans - Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to revise direct farm ownership loan provisions regarding: (1) recipient eligibility; (2) purposes and preferences; (3) hazard insurance requirements; (4) interest rates for joint financings; and (5) insurance of loans (full faith and credit of the United States). (Sec. 606) Establishes specified maximum guarantees for loans, refinanced loans, and beginning farmer loans. Subtitle B: Operating Loans - Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to revise farm operating loan provisions regarding: (1) recipient eligibility; (2) purposes; (3) hazard insurance requirements; and (4) guaranteed assistance eligibility period. (Sec. 613) Repeals provisions regarding: (1) loan participation; (2) hazard insurance requirements; and (3) special assistance for beginning farms and ranchers. (Sec. 614) Authorizes line-of-credit loans. Subtitle C: Emergency Loans - Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to revise emergency loan provisions regarding: (1) hazard insurance requirements; (2) maximum indebtedness; (3) loan terms; and (4) insurance (repealed). Subtitle D: Administrative Provisions - Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to: (1) authorize (through FY 2002) the Secretary to enter into farm loan servicing contracts with eligible financial institutions; (2) authorize use of private collection agencies; (3) reduce loan service notice requirements; (4) revise the definition of veteran for loan preference purposes; (5) set forth property sale provisions; (6) authorize (with set-asides) specified FY 1996 through 2002 loan and guarantee appropriations; (7) reduce the homestead property application period; (8) revise cash flow margin and loan termination provisions; (9) require implementation of certain target participation rates in accordance with a specified Supreme Court holding (Adarand Constructors, Inc. v. Federico Pena, Secretary of Transportation); (10) require partial interest payments by delinquent borrowers as a condition of loan servicing; (11) prohibit direct operating loans to delinquent borrowers and limit borrowing ability of persons who have received debt forgiveness; and (12) require the Secretary to conduct a rural credit study. Subtitle E: General Provisions - Makes conforming amendments to the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act. Title VII: Rural Development - Subtitle A: Amendments to the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 - Chapter I: General Provisions - Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to repeal: (1) the rural investment partnerships program; and (2) the water and waste facility loan and the rural wastewater circuit rider programs. (Sec. 704) Revises the current rural distance learning and medical link programs into programs to finance the construction of facilities and systems to provide rural areas with telemedicine and distance learning services. Authorizes: (1) loans to rural Electrification Act of 1936 borrowers; and (2) financial assistance to other facilities to provide necessary services. Sets forth priority, fund use, and administrative provisions. Authorizes FY 1996 through 2002 appropriations. (Sec. 705) Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to eliminate: (1) the authorization of appropriations limitation on rural technology grants; (2) the Bureau of the Census requirement to monitor rural economic progress; (3) the Office of Technology Assessment requirement to analyze rural computer access to a national library; and (4) a grant project for rural health infrastructure improvement. Chapter 2: Alternative Agricultural Research and Commercialization - Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to replace the Alternative Agricultural Research and Commercialization Center with an Alternative Agricultural Research and Commercialization Corporation (Alternative Corporation) as an agency within the Department of Agriculture. Sets forth operating and administrative provisions. Authorizes FY 1996 through 2002 appropriations for the Alternative Agricultural Research and Commercialization Revolving Fund. (Sec. 729) Authorizes executive agencies to establish procurement preferences and set-asides for alternative agricultural research and commercialization products. (Sec. 730) Directs the Alternative Corporation to develop a five- year business plan and feasibility study. Subtitle B: Amendments to the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act - Chapter I: General Provisions - Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to increase the amount of grants authorized to be made by the Secretary for water and waste facilities. Revises the definition of "rural" and "rural area," for the purposes of eligibility for grants and loans for such facilities, to limit eligibility to only those cities, towns, or unincorporated areas with populations of no more than 10,000. Revises water pollution control funding standards. Revises the purposes for which the Secretary may make rural business development grants to include training in interactive communications technologies to develop international trade. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1996 through 2002. Eliminates provisions for: (1) grants to volunteer fire departments; and (2) loans financing transmission facilities for publicly owned and operated rural electric systems receiving bulk power from specified Department of the Interior power administrations. Increases the maximum amount of appropriated funds to be reserved for grants to nonprofit organizations furnishing technical assistance and training to associations providing water and waste facility services. (Sec. 742) Revises population and income restrictions for emergency community water assistance grants. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 743) Eliminates the program of emergency community water assistance grants for smallest rural communities. (Sec. 744) Revises provisions regarding the Agricultural Credit Insurance Fund and the Rural Development Insurance Fund to eliminate the Secretary's authority to utilize the Fund to make, sell, and insure loans which could be insured under the real estate loan provisions whenever the Secretary has reasonable assurance that they can be sold without undue delay. (Sec. 747) Revises rural industrialization provisions, including: (1) authorizing grants to aid industries to adjust to terminated agricultural programs or increased foreign competition; (2) replacing subterminal facilities loans with a rural cooperative grant program (authorization of appropriations through FY 2002); and (3) authorizing loan guarantees to family farmers for cooperative stock purchases. (Sec. 748) Authorizes the Secretary, with respect to agricultural credit, to compromise and adjust debts and claims arising from loan guarantees. Requires related notification of the Attorney General. (Sec. 749) Repeals agricultural real estate loan provisions regarding: (1) issuance of notes to make direct loans; (2) the Farmers Home Administration direct loan account; (3) sale and assignment of notes and mortgages in such account; and (4) allocation among States of direct loans. (Sec. 750) Repeals the requirement for the Secretary's annual congressional testimony regarding the budget for agricultural credit programs. (Sec. 751) Exempts utility line loans from the prohibition on use of loans to manipulate a wetland. (Sec. 752) Establishes a program under which the Secretary may guarantee rural development loans made by a certified lender. (Sec. 753) Repeals provisions regarding: (1) delivery of certain rural development programs; (2) State rural economic review panels; and (3) allocation and transfer of loans and guarantees. (Sec. 756) Authorizes grants for water systems for rural and Native villages in Alaska. Authorizes FY 1996 through 2002 appropriations. (Sec. 759) Establishes: (1) a National Sheep Industry Improvement Center; and (2) a National Sheep Industry Improvement Center Revolving Fund in the Treasury. Chapter 2: Rural Community Advancement Program - Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to establish a rural community advancement program of grants, loans, guarantees, and other assistance to local communities and federally recognized Indian tribes. Establishes in the Treasury a Rural Development Trust Fund. Authorizes a rural venture capital demonstration program. (Sec. 763) Authorizes a community facilities grant program. Subtitle C: Amendments to the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 - Amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to replace loan and loan allocation provisions with an authorization of appropriations for activities under such Act. (Sec. 773) Eliminates loan authority for: (1) electrical plants and transmission lines; and (2) electrical and plumbing equipment. (Sec. 778) Prohibits restrictions on water and waste facility services to electric customers. (Sec. 780) Repeals: (1) the privatization program; and (2) the Rural Business Incubator Fund. Subtitle D: Miscellaneous Rural Development Provisions - Amends the Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act and the Watershed Protection and Flood Prevention Act to revise interest rate formulas. (Sec. 792) Amends the Rural Development Act of 1972 to repeal the grant program for financially stressed farmers and rural families. (Sec. 793) Establishes in the Treasury a Fund for Rural America for rural research, development, and housing. (Sec. 794) Amends the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to rename the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Economic and Community Development as the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development. Title VIII: Research, Extension, and Education - Subtitle A: Modification and Extension of Activities under 1977 Act - Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to replace the National Agricultural Research and Extension Users Advisory Board with the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board, which shall remain in existence until September 30, 2002. (Sec. 804) Directs the Secretary to monitor and evaluate information technology systems. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 805) Makes university research foundations eligible for food and agricultural sciences education grants and fellowships. Extends program authorization of appropriations through FY 1997. Directs the Secretary to make grants to public secondary schools and associate's degree institutions for agriscience and agribusiness education. (Sec. 806) Authorizes appropriations through FY 1997 for research grants on the production and marketing of alcohols and industrial hydrocarbons from agricultural and forest products. (Sec. 807) Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to eligible policy research centers for research and education programs concerning public policies' effect on agriculture, environment, and consumers. Authorizes FY 1996 and 1997 appropriations. (Sec. 808) Authorizes the Secretary to make grants for human nutrition and health promotion research. Authorizes FY 1996 and 1997 appropriations. (Replaces the current provision providing for a Southeast food science center.) Directs the Secretary to conduct a pilot research program to combine medical and agricultural research (including cancer and heart disease research). Authorizes FY 1997 appropriations. (Sec. 811) Extends authorization of appropriations through FY 1997 for: (1) animal health and disease research (includes aquaculture species within such program); and (2) regional and national animal health and disease research (includes food safety within such program). (Sec. 813) Extends authorization of appropriations through FY 1997 for: (1) grants to upgrade agricultural and food science facilities at 1890 land-grant colleges; and (2) national research and training centers. (Sec. 815) Authorizes the Secretary to make grants for programs serving Hispanic-serving institutions (as defined by this Act). Authorizes FY 1997 appropriations. (Sec. 817) Extends authorization of appropriations through FY 1997 for: (1) international agricultural research and extension; (2) agricultural research programs; (3) extension education; (4) aquaculture programs (includes ornamental fish in such programs); and (5) rangeland research. (Sec. 819) Extends the supplemental and alternative crops research program. (Eliminates such program's pilot status.) Subtitle B: Modification and Extension of Activities Under 1990 Act - Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to extend authority or extend authorization of appropriations through FY 1997 for: (1) the water quality research, education, and coordination program; (2) the national genetics resources program; (3) the national agricultural weather information system; (4) livestock product safety and inspection programs; (5) the plant genome mapping program; (6) agricultural research programs; (7) national centers for agriculture product quality research; (8) the assistive technology program for farmers with disabilities; (9) national rural information center clearinghouse; and (10) the global climate change program. (Sec. 839) Provides for the establishment of a red meat safety research center. Subtitle C: Repeal of Certain Activities and Authorities - Amends specified Acts to repeal authorities for the following: (1) Joint Council on Food and Agricultural Sciences; (2) National Agricultural Research and Extension Users Advisory Board; (3) Animal Health Science Research Advisory Board; (4) resident instruction program at 1890 land-grant colleges; (5) State grants for international trade centers; (6) Rangeland Research Advisory Board; (7) composting research and extension program; (8) agricultural chemical handling program; (9) National Sustainable Agriculture Advisory Council; (10) research and grant program regarding production, processing, and storage of agricultural products; (11) plant and animal pest and disease control program; (12) Commission on agricultural research facilities; (13) special grant to study agricultural trade restraints; (14) pilot project to coordinate food and nutrition education programs; (15) rural economic development demonstration areas; (16) global climate change advisory committee; (17) certain rural development and research grants; (18) human nutrition research grants; (19) 1890 land-grant extension upgrades; and (20) Indian subsistence farming demonstration program. Subtitle D: Miscellaneous Research Provisions - Amends the Critical Agricultural Materials Act to extend the authorization of appropriations through FY 1997 for critical agricultural materials programs. (Sec. 882) Amends the Smith-Lever Act to make funding under such Act available to 1890 land-grant colleges, including Tuskegee University. (Sec. 884) Amends the Research Facilities Act to revise agricultural research facilities provisions. Defines "agricultural research facility" and "food and agricultural sciences." Directs the Secretary to establish the Strategic Planning Task Force to develop a ten-year agricultural research facilities plan. Authorizes FY 1996 and 1997 appropriations. (Sec. 885) Amends the Competitive, Special, and Facilities Research Grant Act to: (1) extend authorization of appropriations through FY 1997 for competitive research grants; and (2) increase set- asides for mission-linked systems research. (Sec. 887) Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act Amendments of 1981 to extend authorization of appropriations through FY 1997 for the dairy goat research program. (Sec. 888) Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to authorize the Secretary to make grants for eradication and control of brown citrus aphid and citrus tristeza virus. (Sec. 889) Amends Federal law to transfer the fish research and experimentation program from the Department of the Interior to the Department of Agriculture (Department). Designates (and transfers to the Department) the Fish Farming Experimental Laboratory Stuttgart, and Kelso, Arkansas, as the Stuttgart National Aquaculture Research Centers. (Sec. 890) Amends Federal law to authorize the National Arboretum to grant concessions, charge fees, license its name and logo, and accept voluntary services. (Sec. 891) Transfers the Southeastern Fish Culture Laboratory in Marion, Alabama, to the Department from the Department of the Interior. Designates it as the Claude Harris National Aquacultural Research Center. (Sec. 892) Provides for the agricultural use of remote sensing data. (Sec. 893) States that it is the sense of the Senate that the Department should continue to make methyl bromide alternative research and extension activities a high priority. Subtitle E: Research Authority After Fiscal Year 1997 - Authorizes, subject to availability of appropriations, FY 1998 through 2002 appropriations for agriculture research, extension, and education activities. Title IX: Miscellaneous - Subtitle A: Commercial Transportation of Equine for Slaughter - Authorizes the Secretary to issue guidelines for the regulation of commercial transportation of equine for slaughter. Subtitle B: General Provisions - Amends Federal law to direct the Secretary, in the case of an agricultural quarantine of a State entirely comprised of islands, to give consideration to passenger and commercial movement. (Sec. 912) Amends the Cotton Statistics and Estimates Act to: (1) extend cotton classification services authority through FY 2002; and (2) require that all cotton classing office locations in Missouri as of January 1, 1996, be maintained until at least January 1, 1999. (Sec. 913) Amends the Plant Variety Protection Act to provide plant variety protection for certain tuber propagated plant varieties. (Sec. 914) Amends the Swine Health Protection Act to authorize termination of State primary enforcement responsibility under such Act. (Sec. 915) Amends the George Washington National Forest Mount Pleasant Scenic Area Act to redesignate the George Washington National Forest Mount Pleasant Scenic Area (in Virginia) as the Mount Pleasant National Scenic Area. (Sec. 916) Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to extend authorization of appropriations through FY 2002 for the pseudorabies eradication program. (Sec. 918) Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act to establish in the Department the Safe Meat and Poultry Inspection Panel. (Sec. 920) Authorizes the Secretary to pay certain overseas tort claims. (Sec. 921) States that the Graduate School of the Department of Agriculture shall operate as a nonappropriated fund instrumentality. (Sec. 922) Sets forth Department student internship provisions. (Sec. 923) Sets forth conveyance of personal and real property provisions regarding: (1) certain educational institutions; (2) White Oak Cemetery, Washington County, Arkansas; and (3) sale of specified land by the University of Arkansas. (Sec. 926) Designates a specified Agricultural Research Service facility near Booneville, Arkansas, as the Dale Bumpers Small Farms Research Center. (Sec. 927) Authorizes the Secretary to obligate funds for road improvements at the Beltsville Agriculture Research Center, Maryland, as part of the Department of Agriculture Washington Area Strategic Space Plan.</summary>
</bill>
