<bill session="106" type="h" number="101" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protect American Jobs Through the Foreign Trade Antitrust Improvements Amendments Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Sherman Act and the Federal Trade Commission Act with respect to commerce with foreign nations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1999-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E51"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
Protect American Jobs Through the Foreign Trade Antitrust Improvements Amendments Act of 1999 - Amends the Sherman and Federal Trade Commission Acts with respect to their application to certain conduct (subject to antitrust prohibitions) and to methods of unfair competition involving commerce with foreign nations only where such conduct or methods have a direct, substantial, and reasonably foreseeable effect on export commerce with foreign nations of a person engaged in such commerce in the United States. Declares that such Acts shall apply only for injury to export business in the United States (as in current law), and without regard to the effect of specified conduct on U.S. consumers. Declares that a determination of whether the effect of such conduct is substantial may be made solely with reference to the product or type of product affected by the conduct and the geographical area in which such conduct occurs.</summary>
</bill>
