<bill session="106" type="h" number="439" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-09T17:47:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-02-09T17:47:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Paperwork Reduction bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Paperwork Elimination Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, popularly known as the Paperwork Reduction Act, to minimize the burden of Federal paperwork demands upon small businesses, educational and nonprofit institutions, Federal contractors, State and local governments, and other persons through the sponsorship and use of alternative information technologies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400587" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1999-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="1999-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="1999-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400609" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400393" joined="1999-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="1999-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-02">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-02">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-02-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-02-08T15:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 106-11, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-09T14:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Kelly moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-09T14:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H494-496, H525" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-09T14:39:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-09T14:59:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-09T17:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-02-09T17:47:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="13" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 413 - 0 (Roll no. 13).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-02-09T17:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO01" subcommittee="National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriate technology"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Information policy"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/1999--Introduced.
Paperwork Elimination Act of 1999 - Amends the Paperwork Reduction Act to require the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to: (1) specifically promote the acquisition and use of alternative electronic information technologies that provide for electronic submission, maintenance, or disclosure of information as a substitute for paper and for the use and acceptance of electronic signatures; and (2) provide within a required information resources strategic management plan a description of progress in providing for the acquisition and use of such technologies as a substitute for paper and for the use and acceptance of electronic signatures. Requires each Federal agency to: (1) ensure that each information collection provides to persons required to submit information the option to use electronic submission, maintenance, or disclosure of information; (2) use information technologies that provide for electronic submission, maintenance, or disclosure of information to reduce burden and improve data quality, agency efficiency, and responsiveness to the public; and (3) publish a description of how respondents may electronically submit, maintain, or disclose the information to be collected. Requires the Director to report to the Congress on the extent to which Federal agencies reduced the collection of information burden on small businesses and other persons through the use of electronic submission, maintenance, or disclosure of information as a substitute for the use of paper.</summary>
</bill>
