<bill session="108" type="h" number="4522" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Space Station Independent Safety Commission Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of an independent, Presidentially-appointed Commission to assess the safety of the International Space Station and its crew.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H837"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Astronautics"/>
    <term name="Astronauts"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in astronautics"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Sabotage"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space stations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2004--Introduced.
International Space Station Independent Safety Commission Act of 2004 - Directs the President to establish, an independent, non-partisan Commission within the executive branch to discover and assess any vulnerabilities of the International Space Station (ISS) that could lead to its destruction, compromise the health of its crew, or necessitate its premature abandonment. Provides for the Commission to consist of 15 members, including the Chairman of the National Transportation Safety Board. Prohibits: (1) any Commission member from having or having pending a contractual relationship with the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA); and (2) the President from appointing any individual as a Commission member who has a current or former relationship with the Administrator of NASA that the President determines would constitute a conflict of interest. Instructs the Commission to undertake the following tasks: (1) catalog threats to and vulnerabilities of the ISS, including sabotage or terrorist attack; (2) make recommendations for corrective actions; and (3) provide any additional findings or recommendations considered by the Commission to be important, whether or not they are related to ISS safety. Sets forth the powers and other authorities of the Commission. Directs the NASA Engineering and Safety Center to provide data and technical support as requested by the Commission. Requires the appropriate Federal agencies or departments to cooperate with the Commission in expeditiously providing appropriate security clearances to the Commission members and staff. Prohibits any person from being provided access to classified information under this Act without the appropriate security clearances. Allows the Commission to submit interim reports containing findings, conclusions, and recommendations for corrective actions to the President and Congress. Terminates the Commission and all the authorities of this Act with respect to the Commission after the Commission's final report containing findings, conclusions, and recommendations for such actions is submitted to the President and Congress and made available to the public. Directs the NASA Administrator to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences for a review of compliance with the Commission's recommendations and to transmit a report to Congress containing the results of such review.</summary>
</bill>
