<bill session="105" type="h" number="4851" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-20T20:10:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-20T20:10:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Iran Nuclear Proliferation Prevention Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Iran Nuclear Proliferation Prevention Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To withhold voluntary proportional assistance for programs and projects of the International Atomic Energy Agency relating to the development and completion of the Bushehr nuclear power plant in Iran, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on International Relations discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11685-11687" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-10-20T20:10:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="3743"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear exports"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/1998--Introduced.
Iran Nuclear Proliferation Prevention Act of 1998 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to withhold U.S. voluntary contributions from programs and projects of the International Atomic Energy Agency in Iran unless the Secretary of State makes a determination in writing to certain congressional committees that such programs and projects are consistent with U.S. nuclear nonproliferation and safety goals and will not provide Iran with training or expertise relevant to nuclear programs' development. Instructs the Secretary to review and report to the Congress annually for five years on all Agency programs and projects in specified countries to determine if they are consistent with U.S. nuclear nonproliferation and safety goals. Requires the Secretary to direct the U.S. representative to the Agency to oppose Agency programs determined inconsistent with U.S. nuclear nonproliferation and safety goals. Directs the Secretary to report annually to the Congress for five years on specified aspects of annual Agency assistance to Iran, including nuclear materials technology transfer, and inconsistencies between Agency technical assistance programs and U.S. nuclear nonproliferation and safety goals. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the United States should pursue internal Agency reforms that will ensure that all programs funded under the Technical Cooperation and Assistance Fund are compatible with U.S. nuclear nonproliferation policy and international nuclear nonproliferation norms.</summary>
</bill>
