<bill session="106" type="h" number="4733" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-11T13:42:00-04:00">VETOED:OVERRIDE_PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-11T13:42:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2001, Energy and Water Development</title>
    <title type="popular">Energy FY2001 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Water Development FY2001 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2001</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for energy and water development for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400601"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-06-23T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 106-693, by Mr. Packard.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-23T16:42:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="390">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 390.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-06-26T23:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 532 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4733 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 4 of rule XIII are waived. Points of order against provisions of the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 or clause 5(a) of rule XXI are waived. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 532 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 532.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5211-5237 " label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5224" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4733 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 4 of rule XIII are waived. Points of order against provisions of the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 or clause 5(a) of rule XXI are waived. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 532 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Bill Barrett to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4733.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Unless and until a unanimous consent agreement is reached concerning debate time on amendments, debate will go forward on all amendments under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hulshof amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Packard demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 532, the Chairman postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T17:20:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gilchrest amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gilchrest demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 532, the Chairman postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, further debate on the Gilchrest amendment was limited to 20 minutes, equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T18:14:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gilchrest amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gilchrest demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 532, the Chairman postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4733 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T18:26:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Packard asked unanimous consent for the specific order of all amendments remaining to be considered. The request was agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - After resolving back into the Committee of the Whole, the Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T18:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5245-5282" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Stupak asked unanimous consent to address the Committee of the Whole out of order. Without objection, Mr. Stupak proceeded with his remarks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T19:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Salmon for 30 minutes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T20:09:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Foley amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Foley demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 532, the Chairman postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ney amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T20:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kingston amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T20:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kingston amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T20:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Visclosky amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T20:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Andrews amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T20:55:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Andrews amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Andrews demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 532, the Chairman postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T20:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gekas amendment. Mr. Packard reserved a point of order against the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T21:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 532, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Sherwood amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T21:42:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sherwood amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sherwood demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 532, the Chairman postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T21:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hansen amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T21:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ryan (WI) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T22:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kingston amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T22:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ryun (KS) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T22:21:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ryun (KS) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ryun (KS) demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 532, the Chairman postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T22:23:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-27T23:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4733 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T00:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5290-5291" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T00:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T00:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4733.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T00:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T00:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-06-28T00:29:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="342" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 407 - 19 (Roll no. 342).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28T00:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-13">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Energy and Water Development. Approved for full committee consideration with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-18">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="688">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 688.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7522-7523" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed presented in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-25">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to proceed invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 100 - 0. Record Vote Number: 229.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7731-7732, S7768" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-30">
      <text>By Senator Domenici from Committee on Appropriations filed written report under authority of the order of the Senate of 01/06/1999. Report No. 106-395.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-05">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7985-7991" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-05">
      <text>The committee substitute agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/06/2000 S8069-8075" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-06">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8069-8090" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-07">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8129-8132, S8163-8187" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-09-07" how="roll" result="pass" roll="237" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 93 - 1. Record Vote Number: 237.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-09-07">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Domenici, Cochran, Gorton, McConnell, Bennett, Burns, Craig, Stevens, Reid, Byrd, Hollings, Murray, Kohl, Dorgan and Inouye.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-14T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Packard asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7627" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-14T16:18:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-14T16:18:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Packard, Rogers, Knollenberg, Frelinghuysen, Callahan, Latham, Wicker, Young (FL), Visclosky, Edwards, Pastor, Forbes, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-14T16:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27T22:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 106-907 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8312-8403" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-27T23:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 598 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 4733.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28T11:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 598 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28T11:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Packard brought up conference report H. Rept. 106-907 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 598.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28T11:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report on H.R. 4733.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28T12:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="2000-09-28T12:44:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="501" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 301 - 118 (Roll no. 501).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8416-8426" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9453-9455" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-10-02" how="roll" result="pass" roll="261" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 57 - 37. Record Vote Number: 261.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9572-9577" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-07">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action state="PROV_KILL:VETO" datetime="2000-10-07">
      <text>Vetoed by President.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-10T18:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair laid before the House the veto message from the President.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-10T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Packard moved to postpone consideration of the veto message until Oct. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-10T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to postpone consideration of the veto message until Oct. 11. Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9575-9576" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-11T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair announced the unfinished business to be the consideration of the veto.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9666-9669" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-11T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the veto message on H.R. 4733.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="VETOED:OVERRIDE_PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-10-11T13:42:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="523" type="override" where="h">
      <text>Two-thirds of the Members present having voted in the affirmative the bill is passed, the Passed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 315 - 98 (Roll no. 523).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-11">
      <text>Veto message received in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10228-10229" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10228-10229" label="text of Veto message"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-11">
      <text>Veto message referred to Committee on Appropriations by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP10" subcommittee="Energy and Water Development" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="532"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="598"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="4635"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="4991"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="h" number="5483"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2906"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Appalachia"/>
    <term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Beach erosion"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Civil engineering"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Dredging spoil"/>
    <term name="Droughts"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Fish culture"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="General Accounting Office"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indian hunting and fishing rights"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Interstate commissions"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation districts"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Northeastern States"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fusion"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="Nuclear warships"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Petroleum storage"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Plutonium"/>
    <term name="Polygraphs"/>
    <term name="Power marketing administrations"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Public utility rates"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive waste disposal in the ground"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="River regulation"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Severance pay"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley development"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Treaty-making power"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water supply engineering"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetland restoration"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h915"/>
    <amendment number="h916"/>
    <amendment number="h917"/>
    <amendment number="h918"/>
    <amendment number="h919"/>
    <amendment number="h920"/>
    <amendment number="h921"/>
    <amendment number="h922"/>
    <amendment number="h923"/>
    <amendment number="h924"/>
    <amendment number="h925"/>
    <amendment number="h926"/>
    <amendment number="h927"/>
    <amendment number="h928"/>
    <amendment number="h929"/>
    <amendment number="h930"/>
    <amendment number="h931"/>
    <amendment number="h932"/>
    <amendment number="s4017"/>
    <amendment number="s4024"/>
    <amendment number="s4025"/>
    <amendment number="s4030"/>
    <amendment number="s4031"/>
    <amendment number="s4032"/>
    <amendment number="s4033"/>
    <amendment number="s4034"/>
    <amendment number="s4035"/>
    <amendment number="s4036"/>
    <amendment number="s4037"/>
    <amendment number="s4038"/>
    <amendment number="s4039"/>
    <amendment number="s4040"/>
    <amendment number="s4041"/>
    <amendment number="s4042"/>
    <amendment number="s4043"/>
    <amendment number="s4044"/>
    <amendment number="s4045"/>
    <amendment number="s4046"/>
    <amendment number="s4047"/>
    <amendment number="s4048"/>
    <amendment number="s4049"/>
    <amendment number="s4050"/>
    <amendment number="s4051"/>
    <amendment number="s4052"/>
    <amendment number="s4053"/>
    <amendment number="s4054"/>
    <amendment number="s4055"/>
    <amendment number="s4056"/>
    <amendment number="s4057"/>
    <amendment number="s4058"/>
    <amendment number="s4059"/>
    <amendment number="s4060"/>
    <amendment number="s4061"/>
    <amendment number="s4062"/>
    <amendment number="s4063"/>
    <amendment number="s4064"/>
    <amendment number="s4065"/>
    <amendment number="s4066"/>
    <amendment number="s4067"/>
    <amendment number="s4068"/>
    <amendment number="s4069"/>
    <amendment number="s4070"/>
    <amendment number="s4071"/>
    <amendment number="s4072"/>
    <amendment number="s4073"/>
    <amendment number="s4074"/>
    <amendment number="s4075"/>
    <amendment number="s4076"/>
    <amendment number="s4077"/>
    <amendment number="s4078"/>
    <amendment number="s4079"/>
    <amendment number="s4080"/>
    <amendment number="s4081"/>
    <amendment number="s4082"/>
    <amendment number="s4083"/>
    <amendment number="s4084"/>
    <amendment number="s4085"/>
    <amendment number="s4086"/>
    <amendment number="s4087"/>
    <amendment number="s4088"/>
    <amendment number="s4089"/>
    <amendment number="s4090"/>
    <amendment number="s4091"/>
    <amendment number="s4092"/>
    <amendment number="s4093"/>
    <amendment number="s4094"/>
    <amendment number="s4095"/>
    <amendment number="s4096"/>
    <amendment number="s4097"/>
    <amendment number="s4098"/>
    <amendment number="s4099"/>
    <amendment number="s4100"/>
    <amendment number="s4101"/>
    <amendment number="s4102"/>
    <amendment number="s4103"/>
    <amendment number="s4104"/>
    <amendment number="s4105"/>
    <amendment number="s4106"/>
    <amendment number="s4107"/>
    <amendment number="s4108"/>
    <amendment number="s4109"/>
    <amendment number="s4110"/>
    <amendment number="s4111"/>
    <amendment number="s4112"/>
    <amendment number="s4113"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/27/2000--Conference report filed in House.
Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2001 - Title I: Department of Defense - Civil - Makes appropriations to the Department of the Army and its Corps of Engineers for FY 2001 for: (1) authorized civil functions of the Department of the Army relating to rivers and harbors, flood control, beach erosion, and related purposes; (2) expenses necessary for the collection and study of information related to such purposes; (3) the prosecution of river and harbor, flood control, shore protection, and related projects; (4) certain flood control projects on the Mississippi River and its tributaries; (5) the navigable waters and wetlands regulatory program; (6) formerly utilized sites remedial action program; and (7) general expenses.States that amounts in the Revolving Fund are available for relocating the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers headquarters to office space in the General Accounting Office headquarters building in Washington, D.C.(Sec. 101) Instructs the Secretary of the Army to enter into an agreement with the City of Grand Prairie, Texas, wherein the City agrees to assume certain contractual responsibilities of the Trinity River Authority of Texas.(Sec. 102) States that agreements proposed for execution by the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works or the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers shall be limited to specified credits and reimbursements per project, and total credits and reimbursements for all applicable projects.(Sec. 103) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act to revise the Missouri River Master Water Control Manual when it is made known to the pertinent Federal authority that such revision provides for an increase in the springtime water release program during the spring heavy rainfall and snow melt period in States with rivers draining into the Missouri River below the Gavins Point Dam.(Sec. 104) Bars the use of funds to implement any activity relating to closure or removal of the St. Georges Bridge across the Chesapeake and Delaware Canal, Delaware.(Sec. 105 ) Directs the Secretary of the Army to provide specified amounts to replace and upgrade the dam which collapsed in Kake, Alaska, in order to provide drinking water and hydroelectricity.Title II: Department of the Interior - Makes FY 2001 appropriations to the Department of the Interior for: (1) the Central Utah Project; (2) the Bureau of Reclamation, water and related resources; (3) Bureau of Reclamation Loan Program Account; (4) Central Valley Project Restoration Fund; and (5) general administrative expenses.(Sec. 201) Prohibits the use of appropriated funds to pay the salaries and expenses of personnel to purchase or lease water in the Middle Rio Grande or the Carlsbad Projects in New Mexico unless such purchase or lease is in compliance with specified statutory purchase requirements.(Sec. 202) States that Drought Emergency Assistance funds under this title shall be made available primarily for leasing of water from willing lessors for specified drought related purposes subsequent to State approval.(Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) assess and collect annually from Central Valley Project water and power contractors specified sums to be remitted to the Trinity Public Utilities District; (2) continue funding from power revenues the activities of the Glen Canyon Dam Adaptive Management Program as authorized by the Grand Canyon Protection Act of 1992; and (3) use up to $1 million to refund specified payments (including the amount of associated interest) to the United States for pre-1994 charges assessed for failure to file certification or reporting forms before receipt of irrigation water under the Reclamation Reform Act of 1982.(Sec. 206) Amends the Omnibus Consolidated and Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1999 to require the Canyon Ferry (Montana) Cabin Site appraisal to be consistent with the Universal Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisition. Repeals the repeal of the limitation on reinvestment of interest earned on the principal of the Canyon Ferry-Broadwater County Trust (thus allowing reinvestment of the interest, and its consideration as part of the Trust corpus, only until $3 million, or a lesser amount as offset by in-kind contributions, is deposited as the initial corpus of the Trust).(Sec. 207) Declares that any amounts provided for the Newlands Water Rights Fund for purchasing and retiring water rights in the Newlands Reclamation Project shall be non-reimbursable as of FY 2000.(Sec. 208) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into contracts with the city of Loveland, Colorado, (and related entities) providing for the use of facilities of the Colorado-Big Thompson Project, Colorado, for specified water uses.(Sec. 209) Amends the Irrigation Project Contract Extension Act of 1998 to extend from December 31, 2000, to December 31, 2003: (1) certain water service or repayment contracts for the Glendo Unit of the Missouri River Basin Project; and (2) certain contract extensions that are coterminous with a specified cooperative agreement.(Sec. 211) Amends the San Luis Rey Indian Water Rights Settlement Act to require the Secretary of the Interior to permanently reserve and furnish water to: (1) the Indian Water Authority; (2) the Bands' reservations; and (3) local entities' service areas.(Sec. 212) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to transfer to the El Dorado Irrigation District, all Federal right, title, and interest in the Sly Park Dam and Reservoir, Camp Creek Diversion Dam and Tunnel, and certain conduits and canals.Title III: Department of Energy - Makes appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for FY 2001: (1) energy supply programs; (2) non-defense environmental management; (3) uranium facilities maintenance and remediation; (4) general DOE science activities; (5) nuclear waste disposal activities; (6) DOE administration; (7) Office of the Inspector General; (8) atomic energy defense weapons activities (including immediate funds for the National Ignition Facility at Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory); (9) atomic energy defense and defense nuclear nonproliferation activities; (10) naval reactors activities; (11) Office of the Administrator of the National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA); (12) defense environmental restoration and waste management; (13) defense facilities closure projects; (14) defense environmental management privatization; (15) other DOE defense activities; (16) defense nuclear waste disposal; (17) the various geographical power marketing administrations of DOE (including specified costs for the hydroelectric facilities at the Falcon and Amistad Dams under the Western Area Power Administration); and (18) the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.Rescinds specified funds earmarked for: (1) interim storage of nuclear waste; and (2) the Tank Waste Remediation System at Richland, Washington.(Sec. 301) Prohibits the use of appropriations under this Act to award a management and operating contract unless it is awarded using competitive procedures, or the Secretary of Energy grants a waiver on a case-by-case basis.Prohibits delegation of such waiver authority.(Sec. 302) Prohibits the use of appropriations under this Act to: (1) develop or implement a workforce restructuring plan for DOE employees, or to provide them with enhanced severance payments or other benefits (unless the Department of Energy submits a reprogramming request); or (2) prepare or initiate Requests for Proposals for a program that has not been funded by Congress.(Sec. 306) Declares that no more than six percent of funds provided to government-owned, contractor-operated laboratories shall be available for Laboratory Directed Research and Development.(Sec. 307) Cites a maximum fund amount for the reimbursement of management and operating contractor travel expenses.(Sec. 308) Denies any funds for the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration to enter into any agreement to perform energy efficiency services outside the Bonneville service territory without certification that such services are not available from private sector businesses.(Sec. 309) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act to dispose of transuranic waste containing concentrations of plutonium exceeding 20 percent by weight in the Waste Isolation Pilot Plant.(Sec. 310) Authorizes the NNSA Administrator to authorize the plant manager of a covered nuclear weapons production plant to engage in research, development, and demonstration activities in order to maintain and enhance plant engineering and manufacturing capabilities.(Sec. 311) Authorizes each Federal Power Marketing Administration to engage in activities and undertake studies and proposals relating to the formation and operation of a regional transmission organization.(Sec. 312) Makes specified funds available to DOE for interim waste storage activities for Defense Nuclear Waste Disposal upon certification by the Secretary of Energy that the Site Recommendation Report cannot be completed timely without additional funding.(Sec. 313) Establishes a three-year term of office for the first person appointed as Under Secretary for Nuclear Security of DOE.(Sec. 314) Amends the National Nuclear Security Administration Act to set forth: (1) the scope of the Secretary of Energy's authority to modify NNSA organization; and (2) a prohibition on the pay of personnel engaged in concurrent service or duties inside and outside the NNSA.Title IV: Independent Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY 2001 for: (1) the Appalachian Regional Commission; (2) the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board; (3) the Delta Regional Authority; (4) the Denali Commission; (5) the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC); (6) the NRC Office of the Inspector General; and (7) the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board.Title V: Fiscal Year 2001 Emergency Appropriations - Makes appropriations for FY 2001 for expenses to remediate damaged DOE facilities and other expenses associated with the Cerro Grande fire.Mandates that a specified amount of such funds be made available to the Army Corps of Engineers to undertake immediate measures to provide erosion control and sediment protection to sewage lines, trails, and bridges in Pueblo and Los Alamos Canyons downstream of the Diamond Drive in New Mexico.Authorizes appropriations to implement programs authorized by the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965, of which specified amounts are available only to the extent that the President transmits an emergency budget request for them to Congress.Title VI: General Provisions - Expresses the sense of Congress that all equipment and products bought with funds under this Act should be American-made. Requires each Federal agency to give notice of this policy to any entity to which it provides financial assistance or contracts. Bars contracts funded under this Act from being awarded to any person determined by a court or Federal agency to have falsely labeled products as made in America.(Sec. 603) Prohibits the use of any funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act to determine the final point of discharge for the interceptor drain for the San Luis Unit until the Secretary of the Interior and the State of California have developed a plan, which conforms to California water quality standards approved by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, to minimize any detrimental effect of the San Luis drainage waters.Directs the Secretary of the Interior to classify the costs of the Kesterson Reservoir Cleanup and the San Joaquin Valley Drainage Programs as reimbursable or nonreimbursable and collected until fully repaid pursuant to the "Cleanup Program--Alternative Repayment Plan" and the "SJVDP--Alternative Repayment Plan" described in a specified report.(Sec. 604) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated under this Act for: (1) promulgations to implement a certain 1997 Kyoto Protocol regarding climate change which has not been submitted to the Senate for advice and consent to ratification; and (2) the basic pay of any individual (other than the Administrator for Nuclear Security and the Deputy Administrator for Naval Reactors) who simultaneously holds or executes responsibilities of a position within NNSA and within the Department of Energy not within the Administration.(Sec. 606) Extends from FY 2000 to 2009 funding for the Coastal Wetlands Planning, Protection and Restoration Act.(Sec. 607) Redesignates: (1) a certain "Interstate Sanitation Commission" for New York, New Jersey, and Connecticut as the "Interstate Environmental Commission"; and (2) a certain "Interstate Sanitation District" for those States as the "Interstate Environmental District."Title VII: Department of the Treasury - Makes a supplemental appropriation for FY 2001 to reduce the public debt.Title VIII: Nuclear Regulatory Commission - Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 to extend to September 20, 2005, the authority of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to assess and collect user fees and annual charges.Revises the formula and percentages used to determine the aggregate amount of annual charges collected from licensees and certificate holders. Reduces the fee recovery requirement from 100 percent to 98 percent in FY 2001 and by yearly increments down to 90 percent in FY 2005.</summary>
</bill>
