<bill session="106" type="hj" number="42" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">War Powers Amendments of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the War Powers Resolution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1999-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1999-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1999-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aggression"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Declaration of war"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="President as Commander-in-Chief"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/1999--Introduced.
War Powers Amendments of 1999 - Amends the War Powers Resolution to: (1) include within its purposes that the collective judgment of Congress and the President shall apply to the participation of U.S. armed forces in certain military operations of the United Nations (UN); and (2) specify that the Constitution grants Congress the power to declare war and the power of the purse (appropriations). (Sec. 3) Authorizes the introduction of U.S. armed forces into hostilities only: (1) pursuant to a declaration of war; (2) under specific statutory authorization; (3) to repel or forestall the imminent threat of attack upon the United States; or (4) for the evacuation of U.S. citizens from areas outside the United States. (Sec. 4) Requires: (1) the President to consult with Congress with respect to such introduction of U.S. armed forces in a foreign country or area, or their use within a UN operation; and (2) the use of an executive-legislative consultative group to aid the President and Congress in such consultation. (Sec. 6) Requires the President to remove U.S. armed forces within 60 days after their introduction unless Congress: (1) has declared war; (2) has enacted a joint resolution specifically authorizing such action; (3) has extended by law such 60-day limit; or (4) is physically unable to meet due to an armed attack upon the United States. Authorizes the President to extend such period by 30 days due to unavoidable military necessity. Prohibits funding after such authorized period(s). (Sec. 7) Provides expedited congressional procedures for the consideration of a joint resolution that: (1) provides specific authorization for the use of armed forces in hostilities; and (2) is introduced after the President has submitted a written request to Congress for enactment of such an authorization (designating such resolution as a privileged resolution). (Sec. 8) Authorizes any member of Congress to bring an action on the ground that the President or the armed forces have not complied with any provision of this joint resolution (providing expedited consideration of such action). (Sec. 9) Provides that authority to introduce U.S. armed forces into hostilities shall not be inferred from: (1) any provision of law that does not specifically authorize such introduction and that does not state that it is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization; or (2) any treaty that is not implemented by legislation specifically authorizing such introduction and that does not state that it constitutes specific statutory authorization.</summary>
</bill>
