<bill session="107" type="h" number="4629" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to establish a program to encourage and support carrying out innovative proposals to enhance homeland security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2002-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="2002-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2002--Introduced.
Amends the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to direct the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy to establish a Government-wide program to encourage and recognize contractor innovation and excellence in facilitating the defense of the United States against, or recovery from, terrorism or nuclear, biological, chemical, or radiological attack.Requires the Administrator to: (1) issue agency announcements seeking innovative solutions to advance defense against or recovery from such an attack; (2) convene a multiagency technical assistance team to assess feasibility, scientific and technical merits, and estimated costs and submit each proposal to each executive agency whose mission most coincides with the proposal's subject matter; and (3) provide monetary awards in recognition of unique and innovative solutions.Directs the Administrator to establish a pilot program under which the Secretaries of Defense, Energy, Commerce, Transportation, and the Treasury may test: (1) the innovative use of streamlined acquisition authorities and procedures; and (2) the feasibility of rapidly entering into contracts with private entities to carry out immediate solutions to key homeland security needs using commercial, off-the-shelf items and commercially available services.</summary>
</bill>
