<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="843" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2895" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2007-10-10T14:57:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <offered datetime="2007-10-10"/>
  <description>Amendment establishes a state minimum allocation percentage, under which every state will receive at least one half of one percent (.5%) of the total funds available each year that are allocated to states, Indian Tribes, and insular areas.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 110-369 to establish a state minimum allocation percentage, under which every state will receive at least one half of one percent (.5%) of the total funds available each year that are allocated to states, Indian Tribes, and insular areas. Allocations to all other states would be reduced pro rata to bring these states up to this .5% minimum. The amendment would also provide that the local jurisdiction in each state that is slated to receive the largest amount by formula in such state would be entitled to receive such funds directly [notwithstanding the bill's provision that jurisdictions entitled to their state in any year that nationwide funding is less than $2 billion]. The amendment includes a technical clarification to ensure that the mixed income limitation capping the number of units initially rented to extremely low income families at 50% applies to all of the units in a project [not just those units assisted by trust fund dollars]. The amendment would provide that the exception to the mixed income rule applies to all `elderly only' projects, not just those projects of 25 or fewer units.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Frank (MA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11430-11431, H11441-11442" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11430-11431" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2007-10-10T14:57:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="955">
      <text>On agreeing to the Frank (MA) amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 418 - 2 (Roll no. 955).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
