<bill session="106" type="h" number="3563" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent the theft of firearms from commercial carriers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400518"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2000-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2000-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2000--Introduced.
Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to provide that a common or contract carrier who is transporting, shipping, or delivering a firearm in interstate or foreign commerce: (1) shall, though electronic tracking, be aware of the identity of each individual who has custody of or control over the firearm, and the location of the firearm; (2) shall complete the transportation, shipment, or delivery within 24 hours; (3) shall report the theft or loss of the firearm within 24 hours after the theft or loss is discovered to the Secretary of the Treasury and to the appropriate local authorities; and (4) shall not authorize an individual to have such custody or control, or assign any individual the function of being aware of the identity of each individual who has custody of or control over the firearm, and the location of the firearm, unless the carrier has contacted the national instant criminal background check system (the system) and requested information on whether receipt of a firearm by the individual would violate the Act or State law, and has received an indication that such receipt would not violate such provisions.Directs the Secretary to impose on any carrier who violates such requirements a civil money penalty of between $100,000 and $250,000 for each shipment with respect to which a violation occurs.Authorizes commercial carriers to contact and receive information from the system.(Sec. 2) Provides for up to five years imprisonment, a fine, or both, for knowingly or with reckless disregard violating provisions regarding the prompt reporting of the theft or loss of a firearm.(Sec. 3) Increases the penalty for stealing a firearm: (1) which is moving as, is a part of, or which has moved in, interstate or foreign commerce; and (2) from a licensed importer, manufacturer, dealer, or collector.</summary>
</bill>
