<bill session="104" type="h" number="3064" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Services Improvement Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the overall economy and efficiency of Government operations and enable more efficient use of Federal funding, by coordinating Federal financial assistance programs and promoting local flexibility.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400189"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight. Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E334-335"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources and Intergovernmental Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO04" subcommittee="Human Resources and Intergovernmental Relations" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Regulatory reform"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/1996--Introduced.
Family Services Improvement Act of 1996 - Directs the President to designate a Federal Coordination Council composed of various specified cabinet secretaries and other Federal agency heads to perform a variety of specified functions for the stated purposes of: (1) removing Federal impediments to coordination of service delivery; (2) enabling more efficient use of Federal, State, and local resources through program coordination and reduction of regulation; (3) facilitating cooperation among and coordination of programs operated by State, local, and tribal governments and private, nonprofit organizations; (4) identifying at least ten qualified consortia of such organizations and State or local agencies that receive federally appropriated funds, together with representatives of specified services, to participate in a demonstration program to determine the benefits of specified accountability procedures; and (5) placing less emphasis in Federal service programs on measuring resources and procedures and more emphasis on accountability for achieving policy goals.</summary>
</bill>
