<bill session="106" type="h" number="4751" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Puerto Rico-United States Bilateral Pact of Non-territorial Permanent Union and Guaranteed Citizenship Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To recognize entry of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico into permanent union with the United States based on a delegation of government powers to the United States by the people of Puerto Rico constituted as a Nation, to guarantee irrevocable United States citizenship as a right under the United States Constitution for all persons born in Puerto Rico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-06-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1113-1114"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="National self-determination"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2000--Introduced.
Puerto Rico-United States Bilateral Pact of Non-territorial Permanent Union and Guaranteed Citizenship Act - Sets forth provisions regarding Puerto Rico's relationship with the United States, including that: (1) the people of Puerto Rico may reaffirm its status as a sovereign Commonwealth in permanent union with the United States; (2) persons born in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall continue being U.S. citizens by birthright; (3) the United States shall maintain its authority and responsibility for matters of defense with respect to Puerto Rico; (4) a common market and currency shall continue to exist between it and the United States; and (5) the Puerto Rican people's self-government emanates from the Commonwealth, and therefore they retain all the powers not delegated to the United States.</summary>
</bill>
