<bill session="107" type="h" number="5215" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Confidential Information Protection and Statistical Efficiency Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Confidential Information Protection and Statistical Efficiency Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the confidentiality of information acquired from the public for statistical purposes, and to permit the exchange of business data among designated statistical agencies for statistical purposes only.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400506"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2002-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="2002-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1397"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Efficiency, Financial Management and Intergovernmental Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-10-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-11-13T19:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 107-778.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-11-13T19:07:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="486">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 486.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO16" subcommittee="Government Efficiency, Financial Management and Intergovernmental Relations" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Statistical services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/13/2002--Reported to House amended.
Confidential Information Protection and Statistical Efficiency Act of 2002 - Requires: (1) the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to coordinate and oversee the confidentiality and disclosure policies established by this Act; and (2) any rules proposed by an executive agency pursuant to this Act to be subject to the Director's review and approval.Requires each Designated Statistical Agency or DSA (defined in title II) to report annually to the Director and the appropriate congressional committees.Establishes the interrelationship of these requirements with the authority of the Bureau of the Census, specified energy laws, and the Congress.Title I: Confidential Information Protection - (Sec. 102) Requires data or information acquired by an agency under a pledge of confidentiality and for exclusively statistical purposes to be used by the agency's officers, employees, or agents only for such purposes. Prohibits such information from being disclosed in identifiable form, for any use other than such a purpose, without the informed consent of the respondent.Requires a statistical agency or unit to clearly distinguish any data or information it collects for nonstatistical purposes by a rule that provides that the respondent is fully informed that the information to be collected could be used for such purposes.(Sec. 103) Sets forth penalties for violations.Title II: Statistical Efficiency - (Sec. 203) Requires Designated Statistical Agencies (the Bureau of the Census and the Bureau of Economic Analysis in the Department of Commerce and the Bureau of Labor Statistics in the Department of Labor) to: (1) identify opportunities to eliminate duplication and reduce the reporting burden and cost imposed on the public in providing statistical information; (2) enter into joint statistical projects to improve quality and reduce the cost of statistical programs; and (3) protect the confidentiality of individually identifiable information acquired for statistical purposes by adhering to safeguard principles.(Sec. 204) Allows a DSA to provide business data in an identifiable form to another DSA under the terms of a written agreement. States that the provision of such data does not alter responsibilities under the Freedom of Information Act or the Privacy Act of 1974.(Sec. 205) Restricts the use of business data provided by a DSA to statistical purposes. Requires publication of data to not identify any particular respondent.</summary>
</bill>
