<bill session="107" type="h" number="1157" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-06-13T12:19:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-06-13T12:19:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pacific Salmon Recovery Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Pacific Salmon Recovery Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Pacific Salmon Recovery Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Commerce to provide financial assistance to the States of Alaska, Washington, Oregon, California, and Idaho for salmon habitat restoration projects in coastal waters and upland drainages, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400403"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400021" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400304" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400305" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2001-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400384" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2001-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2001-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-04">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-05-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-05-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-05-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-06-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Received from State.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Received from Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-12T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-95.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-06-12T14:51:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="51">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 51.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-06-12T18:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 163 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1157 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the Congressional Record and numbered 1. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. House Resolution 156 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13T11:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 163 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13T11:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 163.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H3082-3092" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13T11:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1157 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the Congressional Record and numbered 1. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. House Resolution 156 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 163 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steven C. LaTourette to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1157.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1157.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13T11:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13T11:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-06-13T12:19:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="159" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 418 - 6 (Roll no. 159).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13T12:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13T12:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1157.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="107" type="hr" number="163"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="1825"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered animals"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International employees"/>
    <term name="International fishery management"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Salmon fisheries"/>
    <term name="Sustainable fisheries"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h73"/>
    <amendment number="h74"/>
    <amendment number="h75"/>
    <amendment number="h76"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/13/2001--Passed House amended.
Pacific Salmon Recovery Act- Requires the Secretary of Commerce, subject to appropriations, to provide financial assistance for salmon conservation and habitat restoration activities to: (1) Alaska, Washington, Oregon, and California, and Idaho (qualified States); and (2) tribal governments in such States and Alaska Native villages or regional or village corporations that are involved in salmon management and recovery or conservation activities and have the organizational capability to maximize the benefits of assistance provided under this Act (qualified tribal governments). Allocates 85 percent of assistance per fiscal year equally among such States and 15 percent among qualified tribal governments.(Sec. 3) Requires qualified States, to receive assistance under this Act, to submit a Salmon Conservation and Salmon Habitat Restoration Plan to the Secretary. Directs qualified tribal governments, to receive such assistance, to enter into memoranda of understanding with the Secretary regarding use of the assistance.Requires funds allocated to qualified States to be used for local and regional projects.Permits the use of assistance outside the jurisdiction of the recipient if the assisted activity will provide conservation benefits to naturally produced salmon in streams of concern to the recipient.Requires States to match, in the aggregate, financial assistance provided under this Act.(Sec. 4) Directs States seeking assistance under this Act to establish citizens advisory committees or other similar fora for the public to participate in obtaining and using assistance under this Act. Requires qualified tribal governments to hold public meetings to receive recommendations on the use of such assistance.(Sec. 5) States that specified Federal interagency consultation requirements of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 shall not be required based solely on the provision of financial assistance under this Act.(Sec. 6) Sets forth reporting requirements.(Sec. 7) Includes: (1) Lahontan cutthroat trout and bull trout within the definition of "salmon" for purposes of applying this Act in Oregon; and (2) bull trout within such definition for purposes of applying this Act in Washington and Idaho.(Sec. 8) Directs the President to: (1) determine the number of United States citizens who served as employees of the International Pacific Salmon Fisheries Commission or the International North Pacific Fisheries Commission and who worked in Canada in the course of employment with that commission; (2) calculate for each such employee the difference between the value, in United States currency, of the annuity payments made and to be made (determined by an actuarial valuation) by or on behalf of each such commission to the employee and the value, in Canadian currency, of such annuity payments; and (3) by not later than September 1, 2001, submit to the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science and Transportation of the Senate a report on such determinations and calculations.(Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations through 2004 to carry out this Act.(Sec. 10) Expresses the sense of Congress that, in the case of any equipment or products that may be authorized to be purchased with financial assistance provided under this Act, entities receiving such assistance should, in expending the assistance, purchase only equipment and products made in the United States. Requires any entity receiving funds under this Act to report any expenditures of such funds on items made outside of the United States to the Congress within 180 days of the expenditure.(Sec. 11) Expresses the sense of Congress that Congress supports the bipartisan July 2000 goals, objectives, and recommendations of the Governors of Idaho, Montana, Oregon and Washington to protect and restore salmon and other aquatic species to sustainable and harvestable levels while meeting the requirements of the Endangered Species Act of 1973, the Clean Water Act, the Pacific Northwest Electric Power Planning and Conservation Act, tribal treaty rights, and executive orders and while taking into account the need to preserve a sound economy in Alaska, California, Idaho, Montana, Oregon, and Washington.(Sec. 12) Requires the Secretary, in conjunction with other Federal agencies to annually report to Congress regarding the effects on Pacific Salmon stocks of timber harvesting on publicly owned lands in British Columbia.</summary>
</bill>
