<bill session="104" type="hr" number="57" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To preserve the constitutional role of the House of Representatives to provide for the expenditure of public money and ensure that the executive branch of the United States Government remains accountable to the House of Representatives for each expenditure of public money.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400399"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1995-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="1995-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1995-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1995-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1995-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400578" joined="1995-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1995-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1995-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1995-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="1995-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1995-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400591" joined="1995-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1995-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1995-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="1995-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400398" joined="1995-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="1995-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="1995-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services. subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1298"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-07T11:56:00-05:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. Taylor of Mississippi submitted H. Res. 57 for consideration by the House as a resolution constituting a question of the privileges of the House. The Chair subsequently entertained limited debate from Members on whether or not the resolution raised a question of the privileges of the House. Following debate, the Chair ruled that, in its present form, the resolution did not raise a question of the privileges of the House and could not be considered as such.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Currency devaluation"/>
    <term name="Debt"/>
    <term name="Debt agreements"/>
    <term name="Economic stabilization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/1995--Introduced.
Directs the Comptroller General, within seven days of the adoption of this resolution, to transmit to the House of Representatives a report containing: (1) the opinion of the Comptroller General on whether the proposed actions of the President to strengthen the Mexican peso and support economic stability in Mexico require congressional authorization or appropriation; (2) an evaluation of the terms and conditions of commitments and agreements entered into by the President, including the terms which provide for collateral or methods of assuring repayment of outlays by the United States; (3) an analysis of the resources which the International Monetary Fund has agreed to make available to strengthen the Mexican peso and support economic stability; (4) an evaluation of the role played by the Bank for International Settlements in efforts to strengthen the Mexican peso and support economic stability and the extent of the financial exposure of the United States; (5) an analysis of the relationships between the Bank and the Federal Reserve and the Bank and the Secretary of the Treasury and the extent to which such relationships involve a financial commitment to the Bank, on the part of the United States, of public money or financial resources under control of the Federal Reserve; and (6) an accounting of fund flows, in the 24 months preceding this resolution's adoption, through the exchange stabilization fund, the manner in which the fund has been used domestically and internationally, and the extent to which the use of the fund to strengthen the Mexican peso and support economic stability represents a departure from previous uses.</summary>
</bill>
