<bill session="105" type="h" number="3434" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Retirees Fairness Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide limited authority for concurrent receipt of military retired pay and veterans' disability compensation in the case of certain disabled military retirees who are over the age of 65.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1998-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E364-365"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House National Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled veterans"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/1998--Introduced.
Military Retirees Fairness Act of 1998 - States that the prohibition on the concurrent receipt of military retired pay and veterans' disability compensation shall not apply in the case of a person who has a service-connected disability if: (1) the person has completed at least 20 years of retirement-creditable military service; (2) the disability was incurred or aggravated in the line of duty; and (3) the person has attained the age of 65. Allows such a person, in addition to receiving the full amount of military retired pay, to receive: (1) 50 percent of the authorized veterans' disability compensation due, if such person is at least 65 but not yet 70; and (2) 100 percent, if such person is 70 or older. Requires military retired pay paid concurrently with disability compensation to be paid out of funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for that fiscal year. Makes the concurrent payment provisions effective for months beginning on and after October 1998, with a prohibition against the payment of retroactive benefits.</summary>
</bill>
