<bill session="104" type="h" number="2843" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Insurance Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to change the name of the Servicemen's Group Life Insurance program to Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance, to authorize the termination of life insurance under that program when premiums are not paid, to provide for coverage under that program to be provided automatically at the maximum level unless the servicemember elects a lower level, and to make other improvements to life insurance programs administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400504"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1996-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1996-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400127" joined="1996-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="407838" joined="1996-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1996-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E17"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Compensation, Pension, Insurance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-01">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.3373.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Compensation, Pension, Insurance, and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2156"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2157"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3373"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1996--Introduced.
Veterans' Insurance Reform Act of 1995 - Authorizes the Secretary of the military department concerned to terminate an individual's coverage under the Servicemen's Group Life Insurance (SGLI) if such individual does not pay the required premiums within 60 days after their due date. Requires written notification of such termination. Vacates such termination if such individual, before the effective date of such termination (60 days after notification), remits all past due amounts and demonstrates to the Secretary's satisfaction that the failure to make timely payments was justifiable. Increases from $100,000 to $200,000 the maximum automatic coverage for individuals under the SGLI. Requires specified information to be provided to SGLI holders. Redesignates SGLI as Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance. Merges into SGLI those individuals currently covered under the Retired SGLI program. Revises provisions concerning duration and termination of coverage and premiums with respect to such newly-covered individuals. Allows SGLI policies to be converted, upon the completion of miitary duty or travel, to a commercial life insurance policy with a participating company selected by the individual. Provides for the payment of Veterans' Group Life Insurance (VGLI) to an individual who has in effect at death both SGLI and VGLI coverage, limiting the total benefits payable from both policies to $200,000. Allows VGLI policies to be converted to commercial life insurance policies. Requires SGLI coverage of any member of the Retired Reserve to be converted to VGLI coverage 90 days after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
