<bill session="106" type="h" number="3767" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Visa Waiver bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Visa Waiver Pilot Program bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Visa Waiver Permanent Program Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Visa Waiver Permanent Program Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Visa Waiver Permanent Program Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Visa Waiver Permanent Program Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Visa Waiver Permanent Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to make improvements to, and permanently authorize, the visa waiver pilot program under section 217 of such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="2000-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2000-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="2000-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-04-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-04-06T16:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 106-564.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-04-06T16:33:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="308">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 308.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-04-11T13:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-11T13:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2036-2040" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-11T13:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3767.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-04-11T13:36:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2036-2037" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-04-11T13:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-05-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="524">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 524.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-28">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9451-9453" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-10-03" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9657" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-10T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-10T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-10-10T16:20:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9541-9545" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9541-9543" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-10T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-10">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-10-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-10-30" type="public" number="106-396">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-396.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2367"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2367"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication satellites"/>
    <term name="Computer matching"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Discrimination against the disabled"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Executives"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International employees"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sexual orientation"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Supervisors"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4276"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/3/2000--Passed Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Permanent Program Authorization Title II: Program Improvements Title III: Immigration Status of Alien Employees of INTELSAT after Privatization Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions Visa Waiver Permanent Program Act - Title I: Permanent Program Authorization - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (Act) to make the visa waiver pilot program permanent.Title II: Program Improvements - Amends the Act to grant program privileges to countries that extend reciprocal program privileges either directly with the United States or in conjunction with a designated program participant country and have with such country a common immigration admissions area.(Sec. 202) Establishes deadlines for: (1) participating countries to have a machine readable passport program that is issuing such passports (October 1, 2003); and (2) alien visitors to have such passports (October 1, 2007). Requires programs and passports to meet the international standard for machine readability.(Sec. 203) Requires an automated system check of visitor identity and admissibility, and provides that an alien denied program entry may seek entry only through visa application. Prohibits administrative or judicial review of entry denial.(Sec. 204) Requires periodic written evaluations of a participating country's effect on U.S. law enforcement and security interests. Provides for emergency (war, disruptive social unrest, overthrow of a democratic government, financial crisis) recission of program designation.(Sec. 205) Directs the Attorney General to develop and implement an automated entry-exit program control system by October 1, 2001, which shall include data provision by participating sea or air carriers. Sets forth related recordkeeping and reporting provisions.Directs the Attorney General and the Secretary of State to develop and implement an automated data sharing system, which shall, by October 1, 2002, supply immigration officers conducting port of entry inspections with available photographs and inadmissibility information with respect to aliens seeking program entry.(Sec. 206) Prohibits, in determining visa refusal rates for program eligibility purposes, the use of procedures based upon race, sex, or disability, unless authorized by law or regulation.(Sec. 207) Sets forth required visa waiver information and reporting provisions.Title III: Immigration Status of Alien Employees of INTELSAT after Privatization - Provides for the maintenance of nonimmigrant and special immigrant status of alien officers and employees (and immediate family members) of INTELSAT after its privatization (including precursory employment with a successor entity before completion of privatization), during the period of continued employment with INTELSAT or any successor or separated entity.(Sec. 302) Treats as qualifying circumstances managerial or executive employment for INTELSAT or a successor entity by a nonimmigrant alien seeking to adjust to permanent resident status as a multinational executive or manager.Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions - Amends the Act to exempt certain restructured employers from H-1B employee visa petition requirements.(Sec. 402) Amends the Department of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1993 to extend the immigrant investors pilot program. Revises qualifying criteria.(Sec. 403) Amends the Act to include business airplanes as carriers within the visa waiver program.(Sec. 404) Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to revise foreign student information collection and fee provisions. Extends the program expansion deadline. Redefines "designated exchange visitor program" as a program designated by the Secretary of State rather than the Director of the United States Information Agency.</summary>
</bill>
