<bill session="105" type="h" number="1252" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-23T17:37:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-04-23T17:37:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Judicial Reform Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Judicial Reform Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Judicial Reform Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the procedures of the Federal courts in certain matters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401587" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400549" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1997-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="409228" joined="1997-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1997-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-04-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E616-617"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 8 - 7.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-04-01T18:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 105-478.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-04-01T18:18:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="275">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 275.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 408 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1252 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill, modified by striking section 9. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 408 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 408.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2243-2286" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1252 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill, modified by striking section 9. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T10:41:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 408 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T10:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Frank Riggs to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T10:41:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Lofgren amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the noes had prevailed. Ms. Lofgren demanded a recorded vote and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings were postponed and the point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Following the disposition of the DeLay amendment, a recorded voted on the Lofgren amendment will be the next order of business. Such a vote, if ordered, will be a 5 minute vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T16:30:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Conyers amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the noes had prevailed. Mr. Conyers demanded a recorded vote and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings were postponed and the point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T16:33:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Aderholt amendment and announced that, by voice vote, the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Skaggs demanded a recorded vote and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings were postponed and the point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the postponed proceedings on amendments which had been debated earlier. The first vote will be on the Conyers amendment, followed by a vote on the Aderholt amendment. After the disposition of the Conyers amendment, a recorded vote on the Aderholt amendment, if ordered, will be a 5 minute vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T17:20:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF THE COMMITTEE - Mr. Manzullo asked unanimous consent that the Clerk be directed to strike Section 5 of the bill. Agreed to without objection. Accordingly, Section 5, as amended, was removed from the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T17:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1252.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T17:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T17:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-04-23T17:37:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T17:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T17:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1252.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Oversight and Courts.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Oversight and the Courts" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="408"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Administrative law judges"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Choice of law"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Court congestion and delay"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial corruption"/>
    <term name="Judicial districts"/>
    <term name="Judicial ethics"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Tax assessment"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
    <term name="Video tapes in courtroom proceedings"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h554"/>
    <amendment number="h555"/>
    <amendment number="h556"/>
    <amendment number="h557"/>
    <amendment number="h558"/>
    <amendment number="h559"/>
    <amendment number="h560"/>
    <amendment number="h561"/>
    <amendment number="h562"/>
    <amendment number="h563"/>
    <amendment number="h564"/>
    <amendment number="h565"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/23/1998--Passed House amended.
Judicial Reform Act of 1998 - States that an application for anticipatory relief against a State law adopted by referendum shall not be granted by a district court or judge on the ground that such law is repugnant to the Constitution, treaties, or laws of the United States unless such application is heard and determined by a three-judge panel under Federal law. Provides for expedited appeal of such a determination directly to the Supreme Court. (Sec. 3) Provides for interlocutory appeal (within ten days) to the appropriate court of appeals of a determination of whether an action may be maintained as a class action, without any stay of the class action proceedings in the district court. (Sec. 4) Revises procedures regarding proceedings on complaints against judicial conduct. Directs the chief judge to notify the clerk of the court of appeals of the complaint in specified circumstances where such judge identifies such a complaint and dispenses with the filing of a written complaint, together with a brief statement of the facts underlying the complaint. Authorizes the chief judge to dismiss such a complaint upon finding it to be: (1) not in conformity with specified required procedures; (2) directly related to the merits of a decision or procedural ruling; or (3) frivolous. Requires the judge, if the judge does not dismiss the complaint, to refer the complaint (or statement of facts underlying the complaint, as appropriate) to the chief judge of another judicial circuit in accordance with a system established by the Judicial Conference of the United States which prescribes the appropriate circuits for such referral. Requires such system to be established and submitted to the Congress within 180 days after the enactment of this Act. Authorizes the chief judge, after expeditiously reviewing the complaint, by written order explaining such judge's reasons, to conclude the proceeding upon finding that appropriate corrective action has been taken or that action on the complaint is no longer necessary because of intervening events. Directs the Judicial Conference to prescribe rules establishing: (1) procedures for the filing of complaints regarding the conduct of any judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims, the Court of International Trade, or the Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, and for the investigation and resolution of such complaints; and (2) a system for referring complaints filed regarding the conduct of a judge of any such court to any of the first eleven judicial circuits or to another court for investigation and resolution. Permits disclosure of papers, documents, and records of proceedings related to investigations of judicial conduct to another agency or instrumentality of any governmental jurisdiction within or under the control of the United States for a civil or criminal law enforcement activity authorized by law. (Sec. 5) Directs that applications for writs of habeas corpus received in or transferred to a district court be randomly assigned to the judges of that court. (Sec. 6) Grants the presiding judge of a U.S. appellate or district court the authority to permit the photographing, electronic recording, broadcasting, or televising to the public of court proceedings over which that judge presides. Directs: (1) the court, upon the request of any witness in a trial proceeding other than a party, to order the face and voice of the witness to be disguised or otherwise obscured to render the witness unrecognizable; and (2) the presiding judge to inform each witness who is not a party that the witness has the right to request that his or her image and voice be obscured during the witness' testimony. Authorizes the Judicial Conference to promulgate advisory guidelines to which a presiding judge may refer in making decisions regarding the management and administration of such activity. Sunsets such authority after three years. (Sec. 7) Amends the Federal judicial code to bestow original jurisdiction on Federal district courts in civil actions involving minimal diversity jurisdiction among adverse parties based on a single accident where at least 25 persons have either died or sustained injuries exceeding $50,000 per person, subject to specified limitations. Directs the district court in which such cases are consolidated to retain those cases for determination of liability and punitive damages, and to determine the substantive law that would apply for findings of liability and damage. Requires such district court to promptly notify the judicial panel on multidistrict litigation of the pendency of the action. (Sec. 8) Extends the period during which any petition for judicial review of a final order or decision of the Merit Systems Protection Board must be filed with the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit from 30 to 60 days after the petitioner receives notice of the Board's action. (Sec. 9) Amends judicial code provisions regarding the Judiciary Information Technology Fund to repeal provisions subjecting information technology procurement to provisions of the Clinger-Cohen Act of 1996 applicable to executive agencies. (Sec. 10) Directs that, for FY 1999 and thereafter, any portion of certain miscellaneous fees collected as prescribed by the Judicial Conference exceeding the amount of such fees in effect on September 30, 1998, be deposited into the special fund of the Treasury to be available to offset funds appropriated for the operation and maintenance of the courts of the United States. (Sec. 11) Authorizes judges retired from regular active service to serve as members of the judicial council of the circuit. (Sec. 12) Provides for the sunset of provisions requiring a civil justice expense and delay reduction plan. (Sec. 13) Authorizes the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts to designate judicial branch officers and employees to be disbursing officers and certifying officers. Lists rights and responsibilities of such officers. (Sec. 14) Amends the judicial code to deny a Federal court jurisdiction, in a civil action regarding prison conditions, to enter or carry out a prisoner release order that would result in the release from or nonadmission to a prison, on the basis of prison conditions, of any person subject to incarceration, detention, or admission to a facility because of a felony conviction under the laws of the relevant jurisdiction, or a violation of the terms or conditions of parole, probation, pretrial release, or a diversionary program, relating to the commission of a felony under the laws of the relevant jurisdiction. Terminates existing consent decrees that provide for remedies relating to prison conditions.</summary>
</bill>
