<bill session="105" type="h" number="1832" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To achieve budgetary savings by terminating or limiting certain Department of Defense programs, by reducing the scope of the Stockpile Stewardship Program of the Department of Energy, and by reducing arms transfer subsidies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1997-09-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on National Security, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-03">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOE.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Procurement.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS20" subcommittee="Military Procurement" name="House National Security"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Air defenses"/>
    <term name="Air force procurement"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missile defenses"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Export subsidies"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fighter aircraft"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Guided missiles"/>
    <term name="Intercontinental ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Lasers"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military aircraft"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military technology"/>
    <term name="Naval procurement"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear submarines"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space warfare"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Tactical nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Test facilities"/>
    <term name="Transport aircraft"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tritium"/>
    <term name="Vertical takeoff aircraft"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/1997--Introduced.
Prohibits funds from being appropriated to the Department of Defense (DOD) for any fiscal year after 1997 for research, development, test, and evaluation or for procurement for: (1) the Navy F/A-18E/F aircraft program; (2) the Marine Corps V-22 Osprey aircraft program; and (3) the Air Force F-22 aircraft program. Prohibits the use of funds after FY 1997 for the production of Trident II (D-5) missiles for the Navy. Requires the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) to retire eight Trident I submarines during FY 2000 through 2003. Prohibits the Secretary of the Air Force from procuring more than eight C-17 aircraft in each of FY 1998 through 2000. Directs the Secretary to reduce: (1) by FY 2003 the DOD strategic nuclear force to include a maximum of 300 Minuteman II intercontinental ballistic missiles; and (2) DOD theater missile defense programs by terminating the Navy sea-based area theater missile defense system, the Army Medium Extended Air Defense System, the Air Force airborne laser for destruction of missiles system, and the Space and Missile Tracking System. Prohibits any funds from being appropriated to DOD for fiscal years after 1997 for assistance to Israel for development of the Arrow missile. Directs the Secretary of Energy to reduce activities under the Stockpile Stewardship Program so as to achieve specified savings during FY 1998 through 2002 by consolidating, terminating, and cancelling specified activities at Department of Energy research and development sites. Amends the Arms Export Control Act to provide that any sale of major defense equipment approved under such Act shall include an appropriate charge for costs incurred by the United States in the research, development, and production of such equipment. Provides an exception. Repeals a provision of such Act which allows for the recovery of certain administrative expenses when such expenses are neither salaries of U.S. armed forces nor represent unfunded estimated costs of civilian retirement and other benefits.</summary>
</bill>
