<bill session="105" type="hr" number="230" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-18T12:37:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-09-18T12:37:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 168) to implement the recommendations of the bipartisan House Ethics Reform Task Force.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17T19:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-250, by Mr. Solomon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-17T19:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 168 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the resolution in the Committee of the Whole. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in the report accompanying this resolution, to be considered in the order and manner specified in the report, shall not be subject to amendment or subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-09-17T19:01:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="91">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 91.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18T11:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7536-7544" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 191 (Roll no. 407).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1997-09-18T12:37:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="hr" number="168"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/1997--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (modified closed) for the consideration of H. Res. 168 (implementing the recommendations of the bipartisan House Ethics Reform Task Force).</summary>
</bill>
