<bill session="106" type="h" number="2905" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Integrity in Banking and Money Laundering Prevention Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To eliminate money laundering in the private banking system, to require the Secretary of the Treasury to take certain actions with regard to foreign countries in which there is a concentration of money laundering activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1999-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/1999--Introduced.
Integrity in Banking and Money Laundering Prevention Act of 1999 - Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to report to certain congressional committees on private domestic banking activities, including regulatory efforts to monitor and ensure that such activities are conducted in compliance with Federal banking law governing monetary transactions and depository institution recordkeeping requirements.Instructs the Secretary to: (1) prescribe regulations which require financial institutions to maintain all accounts in such a way as to ensure that the name of the account holder and the number of the account are associated with all of the owner's account activity; and (2) develop criteria for identifying foreign high-intensity money laundering areas.Authorizes courts to double criminal penalties for violations involving high-intensity money laundering areas.Directs the Secretary to: (1) require domestic financial institutions to maintain records within the United States which accurately identify the parties for whom such institutions conduct transactions with foreign counterparts; and (2) promulgate final regulations requiring registered brokers and dealers to report suspicious transactions in accordance with specified banking law.</summary>
</bill>
