<bill session="106" type="h" number="4937" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Protection and Fairness Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide relief to providers of services under the Medicare Program by correcting reductions in payment rates instituted under the Balanced Budget Act of 1997.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2000-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2000-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Increase in Payments for Inpatient Hospital Services Title II: Increase in Payments for Home Health Services Title III: Increase in Payments to Medicare+Choice Organizations Subtitle A: Modifications to Risk Adjustment Methodology Subtitle B: Modifications to the Blended Capitation Rate Subtitle C: Reporting Requirements for Medicare Health Care Services Furnished in Military Treatment Facilities Medicare Protection and Fairness Act of 2000 - Title I: Increase in Payments for Inpatient Hospital Services - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) with respect to payment to hospitals for inpatient hospital services to provide for: (1) elimination of reduction to market basket percentage increase in FY 2001 and 2002; (2) increase in payments for disproportionate share (DSH) hospitals in FY 2001 and 2002; and (3) elimination of reduction in payments for indirect costs of graduate medical education.Title II: Increase in Payments for Home Health Services - Amends SSA title XVIII with regard to the prospective payment system (PPS) for home health services to eliminate the 15 percent reduction in the cost limits and per beneficiary limits under such PPS.Makes such amendment effective as if included in the enactment of the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Balanced Budget Refinement Act of 1999.Title III: Increase in Payments to Medicare+Choice Organizations - Subtitle A: Modifications to Risk Adjustment Methodology - Amends SSA title XVIII part C (Medicare+Choice) with respect to payments to Medicare+Choice organizations to require that the Medicare+Choice risk adjustment methodology be implemented in a budget neutral manner. Provides for a ten year phased-in implementation of such methodology.Subtitle B: Modifications to the Blended Capitation Rate - Authorizes Medicare+Choice organizations to elect to apply blended capitation rate area-specific and national percentages for 2001 and 2002 (instead of one or the other in different years). Provides for an increase in the national per capita Medicare+Choice growth percentage in 2001 and 2002.Subtitle C: Reporting Requirements for Medicare Health Care Services Furnished in Military Treatment Facilities - Amends SSA title XVIII with respect to the Medicare subvention demonstration project for military retirees to add reporting requirements for costs incurred under the project for purposes of calculating Medicare+Choice payment rates.</summary>
</bill>
