<bill session="104" type="h" number="4040" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-18T11:54:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-09-18T11:54:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Intermodal Safe Container Transportation Act Amendments of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, relating to intermodal safe container transportation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1996-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1996-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1996-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-09-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-17T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 104-794.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-09-17T13:28:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="432">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 432.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18T11:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Shuster moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18T11:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10546-10548" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18T11:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1996-09-18T11:54:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3159"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Containerization"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Farm produce"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/1996--Introduced.
Intermodal Safe Container Transportation Act Amendments of 1996 - Amends Federal transportation law to revise the prior notification requirements for intermodal freight transportation. Requires a person who tenders to a first carrier that is a motor carrier (currently, any carrier) a container or trailer with a gross cargo weight of more than 29,000 pounds (currently, 10,000 pounds, including packing material and pallets) for intermodal transportation to give prior notification of the cargo weight and a reasonable description of its contents to the motor carrier. Allows such notification to be made by telephone, and allows the required certification of the container or trailer contents to be electronic. Sets forth administrative and civil penalties for persons who inaccurately transfer certification information. Makes such a person liable to the owner or beneficial owner for any lien filed by a subsequent carrier that incurred a bond, fine, or other penalty as a result of an inaccurate information transfer or a failure to forward a certification. Requires a motor carrier that knows that the gross cargo weight of an intermodal container or trailer violates State vehicle weight laws to give notice to the operator of a leased vehicle that transports such items. Requires the motor carrier to reimburse the operator of the leased vehicle that are fined because of a violation of a State's gross vehicle weight laws. Allows a motor carrier to presume that the gross cargo weight of a container or trailer is under 29,001 pounds if it receives no certification before or when a loaded intermodal container or trailer is tendered to it. Declares that a copy of a certification is not required to accompany the intermodal container or trailer. Prohibits a person from coercing a person transporting a loaded container or trailer having a gross cargo weight of more than 29,000 pounds (currently, 10,000 pounds, including packing materials and pallets) before the required certification is provided. Adds to the circumstances giving certain persons a lien against the contents of the container or trailer as a result of a violation of a State's gross vehicle weight laws. Includes among such circumstances: (1) failure of the party required to provide certification off gross cargo weight to the first carrier to provide it; (2) failure of the party required to forward such certification to forward it; or (3) error in the transfer of information on the certification to another document.</summary>
</bill>
