<bill session="104" type="h" number="2255" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lamprey Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate certain segments of the Lamprey River in New Hampshire as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411997"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1679-1680"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-09">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-06-13">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.2292.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="2292"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1174"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1995--Introduced.
Lamprey Wild and Scenic River Act - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (the Act) to designate a specified segment of the Lamprey River in New Hampshire as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Requires the segment to be: (1) administered as a recreational river by the Secretary of the Interior through cooperative agreements between the Secretary and the State of New Hampshire and the towns of Durham, Lee, and Newmarket, New Hampshire; and (2) managed in accordance with the Lamprey River Management Plan. Deems the Plan to satisfy the requirement for a comprehensive management plan pursuant to the Act. Requires the Secretary to coordinate the Secretary's management responsibilities under this Act with the Lamprey River Advisory Committee. Deems the zoning ordinances adopted by such towns, including provisions for conservation of shorelands, floodplains, and wetlands associated with the segment, to satisfy the standards and requirements of the Act. Applies to the segment provisions of the Act which prohibit Federal acquisition of lands by condemnation. Provides that the acquisition of lands for purposes of this Act shall be limited to donation or acquisition with the owner's consent and shall be subject to the additional criteria set forth in the Plan. Requires the Secretary to offer assistance regarding continued involvement of the town of Epping, New Hampshire, in the implementation of the Plan and in consideration of potential future addition of that portion of the River within Epping as a component of the System. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
