<bill session="105" type="hr" number="385" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-26T15:27:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-03-26T15:27:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 1757) to consolidate international affairs agencies, to authorize appropriations for the Department of State and related agencies for fiscal years 1998 and 1999, and to ensure that the enlargement of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) proceeds in a manner consistent with United States interests, to strengthen relations between the United States and Russia, to preserve the prerogatives of the Congress with respect to certain arms control agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11T17:55:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-434, by Mr. Solomon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11T17:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 1757. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read when called up for consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-11T17:55:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="155">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 155.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1581-1588" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T14:02:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T15:00:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-03-26T15:27:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="75" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 172 (Roll No. 75).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26T15:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="1757"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/1998--Introduced.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the conference report on H.R. 1757 (foreign affairs agencies consolidation, foreign relations authorization, and United Nations funding).</summary>
</bill>
