<bill session="106" type="h" number="3657" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-11-06">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the conveyance of a small parcel of public domain land in the San Bernardino National Forest in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2000-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E145"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-02-18">
      <text>Referred to Department of Agriculture for comments.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-16">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-17T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-744.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-17T16:58:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="425">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 425.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walden moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7399-7401" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3657.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-09-12T15:59:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7399-7400" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10837-10838" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2000-10-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-23T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-23T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2000-10-23T14:45:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H10504-10505" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H10504-10505" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-23T14:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-23">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2000-10-26">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2000-11-06">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2000-11-06" type="public" number="106-434">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 106-434.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="2111"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Antennas"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4328"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/19/2000--Passed Senate amended.
Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to KATY 101.3 F.M. a specified parcel of real property located within the San Bernardino National Forest in Riverside County, California.Requires the Secretary, upon the receipt of a specified payment by KATY, to release KATY from any and all claims of the United States arising from the occupancy and use of the San Bernardino National Forest by KATY for communication site purposes. Declares that by acceptance of such conveyance, KATY and its successors and assigns, will indemnify and hold harmless the United States for any and all liability to General Telephone and Electronics Corporation (GTE), KATY, and any third party that is associated with such parcel, including liability for any buildings or personal property on it belonging to GTE and any other third parties. Requires all funds received pursuant to this Act to be deposited in the fund established under the Sisk Act, and to remain available to the Secretary for the acquisition of lands, waters, and interests in land for inclusion in the San Bernardino National Forest.Amends a certain receipts Act to: (1) authorize the Secretary to acquire by purchase lands, real property or interests in lands within the boundaries of the San Bernardino, Cleveland, and Los Angeles National Forests California; (2) require such lands, real property or interests to be managed for National Forest System purposes; and (3) provide for a specified percentage of the monies otherwise payable to California for the benefit of San Bernardino County to be available to be appropriated for expenditure in furtherance of such Act.(Sec. 2) Amends the Santa Rosa and San Jacinto Mountains National Monument Act of 2000 to: (1) eliminate the requirement that the Secretary of the Interior submit legal descriptions of the boundaries of the National Monument to the Senate Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry; and (2) allow the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior to enter into certain cooperative agreements and shared management arrangements with the Agua Caliente Band of Cahuilla Indians (currently with any person, including such Indians).(Sec. 3) Amends the Santo Domingo Pueblo Claims Settlement Act of 2000 to direct the Secretary of the Interior to acquire by exchange specified New Mexico trust lands and interests, including improvements, mineral rights, and water rights.Requires the Secretary to convey such lands to the Pueblo of Santo Domingo and grants the Pueblo the exclusive right to acquire such lands.Permits the Pueblo to enter into agreements to exchange restricted lands for lands title to which was at issue in Pueblo of Santo Domingo v. Rael and deems to be approved any land exchange agreements between the Pueblo and any of the parties to such action that are executed not later than December 31, 2001.Approves all agreements, transactions, and conveyances authorized by specified boundary dispute resolutions as enacted by the Tribal Council of the Pueblo de Cochiti and the Tribal Council of the Pueblo.</summary>
</bill>
