<bill session="105" type="h" number="2907" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nonself-Destructive Landmine Stockpile Elimination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the destruction of the United States stockpile of landmines other than self-destructive landmines and to prohibit the acquisition of such landmines in the future.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408142"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on National Security, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-07">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-07">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Land mines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/7/1997--Introduced.
Nonself-Destructive Landmine Stockpile Elimination Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense, no later than December 31, 1998, to demilitarize the U.S. stockpile of the M14 and M16 antipersonnel landmines, and the M15, M19, and M21 antitank landmines. Prohibits any Department of Defense funds from being used for the acquisition of any such landmine or for any other antipersonnel or antitank landmine that is not self-destructive. Directs the Secretary to certify to the Congress whether such demilitarization compliance would adversely affect the U.S. national security interest. Terminates such demilitarization and prohibition upon a positive certification. Expresses the sense of the Congress that all other nations should take steps to eliminate nonself-destructive landmines from their military inventories.</summary>
</bill>
