<bill session="108" type="h" number="2406" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Shrimp Importation Financing Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To support the domestic shrimping industry by eliminating taxpayer subsidies for certain competitors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2003-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Resources, and International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Shellfish"/>
    <term name="Turtles"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2003--Introduced.
Shrimp Importation Financing Fairness Act - Prohibits the Secretary of Commerce from imposing any new restrictive regulations on the domestic shrimping industry. Prohibits the Overseas Private Investment Corporation from issuing any contract of insurance or reinsurance or any guaranty, or from entering into any agreement to provide financing for a project undertaken or to be undertaken in a country which exported more than 20 million pounds (excessive amounts) of shrimp to the United States in the first six months of 2002, until three months after it has reduced its shrimp exports to less than three million pounds per month for three consecutive months. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. Executive Director at the International Monetary Fund to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to oppose providing assistance to any foreign country that exported excessive amounts of shrimp to the United States in the first six months of 2002, until it fulfills the reduction requirements of this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to reduce the amount of U.S. contributions to the Fund according to a specified formula if, during the first such three-month period, the Fund provides assistance to any such country. Prohibits the Export-Import Bank of the United States from providing assistance to any country that exported excessive amounts of shrimp to the United States in the first six months of 2002, until it fulfills the reduction requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
