<bill session="107" type="h" number="2995" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Fiscal Integrity Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical and conforming changes to provide for the enactment of the Independence of the Chief Financial Officer Establishment Act of 2001, to establish a reporting event notification system to assist Congress and the District of Columbia in maintaining the financial stability of the District government and avoiding the initiation of a control period, to provide the District of Columbia with autonomy over its budgets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2001-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2001-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2001-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="2316"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Chief financial officers"/>
    <term name="City councils"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economic forecasting"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government spending"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Mayors"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Municipal employees"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Municipal home rule"/>
    <term name="Municipal officials"/>
    <term name="Municipal politics and government"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2001--Introduced.
District of Columbia Fiscal Integrity Act of 2001 - Amends the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to repeal the establishment of the Office of the Chief Financial Officer (CFO) of the District of Columbia. Subjects the authority of the Mayor for administration of the financial affairs of the District of Columbia, and for accounting supervision and control of the District government, to the limitations provided under the Independence of the Chief Financial Officer Establishment Act of 2001 (thus, providing for enactment of such Act).Specifies interim rules regarding: (1) the CFO's authority over the Office's personnel and certain other financial personnel; (2) the CFO's authority over contract procurement of goods and services for the Office; and (3) the preparation and submission of the annual budgets of such Office and the Inspector General.States conditions under which reprogramming of amounts in the budget may occur after the adoption of the annual budget for control and non-control fiscal years.Repeals the requirement for D.C. Council approval of contracts exceeding $1 million during a one-year period.Amends the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995 to direct the CFO to: (1) establish a reporting event notification system to monitor the financial performance of the District government, economic trends in the Washington metropolitan area, and other factors affecting the District's financial stability; (2) make a determination, based on such factors, as to whether an event is likely to occur which will result in the initiation of a control period if the District does not take certain actions to respond to the event; and (3) notify the Mayor and Congress upon such determination. Requires the Mayor to develop an action plan to respond to an event upon such a notification.Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) the enactment of the District's budget without congressional approval; (2) the hiring of employees if the positions are authorized by the D.C. Council (currently, only by an Act of Congress); and (3) repeal of specified Federal authority over the District's budget-making process.</summary>
</bill>
