<bill session="106" type="h" number="2940" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense Superfund Liability Relief Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to provide liability relief for small parties, innocent landowners, and prospective purchasers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Sewage sludge"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/1999--Introduced.
Common Sense Superfund Liability Relief Act of 1999 - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to absolve of liability for response actions a person who does not impede a response action or natural resource restoration to the extent liability is based solely on arrangement, transportation, or acceptance provisions relating to disposal or treatment of hazardous substances and such activities only involved municipal solid waste or sewage sludge possessed by the person and the person is: (1) the owner, operator, or lessee of residential property which is the source of the waste or sewage sludge; (2) a small business; or (3) a small nonprofit organization.Adds provisions related to defenses to liability of an owner of property acquired after April 15, 1994, to deem a person to have made (under current law, "undertaken") appropriate inquiry into the property's previous ownership and uses if the person establishes that an environmental site assessment was conducted which meets specified requirements (compliance with an American Society for Testing and Materials standard or with standards issued by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency) and the person fulfills certain responsibilities concerning information compilation, exercise of appropriate care with respect to hazardous substances at the facility, and cooperation with those conducting response actions.Absolves from liability for response actions certain bona fide prospective purchasers or operators of facilities owned by such purchasers to the extent liability at a facility for a release or threat thereof is based solely on ownership or operation of a facility. Gives a lien upon a facility to the United States in any case in which there are unrecovered response costs not inconsistent with the National Contingency Plan incurred by the United States for which the owner is not liable by reason of this section and the action increases the facility's fair market value.</summary>
</bill>
