<bill session="106" type="h" number="1030" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improved Consumer Access to Travel Information Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a commission to study the airline industry and to recommend policies to ensure consumer information and choice.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1999-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1362"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1362"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airline rates"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Travel agents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/1999--Introduced.
Improved Consumer Access to Travel Information Act - Establishes the National Commission to Ensure Consumer Information and Choice in the Airline Industry. Sets forth the Commission's duties, including to: (1) study consumer access to airline industry information on products and services, the effect on consumers of the declining financial condition of travel agents in the United States, and the impediments imposed by the airline industry on distributors of the industry's products and services, including travel agents and Internet-based distributors; and (2) recommend, based on the study results, to the President and Congress policies necessary to ensure full consumer access to complete information concerning airline fares, routes, and other services, that the means of distributing the products and services of the airline industry (including information on such items) is adequate to ensure that competitive information is available in the marketplace, and that distributors of such products and services have adequate relief from illegal, anticompetitive practices that occur in the marketplace. Requires the Commission to report to the President and Congress on the Commission's activities, including any recommendations made by it.</summary>
</bill>
