<bill session="108" type="h" number="3714" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">BSE and Other Prion Disease Prevention and Public Health Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide better protection against bovine spongiform encephalopathy and other prion diseases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2004-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2004-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2004-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2004-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2004-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2004-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2004-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2004-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2004-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2004-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="2007"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Blood banks"/>
    <term name="Bovine spongiform encephalopathy"/>
    <term name="Brain diseases"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cattle"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Cosmetics"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Deer"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elk"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Fertilizers"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Goats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hormones"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Meat packing industry"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Protection of animals"/>
    <term name="Proteins"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/2004--Introduced.
BSE and Other Prion Disease Prevention and Public Health Protection Act - Prohibits the importation of a covered article that: (1) if containing animal-derived material, does not state in English that the covered article contains animal-derived material and the name of the derivative animal, and if a ruminant, identifies the country of origin and states whether specified risk material from the ruminant is or may be part of the covered article; (2) if not containing animal-derived material, does not state in English that the covered article does not contain animal-derived material; and (3) contains animal-derived material from a ruminant that was in any country at a time at which there was a transmission risk of bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE). Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) to promulgate compliance standards. Prohibits the introduction into interstate or foreign commerce of a covered article that contains: (1) specified risk material from a ruminant, or any material from a ruminant that was in any foreign country when there was a BSE transmission risk; or (2) any material from a ruminant exhibiting signs of a neurological disease. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to promulgate compliance standards. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop an enforcement plan for the regulatory ban of certain animal proteins in ruminant feed; (2) promulgate regulations prohibiting same-farm admixing of ruminant and nonruminant feed; (3) annually assess prion disease prevalence and cattle testing in the United States; and (4) in conjunction with the National Prion Disease Pathology Research Center at Case Western Reserve University, expand survey efforts for prion diseases in humans. Directs the Secretary to establish a ruminant identification program capable of tracing, within 48 hours, the movements of disease-exposed animals from birth to slaughter. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture develop programs to: (1) fund the development of the national animal health laboratory network, and expand the network to include all certified Federal, State, and university veterinary diagnostic laboratories; (2) require rapid prion disease screening tests on nonambulatory ruminants, and on cattle and bison 30 months of age and older and on sheep, goats, deer, and elk 12 months of age and older intended for human consumption; (3) exclude BSE-tested ruminants from animal feed use until test confirmation; (4) expand animal collection by Federal, State, tribal, and local agencies for chronic wasting disease (CWD) testing; (5) require CWD herd certification and interstate movement restrictions for farm raised deer and elk; and (6) increase import inspections. Directs the Secretaries to jointly establish a prion disease task force. Defines: (1) covered article; (2) prion disease; and (3) specified risk material.</summary>
</bill>
