<bill session="105" type="h" number="580" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Federal Government to consider as having arrived on time any sealed bid submitted in response to a solicitation for a procurement of goods or services if the bid was sent by an overnight message delivery service at least two working days before the date specified for receipt of bids.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400554"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on National Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-30">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Express service"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/1997--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act and specified Federal law relating to the armed forces, as both were amended by the Federal Acquisition Streamlining Act of 1994 (Public Law 103-355), to require Federal civilian and military agencies to consider as having arrived on time any sealed bid submitted in response to a solicitation for a procurement of goods or services if the bid was sent by an overnight message delivery system at least two working days before the date specified for receipt of bids.</summary>
</bill>
