<bill session="105" type="h" number="2455" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Railroad Safety Reform Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform the safety practices of the railroad industry, to prevent railroad fatalities, injuries, and hazardous materials releases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="1998-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1998-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="1997-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW09" subcommittee="Railroads" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contractors"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fuel storage"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Locomotives"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Radio"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad equipment"/>
    <term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad rolling stock"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic signs and signals"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Vandalism"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Safety Rulemaking and Enforcement Title II: Grade Crossing Safety Title III: Hours of Service Title IV: Passenger Service Safety Standards Title V: Employee Authority, Certification, and Equipment Railroad Safety Reform Act of 1996 - Title I: Safety Rulemaking and Enforcement - Amends Federal transportation law with respect to railroad safety to direct the Secretary of Transportation to convene an annual conference to determine the most important actions needed to improve railroad safety, and report the results to the Congress. (Sec. 103) Directs the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) to report monthly to specified congressional committees on the status of FRA's safety-related rulemakings and reports. (Sec. 104) Declares that certain railroad power brake safety rules proposed on September 16, 1994, shall take effect as final rules one year after enactment of this Act if before that time the Secretary has not issued all final regulations required by specified law. (Sec. 105) Declares that contingent safety standards contained in certain proposed rules shall take effect if the Secretary has not issued final revised track safety regulations before a specified time. Prescribes additional standards for track inspections and track owner compliance with the Secretary's safety regulations. (Sec. 107) Requires fees imposed on railroad carriers to cover the costs of providing an additional 400 railroad safety inspectors. (Sec. 109) Prohibits a railroad carrier, or an employee of a railroad carrier, from preventing another employee from furnishing, or discharging or disciplining an employee who has furnished, railroad accident and injury information. Sets forth both civil and criminal penalties. Title II: Grade Crossing Safety - Revises grade crossing safety provisions to require each railroad carrier to: (1) establish a toll-free telephone service to receive calls reporting malfunctions of safety equipment, or disabled vehicles blocking railroad tracks, at grade crossings; (2) notify trains operating near a grade crossing of the malfunction or disabled vehicle and contact appropriate public safety officials; and (3) ensure placement of signs at each grade crossing displaying the toll-free telephone information. (Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary to review current local, State, and Federal laws regarding violations of grade crossing signals. Directs the Secretary to develop and make available to State and local governments model State legislation providing for civil or criminal penalties, or both, for violations of grade crossing signals. Title III: Hours of Service - Revises hours of duty limitations for train employees to increase off-duty time requirements. (Sec. 302) Sets forth requirements with respect to: (1) split shifts; (2) employee sleeping quarters; and (3) rotating shifts (including a Secretary of Transportation study of alternative methods of preventing fatigue due to such shifts). (Sec. 306) Includes in the definition of dispatching service employee (thus extending hours of service regulatory coverage to) supervisory train dispatchers, power directors, and other train employees who perform dispatching functions, as well as employees who dispatch trains through control of third rail or pantographic electrical power. (Sec. 307) Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations requiring railroad carriers to develop, in consultation with employees and employee organization representatives, fatigue management plans designed to reduce the fatigue experienced by railroad employees and the likelihood of accidents and injuries caused by fatigue. Requires the Secretary to prescribe such a plan for any railroad carrier which does not submit one, or submits one the Secretary does not approve. Authorizes the Secretary, upon a railroad carrier's request, to waive any Federal hour of service requirements that would prevent a fatigue management plan from achieving the objective of reducing fatigue and enhancing safety. (Sec. 308) Directs the Railroad Safety Advisory Committee to convene a working group to consider what legislative changes might be appropriate with respect to hours of service. Title IV: Passenger Service Safety Standards - Requires all passenger railroad cars to have emergency windows and doors after January 1, 2000. (Sec. 402) Sets forth requirements for: (1) passenger railroad signals; (2) internal and compartmentalized fuel tanks on passenger locomotives; and (3) specified corner posts on passenger cars to improve crashworthiness. (Sec. 405) Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop a model for assessing accident or injury risks on railroad corridors, and compile related information; (2) identify high-priority railroad corridors which shall be required to have positive train control systems; and (3) issue regulations for the use of such systems. Title V: Employee Authority, Certification, and Equipment - Prohibits a railroad carrier from discharging or discriminating against an employee responsible for the inspection or repair of safety-related equipment, track, or structures for refusing to authorize their use because such employee believes they are in hazardous condition and would endanger human life. (Sec. 501) Revises dispute resolution requirements. Requires certification of other safety-related railroad personnel in addition to locomotive engineers. (Sec. 503) Requires each locomotive or cab-forward passenger car from which a train is operated, and each roadway work group or lone roadway worker when working along a railroad's right-of-way, to be equipped with a radio that permits two-way communication with the railroad's dispatcher (or other supervisory official able to communicate with the railroad's locomotive operators and roadway workers).</summary>
</bill>
