<bill session="105" type="h" number="3636" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Africa: Seeds of Hope Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Bill Emerson Humanitarian Trust Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To support sustainable and broad-based agricultural and rural development in sub-Saharan Africa, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="1998-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="1998-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400568" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1998-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400550" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1998-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="1998-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="402626" joined="1998-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400532" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="1998-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="1998-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1998-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1998-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1998-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1998-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1998-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="404996" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="1998-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1998-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1998-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="1998-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1998-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1998-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="1998-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1998-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="1998-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1998-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="1998-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1998-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1998-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1998-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1998-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1998-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1998-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1998-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1998-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1998-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400603" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="1998-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1998-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1998-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1998-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="1998-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1998-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400383" joined="1998-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1998-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1998-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="1998-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="1998-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1998-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-01">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-01">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E588"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry, Resource Conservation and Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG26" subcommittee="Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG27" subcommittee="Forestry, Resource Conservation and Research" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agribusiness"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agricultural productivity"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="International agricultural cooperation"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural poverty"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Small farms"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sustainable agriculture"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban poverty"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Assistance for Sub-Saharan Africa Title II: Worldwide Food Assistance and Agricultural Programs Subtitle A: Non-Emergency Food Assistance Programs Subtitle B: Bill Emerson Humanitarian Trust Act of 1998 Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions Africa: Seeds of Hope Act of 1998 - Declares it to be U.S. policy to support governments of sub-Saharan African countries, U.S. and African nongovernmental organizations, U.S. and African businesses, and international agencies to ensure secure livelihoods and adequate nutrition for all sub-Saharan individuals, through sustainable agricultural and rural development. Title I: Assistance for Sub-Saharan Africa - Directs the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (AID), in providing development assistance under the Africa Food Security Initiative, or any comparable or successor program, to: (1) use resources for programs and projects that improve the food security of children, women, or food-insecure households, or that improve the agricultural productivity, incomes, and marketing of the rural poor in Africa; (2) to solicit and take into consideration the views and needs of intended beneficiaries and program participants during the selection, planning, implementation, and evaluation phases of projects; and (3) ensure that program objectives and interventions are primarily developed and conducted by African and U.S. private and voluntary organizations and other such organizations, including cooperatives and local producer-owned cooperative marketing associations, that have a demonstrated expertise in addressing the needs of the poor, small-scale farmers, entrepreneurs, and rural workers, including women. (Sec. 101) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Administrator of AID should increase resources to the Africa Food Security Initiative, or any comparable or successor program, for FY 2000 and subsequent fiscal years in order to meet the needs of the countries participating in such Initiative. (Sec. 102) Directs the Administrator of AID to provide, through bilateral and multilateral assistance, microenterprise assistance (including credit) to improve the efficiency of agricultural production in sub-Saharan Africa (specifically targeting the needs of women, small-scale farmers, and small rural entrepreneurs). (Sec. 103) Directs the President, acting through the Administrator of AID, to utilize foreign assistance programs and initiatives for sub-Saharan Africa to support producer-owned cooperative marketing associations there, including rural business associations that are owned by farmer shareholders. (Sec. 104) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) should: (1) issue loans, guaranties, and insurance, and utilize existing equity funds and loan and insurance funds, to support agricultural and rural development in sub-Saharan Africa (particularly intermediary organizations that directly serve the needs of women, small-scale farmers, small rural entrepreneurs, and rural producer-owned cooperative marketing associations); and (2) jointly cooperate with AID to ensure that adequate administrative funds are available to carry out such activities. (Sec. 105) Directs the Administrator of AID to develop a comprehensive plan to coordinate the activities of AID-funded international agricultural research centers, U.S. land grant universities, and national agricultural research and extension centers in order that research and extension activities will respond to the needs of small-scale farmers while developing the potential and skills of researchers, extension agents, farmers, and agribusiness persons, and increasing the agricultural productivity, in sub-Saharan Africa. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Administrator of AID: (1) has disproportionately reduced funding for international agriculture and rural development activities and the number of agricultural specialists who carry out such activities; and (2) should devote more resources and staff to such activities. Title II: Worldwide Food Assistance and Agricultural Programs - Subtitle A: Non-Emergency Food Assistance Programs - Sets forth general requirements for the administration of non-emergency assistance programs under title II of the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954. Subtitle B: Bill Emerson Humanitarian Trust Act of 1998 - Bill Emerson Humanitarian Trust Act of 1998 - Amends the Food Security Commodity Reserve Act of 1996 to rename specified provisions of the Food for Development Program as the Bill Emerson Humanitarian Trust Act. (Sec. 212) Includes, as part of the established trust stock of wheat, rice, corn, or sorghum used to meet emergency humanitarian food needs in developing countries, certain funds for Commodity Credit Corporation programs under the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 that are available to acquire such eligible commodities through purchases from producers or in the market to replenish the trust. Authorizes the release of eligible commodities from the trust for emergency food assistance to developing countries, provided such release is at levels consistent with maintaining the long-term value of the trust. Makes permanent the authority for the trust. Subtitle C: International Fund for Agricultural Development - Expresses the sense of the Congress that the United States should maintain its leadership in support for the activities of the International Fund for Agricultural Development (IFAD). (Sec. 221) Directs the Administrator of AID and the Secretary of State to review the effectiveness of the current six-year agreement between AID and the Department of State as it relates to U.S. contributions to IFAD. Directs the Administrator of AID and the Secretary to determine the extent to which the Fund has made progress toward management reforms, self-sufficiency, and poverty reduction in determining the amount of future U.S. contributions to it. Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions - Directs the Administrator of AID to report to the Congress on AID's plans for meeting the goals and objectives of the Africa Food Security Initiative.</summary>
</bill>
