<bill session="107" type="h" number="1099" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-03-22T12:11:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-03-22T12:11:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coast Guard Personnel and Maritime Safety Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Coast Guard Personnel and Maritime Safety Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make changes in laws governing Coast Guard personnel, increase marine safety, renew certain groups that advise the Coast Guard on safety issues, make miscellaneous improvements to Coast Guard operations and policies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2001-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2001-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2001-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T10:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. LoBiondo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1026-1030" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1099.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-21T11:07:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed until March 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-22T12:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1074" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-03-22T12:11:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="58" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 415 - 0 (Roll no. 58).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/21/2001 H1026-1029" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-03-22T12:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-03-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="1214"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Barges"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lighthouses and lightships"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military leave"/>
    <term name="Military promotions"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Naval bases"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Patrol ships"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radio"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Tugboats"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2001--Passed House without amendment.
Coast Guard Personnel and Maritime Safety Act of 2001 - Title I: Personnel Management - Limits the director of the Coast Guard band to the rank of captain (currently, commander).(Sec. 102) Authorizes compensatory absence from duty for Coast Guard military personnel serving at isolated duty stations (currently, at isolated aids to navigation) in certain circumstances.(Sec. 103) Allows a promotion selection board to recommend officers of particular merit for placement at the top of the list of selectees and requires, if approved by the President, placement of those officers (in seniority order) at the top of the list. Requires a survey and report to determine if such placements will improve Coast guard officer retention.Title II: Marine Safety - Amends the Vessel Bridge-to-Bridge Radiotelephone Act to revise requirements regarding the waters on which vessels, dredges, and floating plants must carry a radiotelephone.(Sec. 202) Prohibits the application of the Federal Reports Elimination and Sunset Act of 1995 with respect to specified reports concerning Coast Guard operations and expenditures, summary of marine casualties, user fee activities and amounts, public port conditions, activities of the Federal Maritime Commission, and activities of the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Oil Pollution Research.(Sec. 203) Allows the Coast Guard to borrow a limited amount from the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund when the limit of $50 million in unappropriated funds is inadequate to deal with a discharge or threatened discharge. Mandates repayment to the Fund when, and to the extent that, removal costs are recovered from responsible parties.(Sec. 204) Amends Federal law relating to vessels and seamen to: (1) authorize, in certain circumstances, issuance of interim merchant mariner's documents valid for a period not over 120 days; and (2) exempt, with regard to those employed as entertainment personnel with no duties, including emergency duties, related to navigation or safety of the vessel, crew, cargo, or passengers, a passenger vessel that is not engaged in a foreign voyage from a requirement that a vessel employee have a merchant mariner's document.(Sec. 205) Increases fine limits for negligent vessel operation or interfering with safe vessel operation.Title III: Renewal of Advisory Groups - Renames the Commercial Fishing Industry Vessel Advisory Committee as the Commercial Fishing Industry Vessel Safety Advisory Committee. Extends the Committee's termination date.(Sec. 302) Extends the termination dates of the Houston-Galveston Navigation Safety Advisory Committee, the Lower Mississippi River Waterway Advisory Committee, the Navigation Safety Advisory Council, the National Boating Safety Advisory Council, and the Towing Safety Advisory Committee.Title IV: Miscellaneous - Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation, notwithstanding any other provision of law, to accept, by direct transfer without cost, for use by the Coast Guard primarily for expanded drug interdiction activities required to meet national supply reduction goals, up to seven PC-170 patrol craft from the Department of Defense if it offers to transfer such craft.(Sec. 402) Amends the Ports and Waterways Safety Act to require a commercial vessel to give notification at least 24 hours before entering into U.S. waters. Sets forth information to be contained in such notification.Authorizes denial of entry of a vessel into U.S. waters if: (1) the Secretary has not received notification from the vessel; or (2) the vessel is not in compliance with any other applicable law relating to marine safety, security, or environmental protection.Authorizes the Secretary to direct the operation of any vessel in navigable U.S. waters during hazardous circumstances, including the absence of a pilot required by Federal or State law, weather, casualty, vessel traffic, or the poor condition of the vessel.(Sec. 403) Authorizes the Coast Guard to operate and maintain a Caribbean Support Tender (or similar vessel) to provide technical assistance, including law enforcement training, for foreign coast guards, navies, and other maritime services.(Sec. 404) Amends Federal law to extend the expiration date on the prohibition against new maritime user fees.(Sec. 405) Requires the Coast Guard to: (1) continue to offer assistance to organizations dedicated to Great Lakes lighthouse stewardship; and (2) promptly release information regarding the timing of designations of Coast Guard lighthouses on the Great Lakes as surplus property.(Sec. 406) Directs the Commandant of the Coast Guard to report to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate within 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act on what actions the Coast Guard has taken to implement the recommendations of the National Transportation Safety Board in its Report No. MAR-99-01.(Sec. 407) Authorizes conveyance, without consideration, to the Gulf of Maine Aquarium Development Corporation the Naval Reserve Pier property (exclusive of floating docks) in Portland, Maine. Imposes specified requirements.(Sec. 408) Requires the Coast Guard to: (1) study existing local harbor safety coordinating committees in the United States regarding cooperation with interested groups, organizational models, technological assistance, and recurring resources; and (2) test the feasibility of expanding the harbor safety committee concept to small and medium-sized ports not generally served by such a committee by establishing one or more prototype committees. Makes the Federal Advisory Committee Act inapplicable to harbor safety committees established under any provision of law.(Sec. 409) Authorizes the conveyance of all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to each of the following properties: (1) Coast Guard Slip Point Light Station, located in Clallam County, Washington, to Clallam County, Washington; and (2) the parcel of land on which is situated the Point Pin.AE6os Light, located in Monterey County, California, to the city of Pacific Grove, California. Sets forth terms and conditions.(Sec. 410) Authorizes the Commandant of the Coast Guard to enter into agreements and other arrangements with public and private foreign and domestic entities, to establish partnerships for the performance of work at the Coast Guard Yard, located in Baltimore, Maryland.(Sec. 411) Revises provisions concerning boat safety funding.</summary>
</bill>
