<bill session="105" type="h" number="4158" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Park Enhancement and Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the private ownership and use of certain secondary structures and surplus lands administered as part of any national historical park that are not consistent with the purposes for which the park was established, if adequate protection of natural, aesthetic, recreational, cultural, and historical values is assured by appropriate terms, convenants, conditions, or reservations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400017"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-06">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/1998--Introduced.
National Park Enhancement and Protection Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, under specified conditions and after reviewing and determining that certain National Historical Park structures and lands are secondary structures and surplus lands, to allow private acquisition or use of the structures and lands. Requires the Secretary: (1) before disposing of any secondary structure or surplus land, to allow reacquisition by the original owner of such structure or land by negotiated sale, lease, or use permit; and (2) to report to specified congressional committees on each conveyance, lease, or issuance of a use permit for property under this Act having a total value greater than $150,000, at least 30 days before consummation. Requires amounts in excess of the administrative cost of the sale, lease, or use of the secondary structure or surplus land to be: (1) deposited in a special fund in the Treasury; and (2) available to the Secretary, without further appropriation, for operation, maintenance, or improvement of, or for the acquisition of land or interests therein for, the National Park System unit which generated the proceeds.</summary>
</bill>
