<bill session="106" type="h" number="4514" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rail Merger Reform and Customer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen the standards by which the Surface Transportation Board reviews railroad mergers, and to apply the Federal antitrust laws to rail carriers and railroad transportation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2000-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2000-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E803-804"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Ground Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW10" subcommittee="Ground Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Antitrust actions"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Price fixing"/>
    <term name="Public interest"/>
    <term name="Railroad mergers"/>
    <term name="Railroad rates"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Surface Transportation Board"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2000--Introduced.
Rail Merger Reform and Customer Protection Act - Amends Federal transportation law to condition the Surface Transportation Board's approval of any rail carrier consolidation, merger, or acquisition of control upon a finding that the transaction: (1) will increase competition among rail carriers; (2) will not reduce transportation alternatives available to current railroad customers; (3) will provide additional transportation alternative options for railroad customers; (4) will improve service to customers; and (5) is in conformity with the antitrust laws.Declares that rail carriers and rail transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board shall also be subject to the antitrust laws.Repeals the exemption of rate agreements from the Sherman Act, the Clayton Act, the Federal Trade Commission Act and specified parts of the Wilson Tariff Act (thus subjecting such agreements to Federal antitrust laws). Repeals the mandate that the Federal Trade Commission report to the Board periodically on possible anticompetitive features of approved rate agreements, or agreements submitted for approval, and any organization operating under such agreements.Prohibits a person proceeding against a rail carrier in a complaint before the Board from proceeding against the same rail carrier pursuant to other Federal or State law, and vice versa.Amends the Clayton Act to conform with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
