<bill session="104" type="h" number="1609" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Social Security Act and title 38, United States Code, to provide for sharing of medical information relating to determination of disability between the Social Security Administration and Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Compensation, Pension, Insurance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-08">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Compensation, Pension, Insurance, and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/1995--Introduced.
Amends titles II ( Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) and XVI (Supplemental Security Income Program for the Aged, Blind, and Disabled) of the Social Security Act to require the Commissioner of Social Security , with the approval of the veteran involved, to provide the Secretary of Veterans Affairs with medical information regarding eligibility determinations for disability benefits under such titles. Amends provisions of Federal law relating to veterans to direct the Secretary, when there is an issue of the nature or degree of a disease or disability, to request the Commissioner to provide to the Secretary such medical information obtained when determining the veteran's eligibility under titles II or XVI of the Social Security Act. Requires the Secretary, in those cases where a determination has not been made by the Secretary, to accept the Commissioner's determination regarding the existence of a disability or the nature or degree of such disability for purposes of laws administered by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
