<bill session="104" type="h" number="985" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Domestic Oil and Gas Production Tax Incentive Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide tax incentives to encourage production of oil and gas within the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401774" joined="1995-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1995-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400197" joined="1995-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1995-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="406625" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="1995-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1995-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1995-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E379"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="s" number="447"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depletion allowances"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy tax credits"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Secondary recovery of oil"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Production Credit Title II: Modifications To Percentage Depletion Title III: Other Provisions Domestic Oil and Gas Production Tax Incentive Act - Title I: Production Credit - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a business tax credit for producing crude oil and natural gas from new wells and marginal wells. Provides: (1) a formula for reducing such credit in years in which oil and gas prices increase; and (2) an inflation adjustment for such formula. Allows such credit against the regular and minimum tax. Title II: Modifications to Percentage Depletion - Repeals the net income limitation on percentage depletion for oil and gas properties. Makes all marginal production of domestic crude oil or domestic natural gas eligible for percentage depletion. Revises the percentage depletion rate for such marginal production. Title III: Other Provisions - Allows the election to treat geological and geophysical expenses incurred in connection with the exploration for, or development of, domestic oil or gas as expenses which are not chargeable to capital account. Makes the enhanced oil recovery credit applicable to secondary recovery methods. Allows such credit against the minimum tax. Allows the election of an optional five-year writeoff of intangible drilling costs for minimum tax purposes.</summary>
</bill>
