<bill session="104" type="h" number="831" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-11">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permanently extend the deduction for the health insurance costs of self-employed individuals, to repeal the provision permitting nonrecognition of gain on sales and exchanges effectuating policies of the Federal Communications Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400567"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1995-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1995-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="1995-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-02-08">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-02-14T18:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 104-32.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-02-14T18:04:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="14">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-02-16T14:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 88 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 831 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill shall be considered as read. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T18:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 88 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T18:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 88.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1921-1953" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T18:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 831 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill shall be considered as read. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T18:34:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 88 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T18:34:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Scott McInnis to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T18:34:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T19:47:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 88, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the McDermott substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T21:13:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 831.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T21:13:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T21:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 88, the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means was considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T21:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Stark moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T21:15:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion to recommit the bill to the Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T21:26:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T21:44:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 180 - 245 (Roll no. 149).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1953" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-02-21T21:52:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="150" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 381 - 44 (Roll no. 150).</text>
      <reference ref="CR  H1953" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21T21:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-03-15">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Finance"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-03-20">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Reported to Senate by Senator Packwood with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 104-16. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-03-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="34">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 34.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-03-24">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4532-4559" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="1995-03-24" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-03-24">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment asks for a conference, appoints conferees Packwood; Dole; Roth; Chafee; Grassley; Moynihan; Baucus; Bradley; Moseley-braun.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4559" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T18:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Archer asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T18:13:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3845" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T18:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T18:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gibbons moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T18:15:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion to instruct conferees on the part of the House to agree to Sec. 5 of the Senate amendment, relating to the tax treatment of U.S. citizens who have relinquished their citizenship.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T19:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T19:16:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 193 - 224 (Roll No. 272).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3851-3852" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T19:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28T19:36:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Archer, Crane, Thomas, Gibbons, and Rangel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T14:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 104-92 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3909-3915" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-29T21:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 121 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 831. Waiving all points of order against the conference report and against its consideration. The conference report shall be considered read when called up.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30T12:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 121 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30T12:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Archer brought up conference report H. Rept. 104-92 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 121.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30T12:33:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30T13:40:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30T13:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="1995-03-30T13:40:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4004" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-03-30">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-31">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4974-4980" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-31">
      <text>Cloture motion on the conference report to accompany H.R. 831 presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4979" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-03">
      <text>Cloture on the conference report invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 83-0. Record Vote No: 126.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-03">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1995-04-03" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5029-5047" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-04-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1995-04-03">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1995-04-04">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1995-04-11">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1995-04-11" type="public" number="104-7">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-7.</text>
    </enacted>
    <action datetime="1995-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1222"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="88"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="104" type="hr" number="121"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="34"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="76"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="335"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="442"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="691"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="696"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="697"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1034"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Expatriation"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h182"/>
    <amendment number="h183"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/29/1995--Conference report filed in House.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to make permanent the deduction for health insurance costs of self-employed individuals. Makes such provision effective beginning after December 31, 1993. Increases such deduction from 25 percent to 30 percent effective beginning after December 31, 1994. Repeals provisions that provide for nonrecognition of gain from sales and exchanges certified by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to be necessary or appropriate to effectuate FCC policies regarding ownership and control of radio stations. Makes this amendment effective with respect to sales and exchanges on or after January 17, 1995 (or before such date if the FCC tax certificate is issued on or after that date). States rules for determining whether a contract for sale or exchange was binding before such date and therefore outside the application of this amendment. Treats a contract as non-binding if the sale or exchange, or the material terms of the contract, were contingent, on January 16, 1995, on the issuance of a certificate. Provides that a contract's material terms shall not be treated as contingent on such issuance solely because the terms provide that the sales price would otherwise be increased by an amount not more than ten percent of the sales price. Provides that the rules on nonrecognition of gain from involuntary conversions do not apply, in the case of a C corporation or a partnership in which one or more C corporations own more than 50 percent of the partnership's capital or profits interests at the time of the conversion, if the replacement property or stock is acquired from a related person. Makes such rules applicable to qualified sales or exchanges relating to certain reallocations by the FCC of microwave spectrums for use for personal communications services. Denies the earned income tax credit for individuals who earn more than $2,350 of investment income for a taxable year. Extends, through December 31, 1995, the disallowance of employer deductions of amounts paid or incurred in connection with a group health plan if the plan does not reimburse hospitals for inpatient services provided in New York at the same rate required of licensed commercial insurers for services to individuals not covered by a group health plan. Requires a study and report by the Joint Committee on Taxation of the issues presented by any proposals affecting the taxation of expatriation.</summary>
</bill>
