<bill session="104" type="h" number="748" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Federal Tax Equity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide that individuals who are residents of the District of Columbia shall be exempt from Federal income taxation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental tax relations"/>
    <term name="Internal revenue law"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/1995--Introduced.
District of Columbia Federal Tax Equity Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exempt residents of the District of Columbia from Federal income tax. Exempts District residents from wage withholding requirements and limits the application of estate and gift taxes on such residents. Allows a general business credit for businesses operating in the District of Columbia. Directs the Mayor of the District of Columbia to report to the Congress on studies on: (1) the effects of this Act on District revenues; and (2) the extent to which the revenues of the District are affected by Federal revenues.</summary>
</bill>
