<bill session="106" type="h" number="5025" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Maritime Safety Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 46, United States Code, to require the adoption of response plans for nontank vessels.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cooperative societies"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution control"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution of rivers, harbors, etc."/>
    <term name="Oil pollution of the sea"/>
    <term name="Oil spills and wildlife"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tankers"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Tugboats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2000--Introduced.
Maritime Safety Act of 2000 - Amends Federal shipping law to prohibit any nontank (and non- fishing) vessel over 300 gross tons carrying oil as fuel from operating on U.S. navigable waters without an approved response plan for the prevention, containment, and cleanup of oil spills and for the protection from such a spill of fisheries and wildlife, natural resources, and public and private property. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to issue minimum requirements for such plans. Prescribes procedures for submittal, review, and the Secretary's approval of such plans.Increases the maximum liability of nontank vessels for oil spills to the greater of : (1) $806 (currently $600) per gross ton; or (2) $672,000 (currently $500,000).Requires any passenger vessel, small passenger vessel, and freight vessel (including a foreign vessel) subject to inspection to be equipped with a voyage data recorder of a type prescribed by the Secretary.Requires the Secretary to prescribe regulations for the immediate investigation of responses to marine casualties.Requires certain vessels, including small passenger and towing vessels, to be equipped with a position indicating transponder and an appropriate situation display or other device suitable for accessing information made available by the transponder system.Authorizes the Secretary to prohibit the loading or unloading of a vessel in any port or place subject to U.S. jurisdiction if the vessel is registered in a country that fails to adequately enforce safety standards prescribed by the International Maritime Organization (IMO). Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on: (1) the five such countries with the greatest number of registered vessels detained by the Coast Guard in 1999 for violation of such safety standards; and (2) whether those countries have, since December 31, 1999, adequately enforced such standards.Directs the Secretary to seek to negotiate at the IMO the elimination of single hull bunker tanks on commercial vessels capable of carrying more than 1,000 barrels of fuel on board.</summary>
</bill>
