<bill session="106" type="h" number="5066" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Missile Defense Deployment Criteria Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide deployment criteria for the National Missile Defense system, and to provide for operationally realistic testing of the National Defense system against counter-measures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2000-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2000-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2000-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2000-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2000-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missile defenses"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Intercontinental ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military technology"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2000--Introduced.
National Missile Defense Deployment Criteria Act of 2000 - Amends the National Missile Defense Act of 1999 to allow deployment of a national missile defense system (system) only if: (1) the system is technologically feasible; (2) system cost in relation to other Department of Defense (DOD) priorities will not lead to an overall reduction in national security by reducing resources available for other defense priorities; (3) the system will not diminish overall U.S. national security; (4) the system will not threaten to disrupt relations with U.S. nuclear allies, U.S. European allies, Russia, the People's Republic of China, and other nations; and (5) the threat of a long-range ballistic missile attack from a nation of concern is clearly demonstrated.Prohibits the President from directing DOD to deploy a system unless and until: (1) the President certifies to Congress that the above deployment conditions have been met; and (2) a joint resolution is enacted concurring in the President's certification.(Sec. 4) Prohibits DOD procurement funds from being obligated for a system unless: (1) the President certifies to Congress that adequate system tests have been undertaken to meet identified threats against countermeasures; and (2) a joint resolution is enacted concurring in the President's certification. Outlines procedures for the consideration of each joint resolution.(Sec. 5) Requires the Secretary of Defense to direct the Ballistic Missile Defense Organization to: (1) include specified system countermeasures in system ground and flight testing conducted before the system becomes operational; and (2) determine the extent to which the exoatmospheric kill vehicle and the system can reliably discriminate between warheads and such countermeasures. Directs the Secretary to determine the funding required for fiscal years after 2001 for such countermeasures testing, and to submit such determination to the congressional defense committees. Requires an annual report from the Secretary to Congress on DOD's efforts to establish a program for operationally realistic system testing against countermeasures. Terminate the report requirement when a system becomes operational.Directs the Secretary to have the National Academy of Science establish an independent review panel of scientific and technical experts to assess system countermeasures, the system's operational effectiveness against such countermeasures, and the adequacy of the system's flight testing program. Requires: (1) an evaluation of system testing following such assessment; and (2) an annual report from the panel to the Secretary and Congress on such assessment and evaluation.</summary>
</bill>
