<bill session="104" type="h" number="3117" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to enable the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to improve service-delivery of health care to veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407838"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1996-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1996-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="1996-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1996-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1996-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1996-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1996-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E403"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/1996--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in carrying out responsibilities with respect to the delivery of health care for veterans and their beneficiaries, to establish and operate managed health care plans through a Department of Veterans Affairs health care facility or group of such facilities or through arrangements with public or private entities. Directs the Secretary to prescribe the minimum health care benefits to be provided to veterans enrolled in the plan, which shall include at least those benefits covered under parts A and B of the Medicare Program (title XVIII of the Social Security Act). Authorizes the Secretary to establish cost-sharing requirements for veterans enrolled in such a plan, including premiums, copayments, and deductibles. Requires the director of a Department health care facility to certify, before the operation of a plan at such facility, that sufficient medical care funds have been allotted to such facility to provide the needed services. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS Secretary) to make payments during a year to a Department managed health care plan on behalf of veterans who are Medicare-eligible individuals and are enrolled in the managed health care plan, under similar terms as the HHS Secretary makes payments under Medicare to other eligible managed health care plans. Directs the Secretary to certify to the HHS Secretary each year a list of all Department managed health care plans which conform to the standards required for such payments.</summary>
</bill>
