<bill session="105" type="h" number="3838" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require, in the evaluation of bids and proposals for a contract for the procurement by the Department of Defense of property or services, the consideration of the percentage of work under the contract planned to be performed in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400211"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/1998--Introduced.
Requires the head of a defense agency, in the evaluation of sealed bids and competitive proposals for a defense contract for the procurement of property or services, to: (1) include as a significant evaluation factor the percentage of work under the contract that the bidder or offeror plans to perform in the United States; and (2) assign a high importance to such factor. Requires such agency head to include in such contracts a clause that the contract will be deemed to have been breached if the contractor performs less work in the United States than originally stated in the bid or proposal. Prohibits the renewal of contracts where the percentage of work completed outside the United States exceeds that stated in the bid or proposal. Allows a waiver of such requirements on a case-by-case basis.</summary>
</bill>
