<bill session="104" type="h" number="4204" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Women's Pension Protection Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide comprehensive pension protection for women.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="402762" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400511" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1996-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1996-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Economic and Educational Opportunities, Transportation and Infrastructure, and Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1758"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Divorcees"/>
    <term name="Employee ownership"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Graphs and charts"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
    <term name="Real estate investment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Widowers"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Pension Reform Title II: Protection of Rights of Former Spouses to Pension Benefits Under Certain Government and Government-Sponsored Retirement Programs Title III: Reforms Related to 401(K) Plans Title IV: Modifications of Joint and Survivor Annuity Requirements Title V: Spousal Consent Required for Distributions from Section 401(K) Plans Title VI: Women's Pension Toll-Free Phone Number Title VII: Annual Pension Benefits Statements Comprehensive Women's Pension Protection Act of 1996 - Title I: Pension Reform - Amends the Tax Reform Act of 1986 to apply specified integrated plan nondiscrimination rules to all accrued benefits. Amends the Internal Revenue Code (Code) to repeal the permitted disparity provision with respect to simplified employee pension contributions. (Sec. 102) Applies minimum coverage requirements to a separate line of business employer plan for qualified trust purposes. Establishes a single line of business special rule. (Sec. 103) Sets forth divorce division of pension benefits provisions, including minimum accrued benefits rights for the divorced (nonparticipant) spouse. Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to set forth similar provisions. (Sec. 105) Provides for the continued availability of certain remedies with respect to pre-1985 domestic relations orders. (Sec. 106) Amends the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 to eliminate specified employee-annuitant requirements with respect to a divorced wife's annuity. Title II: Protection of Rights of Former Spouses to Pension Benefits Under Certain Government-Sponsored Retirement Programs - Amends the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 and Federal law to provide for protection of former spouses to railroad and civil service pension benefits. Title III: Reforms Related to 401(K) Plans - Amends the Code to treat 401(K) plan investments in collectibles as distributions. (Sec. 303) Applies a specified limitation on acquisition and holding of employer securities and real property to 401(K) plans. Title IV: Modifications of Joint and Survivor Annuity Requirements - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Code to permit, with respect to specified plans, a qualified joint and two-thirds survivor annuity. Defines such an annuity. Title V: Spousal Consent Required for Distributions from Section 401(K) Plans - Amends the Code to require spousal consent for 401(K) plan distributions. Title VI: Women's Pension Toll-Free Phone Number - Directs the Secretary of Labor to provide for a women's pension toll-free telephone number. Authorizes appropriations. Title VII: Annual Pension Benefits Statements - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require annual pension benefits statements.</summary>
</bill>
