<bill session="107" type="h" number="3548" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for uniform recognition of Indian tribes by the Bureau of Indian Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2001-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2001-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400508" joined="2001-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2001-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2340"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Attorneys general"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Decision making in public administration"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2001--Introduced.
Sets forth procedures regarding the submission and notification of letters of intent by Indian tribes seeking acknowledgment or recognition under Federal law. Provides that petitioning tribes must first submit letters of intent to the Secretary of the Interior. Makes the Governor, the Attorney General, and each municipality located within the vicinity interested parties in the review.Requires the Secretary to: (1) determine when a petition is complete and ready for acknowledgment review, notify the petitioner and all interested parties, and publish notice in the Federal Register; and (2) provide a reasonable period for comment.Directs the Secretary of the Interior to provide grants to assist local governments in participating in the decision making process related to the following actions if the Secretary determines that such actions are likely to significantly affect the people represented by the local governments and to reimburse such governments for the costs of such participation: (1) an Indian group is seeking Federal acknowledgment or recognition (or re-acknowledgment or recognition) and the Secretary determines that such group is located within or adjacent to the area under the local government's jurisdiction, or has asserted or is likely to seek trust status with respect to land within the area over which the local government has jurisdiction; (2) an acknowledged tribe is requesting that land within or adjacent to the area over which the local government has jurisdiction be put into trust status for it; and (3) an Indian group or an acknowledged tribe is claiming, or is expected to claim, interest in land based upon a treaty or law specifically applicable to land or natural resource transfers from, by, or on behalf of Indians. Permits the making of grants also to reimburse local governments for activities that were undertaken before the enactment of this Act.Directs the Secretary to provide grants to local governments to assist them with activities related to infrastructure, public safety, or social services that are made necessary or prudent as a result of a federally-recognized tribe's activities.</summary>
</bill>
