<bill session="105" type="h" number="2329" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Dividend Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish The National Dividend Plan by reforming the budget process, and by amending the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to eliminate the double tax on dividends, to allocate corporate income tax revenues for payments to qualified registered voters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400085"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1997-09-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2225"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dividend tax"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax rebates"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Unrelated business income tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/1997--Introduced.
National Dividend Act of 1997 - Establishes a program for the distribution of certain corporate tax revenues, through the chief financial officer of each State, to the registered voters of each State in the form of dividend payments. Establishes in the Treasury the National Dividend Payment Trust Fund. Authorizes payment into the Fund of specified amounts from: (1) the corporate income tax; (2) the tax on the unrelated business income of certain tax-exempt organizations; (3) the capital gains tax; (4) the tax on insurance company income; and (5) the alternative minimum tax on corporations. Establishes a National Dividend Review Board to review the manner in which payments are made from the Fund and to invest Fund amounts. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income all dividend income received by a taxpayer from domestic corporations, including dividends received under this Act. Increases the corporate income tax deduction for dividends received by a corporation on the preferred stock of a public utility. Prohibits corporate income tax rates from exceeding 34 percent. Amends the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to declare it out of order in either the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider budget resolutions for FY 1999 and thereafter that would increase the level of total budget outlays beyond those budgeted for FY 1998. Requires a two-thirds vote of each House of the Congress to increase the internal revenue, except if there is a: (1) declaration of war; or (2) military conflict causing an imminent and serious threat to national security and a joint resolution declaring so has been adopted.</summary>
</bill>
