<bill session="105" type="h" number="4180" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Fisheries Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce fishing capacity in United States fisheries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1998-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1998-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-07">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Foreign fishing"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/1998--Introduced.
American Fisheries Act of 1998 - Revokes permanently all licenses, permits, and other fishing privileges that have the effect of allowing specified vessels that "are not vessels of the United States" (Subject Fishing Vessels) to operate in U.S. fisheries, as well as any fishing history of such vessels. Exempts from such revocation, until December 31, 2001, the operation of such vessels in the Bering Sea pollock fishery and the Pacific whiting fishery. Mandates a fish harvesting moratorium for large fishing vessels in the U.S. exclusive economic zone until approval and implementation of a fishery management plan (developed by either the Secretary of Commerce, a regional fishery management council, or an interstate marine fishery management commission) specifically authorizing large fishing vessels to harvest fish in such zone. Declares such moratorium inapplicable to any fishing vessel engaged exclusively in a fishery conducted primarily outside the U.S. exclusive economic zone.</summary>
</bill>
