<bill session="107" type="h" number="2983" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-11-27T16:07:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-11-27T16:07:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Price-Anderson Reauthorization Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Price-Anderson Reauthorization Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Price-Anderson Reauthorization Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend indemnification authority under section 170 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400434"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2001-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2001-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2001-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400139" joined="2001-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2001-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2001-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="2001-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2001-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-03">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-10-31">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-11-19T17:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on 107-299, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-19">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Science for a period ending not later than Nov. 20, 2001 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(n), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-20T16:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Science discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-11-20T16:20:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="180">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 180.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-11-27T15:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Barton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-27T15:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8358-8367" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-27T15:29:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2983.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-11-27T16:07:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8358-8360" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-11-27T16:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-11-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="240">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 240.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate corruption"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for nuclear damages"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Location of industries"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear industry"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plant accidents"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Sabotage"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Suicide"/>
    <term name="Supervisors"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/27/2001--Passed House amended.
Price-Anderson Reauthorization Act of 2001 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to extend from 2002 to 2017 the indemnification authority of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) and the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) with respect to certain licensees, Department of Energy (DOE) contractors, and nonprofit educational institutions, respectively.(Sec. 3) Increases the maximum amount of standard deferred premium that may be assessed a licensee following a nuclear incident.(Sec. 4) Specifies $10 billion as the aggregate amount by which the Secretary must indemnify DOE contractors above the amount of the financial protection required for each nuclear incident.(Sec. 5) Increases from $100 million to $500 million the indemnification limits for incidents outside the United States.(Sec. 6) Sets a deadline for status reports to Congress regarding contractor indemnification and limitation of liability.(Sec. 7) Requires an inflation adjustment to the indemnification limits at least once every five years.(Sec. 8) Instructs the NRC to consider a combination of modular reactors at a single site, each of which has between 100,000 and 300,000 electrical kilowatts (but a combined rated capacity of no more than 1.3 million kilowatts), as a single facility having a rated capacity of 100,000 electrical kilowatts or more.(Sec. 10) Prohibits any Federal contract or other arrangement which would impose liability on the U.S. Government for nuclear accidents occurring in connection with the design, construction, or operation of a production facility or utilization facility in any foreign country whose government has been identified as engaged in State sponsorship of terrorist activities (including certain governments identified by the Secretary of State to have repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism).(Sec.11) Instructs the NRC to establish a system to ensure: (1) that specified nuclear materials transferred or received from certain licensees and facilities be accompanied by a manifest describing the type and amount of such materials; (2) each individual transferring or accompanying the transfer of such materials has been subject to a security background check by Federal entities; and (3) such materials are not transferred to or received at a destination other than specified licensed facilities.(Sec. 12) Instructs the President to study and report to Congress on threats to NRC-licensed facilities and Federal actions taken to address them.Instructs the NRC to establish an operational safeguards response evaluation program that ensures that the physical protection capability and operational safeguards response for sensitive nuclear facilities shall be tested periodically through NRC approved or designed, observed, and evaluated force-on-force exercises to determine whether the ability to defeat the design basis threat is being maintained.(Sec. 13) Mandates that the Secretary issue industrial health and safety regulations applicable to contractors and subcontractors at DOE nuclear facilities that: (1) provide worker health and safety protection substantially equivalent to or identical to certain industrial and construction safety regulations of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration; and (2) establish civil penalties substantially equivalent to or identical to those applicable to violations of the industrial and construction safety regulations of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration.(Sec. 14) Requires the NRC, before entering into an indemnification agreement with respect to a utilization facility, to consult with the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security regarding whether the facility location and design ensure that it provides adequate public health and safety protection if subjected to a terrorist attack.(Sec. 15) Authorizes the Attorney General to bring a Federal action to recover amounts paid by the Federal Government under an indemnification agreement for public liability resulting from intentional misconduct of any corporate officer, manager, or superintendent of a DOE contractor (or subcontractor or supplier).(Sec. 16) Repeals the requirement that the Secretary determine by rule whether nonprofit educational institutions should receive automatic remissions of civil monetary penalties for violations of DOE regulations.Repeals the blanket liability exemption from civil money penalties for violations of DOE safety regulations granted to: (1) the University of Chicago for activities associated with Argonne National Laboratory; (2) The University of California for activities associated with Los Alamos National Laboratory, Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory, and Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory; (3) American Telephone and Telegraph Company for activities associated with Sandia National Laboratories; (4) Universities Research Association, Inc. for activities associated with FERMI National Laboratory; (5) Princeton University for activities associated with Princeton Plasma Physics Laboratory; (6) the Associated Universities, Inc. for activities associated with the Brookhaven National Laboratory; and (7) Battelle Memorial Institute for activities associated with Pacific Northwest Laboratory.Subjects certain tax-exempt contractors, subcontractors, and suppliers to such civil penalties, but limited to the amount of any discretionary fee paid to them.</summary>
</bill>
