<bill session="105" type="h" number="2231" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Coal Act Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a sound budgetary mechanism for financing health and death benefits of retired coal miners while ensuring the long-term fiscal health and solvency of such benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400327"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1998-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1997-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1997-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="1998-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1997-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1997-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1997-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1997-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="1997-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1997-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1997-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1997-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1997-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400602" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1997-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="1997-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1997-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1997-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="1997-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1998-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="1105"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/1997--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Assignment of Liability to Coal Operators Title II: Adjustments to Premium Computations Title III: Other Provisions Comprehensive Coal Act Reform Act - Title I: Assignment of Liability to Coal Operators - Amends Internal Revenue Code provisions concerning coal industry health benefits to define "signatory operator" to mean a person that is or was a signatory to the 1978 National Bituminous Coal Wage Agreement or any subsequent coal wage agreement. (Currently, the term is defined as a person that is or was a signatory to a coal wage agreement. The term "coal wage agreement" is, and would continue to be, defined as the National Bituminous Coal Wage Agreement or any other agreement between a coal industry employer and the United Mine Workers of America having specified requirements.) (Sec. 102) Requires: (1) that each eligible coal industry retiree be assigned first to the signatory operator that most recently employed the retiree for at least two years, then to the signatory operator that was the most recent to employ the operator; and (2) revocation of the assignment of any beneficiary to anyone who ceases to be a signatory operator because of the above change in definition, not reassigning the beneficiary, and considering them to be unassigned. Prohibits assigning or reassigning a beneficiary after enactment of this Act, treating as unassigned any beneficiary determined to have been incorrectly assigned. Title II: Adjustments to Premium Computations - Modifies the formula for determining the per beneficiary premium. (Sec. 202) Provides for: (1) annual premium reductions for small reachback signatory operators; and (2) the treatment of a surplus or deficit in the Combined Fund. (Sec. 203) Sets separate requirements for death benefit premiums for reachback signatory operators and other assigned operators. Modifies: (1) requirements regarding the unassigned beneficiaries premium; (2) the definition of "applicable percentage" and (3) requirements regarding applicable premium annual adjustments. Mandates establishment of a separate subaccount in the death benefits premium account for each of: (1) the death benefit premiums of reachback signatory operators; (2) the death benefit premiums of other assigned operators; and (3) the portion of the unassigned beneficiaries premiums attributable to death benefits coverage of unassigned beneficiaries. (Sec. 204) Sets forth a special rule regarding annual premium payment by a related person of an assigned operator. Title III: Other Provisions - Modifies requirements regarding certain 1988 agreement operators paying withdrawal liability. (Sec. 302) Requires the Combined Fund to make available to any person required to make contributions to that Fund all documents: (1) that reflect the Fund's financial and operational status; and (2) prepared at the request of the Fund's trustees or staff that form the basis for any actions or reports.</summary>
</bill>
