<bill session="104" type="h" number="1781" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the continuation of the operations of the California Urban Environmental Research and Education Center.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1995-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1995-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1995-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1995-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-07">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-07">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1196"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Conversion of industries"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industry-university relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/1995--Introduced.
Stipulates that if the California State University, Hayward, matches 20 percent of the funds that the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency provides to the California Urban Environmental Research and Education Center, the Administrator shall enter into a series of cooperative agreements with the University to provide continuing support for the Center. Declares the overall objective of the center to be to promote sustainable economic development throughout California by engaging in specified functions, including: (1) developing an ongoing program of applied environmental research, education, and outreach that the Federal, State, and local governments and the private sector can use; (2) fostering of public-private partnerships to find solutions to environmental problems of California; (3) bringing together university and college researchers to focus on California's most important environmental problems; (4) supporting activities such as the coordination and funding of research activities for the collection and evaluation of data, the conduct of seminars and educational programs, the conduct of a national conference, and the development of bachelors and masters degree programs to prepare individuals for employment as environmental professionals; and (5) working with other university research centers provided funds by EPA to help establish a National Environmental Outreach Program to assist governments and the private sector in programs to promote environmentally sound economic development. Authorizes the Center to provide undergraduate scholarships for individuals studying in environmental fields, assistantships and fellowships for graduate students to encourage study in fields related to sustainable economic development, and research grants to faculty at universities and colleges. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
