<bill session="105" type="h" number="4533" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Long-Term Care Hospital Payment Correction Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to rectify overpayment to certain long-term care hospitals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-09-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1668"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Long-term care facilities"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/1998--Introduced.
Medicare Long-Term Care Hospital Payment Correction Act of 1998 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with regard to calculation of the payment to long-term care hospitals for the operating costs of inpatient hospital services. Requires adjustment, according to a specified formula, of the target amount for such a hospital if the average inpatient length of stay for the two most recent settled cost reporting periods is five percent less than the average inpatient length of stay for the initial 12-month cost reporting period (base year) (thus correcting for overpayments to such hospitals). Amends the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in developing a legislative proposal for establishing a case-mix adjusted prospective payment system for payment of certain long-term care hospitals under Medicare, to consider adjustments in the amount of payments to long-term care hospitals whose average inpatient length of stay during the base year greatly exceeds the hospitals' average inpatient length of stay in later years.</summary>
</bill>
