<bill session="106" type="h" number="1994" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business and Financial Institutions Tax Relief Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand S corporation eligibility for banks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400265"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1999-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="1999-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400501" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="1999-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400540" joined="1999-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank directors"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate debt"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Debt"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family enterprises"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stockholders' voting"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax preferences"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/1999--Introduced.
Small Business and Financial Institutions Tax Relief Act of 1999 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit S corporation eligible shareholders to include individual retirement accounts (IRAs). (Sec. 2) Exempts from prohibited transaction rules any sale of stock in an IRA pursuant to a small business corporation's election to be an S corporation. (Sec. 3) Excludes from the definition of passive income for purposes of S status termination any interest income earned by or dividends on assets required to be held by a bank, a bank holding company, or a qualified subchapter S subsidiary bank. (Sec. 4) Increases from 75 to 150 the maximum number of shareholders a small business organization may have to be eligible to elect S corporation treatment. (Sec. 5) States that stock held by a bank director as required by banking regulations (director qualifying stock) shall not be considered a disqualifying second class of S corporation stock. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to modify a certain regulation to permit an S corporation bank to treat certain bad debt deductions as built-in losses during the entire period during which the bank recognized built-in gains from changing its accounting method for recognizing bad debts from the reserve method to the charge-off method. (Sec. 7) Includes all banks within the three-year deduction preference rule. (Sec. 8) Makes family limited partnerships eligible to be S corporation shareholders. (Sec. 9) Permits the issuance of qualified preferred stock, which shall not be treated as second class stock. Makes any distribution (not in payment in exchange for stock) made by an S corporation with respect to qualified preferred stock includible as ordinary income of the holder and deductible to the corporation as an expense. (Sec. 10) Reduces from 100 percent to 90 percent the percentage of shares held by shareholders necessary for consent to election by a small business organization to be an S corporation. Prescribes rules for such consent. (Sec. 11) Revises exceptions to the criteria for the treatment of certain wholly owned subchapter S subsidiaries with reference to required information returns.</summary>
</bill>
