<bill session="108" type="h" number="2955" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rio Grande Outstanding Natural Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Rio Grande Outstanding Natural Area in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400265"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400020" joined="2003-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2003-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1467"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2003--Introduced.
Rio Grande Outstanding Natural Area Act - Establishes the Rio Grande Outstanding Natural Area, which shall consist of specified land along the Rio Grande River in southern Colorado from the southern boundary of the Alamosa National Wildlife Refuge to the Colorado-New Mexico State line, encompassing the River and its adjacent riparian areas. Establishes the Rio Grande Outstanding Natural Area Commission to assist Federal, State, and local authorities in the development and implementation of an integrated resource management plan for the Area, which shall coordinate existing Federal, State, and local plans. Directs the Commission, upon approval of the plan by the Secretary of the Interior, to assist the Secretary in implementing the plan by taking steps to preserve and interpret the natural resources of the Area and its surrounding area. Provides that the plan will be binding on private lands within the Area only if the landowner agrees. Permits the Secretary to acquire land within the Area from willing sellers only. Terminates the Commission ten years and six months after the enactment of this Act. Prohibits the Secretary or any other Federal agency from approving or issuing any permit or providing any assistance for construction of any new dam, reservoir, or impoundment on any segment of the Rio Grande River or its tributaries within the Area's exterior boundaries. Revokes all reservations of public lands within the Area for Federal purposes that have been made by an Act of Congress or executive order and restores such lands to public land status. Withdraws all public lands within the Area from settlement, sale, location, entry, or disposal under public land laws. Prohibits any Area land or water from being designated as a wild, scenic, or recreational river.</summary>
</bill>
