<bill session="106" type="h" number="1210" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for continued compensation for Federal employees when funds are not otherwise available due to a lapse in appropriations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400438"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Municipal employees"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1999--Introduced.
Prohibits the right of a Government employee to be compensated for any period, at such employee's regular rate of compensation, from being abrogated, diminished, or otherwise affected with respect to an officer or employee of the U.S. Government or of the District of Columbia government who is furloughed as a result of a lapse in appropriations. Appropriates necessary funds for such compensation for any period of lapsed appropriations and provides that expenditures shall be charged to the applicable appropriation when enacted. Requires furloughed officers and employees to be compensated at the regular rate of compensation for the period of the furlough.</summary>
</bill>
