<bill session="107" type="h" number="5422" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-08T12:00:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-08T12:00:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Enhance AMBER Alert bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Abduction Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Child Abduction Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent child abduction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="2002-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400168" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400202" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400212" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2002-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="2002-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400393" joined="2002-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Armed Services, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-01">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-10-02">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 107-723, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Transportation Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 8, 2002.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 8, 2002.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Education and the Workforce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 8, 2002.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T14:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T14:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7048-7053" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T14:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5422.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-07T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-08T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7187" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-10-08T12:00:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="446" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 390 - 24 (Roll no. 446).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/7/2002 H7048-7050" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-10-08T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bail"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Community policing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Courts-martial and courts of inquiry"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forensic medicine"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Missing children"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Sex-oriented businesses"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Traffic signs and signals"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2002--Passed House amended.
Child Abduction Prevention Act - Title I: Sanctions and Offenses - (Sec. 101) Amends the Federal criminal code to make the authorized term of supervised release after imprisonment for kidnaping involving a victim under age 18, sexual abuse, sexual exploitation of children, transportation for illegal sexual activity, or sex trafficking of children any term of years or life .(Sec. 102) Includes aggravated child abuse and child torture murders within the scope of the definition of first degree murder.(Sec. 103) Increases: (1) maximum and minimum penalties for sexual exploitation and other abuse of children; and (2) penalties for transportation for illegal sexual activity and related crimes.(Sec. 104) Directs the United States Sentencing Commission to increase penalties for kidnaping. Amends the code to increase the minimum mandatory sentence for kidnaping involving children.(Sec. 105) Prohibits: (1) traveling in or into the United States for the purpose of engaging in an illicit sexual act with another (currently, with a juvenile); (2) traveling in foreign commerce and engaging in such sexual conduct; and (3) arranging or facilitating such travel knowing its purpose. Makes attempts or conspiracies punishable in the same manner as a completed violation. Establishes as a defense that the defendant reasonably believed that the person with whom the defendant engaged in commercial sex had attained age 18.(Sec. 106) Provides for mandatory life imprisonment of a person convicted of a Federal sex offense in which a minor is the victim if the person has a prior sex conviction in which a minor was the victim, unless a death sentence is imposed.Title II: Investigations and Prosecutions - Subtitle A: Law Enforcement Tools To Protect Children - (Sec. 201) Authorizes the interception of wire, oral, or electronic communications in the investigation of: (1) sexual exploitation of children; (2) selling or buying children; (3) certain activities relating to material involving the sexual exploitation of minors, and constituting or containing child pornography; and (4) transportation for illegal sexual activity.(Sec. 202) Eliminates statutes of limitations for child abduction and for felony offenses of sexual abuse, sexual exploitation and other abuse of children, transportation for illegal sexual activity, or sex trafficking of children or by force.Subtitle B: No Pretrial Release for Those Who Rape or Kidnap Children - Bars pretrial release for persons charged with such offenses..Subtitle C: No Waiting Period To Report Missing Children ("Suzanne's Law") - Amends the Crime Control Act of 1990 to require each Federal, State, and local law enforcement agency to report each case of a missing child under age 21 (currently, 18) reported to it to the Department of Justice's (DOJ) National Crime Information Center.Subtitle D: Record-keeping to Demonstrate Minors Were Not Used in Production of Pornography - Directs the Attorney General to report to Congress: (1) detailing the number of times since January 1993 that DOJ has inspected the records of any producer of sexually explicit materials; and (2) indicating the number of violations prosecuted as a result of those inspections.Title III: Public Outreach - (Sec. 301) Directs the Attorney General to assign a DOJ officer to act as national coordinator of the AMBER Alert communications network regarding abducted children (to be known as the AMBER Alert Coordinator of DOJ).(Sec. 302) Requires the Coordinator to establish minimum standards for the issuance of alerts and the extent of alert dissemination.(Sec. 303) Directs: (1) the Secretary of Transportation to provide grants to States for the development or enhancement of notification or communications systems along highways for alerts for the recovery of abducted children; and (2) the Attorney General to carry out a program to provide grants to States for the development or enhancement of programs and activities for the support of AMBER Alert communications plans. Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Transportation for FY 2003 to carry out this section.(Sec. 305) Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to increase authorized appropriations for the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children.(Sec. 306) Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the use of COPS ("Cops on the Beat"; community policing) grants to assist a State in enforcing a law that requires that a convicted sex offender register his or her address with a State or local law enforcement agency and be subject to criminal prosecution for failure to comply.Title IV: Miscellaneous - Amends the Federal criminal code to authorize the Secret Service, under the direction of the Secretary of the Treasury and at the request of any State or local law enforcement agency or the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, to provide forensic and investigative assistance in support of investigations involving missing or exploited children.</summary>
</bill>
