<bill session="106" type="h" number="1642" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Parental Consent Drug Testing and Counseling Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require local educational agencies to develop and implement a random drug testing and counseling program for students in grades 9 through 12.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Amphetamines"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Cocaine"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Marijuana"/>
    <term name="Opium"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Phencyclidine"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="State aid to education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/1999--Introduced.
Parental Consent Drug Testing and Counseling Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to State educational agencies (SEAs) to enable each local educational agency (LEA) to develop and implement a random drug testing and counseling program on school premises for students in grades nine through 12.Authorizes parents to determine whether their children participate in such programs.Sets forth requirements for State and local allocations and administrative costs.Requires LEAs receiving grants to make certain certifications to SEAs.Sets forth required and optional uses of grant funds.Requires LEAs receiving such grant funds to inform parents about: (1) the random drug testing program, in detail; (2) their option to enroll their child in such program; (3) the counseling program and the services it offers; (4) any positive results of a drug test of their child who participates in the program; and (5) the refusal of their child to take a drug test or participate in the counseling program, if applicable. Requires such LEAs to provide for confidentiality of drug test results.Authorizes appropriations.Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require any LEA that receives ESEA funds to implement a drug testing and counseling program that meets the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
