<bill session="108" type="h" number="2050" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Universal Jurisdiction Rejection Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit cooperation with or assistance to any investigation or prosecution under a universal jurisdiction statute.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2003-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Extraterritoriality"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2003--Introduced.
Universal Jurisdiction Rejection Act of 2003 - Declares that it is the policy of the United States to reject any foreign government's claim of universal jurisdiction and to refuse to assist any such government pursuing an investigation or prosecution under a universal jurisdiction act. Defines "universal jurisdiction act" as a statute of a foreign country that authorizes the investigation, prosecution, and punishment of genocide and other crimes that were not committed by or against citizens of such country, did not occur on the territory of such country, and are otherwise prosecutable by tribunals established by the United Nations Security Council. Prohibits Federal, State and local government agencies, including any courts, from providing assistance to any investigation or prosecution by a foreign government under a universal jurisdiction act. Directs the Federal Government to exercise its rights under mutual legal assistance treaties to deny assistance to any investigation or prosecution under a universal jurisdiction act. Prohibits foreign agents from pursuing any investigation or prosecution under a universal jurisdiction act in the United States. Directs the President to ensure implementation of procedures to prevent the transfer directly or indirectly of classified national security information to foreign governments that is relevant to any investigation or prosecution under a universal jurisdiction act. Allows the President to waive certain prohibitions under this Act. Authorizes the President to use all means, including legal assistance, but not financial incentives, to secure the release of U.S. citizens and citizens of allies of the United States who are being detained or imprisoned by an investigation or prosecution under a universal jurisdiction act.</summary>
</bill>
