<bill session="107" type="h" number="5314" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small and Disadvantaged Business Ombudsman Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a Small and Disadvantaged Business Ombudsman for Procurement in the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400438"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2002-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400532" joined="2002-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2002-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2002-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2002-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2002-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2002-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="2753"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2002--Introduced.
Small and Disadvantaged Business Ombudsman Act - Amends the Small Business Act to require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to designate a Small and Disadvantaged Business Ombudsman for Procurement, who shall: (1) work with each Federal agency with procurement authority to ensure that small businesses are treated fairly in the procurement process; (2) establish a procedure for receiving comments from small businesses and personnel of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization (Office) of each Federal agency regarding the activities of agencies and prime contractors on Federal procurement contracts for small businesses; and (3) establish a procedure for addressing concerns received with respect to small businesses and Federal procurement contracting. Requires an annual report from the Ombudsman to the congressional small business committees evaluating such activities.Requires each Federal agency to assist the Ombudsman to ensure compliance with Federal procurement goals for small businesses, certain procurement policies, and Federal prime contractor small business subcontracting plans. Requires a Federal agency to submit a goal attainment plan upon failure to meet small business procurement goals.Requires each Office director to: (1) have experience assisting small businesses with Federal procurement; (2) not currently serve as the chief procurement officer of such agency; (3) have no other duties; and (4) attend meetings of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization Council. Establishes such Council.Increases, from the current 23 percent to up to 30 percent for FY 2006 and thereafter, the Federal small business procurement goal.</summary>
</bill>
