<bill session="104" type="hc" number="123" updated="2012-11-01T22:45:35-05:00">
  <state datetime="1996-01-22">PASSED:CONCURRENTRES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the provisional approval of regulations applicable to certain covered employing offices and covered employees and to be issued by the Office of Compliance before January 23, 1996.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19T17:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19T17:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (CR H15155-15156)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15155-15156" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19T17:15:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-12-19T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-22">
      <text>Senate Committee on Rules discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="PASSED:CONCURRENTRES" datetime="1996-01-22">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment by Voice Vote. (CR S284)</text>
      <reference ref="CR S284" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-01-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>12/19/1995--Introduced.
Approves, on a provisional basis until approved in accordance with the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, the regulations to be issued by the Office of Compliance before January 23, 1996, applicable to employing offices which are not the House of Representatives or the Senate and their covered employees.</summary>
</bill>
