<bill session="104" type="h" number="295" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to enter into agreements with certain cities and counties for the withholding of city and county income and employment taxes from the pay of Federal employees who are residents of, or regularly employed in, such cities and counties.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1996-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources and Intergovernmental Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO04" subcommittee="Human Resources and Intergovernmental Relations" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental tax relations"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Municipal taxation"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Amends Federal law with respect to the Secretary of the Treasury's authority to enter into agreements with certain cities and counties for the withholding of city and county income and employment taxes from the pay of Federal employees who are residents of, or regularly employed in, such cities and counties. Repeals the limitation of such authority to cities and counties with 500 or more persons regularly employed by all agencies of the Federal Government (thus authorizing the Secretary to enter into such agreements with cities and counties with fewer than 500 Federal employees).</summary>
</bill>
