<bill session="105" type="h" number="2399" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-09-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Investment Package</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide assistance for low-income working families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400532"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child care block grants"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Working poor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/4/1997--Introduced.
Family Investment Package - Amends the Child Care Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to increase the authorization of appropriations for FY 1997 through 2002 for block grants to States for child care assistance for low-income working families. Authorizes separate appropriations for such period for grants to States for specified child care activities in geographic areas with child care supply shortages. Authorizes appropriations in a specified amount to the Secretary of Health and Human Services for FY 1997 through 2002 to award grants to States for providing child care services for families who have left the State program of assistance under part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) of title IV of the Social Security Act because of employment, families that are at risk of becoming dependent on such assistance program, and low-income working families. Requires States and the Secretary to report on access to child care by low-income working families.</summary>
</bill>
