<bill session="106" type="h" number="2906" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sudan Peace Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate famine relief efforts and a comprehensive solution to the war in Sudan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400541"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1999-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1999-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1999-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2000-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="2000-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="1999-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="1999-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2000-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2000-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1999-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>For Further Action See S.1453.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA08" subcommittee="Africa" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1453"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Aerial bombing"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Derivative securities"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Islamic fundamentalism"/>
    <term name="Kenya"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Opposition (Political science)"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Switzerland"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/1999--Introduced.
Sudan Peace Act - Declares that Congress: (1) condemns violations of human rights on all sides of the conflict in Sudan (including the Government of Sudan), the ongoing slave trade there, and the Government's increasing use and organization of "murahalliin", Popular Defense Forces (PDF), and regular Sudanese Army units into raiding and slaving parties in Bahr al Ghazal, the Nuba Mountains, Upper Nile, and Blue Nile regions; and (2) recognizes that the use of raiding and slaving parties is a tool for creating food shortages as a systematic means to destroy the societies, culture, and economies of the Dinka and Nuba peoples in a policy of low-intensity ethnic cleansing.(Sec. 5) Expresses the sense of Congress that it: (1) declares its support for the efforts by U.S. executive branch officials to lead in a reinvigoration of the Inter-Governmental Authority on Development (IGAD)-sponsored peace process; (2) calls on IGAD member states, the European Union, the Organization of African Unity, Egypt, and other key states to support such process; (3) urges Kenya's leadership in the implementation of the process; and (4) views any such diplomatic efforts toward resolution of the conflict in Sudan are best made through IGAD and that the President must not create any process which could be viewed as a parallel or competing diplomatic track.Authorizes the Secretary of State to utilize Department of State personnel for the support of: (1) the secretariat of IGAD; (2) the ongoing negotiations between the Government of Sudan and opposition forces; (3) any peace settlement planning to be carried out by the National Democratic Alliance and IGAD Partners' Forum (IPF); and (4) other U.S. diplomatic efforts with respect to Sudan.(Sec. 6) Expresses the sense of Congress that the President, acting through the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations, should take specified actions to increase pressure on the combatants involved in the war in Sudan.(Sec. 7) Imposes certain trade and financial sanctions against Sudan, subject to waiver on national security grounds, until the President determines, and certifies to Congress, that it has: (1) fully committed to and has made progress toward a peaceful solution to the war or has otherwise committed in a good faith effort with both northern and southern opposition toward a solution to the conflict based on the Declaration of Principles reached in Nairobi, Kenya, on July 20, 1994; (2) made substantial progress in controlling the raiding and slaving activities of all regular and irregular forces, including PDF and other militias and murahalliin; (3) instituted reforms with regard to providing basic human and civil rights to all Sudanese; and (4) ceased aerial bombardment of civilian targets.Declares that it is the sense of Congress that such sanctions should be applied to include the sale of stocks in the United States or to any U.S. person, wherever located, or any other form of financial instruments or derivatives, in support of a commercial, industrial, public utility, or government project or transaction in or with Sudan.(Sec. 8) Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should organize and maintain a formal consultative process with the European Union, the United Nations Security Council, and other relevant parties on coordinating an effort within the UN to revise the terms of Operation Lifeline Sudan (OLS) to end the Government of Sudan's veto power over OLS plans for air transport relief flights.(Sec. 9) Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should continue to increase the use of non- OLS agencies in the distribution of relief supplies in southern Sudan.(Sec. 10) Directs the President to develop and report to Congress on a contingency plan to provide, outside UN auspices, the greatest amount of U.S. Government and privately donated relief to all affected areas in Sudan, including the Nuba Mountains, Upper Nile, and Blue Nile, in the event the Government of Sudan imposes a ban on OLS air transport relief flights.(Sec.11) Supports the President's ongoing efforts to diversify and increase effectiveness of U.S. assistance to populations in areas of Sudan outside of the control of the Government of Sudan, especially the long-term focus shown in the Sudan Transition Assistance for Rehabilitation (STAR) program with its emphasis on promoting democracy, self-reliance, and actively supporting people-to- people reconciliation efforts. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 12) Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should assess the humanitarian needs in the Nuba Mountains, Red Sea Hills, and Blue Nile regions of Sudan, and respond appropriately to those needs.(Sec. 13) Authorizes the President, for purposes of minimizing diversions of food assistance and to insulate noncombatants and the relief operations which serve them from combatants in areas outside the control of the Government of Sudan, to provide such assistance directly to the National Democratic Alliance or other groups engaged in the protection of civilian populations from attacks from regular government forces, associated militias, or other paramilitary groups supported by the Government of Sudan. Sets forth certain limits on, and eligibility requirements with, such assistance.</summary>
</bill>
