<bill session="105" type="h" number="4805" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-13T17:51:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-13T17:51:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require reports on travel of Executive branch officers and employees to international conferences, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10723-10724, H10799" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Hamilton objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-10-13T17:51:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-13T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="2634"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/1998--Introduced.
Requires each officer and employee of an executive agency who travels abroad to attend an international conference to submit to the Director of the Office of International Conferences of the Department of State a report on such travel. Excludes the President, the Vice President, and any employee who is carrying out an intelligence activity, performing a protective function, or engaged in a sensitive diplomatic mission. Requires the Director to submit biannual reports on such travel to the Senate Committees on Foreign Relations and Appropriations and the House Committees on International Relations and Appropriations Directs the President to submit to such committees annual reports setting forth: (1) the total Government expenditures on all official travel abroad by each executive agency during the preceding fiscal year; and (2) the total number of agency officers and employees who engaged in such travel.</summary>
</bill>
