<bill session="108" type="h" number="4808" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-28T15:27:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-28T15:27:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a land exchange involving private land and Bureau of Land Management land in the vicinity of Holloman Air Force Base, New Mexico, for the purpose of removing private land from the required safety zone surrounding munitions storage bunkers at Holloman Air Force Base.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-09-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Radanovich moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T15:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7669-7670" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T15:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4808.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-09-28T15:27:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7669" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2004--Passed House amended.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to Randal, Jeffrey, and Timothy Rabon (the Rabons) of Otero County, New Mexico, all right, title, and interest of the United States in a specified parcel of public land administered by the Secretary through the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) depicted on the map entitled "Alamogordo Rabon Land Exchange" dated September 24, 2004. Directs the Rabons, in exchange for such conveyance, to convey to the United States all right, title, and interest in a specified parcel of land that is contiguous to Holloman Air Force Base, New Mexico, and is located within the required safety zone surrounding munitions storage bunkers. Includes in such land exchanges the conveyance of all surface, subsurface, mineral, and water rights. Requires the Secretary to carry out the land exchanges in accordance with the Federal Land Policy Management Act of 1976 and to bear the costs of appraisals performed as part of the land exchanges. Authorizes a cash equalization payment in excess of 25 percent of the appraised value of the public lands to be conveyed to the Rabons.</summary>
</bill>
