<bill session="107" type="hc" number="49" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress that the Treaty Power of the President does not extend beyond the enumerated powers of the Federal Government, but are limited by the Constitution, and any exercise of such Executive Power inconsistent with the Constitution shall be of no legal force or effect.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2001-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="2001-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400305" joined="2002-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional powers"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Executive agreements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Privileges and immunities"/>
    <term name="Separation of powers"/>
    <term name="States' rights"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Treaty-making power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2001--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) no treaty that denies or abridges any constitutionally enumerated right or any powers reserved by the Constitution to the States or to the people shall be of any legal force or effect; (2) no treaty shall authorize any foreign power or international organization to oversee, supervise, monitor, control, or adjudicate citizens' legal rights, privileges, or immunities subject to the domestic jurisdiction of the United States or the States and that any decision of any international body to the contrary shall be disregarded by U.S. and State courts; (3) no treaty shall have any force or effect as law within the United States except as provided for by appropriate legislation duly enacted by Congress; and (4) no executive agreement or other agreement between the U.S. Government and the government of any other nation shall have any force or effect as law within the United States but shall be subject to the same procedures and limitations on treaties as set forth in the Constitution.</summary>
</bill>
