<bill session="105" type="h" number="2574" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To consolidate certain mineral interests in the National Grasslands in Billings County, North Dakota, through the exchange of Federal and private mineral interests to enhance land management capabilities and environmental and wildlife protection, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400323"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-30T14:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-471.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-03-30T14:48:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="271">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 271.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="750"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental degradation"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Grassland ecology"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Natural gas reserves"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/1997--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to the Burlington Resources Oil and Gas Company (formerly Meridian Oil Inc.) all Federal oil and gas rights and interests identified on a map entitled the "Billings County, North Dakota, Consolidated Mineral Exchange--November 1995," contingent on Burlington's conveyance to the Secretary of title to its own oil and gas rights and interests identified on the same map. States that the values of such exchanged oil and gas rights shall be deemed to be equal. Directs the Secretary, after Burlington makes such conveyance, to convey all remaining Federal non-oil and gas mineral rights, title, and interests in the National Forest System lands and National Grasslands in the State of North Dakota, to owners of the remaining non-oil and gas mineral interests identified on such map, contingent on the owners' conveyance to the Secretary of all their rights, title, and interests. States that the values of such exchanged interests shall be approximately equal, as determined by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to grant to Burlington the use of federally-owned surface lands to explore and develop interests conveyed to Burlington under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
