<bill session="106" type="h" number="514" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-25T11:49:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-02-25T11:49:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Wireless Privacy bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wireless Privacy Enhancement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Wireless Privacy Enhancement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to strengthen and clarify prohibitions on electronic eavesdropping, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400434"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400139" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400605" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1999-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1999-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-02-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-02-23T13:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Commerce. H. Rept. 106-24.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-02-23T13:30:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="14">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-02-23T16:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 77 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 514 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comploy with clause 4(a) of rule XIII are waived. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. During consideration of the bill for amendment, the chairman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whether the Member offering an amendment has caused it to be printed in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose. Amendments shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25T10:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 77 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 77.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H801-806" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 514 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 4(a) of rule XIII are waived. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. During consideration of the bill for amendment, the chairman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whether the Member offering an amendment has caused it to be printed in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose. Amendments shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 77 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ray LaHood to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25T11:25:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 514.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25T11:26:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25T11:26:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-02-25T11:49:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="28" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 403 - 3 (Roll no. 28).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25T11:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="77"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Eavesdropping"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Encryption"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Radio"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Warning labels"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h15"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>2/25/1999--Passed House amended.
Wireless Privacy Enhancement Act of 1999 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit modifying any electronic communication device, equipment, or system in a manner which causes it to fail to comply with regulations governing electronic eavesdropping devices. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to prescribe regulations (and review and revise them when necessary in response to changes in technology and behavior) denying equipment authorization for any scanning receiver capable of: (1) receiving transmissions in frequencies allocated to the domestic cellular or personal communications service; (2) being readily altered to receive such transmissions; (3) being equipped with decoders that convert domestic cellular or personal communications service or protected specialized mobile radio service transmissions to analog voice audio, or which convert protected paging service transmissions to alphanumeric text; or (4) being equipped with devices that otherwise encode encrypted radio transmissions for purposes of unauthorized interception. Directs the FCC, with respect to scanning receivers capable of receiving transmissions in frequencies used by commercial mobile services and that are shared by public safety users, to examine methods and prescribe regulations to enhance the privacy of users of such frequencies. Requires tampering prevention measures and warning labels to be considered by the FCC in prescribing such regulations. Applies penalties for the unauthorized publication or use of electronic communications to the unauthorized receipt, intentional interception, or intentional divulgence of any such communication. Directs the FCC to investigate alleged violations and proceed to initiate action to impose forfeiture penalties.</summary>
</bill>
