<amendment session="107" chamber="h" number="483" updated="2013-07-17T08:15:55-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="4737" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="2002-05-16T15:38:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <offered datetime="2002-05-16"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to expand state flexibility to provide training and education to welfare recipients, increase mandatory funding for child care by $11 billion over the next five years, and remove various barriers to serving legal immigrants.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in House Report 107-466 to expand state flexibility to provide training and education to welfare recipients (such activities would count for up to 24 months against a state's participation requirement); increase to 70 percent the number of welfare recipients that are required to be engaged in work-related activities; provide states with an employment credit that would reduce a state's participation requirement according to the number of welfare recipients that have left welfare for work over the last six months maintain the current-law requirement on total participation hours (30 per week with a State option to go higher) with a requirement that 24 hours be in certain activities; maintain the current 20-hour requirement for mother with young children; maintain the current five-year time limit on TANF benefits; increase mandatory funding for child care by $11 billion over the next five years and increase TANF for inflation; remove various barriers to serving local immigrants, including the current ban on states providing Federally-funded TANF benefits to immigrant families; and to include reducing poverty and increasing self-sufficiency as a new purpose of the TANF program and provide financial bonuses to states reducing child poverty.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-05-16T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Cardin.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2567-2590" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="H2591-2592"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H2567-2579" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-16T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A001) and on the bill pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2002-05-16T15:38:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="168">
      <text>On agreeing to the Cardin amendment (A001) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 198 - 222 (Roll no. 168).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
