<bill session="106" type="h" number="671" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transition to Adulthood Program Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to help children aging out of foster care to make the transition to becoming independent adults, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand the work opportunity tax credit to include individuals who were in foster care just before their 18th birthday, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1999-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1999-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1999-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="1999-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400383" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1999-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="1999-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-02-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E192"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="School-to-work transition"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/1999--Introduced.
Transition to Adulthood Program Act of 1999 - Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code with regard to the transition of foster children to self-sufficiency, including the provision of nonresidential services to assist in such transition, making respective changes chiefly: (1) allowing States with approved part E plans to make foster care maintenance payments with respect to a child who has not attained age 21 who would otherwise be ineligible for such payments because of age if the child is completing secondary education, is enrolled in an institution that provides postsecondary education or vocational training, or is employed for at least 80 hours per month, and has a case plan providing for the child's achievement of independent living and residence in a setting that promotes personal responsibility; and (2) expanding the work opportunity tax credit to include certain individuals who, on the day before before attaining age 18, received foster care maintenance payments under an approved State part E plan or were in foster care under the responsibility of the State. Provides for an increase in the amount of assets allowable for children in foster care under SSA title IV part E. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish an action plan to promote collaboration between HHS and other Federal programs to promote the self-sufficiency of children aging out of foster care. Provides, with respect to the independent living initiatives program under SSA title IV part E, for: (1) the use of updated foster care data in the funding formula for determining the basic amount for such program for a State for a fiscal year (while removing State entitlement to such basic amount under State plan provisions); and (2) a funding increase under such program.</summary>
</bill>
