<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="972" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="hc" number="312" sequence="3"/>
  <status datetime="2008-03-13T17:30:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="400351"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to balance the budget by 2012; retain provisions enacted in 2001/2003; prevent expansion of the AMT for the next 3 years and achieve full repeal in 2013. Amendment also sought to provide total discretionary budget authority of $1.04 trillion in fiscal year 2009, a 4.3-percent increase from 2008 enacted level;. impose a moratorium on congressional earmarks for the balance of the 110th Congress; require a separate vote on increasing the public debt; require cost estimates on conference reports and unreported bills; prohibit domestic add-ons to emergency war spending bills; limit long-term spending commitments; prevent use of reconciliation to increase spending; limit "advance appropriations" to $23.565 billion in 2010; provide a $7.3 billion domestic emergency reserve fund; provide for contingency war funds; incorporate bipartisan Legislative Line Item Veto and called for a 1 percent decrease in entitlement program spending.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute numbered 3 printed in House Report 110-548 to balance the budget by 2012, retain provisions enacted in 2001/2003, prevent expansion of the AMT for the next 3 years, and achieve full repeal in 2013. Provides total discretionary budget authority of $1.04 trillion in fiscal year 2009, a 4.3-percent increase from 2008 enacted level. It imposes a moratorium on congressional earmarks for the balance of the 110th Congress; requires a separate vote on increasing the public debt; requires cost estimates on conference reports and unreported bills; prohibits domestic add-ons to emergency war spending bills; limits long-term spending commitments; prevents use of reconciliation to increase spending; limits `advance appropriations' to $23.565 billion in 2010; provides a $7.3-billion domestic emergency reserve fund; provides for contingency war funds; incorporates bipartisan Legislative Line Item Veto. Calls for 1 percent decrease in entitlement program spending.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Ryan (WI).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1661-1680" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1661-1669" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2008-03-13T17:30:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="140">
      <text>On agreeing to the Ryan (WI) amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 157 - 263 (Roll no. 140).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
