<bill session="106" type="h" number="214" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Democracy 2000 Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restore the management and personnel authority of the Mayor of the District of Columbia and to expedite the suspension of activities of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E29"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Mayors"/>
    <term name="Municipal home rule"/>
    <term name="Municipal politics and government"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
District of Columbia Democracy 2000 Act - Amends the District of Columbia Code, as amended by the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 and the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997, to repeal the mandate and authority of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority to develop and implement management reform plans. (Thus restores the management and personnel authority of the Mayor of the District of Columbia.) Amends the District of Columbia Code, as amended by the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995 and the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, to reduce by one consecutive fiscal year the Authority's control period (thus suspending the Authority's control activities after April 15, 1998).</summary>
</bill>
