<bill session="104" type="h" number="472" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a priority in the disposal of real property resulting from the closure or realignment of military installations toward States and other entities that agree to convert the property into correctional facilities for youthful offenders to be operated as military-style boot camps and to require the Secretary of Defense to develop a program to promote the expanded use of such correctional facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on National Security, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-11">
      <text>Referred to House National Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-11">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-23">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Installations and Facilities.</text>
      <committee name="House National Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS04" subcommittee="Military Installations and Facilities" name="House National Security"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Military training camps"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Prison alternatives"/>
    <term name="Prison boot camps"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/11/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 and the Defense Authorization Amendments and Base Closure and Realignment Act to require the Secretary of Defense, before any action is taken with respect to the disposal or transfer of real property at a military facility being closed or realigned, to notify the State and each local government in which the facility is located, as well as other interested persons, of the suitability of the property or facility for conversion and use as a youthful offender boot camp. Requires the Secretary to transfer the property to a State, local government, or interested party that certifies that the property or facilities will be promptly converted and used for such purpose. Provides certification procedures to be followed by the Attorney General in the case of a certification submitted by a private person. Prohibits any transfer of property under this Act when the head of a military department or other Department of Defense entity notifies the Secretary that there is a further and compelling national security need for the property or facility. Directs the Secretary to develop a model program intended to incorporate military basic training, instruction, and disciplinary procedures into the design and operation of youthful offender boot camps at the Federal, State, and local levels. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to reallocate between public agencies and private nonprofit organizations the percentage of grant funds authorized under such Act for correctional options that provide alternatives to traditional modes of incarceration and offender release programs.</summary>
</bill>
