<bill session="104" type="h" number="2399" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Truth in Lending Act Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Truth in Lending Act Amendments of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to clarify the intent of such Act and to reduce burdensome regulatory requirements on creditors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400523" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="404634" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="409423" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1995-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1995-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-27T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Banking and Financial Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-27T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Leach asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-27T12:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9513-9516" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-27T12:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-27T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-09-27T12:51:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-09-27T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="1995-09-28" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14566-14568" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1995-09-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1995-09-29">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1995-09-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="1995-09-30" type="public" number="104-29">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 104-29.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance charges"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Settlement costs"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1995--Introduced.
Truth in Lending Act Amendments of 1995 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act (TILA) to exclude from the determination of finance charge for any consumer credit transaction fees imposed by third party closing agents, including settlement agents, attorneys, escrow and title companies, that are neither required nor retained by the creditor (thereby exempting such fees from TILA disclosure requirements). Modifies the determination of finance charge to include borrower-paid mortgage broker fees. Exempts from the required computation of finance charge: (1) certain taxes on security instruments or evidences of indebtedness if they are a prerequisite for recordation; (2) fees for loan document preparation; and (3) appraisal fees related to pest infestations and flood hazard inspections. Instructs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to report to the Congress on statutory or regulatory changes necessary to: (1) ensure that finance charges more accurately reflect the cost of credit; and (2) address abusive refinancing practices intended to avoid rescission. (Sec.3) Permits finance charge disclosures to vary within specified accuracy tolerance limits for certain consumer credit transactions secured by real property or a dwelling. Sets disclosure accuracy guidelines for per diem interest rate disclosures on consumer credit transactions. (Sec. 4) Shields a creditor or assignee, except in certain kinds of actions, from liability in connection with disclosures of: (1) certain fees, taxes, and charges; and (2) finance charges that fall within certain statutory tolerance limits. (Sec. 5) Restricts rescission liability arising from the form of written notice used by the creditor. (Sec. 6) Provides for damages ranging from $200 to $2,000 for an individual consumer credit transaction not under an open end credit plan that is secured by real property or a dwelling. (Sec. 7) Modifies assignee liability guidelines to: (1) apply them to consumer credit transactions secured by real property; and (2) provide that a violation is apparent on the face of the disclosure statement if the disclosure does not use the format required by law. States that the servicer of a consumer obligation arising from a consumer credit transaction shall not be treated as an assignee of an obligation unless the servicer owns it. (Sec. 8) Identifies circumstances under which a consumer has a right to rescind a consumer credit transaction after the initiation of any judicial or nonjudicial foreclosure process on the consumer's primary dwelling securing the debt.</summary>
</bill>
