<bill session="106" type="h" number="3831" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fire Safe Dorm Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require colleges and universities to disclose to students and their parents the incidents of fires in dormitories, and their plans to reduce fire safety hazards in dormitories, to require the United States Fire Administration to establish fire safety standards for dormitories, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="2000-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2000-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2000-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Basic Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Basic Research" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2178"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Flammable materials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Smoke detectors"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Student housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Obligations of Institutions of Higher Education Title II: Dormitory Fire Safety Standards Fire Safe Dorm Act of 2000 - Title I: Obligations of Institutions of Higher Education - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require higher education institutions, in order to be eligible for Student Assistance programs, to: (1) keep records of, and disclose, incidents of fires in dormitories, as well as current fire prevention measures there; (2) disclose their plans to bring all campus residential facilities into compliance with specified fire safety standards; and (3) adopt, within ten years of enactment of this Act, plans to install fire sprinklers, smoke detectors, and open flame resistant furniture in dormitories, in compliance with such standards.Exempts from such sprinkler installation requirement any buildings or other structures listed on the National Register for Historic Places, if installation would destroy historic materials, features, and spatial relationships that characterize the historic nature of the property.Title II: Dormitory Fire Safety Standards - Directs the Administrator of the U.S. Fire Administration to: (1) establish fire safety standards for dormitories, including mandatory fire sprinklers, smoke detectors, and open flame resistant furniture and mattresses; and (2) encourage State and local authorities to adopt such standards.</summary>
</bill>
