<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="1308" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:56-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="3734" sequence="3"/>
  <status datetime="1996-07-18T15:46:00-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor id="400395"/>
  <offered datetime="1996-07-18"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to provide that all recipients must work within 2 years of receiving benefits, and establish a 5-year time limit on cash assistance; require teenage mothers to stay in school and live with an adult to receive assistance, and establish a family cap halting benefits for additional children born to welfare recipients; provide States with the flexibility to design welfare reform proposals within broad Federal guidelines; and give States the option of providing vouchers for children or noncash emergency assistance to families that have lost cash assistance as a result of a time limit.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of the bill H.R. 3238. The amendment contains many provisions that are similar to those contained in the bill, but would require the states to provide assistance to children whose parents are denied benefits due to the five-year limitation on receiving benefits, specifies that food stamp benefits would be continued for children of legal aliens, and would not give states the option of accepting a block grant instead of participating in the food stamp program. States would be required to spend at least 85% of the amount they spent on welfare programs in FY 1994. The amendment would create an uncapped contingecy fund that states could draw from during an economic emergency and would provide an additional $3 billion for job training programs. Overall, the amendment would reduce welfare costs by $53 billion over six years, compared to $61.1 billion in savings provided in the bill.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-07-18T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Tanner.</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="1996-07-18T15:46:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="329">
      <text>On agreeing to the Tanner amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 168 - 258 (Roll no. 329).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
