<bill session="104" type="h" number="1752" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Bretton Woods Agreements Act to provide for public notice of all conditions imposed on any country with respect to the use of resources by the International Monetary Fund for monetary stabilization, and to provide for the proposal of amendments to the Articles of Agreement of the Fund to require each member country government to make monthly public reports on the financial condition of the country.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services. subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/1995--Introduced.
Amends the Bretton Woods Agreements Act to prohibit the payment of appropriated funds to the International Monetary Fund, unless: (1) the Fund has agreed, before it uses any resources for monetary stabilization, to report to the Secretary of the Treasury on all conditions, limitations, and restrictions imposed on any country with respect to such use; and (2) the Fund has not violated the agreement. Directs the Secretary to instruct the U.S. Executive Director of the Fund to propose amendments to the Articles of Agreement of the Fund as are necessary to require, as a condition of membership in the Fund, that each member country make public, on a monthly basis, a report on its financial condition.</summary>
</bill>
