<bill session="105" type="h" number="4087" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Demonstration Act Amendments of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Demonstration Act of 1992 to provide for the transfer of services and personnel from the Bureau of Indian Affairs to the Office of Self-Governance, to emphasize the need for job creation on Indian reservations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-06-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1162"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-23">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/1998--Introduced.
Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Demonstration Act Amendments of 1998 - Amends the Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Demonstration Act of 1992 to: (1) revise requirements regarding affected programs to include programs for securing employment, retaining employment, or creating employment opportunities or other programs relating to employment and permits such programs to include, at the option of a tribe, the general assistance program established under the Snyder Act and the Johnson-O'Malley Program established under the Johnson-O'Malley Act, if a tribe's plan includes educational services that familiarize elementary and secondary school students with aspects of employment; (2) require the Secretary of the Interior to reconsider disapproval of any statutory waiver requested by a tribe; (3) authorize the use of a percentage of funds made available by a Federal agency under a statutory or administrative formula for the creation of employment opportunities; and (4) transfer Federal responsibility for demonstration programs under the Act from the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) to the Office of Self-Governance (OSG) of the Department of the Interior and provide for the transfer of personnel and resources from BIA to OSG. Permits a regional consortium of Alaska Native villages or regional or village corporations to carry out a project under a plan that meets the Act's requirements through a resolution adopted by the governing body of that consortium or corporation. Provides that such authorization shall not prohibit such a village or corporation from withdrawing from participation in any portion of a program.</summary>
</bill>
