<bill session="107" type="h" number="4710" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 44, United States Code, to reduce paperwork burdens for small-business concerns.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400002" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2002-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2002-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2002-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2002-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E758"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2002--Introduced.
Requires each Federal agency, with respect to the collection of information and the control of paperwork, to estimate the type and number of small businesses to which each collection of information would apply and how the requirements of such collection would apply to each industry type.Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to: (1) take into account the burden placed on small businesses when approving proposed agency collections of information; (2) publish annually, and make available through the Internet, information regarding all Federal paperwork requirements applicable to small businesses; (3) track requirements for collections of information for which the authorization has expired and publish notice that entities need no longer comply with such requirements; and (4) identify requirements for collections of information for which authorization will soon expire and make efforts to prevent the continuation of collections using such authority.</summary>
</bill>
