<bill session="105" type="h" number="4138" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stolen Artwork Restitution Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage the identification and return of stolen artwork.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="1998-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1998-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1998-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="1998-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="1998-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1998-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1998-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="1998-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="1998-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="1998-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="1998-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1998-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Art objects"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/1998--Introduced.
Stolen Artwork Restitution Act of 1998 - Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants to qualified research organizations to identify and relocate stolen artwork. Directs the Attorney General to require reports from grant recipients as necessary and to transmit an annual report to the Congress listing the recipients. (Sec. 3) Authorizes an individual to request an inquiry upon producing sufficient evidence, according to standards established by the Attorney General, that artwork was stolen from the individual or from a member of the individual's family. Requires the seller or purchaser of artwork with a sales price of $5,000 or more that has been shipped in interstate or foreign commerce, if such request is made before the sale, to undertake a documented, reasonable inquiry into the ownership history of the artwork, including obtaining information from one or more missing or stolen artwork registries. (Sec. 4) Directs the Attorney General to undertake a documented, reasonable, multisource inquiry, including obtaining information from one or more missing or stolen artwork registries to determine whether any artwork in the possession of the Government has been stolen. Sets forth reporting requirements. (Sec. 5) Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) a purchaser or seller of artwork who fails to undertake an inquiry required under this Act should not be permitted to assert in a court in the United States a claim, under Federal, State, or otherwise applicable law, to ownership or former ownership of the artwork; (2) all museums and auction houses should undertake documented, reasonable, multisource inquiries, including obtaining information from one or more missing or stolen artwork registries to determine whether the artwork in their possession has been stolen; (3) all governments in possession of artwork stolen from victims of the Holocaust should return that artwork to its rightful owners; and (4) parties disputing the ownership of stolen artwork should attempt to resolve their disputes by alternative means, such as by arbitration, before seeking judicial remedies. (Sec. 6) Specifies that published or unpublished literary works shall not be considered artwork for purposes of this Act. (Sec. 8) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
