<bill session="106" type="h" number="4631" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Native Nations Institute for Leadership, Management, and Policy Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Native Nations Institute for Leadership, Management, and Policy to provide opportunities for leadership and management training and policy analysis for Native Americans, Alaska Natives, and others involved in tribal leadership and management, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2000-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E965"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-09">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-09">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Leadership"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2000--Introduced.
Native Nations Institute for Leadership, Management, and Policy Act of 2000 - Establishes at the Udall Center for Studies in Public Policy at the University of Arizona the Native Nations Institute for Leadership, Management, and Policy to promote leadership and management training and policy analysis for Native Americans, Alaska Natives, and others involved in tribal leadership and management.Directs the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation to award grants to the Center to provide startup funding for the Institute (conditioned on a 25 percent match from other sources). Requires the Foundation's Board of Trustees to approve the annual budget of the Institute.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
