<bill session="106" type="h" number="3035" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Utah National Parks and Public Lands Wilderness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate certain lands in the State of Utah as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-10-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9519"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Natural monuments"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Wilderness Areas in Utah National Park System Lands Title II: Public Land Wilderness Utah National Parks and Public Lands Wilderness Act - Title I: Wilderness Areas in Utah National Park System Lands - Designates specified lands within the following areas of Utah as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System: (1) Arches National Park; (2) Bryce Canyon National Park; (3) Canyonlands National Park; (4) Capitol Reef National Park; (5) Cedar Breaks National Monument; (6) Dinosaur National Monument; (7) Glen Canyon National Recreation Area; and (8) Zion National Park. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to administer and manage such lands. Authorizes on such designated lands the continuation of current livestock grazing, valid existing water rights, and overflights.Authorizes appropriations.Title II: Public Land Wilderness - Designates specified public lands in Utah as components of the System. Requires the Secretary to administer such lands.Prohibits the restriction or preclusion of low-level overflights and low-level military overflights over designated System lands, as well as the removal of existing communications and tracking systems. Prohibits restricting or precluding the timely access to any area to respond to emergency situations. Authorizes the control or restriction of public access to designated areas when required by national security or public safety. Authorizes on such designated lands the continuation of current livestock grazing and valid existing water rights.(Sec. 203) Provides for the release from wilderness designation, as well as study for possible designation, of certain lands in specified Utah counties.(Sec. 205) Withdraws lands designated under this title from all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, mining laws, and mineral and geothermal leasing.(Sec. 206) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
