<bill session="104" type="h" number="2522" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Remediation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a maximum level of remediation for dry cleaning solvents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400575" joined="1995-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="1995-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1995-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1996-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Cleaning industry"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Soil remediation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/24/1995--Introduced.
Small Business Remediation Act of 1995 - Requires the maximum level of remediation of dry cleaning solvents in soil, surface water, groundwater, and other environmental media (soil) that a Federal, State, local agency, or court may require of a person engaged in dry cleaning, or of the owner of land or a facility in which such a person is conducting dry cleaning, to be one-tenth the equivalent exposure of the workplace standard for such solvents established by the Secretary of Labor under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970. Requires: (1) the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences to publish in the Federal Register its computation, based on realistic scientific assumptions, of equivalent exposure by ingestion, inhalation, and absorption indices for the general public, for soil in nonoccupational circumstances; and (2) the equivalent exposure to be calculated from the workplace standard for dry cleaning solvents which assures that no employee will suffer material impairment of health or functional capacity even if such employee has regular exposure for the employee's entire working lifetime. Specifies that nothing in this Act shall: (1) preempt or otherwise prevent a Federal, State, or local government or private party from remediating soil to a lower level than the maximum level of remediation at its own cost and expense; or (2) alter or affect the Federal drinking water standards under the Public Health Service Act.</summary>
</bill>
