<bill session="105" type="h" number="3968" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Year 2000 Readiness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require within 90 days an assessment of, and a national strategy for addressing, the Year 2000 computer problem to ensure that critical public and private services to the American public are not disrupted, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1998-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1998-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1998-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committees on Government Reform and Oversight, and Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY17" subcommittee="Technology" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing personnel"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Year 2000 computer problem"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/1998--Introduced.
National Year 2000 Readiness Act - Directs the Chairperson of the Year 2000 Conversion Council to submit to the Congress: (1) a national assessment of the Year 2000 computer problem covering all critical national infrastructures and key sectors of the economy; and (2) a national strategy to ensure that the most critical services provided by the Federal, State, and local governments as well as key sectors of the economy will be prepared for the Year 2000 date change. Requires the Chairperson, in preparing the strategy, to: (1) include a plan for ensuring the availability of an adequate supply of technical personnel to remedy the Year 2000 computer problem in the private sector as well as the Federal Government before December 31, 1999; and (2) in formulating such plan, make recommendations relating to any need to raise immigrant visa ceilings under the Immigration and Nationality Act for such purpose. Requires the Chairperson, in preparing such plan, to: (1) make recommendations relating to the capacity of the Federal Government to attract and retain individuals of high-quality technology competence; and (2) consider whether a Federal technology information service should be established in a form similar to the Senior Executive Service. Directs the Chairperson, in preparing the strategy, to include: (1) the goals and strategies the United States will pursue at the Bank for International Settlements, the Group of Ten Industrialized Nations, the European Union, and elsewhere to encourage an international effort to ensure readiness for the Year 2000 at banks and other financial institutions; and (2) the initiatives which U.S. representatives to the International Monetary Fund, the International Bank for Development and Reconstruction, and other international development banks are taking to engage such institutions in providing funding or technical assistance to developing countries for remedying the Year 2000 computer problem. Requires the submission of quarterly progress reports after the submission of the report on the national assessment and strategy. Permits the revision of the Federal Acquisition Regulation to provide for an appropriate period for which contractors who knowingly provide goods or services to Federal agencies that are not Year 2000 compliant shall be ineligible for award of any Federal contract. Permits waiver of any restrictions developed pursuant to the revision of such Regulation, at the discretion of the applicable Federal agency, if the new goods or services are Year 2000 compliant.</summary>
</bill>
