<bill session="105" type="h" number="1467" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-15T11:56:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-15T11:56:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the continuance of oil and gas operations pursuant to certain existing leases in the Wayne National Forest.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400293"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-05">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-08-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-05T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-770.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-10-05T17:52:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="439">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 439.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-10-15T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Cubin moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-15T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10939-10940" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-15T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-10-15T11:56:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-10-15T11:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Severance tax"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/15/1998--Passed House amended.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into noncompetitive oil and gas production and reclamation contracts with well operators in the Wayne National Forest (Ohio) who meet specified statutory criteria pursuant to private land mineral leases, subject to the same laws and regulations that applied to such leases. Proscribes contractual arrangements authorizing deeper completions or additional drilling. Requires contracts to require contractors to provide a Federal oil and gas bond to ensure complete and timely reclamation of the former lease tract in accordance with regulations of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and the Forest Service, unless the Secretary accepts in lieu thereof assurances from the Ohio Department of Natural Resources, Division of Oil and Gas, that: (1) the contractor is in compliance with specified Ohio bonding requirements; (2) the United States is entitled to receive funding under Ohio law to properly plug and restore oil and gas sites and lease tracts; and (3) at least 20 percent of Ohio State severance tax revenues have been allocated to the State of Ohio Orphan Well Fund. Declares that, in entering into any contract under this Act, the Secretary shall reserve the right to require contractor compliance with BLM and Forest Service oil and gas lease bonding requirements whenever the Secretary finds that less than 20 percent of State severance tax revenues has been allocated to such Fund.</summary>
</bill>
