<bill session="104" type="h" number="3470" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Minnesota National Treasures Conservation and Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance the conservation and protection of the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness and the Voyageurs National Park.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400612"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E820"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Snowmobiles"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/1996--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: The Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness Preservation Title II: The Voyageurs National Park Preservation Act Minnesota National Treasures Conservation and Protection Act - Title I: The Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness Preservation - Amends the Wilderness Act to designate the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness. Modifies the area within which the use of motorboats with motors no greater than 25 horsepower is permitted to include Pipestone Bay of Basswood and that portion of Jackfish Bay of Basswood generally south of the narrows at the north end of Jackfish Bay. Repeals a provision specifying that nothing in such law shall be construed to limit mechanical portages or the horsepower of motors used on motorboats on Loon Lake, Saint Louis County, and that portion of the Lac La Croix, Saint Louis County, south of Snow Bay and east of Wilkins Bay. Makes the provisions of an executive order establishing an airspace reservation over certain areas of the Superior National Forest, Minnesota, applicable to the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness. Title II: The Voyageurs National Park Preservation Act - Designates the Voyageurs National Park Wilderness. Directs that such Wilderness, subject to valid existing rights, be administered by the Secretary of the Interior in accordance with applicable provisions of the Wilderness Act. Requires the Secretary to continue to provide for the use of existing safety portages for snowmobiles.</summary>
</bill>
