<bill session="105" type="h" number="2610" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-21T16:22:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-10-21T16:22:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Narcotics Leadership bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Narcotics Leadership Act Amendments of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Narcotics Leadership Act Amendments of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Narcotics Leadership Act of 1988 to extend the authorization for the Office of National Drug Control Policy until September 30, 1999, to expand the responsibilities and powers of the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1997-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1997-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-10-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-10-21T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastert moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-21T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8874-8882" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-21T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-10-21T16:22:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-10-21T16:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-11-06">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-11-06">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Reported to Senate by Senator Hatch with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-11-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="273">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 273.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Agricultural statistics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Cocaine"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug legalization"/>
    <term name="Drug policy"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Heroin"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Marijuana"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Psychotropic drugs"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/6/1997--Reported to Senate amended.
Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 1997 - Amends the National Narcotics Leadership Act of 1988 to add and revise definitions. Reestablishes the responsibilities of the Office of National Drug Control Policy and revises its responsibilities to include the development of national drug control policy, coordination and oversight of the implementation of such policy, assessment and certification of the adequacy of national drug control programs and the budget for those programs, and the evaluation of the effectiveness of such programs. Revises provisions concerning Deputy Director offices and responsibilities, including to provide for: (1) a Deputy Director of National Drug Control Policy; and (2) a Deputy Director for State and Local Affairs. Establishes in the Treasury a fund for the receipt of gifts to aid or facilitate the work of the Office. Sets forth or modifies provisions regarding the responsibilities and coordination of national drug control program agencies and the drug control budget request certification process. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to annually submit an assessment of the acreage of illegal drug cultivation in the United States. Revises provisions regarding the National Drug Control Strategy to require: (1) the President to submit to the Congress by February 1, 1997, a Strategy which sets forth a comprehensive plan, covering a period of not more than ten years, for reducing drug abuse and the consequences of drug abuse in the United States, by limiting the availability of and reducing the demand for illegal drugs; and (2) annual reports on progress in implementing the Strategy. Permits the President to submit a revised Strategy that meets the requirements of this Act under specified conditions. Requires the Director of National Drug Control Policy to submit a description of the national drug control performance measurement system. Requires the inclusion of a description of any modifications made during the preceding year to the performance measurement system to be included in each annual report. Establishes in the Office a High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program. Revises provisions regarding the Counter-Drug Technology Assessment Center, which shall be directed by a Director of Technology whose duties shall include identifying demand reduction basic and applied research needs and initiatives. Requires the Departments of Defense and Health and Human Services to render assistance and support to the Office and to the Director in the conduct of counter-drug technology assessment. Terminates the Office on September 30, 2001. Establishes the President's Council on Counter-Narcotics to advise and assist the President in: (1) providing direction and oversight for the national drug control strategy, including relating drug control policy to other national security interests and establishing priorities; and (2) ensuring coordination among Federal agencies concerning the implementation of the President's national drug control strategy. Requires the Director to serve as the Executive Director of the Council, the senior drug control policy official in the executive branch, and the chief drug control policy spokesman for the President. Requires the Director to work in conjunction with the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs. Establishes the Parents Advisory Council on Youth Drug Abuse to advise the President and the Cabinet, including the Director, on drug prevention, education, and treatment and issue reports and recommendations as considered, in addition to submitting annual reports to the Director. Authorizes appropriations to the Council of such sums as may be necessary. Authorizes appropriations of such sums as may be necessary for FY 1998 through 2001. (Sec. 3) Sets forth drug interdiction reporting requirements relating to the budget process. (Sec. 4) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the President should discuss with the democratically-elected governments of the Western Hemisphere the prospect of forming a multilateral alliance to address problems relating to international drug trafficking in the Western Hemisphere. Requires a specified report.</summary>
</bill>
