<bill session="105" type="h" number="976" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-09-08T14:08:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-09-08T14:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mississippi Sioux Tribes Judgment Fund Distribution Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Mississippi Sioux Tribes Judgment Fund Distribution Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Mississippi Sioux Tribes Judgment Fund Distribution Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the disposition of certain funds appropriated to pay judgment in favor of the Mississippi Sioux Indians, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400587"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1997-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="1997-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-24">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-07-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-09-03T19:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-242.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-09-03T19:11:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="138">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 138.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-09-08T14:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hill moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-08T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6967-6968" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-08T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-09-08T14:08:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-09-08T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-21">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-11-04">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="391"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="391"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/1997--Passed House amended.
Mississippi Sioux Tribes Judgment Fund Distribution Act of 1997 - Provides for distribution to, and use of certain funds by, the Sisseton and Wahpeton Tribes of Sioux Indians. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of the Interior, one year after enactment of this Act, to distribute specified amounts to the tribal governing body of the: (1) Spirit Lake Sioux Tribe of North Dakota; (2) Sisseton and Wahpeton Sioux Tribe of South Dakota; and (3) Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes of the Fort Peck Reservation in Montana. Designates the Sisseton and Wahpeton Sioux Council of the Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes as the tribal governing body of the Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes of the Fort Peck Reservation. (Sec. 5) Directs each tribal governing body, as a condition for receiving the distributed funds, to establish a tribal trust fund for the benefit of the covered Indian tribe under its jurisdiction. Requires that each tribal governing body shall: (1) serve as the trustee of the trust fund; and (2) administer the trust fund. (Sec. 6) Prohibits funds distributed to a covered Indian tribe from being used to make per capita payments to members of the covered Indian tribe. Allows funds distributed to be used by a tribal governing body only for the purpose of making investments or expenditures that the tribal governing body determines to be related to: (1) economic development that is beneficial to the covered Indian tribe; (2) the development of resources of the covered Indian tribe; or (3) the development of a program that is beneficial to members of the covered Indian tribe, including educational and social welfare programs. Directs the Secretary to conduct an annual audit. (Sec. 7) Sets forth provisions concerning the effect of payments to a covered Indian tribe or an individual on eligibility for, or the reduction or denial of, Federal benefits. (Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary, not later than one year after enactment, to distribute a specified amount to the lineal descendants of the Sisseton and Wahpeton Tribes of Sioux Indians.</summary>
</bill>
